<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1393</YEAR>
<VOL>12</VOL>
<NO>4</NO>
<MOSALSAL>4</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>138</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>صفحات آغازین</TitleF>
				<TitleE>First Pages</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT></CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>-</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>3</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>آسیب شناسی چالش ها و مشکلات دختران در جوامع روستایی (مورد مطالعه‌: دهستان ماهیدشت شهرستان کرمانشاه)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A pathology of the challenges and problems of girls in rural communities (Case study: Mahidasht Region of Kermanshah County)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>توسعۀ منابع انسانی عامل کلیدی و پیش‌شرط لازم برای دستیابی به توسعۀ پایدار روستایی به‌شمار می‌رود. در این بین توجه به زنان و دختران روستایی، به‌منزلۀ نیمی از منابع انسانی بالقوۀ فعال جوامع روستایی، بر کسی پوشیده نیست. از‌این‌رو، جهت تحقق رشد و توسعة بلندمدت در این جوامع، پرداختن به مسائل و مشکلات آنان ضرورتی انکارناپذیر است. بنابراین، این پژوهش با هدف آسیب‌شناسی چالش‌ها و مشکلاتدختران در جوامع روستاییانجام گرفت. جامعۀ مطالعه‌شده در این پژوهش را دختران دهستان ماهیدشت شهرستان کرمانشاه (3600N=) تشکیل دادند. سپس، با استفاده از روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی، 132 نفر از آنان برای نمونۀ تحقیق انتخاب و به‌صورت انتساب متناسب این تعداد نمونه در میان 10 روستای این دهستان توزیع شدند. ضریب پایایی تحقیق نیز با استفاده از آلفای کرونباخ 7/0 به‌دست آمد. طبق نتایج به‌دست‌آمده از تحلیل عاملی، پنج عامل آسیب‌های روانی، فقر آموزشی‌ـ رفاهی، آسیب‌های اجتماعی، فقر اقتصادی‌ـ بهداشتی، و چالش‌های فراروی ازدواج، 53/65‌درصد مشکلات دختران روستایی را به‌خود اختصاص داده‌اند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Human resources development is a key factor and a pre-requisite for achieving sustainable rural development. Therefore, it is necessary to pay attention to rural women and girls, as half of the human resource potential of rural communities.Women and girls form an important part of society toward rural sustainability development because of their role as future mothers. So, improving their situation leads to improve the situation of rural communities in the future. Also, it is crucial to solve their problems to achieve sustainable growth and development in these communities. Therefore, pathology of the challenges and problems of girls in the rural communities is the main concern of the current study. A total of 3600 girls (N=3600) in Mahdasht reign were selected based on simple random sampling (n= 132), among ten villages by assigning appropriate method. Research instrument was a questionnaire the reliability of which was confirmed by Cronbach&#039;s alpha coefficients (α= 0.7). Factor analysis was used to analyze the data. Research findings indicated five factors including psychological trauma, less education– welfare, social pathologies, economic– health poverty and the girls facing challenges in the marriage, to form 65.53 percent of total variance of girls&#039; problems.    </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>489</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>506</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فرحناز</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رستمی</Family>
						<NameE>Farahnaz</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rostami</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار و عضو هیئت علمی پردیس کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی دانشگاه رازی کرمانشاه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار و عضو هیئت علمی پردیس کشاورزی و</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>fr304@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ماریه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صحرایی</Family>
						<NameE>Mariyeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sahraee</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی دانشگاه رازی کرمانشاه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mariyeh.sahraie@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>طاهره</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ملکی</Family>
						<NameE>Tahere</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Maleki</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری توسعۀ کشاورزی دانشگاه تبریز</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری توسعۀ کشاورزی دانشگاه تبریز</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>golenarjes_313@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فاطمه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ساسانی</Family>
						<NameE>Fatemeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sasani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی دانشگاه رازی کرمانشاه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>fateme.sasani@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهنا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شاهمرادی</Family>
						<NameE>Mahna</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Shahmoradi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری توسعۀ کشاورزی دانشگاه رازی کرمانشاه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری توسعۀ کشاورزی دانشگاه رازی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>shahmorade44@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دختران روستایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آسیب‌شناسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تحلیل عاملی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دهستان ماهیدشت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] آل آقا، فریده (1385). «شناسایی مشاغل درآمدزا برای زنان روستایی و تعیین نیازهای آموزشی و مهارت‌های متناسب با آن»، پژوهش زنان، ش11، ص147ـ169.##[2] ابتکار، تقی (1371). «معرفی آموزش‌های علمی کاربردی در ایران»، مجلة شریف، س اول، ش2، ص22.##[3] افشارکهن، جواد (1388). «گونه‌شناسی مسائل اجتماعی جوانان ایران با تأکید بر دختران روستایی»، فصلنامۀ مطالعات راهبردی زنان، س11، ش44، صص‌111ـ144.##[4] ثابت‌قدم، شهین (1391). «نقش و جایگاه زنان در توسعۀ روستایی»،‌ ماهنامۀ فرزانه، اردیبهشت1391، ش2 و3.##[5] خانی، فضیله؛ احمدی، منیژه (1388). «تبیین عوامل مؤثر بر مشارکت زنان در تصمیم‌گیری‌های اقتصادی‌ـ اجتماعی در مناطق روستایی»، پژوهش زنان، دورۀ 7، ش4.##[6] سعدی، حشمت‌اله؛ لطیفی، سمیه؛ ودادی، الهام (1391). «بررسی مشکلات و مسائل دختران روستایی در استان همدان»، فصلنامۀروستاوتوسعه، س15، ش1، ص153ـ176.##[7] شادی‌طلب، ژاله؛ وهابی، معصومه؛ ورمزیار، حسن (1384). «فقر درآمدی فقط یک جنبه از فقر زنان سرپرست خانوار»، فصلنامۀ رفاه اجتماعی، س4، ش17.##[8] شهبازی، اسماعیل (1372). «توسعهوترویجروستایی». انتشارات دانشگاه تهران.##[9] ضمیری، محمدرضا (1382). «دختران و ازدواج تحمیلی»، فصلنامة مطالعات راهبردی زنان، س7، ش24، ص30ـ67.##[10] صالح‌نسب، غلام‌حسین (1378). «نقش زنان در توسعۀ کشاورزی»، سازمان فائو، مجلۀ جهاد، ش3.##[11] صفری شالی، ر. (1380). نقش توانمندی اقتصادی و اجتماعی زنان در توسعة پایدار روستایی، مجموعه مقالات همایش اعتبارات خرد زنان روستایی و عشایر: معاونت ترویج و مشارکت مردمی وزارت جهاد کشاورزی، ص113ـ138.##[12] طالبی‌فر، محمدرضا (1382). «بررسی عوامل اجتماعی‌ـ اقتصادی مؤثر بر اشتغال زنان (مورد مطالعه: شهرستان قائنات)»، پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد جامعه‌شناسی، اصفهان: دانشکدۀ ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه اصفهان.##[13] عباس‌زاده، محمد؛ بوداقی، علی؛ اقدسی علمداری، فرانک (1390). «توانمند‌سازی زنان سرپرست خانوار با تأکید بر راهکارهای بومی»، همایش ملی توانمندسازی با رویکرد جهاد اقتصادی در کمیتۀ امداد امام خمینی(ره)، خرداد ماه، تهران.##[14] غفاری، غلامرضا؛ تاج‌الدین، محمدباقر (1384). «شناسایی مؤلفه‏های محرومیت اجتماعی»، فصلنامۀ علمی پژوهشی رفاه اجتماعی، س4، ش17، ص1ـ27.##[15] عبدالهی، محمد (1386). مجموعهمقالاتهمایشملیزنانوچالش‌های پیش رو، ج3، انتشارات برگ‌آذین به سفارش دانشگاه ایلام.##[16] فرضی زاده، زهرا (1393). «طرد اجتماعی دختران روستایی مجرد»، فصلنامۀ توسعۀ روستایی، دورۀ 6، ش اول، ص123ـ146.##[17] فیروزآبادی، سید احمد؛ صادقی، علیرضا (1389). «وضعیت طرد اجتماعی زنان فقیر روستایی»، مجلۀ بررسی مسائل اجتماعی، س اول، ش اول.##[18] گیدنز، آنتونی (1392). جامعه‌شناسی، ترجمۀ حسن چاوشیان، تهران: نی.##[19] لطیفی، سمیه؛ سعدی، حشمت‌الله، شعبانعلی فمی، حسین (1392). «تحلیل عاملی مشکلات زنان قالی‌باف روستایی»،‌ فصلنامۀ علمی‌ـ پژوهشی زن و جامعه، س4، ش اول، ص29ـ51.##[20] مجدالدین، اکبر (1386). «بررسی دلایل و آثار افزایش سن ازدواج دختران روستایی»، پژوهشنامة علوم انسانی، س8، ش53، صص 375ـ386.##[21] میرک‌زاده، علی‌آبادی؛ و. شمس، ع. (1389). «واکاوی مانع‌های مشارکت زنان روستایی در برنامه‌های آموزشی و ترویجی»، فصلنامۀروستاوتوسعه، ش2، س13.##[22] نقدی، اسداله؛ بلالی، اسماعیل (1389). «مسئلۀ اجتماعی خاموش و نامرئی: کاهش شانس ازدواج برای دختران روستایی (با تأکید بر یافته‌هایی از نقاط روستایی همدان)»، مجلۀ توسعۀ روستایی، دورۀ دوم، ش2، پاییز و زمستان 1389.##[23] Asante, Wrigley and Charlotte (2008). ‘Men are poor but women are poorer: Gendered poverty and survival strategies in the Dangme West District of Ghana’, Norwegian Journal of Geography##[24] International Fund for Agricultural Development (IFAD) (2011). ‘Equality begins at home for rural girls and women’ Available on: http://www.ifad.org/media/events/2012/women.htm.Retrieved at: 15/08/2011.##[25] Qiang, Dong; Xiaoyun,Li ; Hongping, Yang and Keyun, Zhang (2008). ‘Gender Inequality in Rural Education and Poverty’ Chinese Sociology &amp; Anthropology##[26] Sen. A. (1885). Commodities and Capabilities. North Holland, Amsterdam.##[27] Shaaban, Safaa (2011). ‘A Conceptual Framework Review of Social Exclusion,and its Relation with Social Cohesion and Poverty in Europe’. The International Journal of Diversity in Organisations, Communities and Nations, 11(1), pp 117-131.##[28] Social Exclusion Unit (2008). ‘Social Exclusion and Why It Matters In David Byrne’. Social Exclusion; Critical Concept In Mobility Sociology (333-347). Vol I Social Exclusion – the History and Use of a Concept.##[29] Townson, M. (2009). ‘Women&#039;s Poverty and recession’. Canadian center For Policy Alternative (CCPA). Available on: http://www. Policy Alternatives.ca/publications/reports/womens Poverty and recession. Retrieved at :20/11/2010.##[30] UNDP (2011). ‘Human development report 2011’. Available on: http://www.undp.org/content/en/home/librarypage/hdr/human_developmentreport2011.html. Retrieved at:10/10/2011.##[31] UNFPA (2011). ‘The state of world population 2011’. Available on: http://foweb.unfpa.org/SWP2011/reports/EN-SWOP2011-FINAL.pdf. Available on:06/02/2011.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مطالعۀ کیفی شرایط و زمینه‌های شکل‌گیری ازدواج موقت زنان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A qualitative study on terms and conditions of women&#039;s temporary marriage</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هرچند ازدواج موقت یکی از اشکال ازدواج‏های مشروع به لحاظ تطابق با نهادهای حقوقی و دینی حاکم بر جامعۀ‏ ایران است، در پژوهش حاضر به‌منزلۀ یک سنت اجتماعی و قرائت عرفی‌شده یک حکم دینی مورد توجه بوده است. در این مطالعه، به درک و تصوری که از عوامل زمینه‏ساز و انگیزه‏های ازدواج موقت زنان وجود دارد پرداخته شده است. این مهم از طریق روش کیفی و با اتخاذ تکنیک مصاحبۀ عمیق انجام پذیرفته است. یافته‏های پژوهش از خلال مصاحبه با 26 زن ساکن شهر تهران، که برخی دارای تجربۀ ازدواج موقت و برخی فاقد این تجربه بوده‏اند، به‌دست آمده است. نتایج این پژوهش نشان می‏دهد از نظر مشارکت‏کنندگان، «فشار اجتماعی»، «تسهیل دینی»، «فشار فرهنگی»، «احساس نیاز اساسی»، «ناکارآمدی تعاملات زناشویی (به‌خصوص برای برخی مردان)»، «فراهم‌نبودن موقعیت ازدواج دائم»، «فرار از تعهدات ازدواج دائم»، «زمینه‏سازی برای ازدواج دائم»، «تنوع‏طلبی‌ـ سیالیت»، و «رجحان نسبی ازدواج موقت به رابطۀ خارج‏ از‏ چارچوب»، شرایط و زمینه‏های تأثیر‏گذار بر ازدواج موقت زنان‌اند. ذکر این نکته ضروری است که یافته‏ها، ماهیت بسترمند و موقعیتی دارند و به‌هیچ‌وجه از تعمیم آماری کمّی برخوردار نیستند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Although temporary marriage is a form of legitimate marriages in conformity with legal and religious institutions of the Iranian society, in this study it has been considered as a social tradition and customary recitation of a religious order. In this study, the perception of respondents about the conditions and motives that lead to temporary marriage has been investigated. Qualitative method and emic approach have been applied for this aim. Data is collected through depth interviews with 26 women who reside in the city of Tehran (whether they have practiced mut&#039;a or not). Concluding points of depth interviews revealed that &quot;social strain&quot;, &quot;religious facilitation&quot;, &quot;cultural strain&quot;, &quot;a feeling of essential need&quot;, &quot;deficiency of marital interaction&quot;, &quot;lack of opportunity for permanent marriage&quot;, &quot;escape from permanent marriage and its commitments”, “relative preference of temporary marriage over illegal relationship” and preparation of the stage for permanent marriage are conditions which affect the temporary marriage for women. It should be mentioned that the results of this study are largely exploratory and do not attempt to generalize in any way, due to the small sample size.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>507</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>523</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عبدالحسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کلانتری</Family>
						<NameE>Abdol Hosein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Kalantari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه جامعه شناسی دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه جامعه شناسی دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>abkalantari@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سهیلا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صادقی فسایی</Family>
						<NameE>Soheila</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sadeghi Fasaei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه جامعه شناسی دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه جامعه شناسی دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ssadeghi@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>صدیقه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رضانیا</Family>
						<NameE>Sedigheh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rezaniya</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مطالعات زنان دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مطالعات زنان دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>se.rezania@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ازدواج دائم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ازدواج موقت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>روش کیفی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زنان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>آذرکمان، زهره (1386). «بررسی آسیب‌های اجتماعی ازدواج موقت در ایران»، پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد، تهران، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس.##استراوس، انسلم ال؛ کربین، جولیت (1390). مبانی پژوهش کیفی: فنون و مراحل تولید نظریۀ زمینه‏ای، ترجمۀ ابراهیم افشار، تهران: نی.##اسکیدمور، ویلیام (1372). تفکر نظری در جامعه‏شناسی، ترجمۀ علی محمد حاضری و دیگران، تهران: سفیر.##ایمانی‏راد، لیلا؛ وزیری‏فرد، محمدجواد (1388). «ماهیت متعه زن»، بانوان شیعه، بهار، ش 19: ص187ـ224.##باومن، زیگمونت (1384). عشق سیال: در باب ناپایداری پیوند‌های انسانی، ترجمۀ عرفان ثابتی، تهران: ققنوس.##بدار، لوک؛ دزیل، ژوزه؛ لامارش، لوک (1387). روان‏شناسی اجتماعی، ترجمۀ حمزه گنجی. چ6، ساوالان.##پریشی، معصومه (1387). «زمینه‏ها و پیامد‏های ازدواج موقت»، پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد، تهران، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی.##تانگ، رزمری (1387). نقد و نظر: درآمدی جامع بر نظریه‏های فمینیستی، ترجمۀ منیژه نجم‌عراقی، تهران: نی.##توسلی، غلامعباس (1387). نظریه‏های جامعه‏شناسی، چ14، تهران: سمت.##جزایری، محمد (1381). ازدواج موقت (و گذر از بحران)، تهران: قادر.##حائری، شهلا (2010).المتعه الزواج الموقت عند الشیعه حاله ایران (1978- 1982)، ترجمۀ فادی حمود، الطبعه الثالثه عشره، بیروت: شرکه المطبوعات للتوزیع و النشر.##حجتی، احمد (1370). در مسیر زندگی با ازدواج دائم یا موقت؟، قم: ناشر مؤلف.##رافعی، طلعت (1382). تحلیلی بر روانشناسی زن در ازدواج موقت، تهران: دانژه.##سعیدی، علی‌اصغر (1378). «بدن و فرهنگ مصرفی»، در: مطالعات فرهنگی، مصرف فرهنگی، و زندگی روزمره در ایران، گردآورندۀ عباس کاظمی، تهران: انتشارات جهاد دانشگاهی دانشگاه تهران.##صادقی فسایی، سهیلا (1390). جزوۀ روش تحقیق کیفی، دانشکدۀ علوم اجتماعی دانشگاه تهران.##فلیک، اووه (1390). درآمدی بر تحقیق کیفی، ترجمۀ هادی جیلی، چ3، تهران: نی.##قانون حمایت خانواده، مصوب 1/12/1391.##گود، ویلیام جی (1352). خانواده و جامعه، ترجمۀ ویدا ناصحی، تهران: بنگاه ترجمه و نشر کتاب.##گیدنز، آنتونی (1383). جامعه‏شناسی، ترجمۀ منوچهر صبوری، چ11، تهران: نی.##محقق دایکندی، محمداکبر (1386). «ازدواج موقت در قرآن کریم»، ماهنامۀ سفیر، بهار، ش1، ص157ـ202.##مزلو، ابراهام اچ (1372). انگیزش و شخصیت، ترجمۀ احمد رضوانی، چ3، مشهد: مؤسسۀ چاپ و انتشارات آستان قدس رضوی مشهد.##موسوی، سید حجت (1385). «ازدواج موقت، حکمت‏ها، و ضرورت‌ها»، دوماهنامۀ مبلغان، آذر و دی، ش 85، ص38ـ52.##مورالی‏دانینو، آندره (1383). جامعه‏شناسی روابط جنسی، ترجمۀ حسن پویان، تهران: توس.##میرخانی، عزت‌السادات (1379). «مرزشناسی در ازدواج موقت (قسمت اول)»، مطالعات راهبردی زنان (کتاب زنان سابق)، پاییز، ش 9، ص7ـ26.##میرخانی، عزت‌السادات (1379). «مرزشناسی در ازدواج موقت (قسمت دوم)»، مطالعات راهبردی زنان (کتاب زنان سابق)، زمستان، ش10، ص6ـ23.##وکیلی، شروین (1383). «دگردیسی صمیمیت»، کتاب ماه علوم اجتماعی، اسفند، ش 89، ص71ـ75.##Corbetta,Piergiorgio (2003). Social Research: Theory, Method and Techniques. Translated by Bernard Patrick. London: SAGE Publications.##Haeri Sh. (1992). Temporary Marriage and the State in Iran: An Islamic Discourse on Female Sexuality, Social Research, Vol 59, No 1, 201-223.##Manning W D.; Smock P J. (2005). Measuring and Modeling Cohabitation: New Perspectives from Qualitative Data, Journal of Marriage and Family, 989-1002.##Nagar R. (2000).Religion, Race, and the Debate over Mut&#039;a in Dar es Salaam. Feminist Studies. 26, no 3. pp 661-690.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>سنجش عوامل جمعیتی مؤثر بر مشارکت اقتصادی زنان در منطقۀ شهری ایران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Measurement of effective demographic factors on women&#039;s economic participation in urban areas of Iran</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>امروزه، میزان مشارکت زنان در بازار کار به‌منزلۀ یکی از عوامل توسعه‏یافتگی جوامع شناخته‏ می‏شود؛ از‌این‏رو، این پژوهش به بررسی عوامل اثرگذار مانند آموزش، وضعیت زناشویی، سن زن، و سرپرست خانوار بودن زن بر احتمال مشارکت زنان در بازار کار می‏پردازد. بدین منظور، از ریزداده‏های طرح هزینه‌ـ درآمد خانوار شهری مرکز آمار ایران در سال 1390 و از مدل پروبیت داده‏های تابلویی و روش برآورد حداکثر درستنمایی استفاده شده‏ است. براساس نتایج برآورد، انتظار می‏رود که در مناطق شهری ایران، آموزش در مقاطع پایین تحصیلی (ابتدایی و راهنمایی)، انگیزه‏ای برای ورود زنان به بازار کار نباشد؛ اما تحصیل در مقاطع بالاتر، به‌خصوص در دانشگاه، سبب ورود زنان به بازار کار شود. از نظر تأثیر وضعیت زناشویی، مطلقه و مجرد بودن زنان اثر مثبت، ولی بی‏همسر بودن بر اثر فوت اثر منفی بر احتمال مشارکت زنان در بازار کار دارند. رابطة میان سن و احتمال مشارکت زنان، U وارونه است؛ بدین مفهوم که در سن جوانی احتمال ورود زنان به بازار کار بیش از دوران میانسالی است. سرپرست خانوار بودن زن نیز بر احتمال مشارکت زنان اثر مثبت می‏گذارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Nowadays, the female participation rate is known as one of the reasons of societies&#039; development. Hence, this study explores some of the effective factors such as education, marital status, age, and female-headed households on female participation probability in labor market. To achieve this goal, by using micro data of household survey in 2011, which is carried out by the Statistical Center of Iran, Panel Data with Limited Dependent Variable Models is estimated with maximum likelihood approach. Based on the obtained results, in the urban area of Iran, low levels of education (primary and secondary), could not cause the entry of women into the labor market, higher levels of education, however, especially university education, would cause the entry of women into the labor market. Divorced and single women have a positive effect on the probability of female participation rate, but widows have shown to have a negative effect. The relationship between age and the likelihood of participation of women is an inverted U; that is, at a young age, women are more likely to take part in the labor market than middle-age women. Being female-headed households also has a positive effect on the probability of female participation.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>525</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>544</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>زهرا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>میلا علمی</Family>
						<NameE>Zahra</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mila Elmi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار اقتصاد دانشگاه مازندران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار اقتصاد دانشگاه مازندران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>zelmila@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>شهریار</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>زروکی</Family>
						<NameE>Shahyar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Zaroki</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار اقتصاد دانشگاه مازندران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار اقتصاد دانشگاه مازندران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>zarokish@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سیده مونا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مهدوی‌چابک</Family>
						<NameE>Sayyedeh Mona</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mahdavi Chabok</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد اقتصاد دانشگاه مازندران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد اقتصاد دانشگاه مازندران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>s.mona_mahdavi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نرخ مشارکت زنان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آموزش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>وضعیت زناشویی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدل داده‏های تابلویی با متغیر وابستۀ دوتایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ریزداده‏های طرح هزینه‌ـ درآمد خانوار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>منطقۀ شهری ایران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] روستایی شلمانی، خیزران (1390). «تأثیر آموزش بر نرخ مشارکت زنان در کشورهای خاورمیانه و شمال افریقا»، پایان‏نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه مازندران، دانشکدۀ اقتصاد و علوم اداری.##[2] کار، مهرانگیز (1379). زنان در بازار کار ایران، تهران: روشنگران و مطالعات زنان.##[3] کاوند، حسین؛ عوضعلی‌پور، محمد‌صادق؛ زندی، فاطمه؛ دامن‌کشیده، مرجان (1390). «نقش جنسیت در مشارکت اقتصادی و عوامل مؤثر بر اشتغال زنان در ایران»، مجلة سیاستگذاری اقتصادی، س3، ش6، ص189ـ211.##[4] مرکز آمار ایران (1990). طرح نمونه‏گیری از هزینه‌‌ـ درآمد خانوار در ایران.##[5] میرزایی، حسین (1383). «عوامل مؤثر بر مشارکت اقتصادی زنان ایران با استفاده از مدل رگرسیونی داده‏های پانلی»، پژوهش زنان، دورۀ 2، ش اول، ص113ـ132.##[6] نوروزی، لادن (1381). «مدلی برای تبیین نرخ مشارکت اقتصادی زنان شهری و تحولات آینده»، زن در توسعه و سیاست (پژوهش زنان)، دورۀ 1، ش 4، ص138ـ160.##[7] ــــــــــ (1383). «تفاوت‏های جنسیتی در ساختار شغلی»، پژوهش زنان، دورۀ 1، ش اول، 178-165.##[8] Anker, R. (1998). Gender and Jobs: Sex Segregation of Occupation in the World. Geneva, ILO.##[9] Anker, R., Melkas,H. &amp; Korten,A. (2003). Gender-based occupational segregation in the 1990s, WP.16. ILO.##[10] Arango, L. E., &amp; Posada, C. E. (2007). Labor Participation of Married Women in Colombia. Desarrollo y Sociedad, 93-126.##[11] Aziz, F. (2009). Trend in Labor Force Participation Rates by Gender and Race. Economics School of Business, 351-379.##[12] Becker, G. S. (1965). A Theory of the Allocation of Time. The Economic Journal, 75, 299, 493-517.##[13] Ejaz, M. (2007). Determinants of Female Labor Force Participation in Pakistan: an Empirical Analysis of PSLM (2004-05) Micro Data. The Labor Journal of Economics, 203-235.##[14] Faridi, Z. M., Malik, Sh., &amp; Basit, A. B. (2009). Impact of Education on Female Labor Force Participation in Pakistan: Empirical Evidence from Primary Data Analysis. Pakistan Journal of Social Siences (PJSS), 29, 1, 127-140.##[15] Ghazouani, S., &amp; Goaied, M. (2001). Determinants of Urban and Rural Poverty in Tunisia. ERF (Economic Research Forum), Working Paper Series, No. 2001/126.##[16] Gündüz-Hosgör, A., &amp; Smits, J. (2006). Variation in Labor Market Participation of Married Women in Turkey. Women&#039;s Study Journal, 31.##[17] Lisaniler, F. G., &amp; Bhatti, F. (2005). Determinants of Female Labour Force Participation: A Study of North Cyprus. Review of Social, Economic &amp; Business Studies, 5/6, 209-226.##[18] Mincer, J. (1962). Labor Force Participation of Married Women: A Study of Labor Supply, In Aspects of Labor Economics. Princeton: Princeton Univ. Press (for Nat. Bur. Econ. Res), 63-106.##[19] Ntuli, M. (2007). Determinants of South Africa Women&#039;s Labour Force Participation, 1995-2004. IZP Discussion Paper Series, 3119.##[20] Pieters, J., &amp; Klasen, S. (2011). Drivers of Female Labour Force Participation in Urban India during India&#039;s Economic Boom. Leibniz Information Center for Economics, Proceedings of the German Development Economics Conference, 65.##[21] Verbeek, M. (2008). A Guide to Modern Econometrics, Erasmus University Rotterdm.##www.amar.org.ir##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>سنجش عوامل موثر بر عملکرد کسب و کارهای زنان کارآفرین در روستاهای شهرستان میانه</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Measuring factors affecting Female entrepreneur&#039;s business performance in rural areas of Mianeh County</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>برنامه‌ریزی برای توسعة کسب‌وکارهای زنان روستایی در گام نخست نیازمند شناسایی عوامل بهبود‌دهندۀ عملکرد این‌گونه کسب‌وکارهاست. بر همین اساس، در پژوهشی پیمایشی به بررسی ماهیت و کیفیت اثر‌گذاری هر‌یک از عوامل مؤثر بر ارتقای عملکرد کسب‌وکارهای زنان کارآفرین در روستاهای شهرستان میانه پرداخته شده است. جامعۀ آماری تحقیق را زنان روستایی دارای کسب‌وکار در روستاهای شهرستان میانه تشکیل دادند که از بین آن‌ها 111 نفر برای‌ حجم نمونه انتخاب شدند. داده‌های مورد نیاز تحقیق از طریق پرسشنامه به‌منزلۀ ابزار اصلی تحقیق جمع‌آوری شد. تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها و مدل‌یابی معادلات ساختاری نشان داد که ارتباط بین متغیرهایی نظیر اهداف، انگیزه‌ها، داشتن مهارت برنامه‌ریزی، مهارت‌های مختلف کسب‌وکار و در‌نهایت برخورداری زنان از برخی نقاط قوت در کسب‌وکار با عملکرد کسب‌وکار آن‌ها معنادار است و این متغیرها می‌توانند عملکرد کسب‌وکارهای کارآفرینانۀ زنان روستایی را تبیین کنند. بر مبنای نتایج تحقیق می‌توان گفت تقویت متغیرهای مذکور می‌تواند روند توسعة کارآفرینی زنان روستایی را در این مناطق سرعت بخشد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The main purpose of this applied research is to investigate the factors affecting rural female entrepreneur’s business performance. Based on theoretical literature, business performance is affected by several factors such as demographic characteristics, environmental factors, motives, social networks, skills, human capital and social learning. This research has been conducted applying a surveying technique by using questionnaire as the main tool. The population consists of 111 rural women who owned business in Mianeh County. The analysis and structural equation modeling showed the significant relationship between independent variables such as rural women’s goals, motives, planning skill, business skills and their business performance. Based on the research results, straightening these variables can enhance rural women entrepreneurship development.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>545</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>558</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>غلامحسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حسینی نیا</Family>
						<NameE>Gholamhossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hosseininia</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشکدۀ کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشکدۀ کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hosseininia@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>احمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>یعقوبی فرانی</Family>
						<NameE>Ahmad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Yaghoubi Farani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشکدۀ کشاورزی دانشگاه بوعلی‌سینا</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشکدۀ کشاورزی دانشگاه بوعلی‌سینا</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>yaghoubi@basu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سیدین</Family>
						<NameE>Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Seyedin</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت کارآفرینی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت کارآفرینی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>reza_seyedin@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زنان روستایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کارآفرینی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کسب‌وکار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عملکرد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>آراستی، زهرا (1385). «زنان کارآفرین ایرانی، ساختارهای فرهنگی‌ـ اجتماعی مؤثر در ایجاد کسب‌وکارهای کار‌آفرینانه»، مجلۀ زن در توسعه و سیاست، ش14، ص93ـ120.##آراستی، زهرا؛ اکبری جوکار، محمدرضا (1385). «بررسی شیوه‌های ارتباط شبکه‌ای زنان کارآفرین ایرانی و تأثیر آن در راه‌اندازی کسب‌وکار»، س4 ش3، ص5ـ22.##احمدپور داریانی، محمود؛ نیک‌بین، حسین؛ کریمی، آصف (1391). «عوامل مؤثر بر توسعة کارآفرینی در شرکت‌های خدمات مشاوره‌ای فنی مهندسی کشاورزی استان زنجان»، فصلنامۀ تحقیقات اقتصاد و توسعۀ کشاورزی ایران، س42، ش4، ص535ـ546.##حیدری مکرر، حمید؛ محبی، زهرا (1391). «بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر توسعة کارآفرینی در مناطق»، کنفرانس ملی کارآفرینی و مدیریت کسب‌وکارهای دانش‌بنیان.##رازقندی، ناهدی؛ درانی، کمال (1388). «شناسایی عوامل فردی و محیطی مؤثر بر موفقیت کارآفرینان برتر استان تهران جهت ارائۀ الگوی آموزشی»، نشریۀ توسعة کارآفرینی، دورۀ 2، ش6، ص39ـ55.##سلیمانی، عطیه (1391). «عوامل مؤثر بر توسعة کارآفرینی زنان روستایی در استان همدان»، پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد رشتۀ ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی»، دانشکدۀ کشاورزی دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، چاپ‌نشده.##شهبازی، اسماعیل (1376). توسعه و ترویج روستایی، تهران: دانشگاه تهران##صابر، فیروزه (1385). «راه‌های توسعة کارآفرینی زنان در ایران، راهکارهای توناسازی زنان در راستای برابری اقتصادی، اجتماعی و سیاسی در ایران»، ص174ـ176##فلاح جلودار، ربیع؛ فرج الله حسینی، سید جمال؛ حسینی، سید محمود؛ میردامادی، محمد (1386). «عوامل مؤثر بر موفقیت کارآفرینی زنان روستایی شمال کشور»، فصلنامۀ روستا و توسعه، س10، ش4، ص87ـ115.##قلی‏پور، آرین؛ رحیمیان، اشرف (1388). «رابطۀ عوامل اقتصادی، فرهنگی، و آموزشی با توانمندسازی زنان سرپرست خانوار»، فصلنامة علمی پژوهشی رفاه اجتماعی، س11، ش40، ص30ـ62.##گلستانی، سید هاشم؛ سعادتمند، زهره؛ قلی‌زاده، آذر؛ رجائیان، محمد حسین؛ احتشامی، طیبه (1389). «عوامل مؤثر بر توسعة کارآفرینی زنان و دختران دانشجو»، کارآفرین ناب، ش12، ص61ـ65.##گلرد، پروانه (1384). «عوامل مؤثر در توسعة کارآفرینی زنان ایرانی»، مجلۀ زن در توسعه و سیاست، ش11، ص101ـ124.##ــــــــــ (1384). «عوامل مؤثر در توسعة کارآفرینی زنان ایرانی»، پژوهش زنان، س3، ش2، ص101ـ123.##ــــــــــ (1388). «خانواده و راهکارهای توسعة کارآفرینی زنان ایرانی»، پژوهش زنان، س7، ش21، ص131ـ149.##گلیج، زهرا (1384). «کارآفرینی روستایی و توسعۀ پایدار»، ماهنامۀ سروش بانوان، ش63، ص12ـ13.##مرادی، گیتی (1390). «نقش زنان در فرایند توسعه روستایی»، دوهفته‌نامۀ پژوهشی‌ـ آموزشی‌ـ خبری و تحلیلی گیلان.##موحد محمدی، حمید؛ لشگرآرا، فرزاد؛ کرکه‌آبادی، نیره (1385). «تحلیل جنسیتی و زنان روستایی»، ماهنامۀ جهاد، س26، ش273، ص266ـ291.##میرک‌زاده، علی‌اصغر؛ بهرامی، مجید (1389). «گسترش کارآفرینی زنان از طریق کاربرد ICT»، اولین کنفرانس بین‌المللی مدیریت و نوآوری.##یعقوبی، جعفر (1387). «راهکارهایی تقویت کارآفرینی و حمایت از کارآفرینان از طریق تعاونی‌ها»، اولین همایش ملی تعاون و کارآفرینی.##یعقوبی فرانی، احمد؛ موحدی، رضا (1391). «بررسی و تحلیل موانع و محدودیت‌های توسعة کارآفرینی زنان روستایی در ایران»، ماهنامۀ کار و جامعه، ش142، ص38ـ50.##ــــــــــ (1391). «بررسی و تحلیل موانع و محدودیت‌های توسعة کارآفرینی زنان روستایی در ایران»، مجلۀ کار و جامعه، ش142، ص38ـ50.##یعقوبی فرانی، احمد؛ سلیمانی، عطیه؛ موحدی، رضا؛ فرزاد اسکندری (1392). «تأثیر عوامل آموزشی و نهادی بر کارآفرینی زنان روستایی (مورد مطالعه: استان همدان)»، توسعة کارآفرینی، دورۀ6، ش2، ص115ـ134.##Aly, Y.H. and Quisi, I.A. (1996). “Determinants of women labor force participation in Kuwait: a logit analyses”.The Middle East Business and Economic Review, 8(2):1-9.##Ambiga, S. &amp; Ramasamy, M. (2013). “Rural Women Entrepreneurship-A Step towards Self Contained Economy”, Tenth AIMS International Conference on Management, pp. 6-9.##Bergmann Lichtenstein, B.M., Brush, C.G. (2001). How do “resource bundles” develop and change in new ventures? A dynamic model and longitudinal exploration. Entrepreneurship Theory and Practice, 25 (spring), 37–58.##Hisrich R. &amp; C. Brush (1998). &quot;The woman entrepreneur: Management Skill and business problems&quot;, Journal of small Business Managemant, Vol.22, pp.30-37.##Gaglio, C.M., Katz, J.A.(2001). The psychological basis of opportunity identification: entrepreneurial alertness. Small Business Economics, 16 (2) 95-111##Kantor, P. (2002). “Promoting Women s Entrepreneurship Development Based on Good Practice Programmes: Some Experience From the North to the South”. ILO S in Focus Programme, Working paper, (9): 79.##Lerner, M., Brush, C.G and Hisrich, R.D. (1995). “Factors affecting performance of Israeli women entrepreneurs: An examination of alternative perspectives”. In: W.D. Bygrave, B.J. Bird, S. Bireley, N.C. Churchill, M. Tlay, R.H. Keeley, and W.E.Wetzel, Jr. (Eds), Frontiers of Entrepreneurial Research. pp. 308-322. Boston, MA: Babson College.##Lerner M.; Brush C.; Hisrich R. (1997). “Israeli women entrepreneurs: an examination of factors affecting performance, Journal of Business Venturing, Volume 12, Number 4, pp. 315-339 (25)##Morris, M. and Lewis, P. (1995). “The Determinants of Entrepreneurial Activity: Implication for Marketing”. European Journal of Marketing&quot;, 29(7).##Nawaz, F. (2009). “Critical Factors of Women Entrepreneurship Development in Rural Bangladesh”.U.S.A: Bangladesh Development Research Center (BDRC).##OECD. (1998). “Fostering Entrepreneurship”. Paris.##Ozkan, S. and Erdogan, Z., (2008). ”The change that handicrafts of turkey have Gone Through”, the social science 3: 41-44.##Shane, S. Locke, E. A. and Collins, C. J.(2003). Entrepreneurial motivation. Human Resource Management Review, 13 (3), 257–279##Sidhu, K., and Kaur, S. (2006). “Development of Entrepreneurship among Rural women”. Journal of social science, 13(2): 147-149##Thomas, A.S. &amp; Mueller, S.L. (2000). “A case for comparative entrepreneurship: Assessing the relevance of culture”. Journal of International Business Studies, 31 (2), 287-301.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>سنخ بندی دوستی‌های بین دو جنس (مورد مطالعه: دختران جوان شهر کرمانشاه)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Typology of friendships between both sexes (Case study: young girls in Kermanshah)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف این تحقیق سنخ‌شناسی روابط با جنس مخالف در بین دختران جوان است. این پژوهش با استفاده از روش کیفی، با رویکرد نظریه‌پردازی داده‌محور و به‌کارگیری تکنیک مصاحبۀ نیمه‌ساخت‌یافته و تعاملی انجام شد. جامعة مطالعه‌شده در این پژوهش دختران جوان 19ـ30 سالة ساکن در شهر کرمانشاه بود. با استفاده از روش نمونه‌گیری هدفمند و نظری، با 48 نفر از دخترانی که در این‌گونه روابط درگیر بودند، مصاحبه شد. یافته‌های این تحقیق نشان داد که در جامعة مطالعه‌شده، شش سنخ ارتباط با جنس مخالف در بین دختران وجود دارد که شامل روابط ناب، روابط مصلحتی، روابط هم‌بالینی، روابط ازدواج‌محور، روابط ابزاری، و روابط سیال‌اند. بر‌اساس یافته‌ها، همۀ سنخ‌های ارتباطی (به غیر از رابطة ناب)، از گفتمان پسامدرن متأثر بوده و ویژگی‌هایی چون سیالیت، شکنندگی، مقطعی‌بودن، عدم تعهد، و تکثرگرایی در دوستی دارند. رابطة ناب نیز متأثر از گفتمان مدرن ویژگی‌هایی مانند تعهد و تعلق عاطفی، عشق، رابطة جنسی، و نگرش غیر‌ابزاری به رابطه دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The current research aims to present a typology of relationships with the opposite sex among young girls. The research was conducted using qualitative methods and grounded theory in addition to applying Semi-Structure and Interactive Interview techniques. The population consists of young girls aged 19-30 who live in the city of Kermanshah. Using purposive and theoretical sampling, 48 girls, who were involved in these types of relationships, were interviewed. Results of the study revealed six types of relationship with the opposite sex among girls including: pure relationship, relationships of convenience, passionate relationship, Marriage-oriented relationship, instrumental relationships and liquid relationship. According to the findings, all types of relationships (other than pure relationship) have been influenced by postmodern discourse with features such as: fluidity, fragility, temporality, lack of commitment and pluralism in friendship. Pure relationship is also influenced by the modern discourse with features such as: commitment and emotional attachment, love, sex and non-instrumental approach to the relationship.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>559</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>576</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نیازی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohsen</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Niazi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد جامعه‌شناسی، عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه کاشان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد جامعه‌شناسی، عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>niazim@kashanu.ac.ir.</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>لیلا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>پرنیان</Family>
						<NameE>Leila</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Parnian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری بررسی مسائل اجتماعی ایران، دانشگاه کاشان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری بررسی مسائل اجتماعی ایران،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>parnian.leila@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دختران جوان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دوستی بین دو جنس</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رابطۀ ناب</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عشق سیال</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدرنیتۀ سیال</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ناپایداری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] آزاد ارمکی و همکاران (1390). «سنخ‌شناسی الگوهای روابط جنسی پیش از ازدواج در ایران»، جامعه‌پژوهی فرهنگی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی، س2، ش2، ص1ـ34..##[2] آزاد ارمکی، محمدتقی؛ شریفی ساعی، محمدحسین (1390). «تبیین جامعه‌شناختی روابط جنسی آنومیک در ایران»، فصلنامۀ خانواده‌پژوهی، س7، ش28، ص435ـ462.##[3] اسدی، مسعود؛ رضایی‌نژاد، سالار؛ نادرمیری، امیر (1390). «رابطة مذهب‌گرایی و عوامل جمعیت‌شناختی با گرایش به خشونت و رفتار جنسی پر‌خطر در دانشجویان دختر و پسر»، زن و مطالعات خانواده، س3، ش12، ص13ـ25.##[4] احمدی، علی‌اصغر (1387). تحلیلی بر روابط دختر و پسر در ایران، تهران: سازمان انجمن اولیا و مربیان.##[5] احمدنیا، شیرین؛ مهریار، هوشنگ (1383). «نگرش و ایده‌آل‌های نوجوانان تهران در زمینة همسرگزینی، فرزندآوری، و تنظیم خانواده»، مقالة ارائه‌شده در همایش جمعیت‌شناسی با تأکید بر جوانان: شیراز.##[6] باومن، زیگموند (1384). عشق سیال: در باب ناپایداری پیوندهای انسانی، ترجمة عرفان ثابتی، تهران: ققنوس.##[7] بیرامی، منصور، اسمعلی، احمد؛ واحدی، حسین (1389). «مقایسۀ عوامل و صفات شخصیتی دانشجویان دارای روابط جنسی پرخطر و فاقد روابط جنسی پرخطر»، مجلۀ پزشکی ارومیه، دورۀ21، ش3، ص 215ـ220.##[8] تورن، آلن (1382). «ایران در جریان فرایند مدرنیزاسیون قرار دارد»، همشهری، ویژه‌نامة نوروز، ص 47.##[9] خواجه‌نوری، بیژن؛ دل‌آور، مریم السادات (1391). «عوامل مؤثر بر دوستی دختر و پسر بین جوانان شهر شیراز، با تأکید بر فرایند جهانی‌شدن»، جامعه‌شناسی کاربردی اصفهان، س23، ش پیاپی (46)، ش2، ص 41ـ64.##[10] دلخموش، محمدتقی (1385). «ارزش‌های ازدواج در جوانان ایرانی»، فصلنامۀ روان‌شناسان ایرانی، س3، ش12، ص 299ـ318.##[11] دورکیم، امیل (1383). قواعد روش جامعه‌شناسی، ترجمۀ علی محمد کاردان، تهران: دانشگاه تهران، چ6.##[12] رفاهی، ژاله؛ گودرزی، محمود؛ میرزایی چهارراهی، مرتضی (1391). «بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر شکل‌گیری رابطۀ دوستی پیش از ازدواج بین دختران و پسران از دیدگاه دانشجویان»، فصلنامۀعلمی‌ـ پژوهشی جامعه‌شناسی زنان، س3، ش اول، ص 117ـ134.##[13] روزی بیدگلی، زهرا (1382). «نوگرایی زنان فعال در حوزة فرهنگی»، پژوهش زنان، دورة 1، س3، ش7، ص 177ـ198.##[14] زارع شاه‌آبادی، اکبر؛ سلیمانی، زکیه (1391). «نگرش به روابط پیش از ازدواج، عوامل مؤثر بر گرایش به آن»، فصلنامۀعلمی‌ـ پژوهشی رفاه اجتماعی، س12، ش45، ص339ـ364.##[15] زیمل، گئورگ (1392). دربارة فردیت و فرم‌های اجتماعی، ترجمة شهناز مسمی‌پرست، تهران: ثالث.##[16] ساروخانی، باقر؛ رفعت‌جاه، مریم (1383). «زنان و بازتعریف هویت اجتماعی»، مجلة انجمن جامعه‌شناسی ایران، س5، ش2، ص 133ـ160.##[17] سراج‌زاده، سید حسین؛ جواهری، فاطمه (1382). بررسی گرایش‌های فرهنگی، اجتماعی و رفتارهای نابهنجار دانشجویان دانشگاه تهران، تهران: معاونت اجتماعی فرهنگی وزارت علوم، تحقیقات و فناوری.##[18] سراج‌زاده، سید حسین (1383). «نیمۀ پنهان، گزارش نوجوانان شهر تهران از کجروی‌های اجتماعی و دلالت‌های آن برای مدیریت فرهنگی»، مجلۀ علوم انسانی دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، ش41 و 42، ص53ـ84.##[19] سراج‌زاده، سید حسین؛ بابایی، مینا (1389). «جهانی‌شدن، فرهنگ جهانی، و کجروی فرهنگی»، فصلنامۀ علوم اجتماعی، ش48، ص43ـ71.##[20] سهرابی، فرامرز؛ رسولی، فاطمه (1387). «بررسی رابطۀ بین سبک دلبستگی و روابط جنسی فرازناشویی در بین زنان بازداشت‌شده در مرکز مبارزه با مفاسد اجتماعی شهر تهران»، فصلنامۀ خانواده‌پژوهی، س4، ش14، ص133ـ143.##[21] شریفی، مرضیه و همکاران (1391). «رابطة طرح‌واره‌های عشق و توجیه روابط فرازناشویی در زنان متأهل شهر اصفهان»، فصلنامۀ تحقیقات علوم رفتاری، دورۀ 10، ش6، ویژه‌نامۀ سلامت روان.##[22] شیخ دارانی، هما و همکاران (1387). «تأثیر آموزش مبتنی بر افزایش آگاهی از آسیب‌های حاصل از روابط آسیب‌زای دختر و پسر بر نگرش دانش‌آموزان دختر دورة متوسطه»، دانش و پژوهش در روان‌شناسی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد خوراسگان (اصفهان)، ش38، ص41ـ62.##[23] صفایی، مهشید (1390). «جوانان و عشق؛ تأثیر زمینۀ اجتماعی در مفهوم‌پردازی رابطة عاشقانه»، مطالعات اجتماعی‌ـ روان‌شناختی زنان، س9، ش2، ص81ـ104.##[24] عبدالهیان، حمید (1383). «ارزش سنتی و بازتولید فرهنگی»، مقالۀ ارائه‌شده در همایش جمعیت‌شناسی با تأکید بر جوانان: شیراز.##[25] فلیک، اووه (1387). درآمدی بر تحقیق کیفی، ترجمۀ هادی جلیلی، تهران: نی.##[26] قاسمی، وحید (1383). «سنخ‌شناسی دانشجویان بر مبنای پدیدۀ روابط دوستانۀ دختر و پسر»، فصلنامۀ مطالعات جوانان، ش7، ص90ـ113.##[27] گلزاری، محمود (1383). آموزش مشاوره با نوجوانان در زمینۀ ارتباط با جنس مخالف، دومین کنگرۀ بین‌المللی روان‌درمانی در شرق و گفت‌وگوی تمدن‌ها، تهران: دانشگاه علوم پزشکی ایران.##[28] گیدنز، آنتونی (1392). تجدد و تشخص: جامعه و هویت شخصی در عصر جدید، ترجمۀ ناصر موفقیان، تهران: نی.##[29] ــــــــــ (1377). پیامدهای مدرنیت، ترجمۀ محسن ثلاثی، تهران: مرکز، چ3.##[30] ماهینی، انیسه؛ دیره، عزت (1391). «پژوهشی در ارتباط با دختر و پسر در دانشگاه‌ها و نقد دیدگاه‌ها»، فصلنامۀ علمی‌ـ پژوهشی پژوهش‌نامۀ اخلاق، س5، ش16، ص86ـ109.##[31] محمدپور، احمد و همکاران (1393). «تأثیر عوامل فردی‌ـ محیطی بر پایبندی به شیوه‌های ازدواج (مطالعۀ موردی دانشجویان روستایی‌ـ شهری دانشگاه‌های سنندج)»، جامعه‌شناسی کاربردی اصفهان، س25، ش پیاپی 53، ص159ـ174.##[32] مرکز آمار ایران. سالنامۀ آماری کشور (1381). تهران: مدیریت انتشارات و اطلاع‌رسانی.##[33] موحد، مجید؛ عباسی شوازی، محمدتقی (1385). «بررسی رابطة جامعه‌پذیری و نگرش دختران به ارزش‌های سنتی و مدرن در زمینة روابط بین‌شخصی دو جنس پیش از ازدواج»، مطالعات زنان، س4، ش1، ص68ـ99.##[34] موحد، مجید؛ عنایت، حلیمه؛ عباسی شوازی، محمدتقی (1385). «بررسی رابطة عوامل اجتماعی و فرهنگی با نگرش دانشجویان نسبت به معاشرت و دوستی دختر و پسر پیش از ازدواج»، مجلة علوم اجتماعی و انسانی دانشگاه شیراز، دورۀ 24، ویژه‌نامۀ جمعیت و توسعه، ش2، (پیاپی 47)، ص147ـ165.##[35] مهدی‌زاده، شراره؛ عبداللهی، الهه (1386). «بررسی رابطة میان نحوۀ استفاده از اینترنت و ماهواره با برگزاری روز دوستی (ولنتاین) در میان جوانان تهرانی»، فصلنامۀ انجمن مطالعات فرهنگی و ارتباطات، دورۀ 3، ش9، ص161ـ184.##[36] میرباقری، مرتضی (1381). نتایج پژوهش ملی در وضعیت و نگرش و مسائل جوانان 14 تا 19 سالۀ استان تهران، تهران: انتشارات سازمان ملی جوانان.##[37] میرزایی، خلیل؛ برغمدی، هادی (1388). «رابطه با جنس مخالف و عوامل مرتبط با آن»، فصلنامۀ علمی‌ـ پژوهشی رفاه اجتماعی، س10، ش34، ص 131ـ158.##[38] هدایتی‌مقدم، محمدرضا؛ فتحی مقدم، فرهاد (1388). بررسی رفتارهای پرخطر مرتبط با سلامت در دانشجویان مقطع کارشناسی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد در سال 1387، طرح تحقیقاتی، واحد استان خراسان رضوی.##[39] Adams, G.R. (2000). “The transition to university and beyond [special issue]”. Journal of Adolescent Research. 15 (1), pp 145-156.##[40] Buhrmester, D. &amp; Furman, W. (1992). The Changing functions of friends in childhood: A neo-sullivanian perspectives, In V.J. Derlega, &amp; B.A. Winsted (Eds.), Freindship and Social Interaction (pp. 41-62). New York: Springer.##[41] Buss, D.M. Shackelford, T.K. Kilkpatrick, L.A. &amp; Larsen, R.J. (2007). A Half century of mate perefence: the cultural evolution of values.##[42] Carver, K. Joyner, K. &amp; Udry, J.R. (2003). National estimates of adolescent romantic relationship, In P. Florsheim (Ed.), Adolescent romantic relations and sexual behavior: Theory, research and practical implications, Mahwah, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates.##[43]. Conolly, J.A. &amp; Konarski, R. (1994). “Peer self-concept in adolescence: Analysis of factor structure and of associations with peer experience”, Journal of Research on Adolescence, 4, pp 385-403.##[44] Collins, W. (2003). More than myth: The developmental significance of romantic relationships during adolescence, Journal of Research on Adolescence.##[45] Demaris, A., and W. Mac Donald. (1993). “Premarital cohabitation and marital instability: A test of the unconventionality hypothesis”, Journal of marriage and the family, 55 (2): pp 399-407.##[46] Durant, R.H. &amp; et. Al. (1990). “Contraceptive behavior among sexually active Hispanic Adolescents”, Journal of Adolescence Health Care, 11, pp 490-496.##[47] Fehr, B. (1996). Friendship processes. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage.##[48] Forman, L. (2002). Clinical handbook of couple therapy, New York: Guilford publishing.##[49] Furman, W. (1989). The Development of children’s social networks, In D. Belle (Ed.), Children Social Networks and Social Supports, pp 151-172. New York: Wiley.##[50] Giddens, A. (1992). The Transformation of Intimacy: Sexuality, Love &amp; Eroticism in Modern Societies, California, Stanford University press.##[51] Hall, D., R. (1996). “Marriage as a pure relationship: Exploring the link between premarital cohabitation and divorce in Canada, Journal of Comparative Family studies, 27 (1): pp 1-12.##[52] Hardie, E. &amp; S. Buzwell. (2006). &quot;Finding love online: The Nature and frequency of Australian&quot;, Journal of emerging technologies and society, vol. 4, no. 1, pp: pp 1-14.##[53] Hendrick, S. S. &amp; Hendrick, C. (1993). Lovers as Friends, Journal of Social and Personal Relationship, 10, pp 459-466.##[54] Holder, D. W. (2000). “The association between adolescent sexual spirituality and voluntary sexual activity”, Journal Adolescent Health 2000, 26: pp 295-320.##[55] Howes, C. (1988). “Same- and cross – sex friendships: Implications for interactions and social skills”, Early childhood research quarterly, 3, pp 21-37.##[56] Jassor, R. (1992). “Risk behavior in adolescence: A psycho social frame work for understanding &amp; action”. Developmental Review. 12: pp 374-390.##[57] Joyner, K. &amp; Udry. J. R. (2000). You don’t bring me anything but down: Adolescent romance and depression”, Journal of health and social behavior, 41, pp 369-391.##[58] Kahn, J. R. and K., A. London (1991), “Premarital sex and the Risk of Divorce”, Journal of Marriage and the Family, 53(4), pp 845-855.##[59] Laursen, B. (1993). Conflict management among close peers, New Direction for child development, 60, pp 39-54.##[60] Laursen, B. &amp; Williams, V. A. (1997). Perceptions of interdependence and closeness in family and peer relationships among adolescents with or without romantic partners, New Directions for child development, 78, pp 3-20.##[61] Masten, A. (2001). “Resilience process in development”, American psychology, 56.##[62] Miller, B. C., &amp; Chistopherson, C.R. &amp; King, P.K. (1993). Sexual behavior in adolescence, IN R. Gullotta, G. Adams, &amp; R. Montemayor (Eds.), Adolescent Sexuality, New bury park, CA: Sage.##[63] Ramakrishna, I., Karoptt, M. &amp; Murthy, R.S. (2006). Experiences of sexual coercion among street boys in Bangalore, India.Http://www.who. int/ reproductive health/publications/ to wards adu thood/14.pdf.##[64] Rector, R., E. &amp; et. Al (2003). Sexually Active teenagers are more likely to be depressed and to attempt suicide.##[65] Rosenzweig, L. W. (2008). Encyclopedia of children and childhood in history and society, The gale group INC.##[66] Silva, M. &amp; Ross, I. (2002). Association of perceived parental attitudes towards premarital sex with initiation of sexual intercourse in adolescence, psychology Report, 91 (3 PT 1), pp 40-781.##[67] Simmons, R. (2002). Odd Girl Out: The Hidden Culture of Aggression in Girls, New York: Harcourt.##[68] Sinha, j.w. &amp; Cnaan, R.A. (2004). Exploring the impact of a faith-based demonstration program for at-risk youth. Washington, DC: Administration for children and families, Health and Human services.##[69] Smock, P. (2000). “Cohabitation in the United States: An appraisal of research themes, findings, and implications”, Annual Reviews Sociology, 26 (1): pp 1-20.##[70] Teachman, J. (2003). “Premarital sex, premarital cohabitation, an the risk of subsequent marital dissolution among women”, Journal of Marriage and family, 65 (2): pp 444-455.##[71] Torres, A. &amp; Singh, S. (1986). &quot;Contraceptives practice among Hispanic adolescents&quot;, Family planning perspectives, 18, 193-194.##[72] Urberg, K.A. &amp; Et al (1995). The Structure of adolescent peer networks, Developmental psychopathology, 31, pp 540-547.##[73] Whitty, M.T. (2008). &quot;Liberating or debilitating? An examination of romantic relationship, sexual relationships and friendships on the Net&quot;, Computers in Human Behaviors, vol.24, pp 1837-1850.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>سنجش عوامل مؤثر بر محیط‌ زیست‌گرایی زنان ایرانی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The factors affecting women′s environmentalism in Iran</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>بحران محیط زیست، امروزه یکی از گرفتاری‌های مهم جهانی به‌شمار می‌رود. مواجهه با این بحران به‌منزلۀ یک تلاش جمعی نیازمند ایجاد نگرش‏های محیط زیست‌گرایانه در مردم است. آنچه در این زمینه درخور تأمل است شناسایی عوامل مؤثر بر محیط‏زیست‏گرایی افراد مختلف جامعه، بالاخص زنان است، زیرا بنا بر دو محور اصلی نظریۀ اکوفمنیسم، یعنی رابطۀ زنان با محیط زیست و نقش آنان در حل مشکلات اکولوژیکی، زنان در توجه به محیط زیست جایگاه ممتاز و ویژه‏ای دارند و از طرف دیگر به علت اینکه زنان با محیط زیست بیشتر عجین‌اند، می‏توانند از طریق انتقال دانش و علاقۀ زیست‌محیطی به کودکان در حفظ محیط زیست فعال باشند. از‌این‌رو، مطالعۀ عوامل تأثیرگذار بر محیط‏‌زیست‏‏گرایی زنان می‏تواند راهگشای بسترسازی برای ایجاد این عوامل و جلب مشارکت زنان در حفاظت از محیط زیست باشد. تحقیق حاضر ‌درصدد شناسایی و مطالعۀ عوامل مؤثر بر محیط‏زیست‏گرایی زنان ایرانی است. بدین منظور، با توجه به تحقیقات انجام‌شده در این خصوص و با پشتوانۀ نظری اکوفمنیسم و با تحلیل ثانویه داده‏های موج پنجم پیمایش‏ «داده‏های ارزش‏های جهانی»در کشور ایران با حجم نمونۀ 2 هزار و 667 نفر، که با روش نمونه‌گیری احتمالی چندمرحله‏ای صورت پذیرفته است، به کنکاش در این عوامل می‏پردازد. یافته‏های تحقیق نشان می‏دهد متغیرهای مشارکت اجتماعی، دینداری، دانش زیست‌محیطی، سن، و تحصیلات با محیط‏زیست‏گرایی زنان ارتباط معنا‏داری ‏دارند، ولی طبقۀ‏ اقتصادی زنان تأثیری بر محیط‏زیست‏گرایی آنان ندارد. همچنین، یافته‏های تحقیق نشان می‏دهد که سه متغیر دانش زیست‌محیطی، دینداری، و مشارکت توانسته‌اند 82‌درصد از واریانس متغیر وابسته را تبیین کنند و توضیح دهند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Environmental crisis is one of the most important global problems. Dealing with this crisis as a collective effort requires formation of environmentalism attitudes among people. What is considerable in this field is to identify the factors affecting people’s attitudes towards environmentalism especially women. Since, based on two main perspectives of ecofeminism; i.e. women&#039;s relationship with the environment and their role in solving ecological problems, women have a privileged position in regard to the environment. On the other hand, women status is notable due to their roles in nurturing children and transmitting knowledge and culture to the future generation; therefore, they have the most important role for protecting environment. Accordingly, study of the factors affecting women’s environmentalism can pave the way to attract women to participate in activities of protecting environment. The current study aims to identify the factors which affect Iranian women’s environmentalism. We have used ecofeminism, secondary analysis of fifth wave data and empirical literature for this purpose. In Iran, a sample size of 2667 subjects with multi-stage probability sampling was studied. Findings have shown that such variables as social participation, religious practice, environment knowledge, age and level of education have significant relationship with women’s environmentalism but economic class has shown to have has no effect. The research findings showed that three variables including environmental awareness, religiosity and participation explain 82% of the dependent variable variance.  </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>577</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>592</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>امیر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ملکی</Family>
						<NameE>Amir</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Maleki</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه جامعه‌شناسی دانشکدۀ علوم اجتماعی و اقتصادی دانشگاه پیام نور</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه جامعه‌شناسی دانشکدۀ علوم اجتماعی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>a_maleki@pnu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>پروین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>علی پور</Family>
						<NameE>Parvin</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Alipoor</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>پژوهشگر مؤسسۀ مطالعات و تحقیقات اجتماعی دانشگاه تهران، دانشجوی دکتری جامعه‌شناسی دانشگاه پیام نور</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>پژوهشگر مؤسسۀ مطالعات و تحقیقات اجتماعی دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>palipoor@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اکوفمنیسم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دانش زیست‌محیطی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دینداری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>محیط‏زیست‏گرایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مشارکت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>احمدوند، مصطفی؛ نوری‌پور، مهدی (1389). «نگرش‌های زیست‌محیطی دانشجویان کشاورزی دانشگاه یاسوج؛ تحلیلی جنسیتی»، مجلۀ علوم ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی ایران، ج6، ش2، ص1ـ13.##ادارۀ کل امور بانوان (1390). سند بهبود وضعیت بانوان در شهر تهران، شهرداری تهران.##جوادی آملی، عبدالله (1386). اسلام و محیط زیست، قم: مرکز چاپ و نشر اِسراء.##درسنر، سایمون (1384). مبانی پایداری، ترجمۀ محمود دانشور و همکاران، مشهد: انتشارات دانشگاه فردوسی.##دواس، دی.ای (1385). پیمایش در تحقیقات اجتماعی، ترجمۀ هوشنگ نایبی، تهران: نی.##رحمانی، بیژن؛ مجیدی خامنه، بتول (1388). «عوامل مؤثر بر مشارکت زنان در حفظ محیط زیست شهری با تأکید بر نگرش اکوفمنیستی مطالعۀ موردی: مناطق 6 و 8 شهرداری شهر تهران»، فصلنامۀ جغرافیایی آمایش محیط، ش7:، ص 15ـ37.##ساتن، فیلیپ (1392). درآمدی بر جامعه‏شناسی محیط زیست، ترجمة صادق صالحی، تهران: سمت.##صالحی، صادق؛ امامقلی، لقمان (1391). «مطالعۀ تجربی رابطۀ آگاهی و رفتارهای زیست‌محیطی»، مسایل اجتماعی ایران، س3، ش1، ص‌121ـ147.##صالحی، صادق؛ حمایت‏خواه جهرمی، مجتبی (1392). «مقایسۀ تحلیلی ارزش‏های زیست‌محیطی جهان اسلام و غرب (تحلیل ثانویۀ داده‏های پیمایش ارزش‏های جهانی)»، فصلنامۀ مطالعات و تحقیقات اجتماعی در ایران، دورۀ دوم، ش3، ص‌505ـ523.##صالحی، صادق؛ کریم‏زاده، سارا (1393). تحلیل اکو‌فمنیستی بر نگرش نوین زیست‌محیطی زنان (مورد مطالعه: شهر ارومیه)، بی‏جا.##علی احمدی، امید (1389). پژوهشی در تحولات معاصر خانواده در شهر تهران، تهران: معاونت امور اجتماعی و فرهنگی شهرداری تهران.##فردوسی، سیما؛ مرتضوی، شهرناز؛ رضوانی، نعیمه (1386). «رابطۀ بین دانش زیست‌محیطی و رفتارهای محافظت از محیط»، پژوهشنامۀ علوم انسانی، ش53، ص‌253ـ266.##کاظمی، جمال (1389). «نگاهی به آراء توماس بری، بنیانگذار الهیات زیست‌محیطی: روایت نو از دین، زمین و زندگی»، ماهنامۀ اخبار ادیان، س8، ش1، ص‌19ـ25.##محقق داماد، سید مصطفی (1389). «الهیات محیط زیست»، ماهنامۀ اخبار ادیان، س8، ش1،‌ ص 38ـ45.##ملکی، امیر؛ عبداللهی، عظیمه‌السادات (1392). «تبیین جامعه‌شناختی محیط‏گرایی ایرانیان در دو سطح خرد وکلان»، فصلنامۀ مطالعات و تحقیقات اجتماعی در ایران، ش2، ص‌177ـ202.##نوکل، زیگرید (1389). «مفاهیم محیط زیستی در اسلام»، ماهنامۀ اخبار ادیان، س8، ش1‌، ص36ـ37.##وزیری، رویا. جایگاه محیط زیست در علوم اجتماعی، سایت انسان‌شناسی و فرهنگ.##http://anthropology.ir/node/750##Budak. D.B, Budak. F, Zaimoglu. Z, Kekec. S, and Yavuz Suca. M (2005). Behavior and attitudes of students toward environmental Issues at faculty if Agriculture, Turkey. Journal of Applied sciences, No 7: pp 1227- 1244.##Cudworth, E. (2003). Environment and Society, London and New York: Routledge##Deng, J, Walker, G. J and Swinnerton, G (2006). A camparison of environmental values and attitudes between Chines in Canada and Anglo-Canadians. Environment and behavior, 38 (1): pp 11-47.##Ewers, A., Galloway, G (2004). Expressed environmental attitudes andactual behavior: Exploring the Concept of Environmentally DesirableResponses, Paper presented at theInternational Outdoor EducationResearch Conference, La Trobe University, Bendigo, Victoria, Australia, July 6-9.##Honnold, J. A. (1981). “ Predictors of public environmental concern in the 1990s”, Field Research: A Sourcebook and Field Manual, London: Allen &amp; Unwin. pp. 79- 90.##Kaiser, F. G; Wolfing , S; Fuhrer, U.(1999). &quot;Environmental attitude and ecological behavior&quot;. Journal of Environmental psychology. 19, pp 1-19.##Lowe, G. D. and others (1980). “Public support for environmental protection: new evidence from national surveys”, Pacific Sociological Review, No 23: pp 423- 45.##Lowe, G. D. and T. K. Pinhey (1982). “ Rural-urban differences in support for environmental protection”, Rural Sociology, No 47: pp 114- 28.##Mohai, p and B.W, Twight (1987). “Age and environmentalism: an elaboration of the Buttel model using national survey evidence”, Social Science Quarterly, No 68: pp 798- 815.##Van Liere, k. D and R. E. Dunlap (1980). “Social bases of environmental concern: a review of hypotheses, explanations and empirical evidence”, Public Opinion Quarterly, No 44: pp 181-97.##World Values Survey, Values Change the World: World Values Survey, website: http://www.worldvaluessurvey.org.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>اکوتوریسم و توانمندسازی زنان روستایی (مورد مطالعه: روستای شیب‌دراز، جزیره قشم)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Ecotourism and empowerment of rural women (Case study: Shibderaz village, Qeshm Island)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>با توجه به وجود نابرابری‌های جنسیتی که عمدتاً در بسیاری از جوامع علیه زنان دیده می‌شود، بحث توانمندسازی آن‌ها در سال‌های اخیر اهمیت خاصی یافته است. در این زمینه، تحقیقات بسیاری به رابطۀ کارایی نقش اکوتوریسم در توانمندسازی جامعۀ محلی، از طریق جلب مشارکت آنان در فعالیت‏های گردشگری، تأکید کرده است. با توجه به این موضوع، پژوهش حاضر با هدف ارزیابی نقش توسعۀ اکوتوریسم بر ابعاد مختلف توانمندسازی زنان روستایی، با بهره‏گیری از روش پیمایشی انجام شد. جامعۀ آماری این تحقیق، زنان روستای شیب‏دراز جزیرۀ قشم بودند که در طرح حفاظتی «لاک‏پشت‏های دریایی پوزه‌عقابی» با تأکید بر توسعۀ اکوتوریسم و صنایع‌دستی مشارکت داشتند. جهت گردآوری داده‏ها نیز از پرسشنامۀ محقق‌ساخته استفاده شد. نتایج تحقیق نشان داد که توسعة‏ اکوتوریسم میزان توانمندسازی اجتماعی، اقتصادی، و روانی زنان را به‌طور معناداری در روستای مطالعه‌شده افزایش داده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Regarding gender inequality in many communities, empowerment of women has become an important subject and received more attention in recent years. Results of many researches show that tourism especially ecotourism affects women empowerment in its different aspects by making them interested in participating tourism activities. Based on findings of previous researches, the current study aims to assess the role of ecotourism development on empowerment of rural women using a descriptive survey method. The population consists of women of Shib-Deraz in Qeshm Island who participate in environmental plan of “conservation of Eretmochelys Embricate “with an emphasis on ecotourism and handicrafts”. A questionnaire was designed based on a theoretical framework. Results show that development of ecotourism can influence social, psychological and economic empowerment of rural women.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>593</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>610</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>لیلا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>وثوقی</Family>
						<NameE>Leila</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Vossoughi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشکده گردشگری، دانشگاه سمنان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشکده گردشگری، دانشگاه سمنان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>vossoughi.la@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدیه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قاسمی</Family>
						<NameE>Mahdieh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ghasemi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد برنامه‌ریزی توسعۀ جهانگردی، دانشگاه سمنان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد برنامه‌ریزی توسعۀ جهانگردی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mhd.gh1368@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اکوتوریسم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>توانمندسازی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زنان روستایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>روستای شیب‏دراز</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] اکبرپورسراسکانرود، محمد؛ نوربخش، فاطمه (1389). «نقش اکوتوریسم در توسعة پایدار شهری و روستایی نمونۀ موردی جزیرۀ قشم»، فصلنامۀ مسکن و محیط روستا، ش132، ص61ـ76.##[2] آذری، نیما (1385). «گزارش پروژۀ اکوتوریسم جزیرۀ قشم شیب‌دراز، با هدف ارتقای سطح معیشت جامعة محلی با تکیه بر حفاظت از لاک‏پشت پوزه‏عقابی»، بخش کمک‏های کوچک تسهیلات محیط زیست جهانی سازمان ملل متحد، مؤسسۀ آوای طبیعت پایدار.##[3] برقی، حمید و همکاران (1391). «برنامه‏ریزی توسعۀ پایدار گردشگری در منطقۀ خلیج فارس (مطالعۀ موردی: جزیرۀ قشم)»، مجلۀ علمی‌ـ پژوهشی برنامه‏ریزی فضایی، س2، ش3 (پیاپی 7)، ص75ـ94.##[4] خانی، فضیله و همکاران (1391). «ارائۀ الگوی توانمندسازی زنان روستایی استفاده‌کننده ازICT»، توسعۀ روستایی، دورۀ 4، ش1.##[5] خانی، فضیله (1390). «تحلیل جنسیتی از درک آثار گردشگری روستایی، (روستاهای کن و سولقان)»، فصلنامۀ توسعۀ روستایی، دورۀ3، ش1.##[6] ــــــــــ (1388). «جنسیت و گردشگری»، رشد علوم اجتماعی، دورۀ12، ش42.##[7] خواجه‌شکوهی، علیرضا؛ خوش‏فر؛ علیرضا؛ لیلا، کریمی (1391). «نقش گردشگری در توانمندسازی زنان روستایی (مورد مطالعه: روستای زیارت شهرستان گرگان)»، مجلۀ برنامه‌ریزی و توسعۀ گردشگری، س اول، ش3، ص 95ـ114.##[8] دشتی، سولماز و همکاران (1391). «ارائۀ مدل برنامه‌ریزی کاربردی اراضی جهت توسعۀ گردشگری در جزایر خلیج فارس (مطالعۀ موردی جزیرۀ قشم)»، فصلنامۀ علمی‌ـ پژوهشی اکوبیولوژی تالاب، س4، دورۀ4، ش13،ص 49ـ61.##[9] رحمانی، مریم و همکاران (1387). «نقش اعتبارات خرد در توانمندسازی زنان»، مطالعات اجتماعی روان‌شناختی زنان، ش18،ص105ـ132.##[10] رضایی، زهرا (1388). «توانمندسازی زنان در فرایند توسعه»، پژوهشنامه‏، ش42، ص57ـ82.##رضوانی، محمدرضا و همکاران (1391). «تأثیر گردشگری بر تقویت نگرش‏های کارآفرینانه در مناطق روستایی»، فصلنامۀ پژوهش‏های روستایی، س3، ش2، ص153ـ174.##[11] ریاضی، برهان (1386). «بررسی روابط زیست‌سنجی لاک‌پشت عقابی در سواحل قشم»، مجلۀ علوم و تکنولوژی محیط زیست، دورۀ9، ش4.##[12] شکوری، علی و همکاران (1386). «مؤلفه‏های توانمندی زنان و تبیین عوامل مؤثر بر آن‌ها»، زن در توسعه و سیاست، ش17، ص1ـ26.##[13] غنیان، منصور و همکاران (1389). «تحلیل ابعاد گردشگری روستایی با رویکرد جنسیتی از دیدگاه جامعۀ میزبان»، زن در توسعه و سیاست (پژوهش زنان)، دورۀ 8، ش3، ص93ـ109.##[14] فرجی‌راد، عبدالرضا؛ احسانی، افسانه (1390). «بررسی تأثیر اقامتگاه‏های محلی (خوشه‏سار بوم‏گردی) بر ارتقای سطح زندگی جامعة محلی»، فصلنامۀ علمی‌ـ پژوهشی جغرافیایی سرزمین، س8، ش30، ص 63ـ77.##[15] کتابی، محمود و همکاران (1382). «توانمندسازی زنان برای مشارکت در توسعه»، پژوهش زنان، دورۀ 1، س3، ش7.##[16] Afifi, G. M., &amp; Al-Sherif, N., 2014,WomenOcuupational Empowerment in the Omani Tourism Sector, European journal of tourism, hospitality and recreation Vol. 5, Issue 1, pp 53-84.##[17] Anderson, W., 2009, Promoting Ecotourism through Networks: Balearic Islands. Journal of Ecotourism. Vol. 8 No.1, pp 51-69.##[19] Barry, Katherine S., 2012,Women Empowerment and Community Development through Ecotourism, Capstone Collection. Paper 2579.##[19] Boley, B. B., &amp; McGehee, N. G., 2014, Measuring empowerment: Developing and validating the Resident Empowerment through Tourism Scale (RETS), Tourism Management, vol. 45,pp 85-94.##[20] Cole, S. 2006. Information and empowerment: The keys to achieving sustainable tourism. Journal of Sustainable Tourism, 14 (6), pp 629-644.##[21] Dorobantu, M. R., &amp; Nistoreanu, P., 2012,Rural Tourism and Ecotourism–the Main Priorities in Sustainable Development Orientations of Rural Local Communities in Romania.##[22] Dunn, S. F. 2007. Toward empowerment: Women and community-based tourism in Thailand (Doctoral dissertation, Uni of Oregon).##[23] Eshun, G. ,2011, Ecotourism development in Ghana: a postcolonial study with focus on Boabeng-Fiema Monkey National Park (Doctoral dissertation, University of Leicester).##[24] Garrod, B., &amp; Wilson, J. C., (Eds.), 2003, MarineEcoturism: Issues and Experiencies, Channel View Publications.##[25] Höckert, E. 2009. Sociocultural sustainability of rural community-based tourism, .Lapin yliopiston matkailun ja liiketoiminnan tiedekunnan julkaisuja B: 5.##[26] Holtz, C., &amp; Edwards, S.,2003, Linking biodiversity and sustainable tourism policy. Ecotourism policy and planning.##[27] Jackson, M. A. ,2010, Empowering women of Nepal: an experience of empowerment in the land of the Himalaya(Doctoral dissertation, PRESCOTT COLLEGE).##[28] Kiss, A. 2004. Is community-based ecotourism a good use of biodiversity conservation funds?. Trends in Ecology &amp; Evolution, 19 (5), 232-237.##[29] Ontiveros, M. M. &amp; Carrillo ,2015. Tourism, female work and women&#039;s empowerment at Bahía1s de Huatulco, Oaxaca. Estudios y Perspectivas en Turismo, Vol. 24 No. 2 pp 316-335.##[30] Pasape, L., Anderson, W., &amp; Lindi, G. (2014). Sustaining Ecotourism in Tanzania through Community Empowerment, Journal of tourism Research vol.7.##[31] Pleno, M. J. L. 2006. Ecotourism projects and women&#039;s empowerment: A case study in the province of Bohol, Philippines.##[32] Sabina, J. M., &amp; Nicolae, J. C., 2013,Gender Trends in Tourism Destination, Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences,Vol. 92.##[33] Scheyvens, R. (1999). Ecotourism and the empowerment of local communities, Tourism management, 20(2), pp 245-249.##[34] Scheyvens, R., 2000, Promoting women&#039;s empowerment through involvement in ecotourism: Experiences from the Third World, Journal of sustainable tourism,Vil. 8. No. 3,pp 232-249.##[35] Scheyvens, R., 2007, Exploring the tourism-poverty nexus. Current Issues in Tourism, Vol. 10.No. 2-3 pp. 231-254.##[36] Stronza, A., &amp; Gordillo, J., 2008, Community views of ecotourism. Annals of Tourism Research, Vol.35. No. 2.##[37] Sutawa, G. K., 2012, Issues on Bali Tourism Development and Community Empowerment to Support Sustainable Tourism Development. Procedia Economics and Finance, Vol. 4.N. 1.##[38] Thampi, S. P., 2005, Ecotourism in Kerala, India: Lessons from the eco-development project in Periyar Tiger Reserve. International Ecotourism Monthly, vol. 13, No. 6.##[39] Thien, O. S. 2009 women empowerment through tourism from social entrepreneurship perspective.##[40] Walter, P. &amp; Tran, L., 2014. Ecotourism, gender and development in northern Vietnam. Annals of Tourism Research, 44, pp 116-130.##[41] Wang, H., Guan, Y., &amp; Wang, Z., 2013,Analysis on Present Situation and Countermeasures of Rural Ecotourism in Jiangsu Province. Asian Agricultural Research. vol. 5. No. 4.##[42] Wearing, S., &amp; Neil, J.,2009, Ecotourism: impacts, potentials and possibilities?. Routledge.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تبیین فرسودگی شغلی زنان شاغل با تأکید بر نقش متغیرهای سازمانی و روان شناختی (مورد مطالعه: دانشگاه فنی و حرفه ای و آزاد اسلامی شیراز)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Explaining burnout of working women with an emphasis on the role of organizational and psychological variables (Case study: Technical &amp; Vocational and Islamic Azad University of Shiraz)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>فرسودگی شغلی سندرمی مشتمل بر خستگی هیجانی، مسخ شخصیت، و کاهش موفقیت فردی است که افراد به دلیل مواجهه با استرس‏های فیزیکی، روانی، و هیجانی در معرض آن قرار می‏گیرند. از جمله ضرورت‏های این پژوهش، ناکافی بودن پژوهش در خصوص جامعۀ زنان است. هدف پژوهش حاضر تبیین فرسودگی شغلی زنان شاغل با تأکید بر نقش متغیرهای سازمانی و روان‌شناختی در دانشگاه فنی و حرفه‌ای و آزاد اسلامی شیراز است. پژوهش حاضر از نوع توصیفی همبستگی است. جامعۀ آماری شامل کلیۀ کارکنان زن شاغل در دانشگاه فنی و حرفه‏ای و آزاد شیراز (225=N) است. حجم نمونه با استفاده از فرمول کوکران 143 نفر است که با استفاده از روش نمونه‏گیری خوشه‏ای چند‌مرحله‏ای تصادفی انتخاب شدند. جهت جمع‏آوری اطلاعات از پرسشنامۀ فرسودگی شغلی ماسلاچ، پرسشنامۀ تعهد سازمانی آلن و می‏یر، پرسشنامۀ تعارض و ابهام نقش لو و همکاران، و پرسشنامۀ عدالت سازمانی کلکوئیت استفاده شده است. اطلاعات جمع‏آوری‌شده به کمک روش‏های آماری توصیفی و روش‏های آماری استنباطی شامل ضریب همبستگی پیرسون و تحلیل مسیر تجزیه و تحلیل شد. نتایج نشان داد که: تعهد سازمانی اثر مستقیم و اثر غیرمستقیم با میانجی‏گری ابهام نقش و تعارض نقش بر فرسودگی شغلی دارد. همچنین عدالت سازمانی اثر مستقیم و اثر غیرمستقیم با میانجی‏گری ابهام نقش و تعارض نقش بر فرسودگی شغلی دارد. در‌نهایت، ابهام نقش و تعارض نقش اثر مستقیم بر فرسودگی شغلی دارد. طبق شاخص‏های برازش‌شده، مدل نهایی پژوهش از برازش نسبتاً خوبی برخوردار است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Burnout syndrome includes aspects of emotional exhaustion, depersonalization and decrement of personal accomplishment to which staffs vulnerable to because of their exposure to physical and psychological stressors. The necessity of this research is related to inadequate research on women. The current research aims to explain burnout of working women with an emphasis on the role of organizational and psychological variables in Technical &amp; Vocational and Islamic Azad University of Shiraz. The research was conducted based on a descriptive-correlational method. The population includes all women employed at technical and vocational &amp; Islamic Azad university of Shiraz (N=225). According to the Cochran formula, the sample size was 143 women who were selected by multi-stage cluster random sampling method. Data was collected using Maslach burnout inventory, Allen and Meyer`s organizational commitment questionnaire, Lu et al role- conflict and ambiguity questionnaire, Colquitt’s organizational justice questionnaire. Data was analyzed using descriptive-statistic method that includes Pearson correlation coefficient and path analysis. The results show that justice and organizational commitment through role conflict and ambiguity mediation have indirect and negative effect on burnout. The results showed that organizational commitment has both direct and indirect effect on burnout via the mediation of role conflict and role ambiguity. Organizational justice has also both direct and indirect effect on burnout via the mediation of role conflict and role ambiguity. Role conflict and role ambiguity have shown to have direct effect on burnout. According to the fitted indices, the final model of the study has a relatively good fit.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>611</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>626</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدحسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صیف</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Hassan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Seif</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه علوم تربیتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه علوم تربیتی، دانشگاه پیام</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>seyfstudent@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>میترا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>یادگار</Family>
						<NameE>Mitra</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Yadegar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت آموزشی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد شیراز،گروه علوم تربیتی، شیراز، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت آموزشی، دانشگاه آزاد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.y_90@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ابهام نقش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تعارض نقش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تعهد سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زنان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عدالت سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فرسودگی شغلی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] آقایی، اصغر؛ جلالی، داریوش؛ حسن‏زاده، ریحانه؛ اصلان، زهرا (1390). «پیش‏بینی ابهام نقش، تعارض نقش، فرسودگی شغلی و ابعاد چهارگانه سرریز‌شدگی استرس مشاوران مراکز مشاورۀ شهر اصفهان بر اساس ویژگی‏های جمعیت‏شناختی آنان»، یافته‏های نو در روانشناسی، 20، ص‌69ـ88.##[ 2] ابیلی، خلیل؛ ناستی‏زایی، ناصر (1389). «بررسی رابطۀ توانمندسازی روان‌شناختی با تعهد سازمانی در پرسنل پرستاری بیمارستان‏های شهر زاهدان»، فصلنامۀپژوهشی دانشکدۀ بهداشت یزد، ص1و2، 1ـ14.##[3] پرداختچی، محمد‌حسن؛ احمدی، غلامعلی؛ آرزومندی، فریده (1388). «بررسی رابطۀ بین کیفیت زندگی کاری و فرسودگی شغلی مدیران و معلمان مدارس شهرستان تاکستان»، فصلنامۀ رهبری و مدیریت آموزشی، 3، ص25ـ50.##[4] سیدجوادین، رضا؛ عابدی، احسان؛ یزدانی، حمیدرضا؛ پورولی، بهروز (1392). «بررسی نقش میانجی اعتماد و تعهد سازمانی در رابطۀ بین عدالت سازمانی و رفتار شهروندی سازمانی در بیمارستان‏ها»، مدیریت بازرگانی، 1، ص105ـ118.##[5] جمالی، اختر؛ تقی‏پورظهیر، علی؛ صالحی، مسلم (1388). «رابطۀ بین عوامل شغلی و سازمانی با رفتار شهروند سازمانی اعضای هیئت علمی واحدهای منطقۀ یک دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی به منظور ارائۀ مدل مناسب»، فصلنامۀ رهبری و مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد گرمسار، 2، ص87ـ106.##[6] خدابخش، محمدرضا؛ منصوری، پروین (1389). «فراوانی ابعاد فرسودگی شغلی در پرستاران زن و مرد»، مجلۀ تحقیقات علوم پزشکی زاهدان، گزارش کوتاه.##[7] راهپیما، نازیلا؛ کاظمی، سلطانعلی؛ سهرابی، تادره (1391). «رابطۀ بین سلامت عمومی و رضایت زناشویی با فرسودگی شغلی زنان شاغل در استانداری و فرمانداری‏های تابعه در استان فارس»، جامعه‌شناسی زنان، 2، ص162ـ137.##[8] ریاحی‏نیا، نصرت (1390). «تأثیر مشاورۀ گروهی و کتاب‏درمانی بر کاهش فرسودگی شغلی زنان کتاب‏داران دانشگاهی»، فصلنامۀ مشاورۀ شغلی و سازمانی، 7، ص97ـ112.##[9] صیف، محمدحسن؛ ثابت مهارلوئی، عباس؛ رستگار، احمد؛ رکنی، احسان (1393). بررسی عوامل سازمانی و روان‌شناختی موثر بر تعارض کار‌ـ خانواده پرستاران زن متأهل»، فصلنامۀ علمی‌ـ پژوهشی زن و جامعه، 2، ص49ـ68.##[10] طلایی، علی؛ مخبر، نغمه؛ محمدنژاد، مریم؛ ثمری، علی‏اکبر (1387). «فرسودگی شغلی و عوامل وابسته به آن در کارکنان بیمارستان‏های دانشگاهی مشهد در سال 1385»، مجلۀ علمی دانشگاه علوم پزشکی سمنان، 3، ص237ـ246.##[11] عزیزی، لیلا؛ فیض‏آبادی، زهرا؛ صالحی، مریم (1387). «تحلیل عاملی اکتشافی و تأییدی پرسشنامۀ فرسودگی شغلی مسلچ در کارکنان دانشگاه تهران»، فصلنامۀ مطالعات روان‌شناختی، 3، ص38ـ52.##[12] کوهپایه‏زاده، جلیل؛ عقیلی‏نژاد، ماشالله؛ کبیرمکمل‏زاده، الهه؛ گل‏آبادی، مجید (1390). «بررسی میزان فرسودگی شغلی و عوامل موثر بر آن در کارکنان دانشکده‏ علوم پزشکی ایران سابق در سال 1389»، مجله علوم پزشکی رازی، 90، ص27ـ36.##[13] مشبکی، اصغر؛ دوستار، محمد (1386). «تبیین مدل تأثیرگذاری هوش عاطفی مدیران بر تعهد سازمانی کارکنان با توجه به نقش سبک‏های رهبری»، مدرس علوم انسانی، ویژه‌نامه مدیریت: ص234ـ211.##[14] مقصودی، منیژه؛ محمدی، شهناز (1389). «فرسودگی شغلی و دل‏زدگی زناشویی»، زن در توسعه و سیاست، 3، ص 71ـ57.##[15] هومن، حیدرعلی (1384). مدل‏یابی معادلات ساختاری، تهران: سمت.##[16] یعقوبی م. سقاییان‏نژاد اصفهانی س. ابوالقاسم‏گرجی ح. نوروزی م. رضایی ف. (1388). «رابطۀ‏ عدالت سازمانی با رضایت شغلی و تعهد سازمانی در بین کارکنان بیمارستان‏های منتخب دانشگاه علوم پزشکی اصفهان»، فصلنامۀ علمی‌ـ پژوهشی مدیریت سلامت، 35، ص25ـ32.##[17] Abedi, A. (2011). &quot;Recognising workplace burnout&quot;. {Internet}. Available form: http :// www.health guidance.org /entry/ 5051/1/ Recognising Workplace Burnout.html.##[18] Ahola, K. Hakanen J. (2007). &quot;Job strain, burnout, and depressive symptoms: A prospective study among dentists&quot;. Journal of affective disorders, 104: pp 103-110.‏##[19] Andrew, L.I. &amp; Jessica, B. (2008). &quot;Role ambiguity and self- efficacy: The moderating effects of goal orientation and procedural justice&quot;. Journal of Vocational Behavior, 73: pp 378.##[20] Celik, K. (2013). &quot;The Effect of Role Ambiguity and role conflict on performance of vice principals: the mediating role of burnout&quot;. Eurasian Journal of Educational Research (EJER), 51: pp 195-214.##[21] Chênevert, D., Jourdain, G., Cole, N., &amp; Banville, B. (2013). &quot;The role of organisational justice, burnout and commitment in the understanding of absenteeism in the Canadian healthcare sector&quot;. Journal of Health Organization and Management, 27: pp 350-367.##[22] Fernet, C., Austin, S., &amp; Tre´panier, S., &amp; Dussault, M. (2013). &quot;How do job characteristics contribute to burnout? Exploring the distinct mediating roles of perceived autonomy, competence and relatedness&quot;. European Journal of Work and Organizational Psychology, 22: pp 123- 137.##[23] Fichter, C., Cipolla, J., &amp; Raton, B. (2010). &quot; Role conflict, role ambiguity, job satisfaction, and burnout among financial advisors&quot;. The Journal of American Academy of Business, Cambridge, 15: pp 256-261.##[24] Gonzalez-Morales, M.G., Peiro, J.M. Rodriguez, I., &amp; Bliese, P.D. (2011). Perceived Collective Burnout: A Multilevel Explanation of Burnout. Anxiety Sterss Coping. Jan , 12: pp 1-19.##[25] Hooper, R. (2013). Role conflict experienced by teachers and its relationship to stress and burnout. PhD thesis. College of education.Walden University.##[26] Jones, GR. (2007). Organizational Theory, Design, and Change. 5th Ed. New Jersey, Publication: Upper Saddle River, pp 168-169.##[27] Judeh, M. (2011). &quot;Role Ambiguity and Role Conflict as Mediators of the Relationship between Orientation and Organizational Commitment&quot;. International Business Research, 4: pp 171-181.##[28] Lackritz, J. R. (2004). Exploring burnout among university faculty: Incidence, performance, and demographic issues. Teaching and Teacher Education, 20 (1), pp 713-729.##[29] Maslach, Christina, Susan E. Jackson, and Michael P. Leiter. &quot;Maslach burnout inventory.&quot; Evaluating stress: A book of resources 3 (1997): pp 191-218.‏##[30] Meredith, T.N. (2007). Analysis of physician satisfaction, stress, and leadership role ambiguity relative to turnover and cognttion. PhD thesis. UNIVERSITY OF PHOENIX.‏##[31] Najafaghaei, N., Moshiri, K., &amp; Shahrbanian, S. (2012). &quot;Relationship between organizational justice and job burnout in employees of sport and youth head office of Tehran&quot;. Pelagia Research Library, Advances in AppliedScience Research. 3: pp 2438-2445.##[32] Papastylianou, A., Kaila, M., &amp; Polychronopoulos, M. (2009). &quot;Teachers burnout, depression, role ambiguity and conflict&quot;. Published Online: 14 Jannuary 2009/SOC Psychol Educ (2009) 12: pp 295-314.##[33] Purvanova, R. K. Muros, J. P. (2010). &quot;Gender differences in burnout: Ameta-analysis&quot;. Journal of Vocational Behavior, 77: pp 168-185.##[34] Safikhani, M. (2014). The relatuion between organizational justice with burnout among employees in fars province gas company. Faculty of Literature and Humanities Science, Islamic Azad University, Arsanjan Branch.##[35] Shirom, A. (2003) Job-related Burnout: A review. In J.C. Quick, &amp; L. E. Tetrick (Eds.), Handbook of occupational health psychology (pp.245-264). Washington, DC: American Psychological Association.##[36] Sin, S. (2012). The Relationship Between Burnout And Role Stressors Amons Direct Service Providers At Centers For Independent Living In Region V. Rehabilitation Institute in the Graduate School Southern Illinois University Carbondale.##[37] Soltani, I., &amp; Ruhanei, A. (2005). &quot;Burnout in industrial and productive institution&quot;. Tadbir Educational and Scientific Journal, pp 109-123.##[38] Timms, C. Graham, D. Caltabiano M. (2006). &quot;Gender implication of perceptions of trust worthiness of school administration and teacher burnout, job stress&quot;. Australian Journal of School Issues, 41: pp 343-358.##[39] Tunc, T., &amp; Kutanis R.O. (2009). &quot;Role conflict, role ambiguity, and burnout in nurses and physicians at a university hospital in Turkey&quot;. Nursing &amp; health sciences, 11: pp 410-416.‏##[40] Vakola, M., &amp; Nikolaou, I. (2005). &quot;Attitudes towards organizational change: what is the role of employees’ stress and commitment? Employee relations&quot;, 27: pp 160-174##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>چکیده های انگلیسی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>English Abstracts</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT></CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>-</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>8</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				