<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>17</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Model for Sexual Deviant Behaviors of Teen Girls: Thinking on the Grounded Theory</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارائه مدل رفتار منحرفانه جنسی نوجوانان دختر: تاملی بر رویکرد زمینه‌ای</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>71</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>95</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">71923</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2019.276379.1007594</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نفیسه</FirstName>
					<LastName>فقیهی مقدس</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه معارف قرآن و اهل بیت(ع)، دانشکدة الهیات و معارف اهل البیت(ع)، دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فهیمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>مومنی راد</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد مطالعات زنان، دانشکدة الهیات و معارف اهل البیت(ع)، دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعید</FirstName>
					<LastName>شریفی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت فرهنگی، دانشکدة مدیریت، دانشگاه خوراسگان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>24</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Maturity is one of the most important stages of human development, and its developmental characteristics can cause various kinds of deviations and disorders. Girls, due to their experiences of physical and mental changes, enter the stage of physical and sexual maturity earlier than boys. Their problems in the health, psychological and social dimensions are more than boys due to physiological differences, social roles and governing traditions in society. Because no research has been conducted to identify and disclose the diverse behaviors of adolescent girls, this present study is to analyze the deviant sexual behaviors of matured girls by inductive qualitative method. This research was carried out using theoretical sampling method. Up to 17 girls aged from 12 to 15 years old were purposefully sampled for the aim. In this research, the technique used for data collection was semi-structured and deep interviewing, and the grounded method (systematic: Strauss &amp; Corbin) was used for data analysis. The analysis ultimately addresses 9 main categories including technology-driven sexual activity, risky leisure, passive self-stimulation, emotional disturbances, poorly-sustained parenting-and-addiction, lack of good sexual education, lack of self-regulation motivational skills, religious environments and environmental stimuli, incitement and the core of abnormal sexual socialization.   </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">نوجوانی از مراحل مهم رشد و تکامل انسان است که ویژگی‌های رشدی آن می‌تواند زمینه‌ساز بروز انواع انحرافات و اختلالات شود. دختران به دلیل ویژگی‌های جسمی و روانی خاص خود زودتر از پسران وارد مرحلة رشد جسمی و جنسی می‌شوند و مشکلات آن‌ها در ابعاد بهداشتی، روانی و اجتماعی به دلایل تفاوت‌های فیزیولوژیک، نقش‌های اجتماعی و سنت‌های حاکم در جامعه بیش از پسران است. با توجه به اینکه تاکنون پژوهشی در جهت کشف و تبیین چگونگی رفتارهای انحرافی نوجوانان دختر انجام نگرفته است، پژوهش حاضر در نظر دارد با روش کیفی استقرایی به تحلیل رفتارهای منحرفانة جنسی نوجوانان دختر بپردازد. این تحقیق با استفاده از روش نمونه‌گیری نظری و مشارکت 17 نوجوان دختر بین 12ـ15 سال به صورت هدفمند انجام شد. در این تحقیق، تکنیک استفاده‌شده برای جمع‌آوری داده‌ها مصاحبة نیمه‌ساختاریافته و عمیق بود و از روش گراندد (سیستماتیک: استراوس و کوربین) برای تحلیل داده‌ها استفاده شد. تحلیل درنهایت به 9 مقولة اصلی کنش جنسی‌شدة فناوری‌محور، فراغت خطر‌ساز، خود‌تحریکی انفعالی، اختلالات هیجانی، سیستم نامطلوب حمایتی والدـ والدینی، فقدان آموزش جنسی مطلوب، فقدان مهارت‌های خودتنظیمی انگیزشی، بی‌هویتی ‌دینی و محرک‌های محیطی خود‌تحریکی و مقولة هستة «جامعه‌پذیری جنسی نابهنجار» انجامید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آگاهی جنسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفتار انحرافی جنسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوجوانان دختر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هویت دینی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_71923_1696e8ffc54bf92c9a69cd88c80f010b.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
