<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>First Pages</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract></abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>2</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_62761_e27d80f852a29c91d1870a0ba862a108.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Study of social factors related to anorexia nervosa in Hamedan high school girl students</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghodsi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor of Sociology, Bu Ali Sina University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Esmaeel</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Balali</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor of Sociology, Bu Ali Sina University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Zahra</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Samadi Akhi Jani</namePart>
				<affiliation>MA of Sociology, Bu Ali Sina University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fereshteh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Behrooz</namePart>
				<affiliation>MA of Sociology, Bu Ali Sina University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In the past, an attractive and normal woman was characterized by having a fat and large body; nowadays, however, values have changed. Now, women consider having a thin, delicate and elongated body as a value trying so hard to gain such value. Based on social values ascribed to a balanced and normal body, it has become necessary for women to gain this special type of body thereby causing  dissatisfaction of body and its resultant increasing rate of anorexia nervosa among adolescents who are the most vulnerable groups exposed to this eating disorder. The current study aims to consider some social factors associated with anorexia nervosa in girl students of Hamadan high schools. This study was conducted using a questionnaire and surveying a sample of 300 girl students. Findings show that there are direct and positive relationships between anorexia nervosa with social comparison, parents’ normative pressure to thinness, friends’ normative pressure to thinness, media and body mass index variables, but there is a reverse and negative relationship between anorexia nervosa with body image variable. Also, friends’ normative pressure to thinness (beta=.24) and body mass index (beta = .13) variables were shown to be effective factors in explaining anorexia nervosa in studying the girl students.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>149</start>
					<end>168</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_62351_d8b5f3260e95b1fd6fb865e842064a72.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2017.62351</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Content analysis of women’s management and job promotion obstacles</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Esmaeil Pour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Faculty of Literature and Humanities, Guilan University, Rasht, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hamid Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Tafaghodi</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Student in Business Policy making Management, Faculty of Literature and Humanities, Guilan University, Rasht, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The current paper aims to analyze the factors that prevent women’s job advancement and promotion in organizations. In this study, qualitative methodology and  Directed Qualitative Content Analysis approaches were applied, and 16 women of the municipal districts 2, 4, 13, 16, and 22 of Tehran were interviewed during a four-month period from May, 2016 to August, 2016. After repeated review and analysis of the written interviews, 85 semantic units, 33 codes, 5 classes, and 2 themes were extracted. Two concepts of Social-Cultural Requirements and Role Requirements were recognized as the research themes as well as the main factors preventing women from job promotion. Social-Cultural Requirements are related to the factors which are obstacles to women&#039;s job promotion, as the forces from society structure. Role Requirements are related to the factors which do not prevent job promotion directly, but ruin women personal passion for advancement, by affecting their inner desire. Based on this study, it is concluded that by focusing on Role Requirements, the obstacles to women&#039; job promotion can be overcome.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>169</start>
					<end>185</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_62352_651bb0fce5e331d8bf8895f308080c6f.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2017.62352</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The effect of marriage on women’s work at home</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Vahid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mehrbani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Since family economics is the application of economic theory in explaining behavior with respect to family, marriage is undoubtedly one of the items in this realm. The aim of this paper is to investigate the impact of marriage on women&#039;s home labor supply theoretically and empirically. Accordingly, the utility maximization approach is applied to demonstrate how the behavior of a typical single woman changes after marriage. The theoretical model predicts that women turn to specialization at home production following marriage and thereby their welfare will increase. Two samples including single and married women who reside in Tehran have been used to present empirical evidence. These samples are restricted to all regions of Tehran on the basis of segmentation carried out by municipality. Data have been gathered by questionnaire which was constructed by author. Results approve the prediction of theoretical analysis. Estimations show that the event of marriage will significantly lead to an increase in home labor supply. These findings suggest that women specialize at home production due to marriage. In addition, results also indicate that income, education and employment have negative and statistically significant effect on work within home while, by contrast, the number of children has positive and statistically significant impact.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>187</start>
					<end>204</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_62353_7b68e2d213fcec803f5c34bcc8d562dc.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2017.62353</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Women and activism in social media (Case study: “Stealthy Freedom of Women” page in the Facebook)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hamed</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Talebian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Faculty Member of Culture, Art and Communication Research Institute, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sara</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Talebian</namePart>
				<affiliation>MA in Global Media and Communication at Helsinki University, Finland</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>&quot;My Stealthy Freedom&quot; is the name of a Facebook page that demands to protest against compulsory Hijab and demonstrate willing of clothing freedom for women in Iran. The foundation and activity of the page had been described as a &quot;social movement&quot;. Some western media claimed that this would be a successful social movement for Iranian women and some others asserted that this page would be a new platform in which Iranian women represent a new image of their identity. In this paper, analyzing qualitatively a purposive sample of photos with their captions, we are questioning these claims again. Our findings indicate that despite some excitements about a new social movement for Iranian women in western media and western human rights association, &quot;My Stealthy Freedom&quot; cannot be considered as a new applicable social movement against Iran&#039;s government and the law of compulsory hijab in Iran. Finally, we conclude that this Facebook page is not only incapable of organizing a real social movement against hijab, but also can be a well-suited example for the concept of slacktivism.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>205</start>
					<end>222</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_62354_90220665895b1eb28cc8a256cf9a9eef.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2017.62354</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Life experience of divorced women in Saveh City in the scope of family and social relations</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Farideh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khalajabadi Farahani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Institute for the Study and Research of the Population and Population of the country</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fatemeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Tanha</namePart>
				<affiliation>MA in Demography, University of Shiraz</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fatemeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Abootorabi Zarchi</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Student of Sociology of Economics and Development, Yasouj University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Today, the number of women who have lost their husbands as a result of divorce is on the rise. The experiences of these women often change in their relationships because of economic and social pressures. This study aims to explore the experiences of divorced women aged under 35about changes in family and social relationships, the results were then applied to the women living in Saveh. Interviewees were in different position with employment and mother. Sampling of this research was done purposefully using snowball method. This research is phenomenological given that women experience about the nature of their relationships after divorce is explored. In family relationships, the essence of women experience was supportive, and in social relations, their relationship was characterized with internal and external social exclusion and unsafe occupational and social environment. This resuls will be have many uses for social protection from women after divorce and also for married couple training about changing relationship after divorce.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>223</start>
					<end>240</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_62355_06127f05353be41fb1b99816df20fbe3.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2017.62355</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Rural women's knowledge and social needs for the integrated watershed management in the Ghezel Tape Ali Gholi Village in the Zanjan Province</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Esmail</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Karami Dehkordi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor of Agricultural Extension, Communication and Rural Development Department, University of Zanjan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Roghayeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Babaee</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc Graduate of Agricultural Extension and Education, University of Zanjan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Rural women play an important role in supporting their rural households&#039; livelihoods and can significantly contribute to the sustainable natural resources management programmes. The current research aims to investigate rural women&#039;s livelihood activities and their related needs for enhancing their knowledge and social capacities. The study was conducted using a case study through participatory rapid appraisal techniques in the Ghezel Tape Aligholi Village located in the Zanjan Province of Iran. Rural women contributed to their households&#039; livelihoods through various livelihood strategies, comprising non-agricultural activities including carpet weaving; agricultural activities dependent on rangelands, specially collecting naturally medicinal and edible plants; and agricultural activities with low dependency on rangelands, particularly product harvest and local processing. Assessing rural women&#039; needs showed that they mostly needed updated knowledge and skills regarding proper harvest, processing and packaging of horticultural and dairy products, natural resources conservation methods, new agricultural and non-agricultural activities, and higher literacy. The necessity to improve rural women&#039;s environmental attitude, particularly about rural waste management was also recognised to be an important need. Moreover, they need to strengthen their social capacities, particularly in regard to influencing agricultural markets, relations and trust in rural communities and with external actors, and strengthening rural women organisations. These needs imply the necessity of developing agricultural extension and natural resources management programmes for human and social capacity building of rural women.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>241</start>
					<end>264</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_62356_8f5b2ae376a700db10e3e9e168e33a2d.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2017.62356</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Women’s encounter with disruption of the tranquility in marital life</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Susan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Bastani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor, Department of Sociology, Alzahra University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Shohre</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rowshani</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Candidate of Women Studies, Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Nahle</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Gharavi Naeeni</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor, Department of Quran &amp; Hadith Sciences, Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The current study aims to investigate the way married women living in Tehran face with disruption of sense of tranquility in marital life. This research has been done using grounded theory method and deep interview technique. As a result of encounter with disruption of sense of tranquility, which is the result of the gap between the assets and demands of women, it has become necessary for women to adopt a set of strategies with two general approaches of &quot;change in assets&quot; including modification of the spousal relationship, management of interactive problems with families, improvement of the status of children,  attention to self and removal of structural barriers, with the aim of changing the available status into a desirable one, and &quot;change in demands&quot; including reduced demands, patience and forgiveness and selection of the null relationship, with the aim of accepting the available status. Choosing these strategies and their effectiveness is affected by a set of conditions such as “decision-making factors&quot; including the husband&#039;s approach, religious beliefs, dominance of affection and exterior constraint.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>265</start>
					<end>289</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_62357_32bcbbbf1a1ea68f80af1c910b8e0033.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2017.62357</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>English Abstrscts</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract></abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>7</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_62760_79d3896cae27bd3398a34fd805b03635.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>