<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1398</YEAR>
<VOL>17</VOL>
<NO>3</NO>
<MOSALSAL>0</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>163</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی و مقایسة شاخص‌های توانمندی روان‌شناختی زنان روستایی و شهری در بحران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Study and comparison of psychological empowerment indices of rural and urban women in crisis</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>توانمندی روان‌شناختی زنان فرایندی است که در آن زنان به لحاظ شناختی و رفتاری برای سازماندهی زندگی فردی، خانوادگی و اجتماعی خود توانمند می‌شوند. این پژوهش با هدف مقایسة شاخص‌های توانمندی روان‌شناختی در زنان روستایی و شهری انجام گرفت. در این پژوهش، زنان ساکن در شهر سرپل ذهاب و روستاهای همجوار، که پس از زلزلة کرمانشاه همچنان در شهر و روستای خود ماندند و با وضعیت منطقة سکونت خود انطباق یافتند، جامعة ‏آماری مطالعه را تشکیل می‌دادند. برای انتخاب اعضای نمونه از شیوة تصادفی خوشه‏ای استفاده شد. از بین مجموع زنان ساکن در شهر سرپل ذهاب پنج منطقه انتخاب شدند و با توجه به موارد ذکرشده، تعداد 219 زن و 154 زن از روستاهای واقع در دشت ذهاب به‌عنوان نمونة پژوهش انتخاب شدند و پرسش‌نامة توانمندی روان‌شناختی را تکمیل کردند. به منظور اندازه‏گیری شاخص‌های توانمند‌سازی روان‌شناختی در بحران از پرسش‌نامة محقق‌ساخته استفاده شد. ساخت و تنظیم این پرسش‌نامه از طریق مضمون‏های احصایی از داده‏های کیفی به‌دست آمد. در پژوهش حاضر، ضریب اعتبار کل پرسش‌نامه در گروه نمونة مطالعه‌شده برابر با 868/0 به‌دست آمد. برای تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها، از تحلیل واریانس چند‌متغیری استفاده شد و به منظور بررسی جزئی‌تر نتایج آزمون تعقیبی توکی گزارش شد. یافته‌های پژوهش نشان داد از میان مؤلفه‌های درون‌شخصی، مدار شناختْ متغیری بود که در زنان شهری نمره‌های کمتری از زنان روستایی را به خود اختصاص داد. همچنین، تفاوت معناداری در مؤلفه‌های بین‌شخصیِ توانمندی روان‌شناختی میان زنان شهر و روستا به‌دست نیامد و به‌طور‌کلی نشان می‌دهد متغیر مستقل، که همان مکان زندگی است، تأثیر زیادی بر مدار شناخت دارد؛ اما بر مؤلفه‌های بین‌شخصی تأثیر بسزایی ندارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Introduction: The psychological empowerment of women is a process in which women are empowered cognitively and behaviorally to organize their personal, family and social life. This research was conducted to compare psychological empowerment indices in rural and urban women. Methods: The study population consisted of women residing in Saral-e-Zahab and neighboring villages who remained in their city and village after the earthquake in Kermanshah and adapted to the conditions of their area of residence. A cluster random method was used to select sample members. Of the total number of women living in Saral-e-Zahab city, five regions were selected. According to the above, 154 women and 154 women from villages located in Zahab plain were selected as the sample and completed the psychological empowerment questionnaire. Researcher-made questionnaire was used to measure psychological empowerment indices in crisis. This questionnaire was developed through qualitative data through thematic content. In this study, the total validity of the questionnaire in the sample group was 0.886. To analyze the data, multivariate analysis of variance was used and for the purpose of a more detailed examination, the results of Tukey&#039;s post hoc test were reported. Results: The findings of this study showed that among in-person components, there was a variable cognitive circuit that received less scores from rural women in urban women. Also, there is no significant difference in the interpersonal components of psychological empowerment between urban and rural women. In general, the independent variable, which is the same place of life, has a great influence on the cognitive circuit, but does not affect the interpersonal components.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>349</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>368</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سمیه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کاظمیان</Family>
						<NameE>Somaye</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Kazemian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>somaye.kazemian@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فهیمه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فداکار داورانی</Family>
						<NameE>FAHIME</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>FADAKAR DAVARANI</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری  تخصصی و مدرس دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری  تخصصی و مدرس دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>azadi209@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مریم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سیفی</Family>
						<NameE>maryam</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>seifi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناسی ارشد دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناسی ارشد دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>maryamseifi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>توانمندی روان‌شناختی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زنان روستایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زنان شهری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF> ازکیا، مریم. (1372). بررسی نیازهای بهزیستی در جامعة روستایی ایران، تهران: دانشگاه علوم بهزیستی و توانبخشی.##[2]  آقاجانی، زهرا؛ جهانگیری، جهانگیر؛ لهسایی‌زاده، عبدالعلی (1396). «فرایند برساخت هویت زنان در جریان طلاق: بازاندیشی در تقدس خانواده و قبح طلاق»، فصل‌نامة توسعة اجتماعی، ش 3، ص 129ـ166.##[3]  باقری‏یزدی، سیدعباس؛ یاسمی، محمدتقی؛ خواصی، لیلا؛ کافی، اقدس (1389). «اثربخشی مداخلات روانی‌ـ اجتماعی در بازماندگان زلزلة قزوین»، فصل‌نامة امداد و نجات، س 2، ش 2، ص 1ـ9.##[4]  حسین چاری، مسعود؛ محمدی، مژگان (1390). «پیش‌بینی تاب‌آوری روان‌شناختی براساس اعتقادات مذهبی در دانشجویان شهری و روستایی»، روان‌شناسی معاصر، س 6، دورة 2، ص45ـ56.##[5] حیدری، آرمان؛ میرزایی، عزت‌الله (1393). «بررسی وضعیت سلامت زنان سرپرست خانوار شهری و روستایی شهرستان جهرم و عوامل اجتماعی‌ـ اقتصادی مرتبط با آن»، فصل‌نامة فرهنگی‌ـ تربیتی زنان و خانواده، س 9، ش 27، ص 136ـ163.##[6] داورخانی، فضیله؛ حسام، مهدی؛ چراغی، مهدی؛ امیدی، امید؛ محمدی، زینب (1396). «تحلیل اثرات تغییرات الگوی مسکن بر کارکرد زنان روستایی»، مجلة مسکن و محیط روستا، ش 163، ص 61ـ78.##[7] رحمانی، جبار (1391). «جایگاه دین روستایی در جامعه‌شناسی روستا: علل بی‌توجهی و پیامدهای آن»، فصل‌نامة مطالعات و تحقیقات اجتماعی در ایران، دورة اول، ش 3، ص 85ـ105.##[8]  ریاضی، ابوالحسن (1392). «شهر؛ پدیده‌ای میان‌رشته‌ای»، فصل‌نامة مطالعات میان‌رشته‌ای در علوم انسانی، دورة 6، ش اول، ص101ـ115.## [9] ریو (1397). انگیزش و هیجان، ترجمة یحیی سید محمدی، تهران: ویرایش.##[10]  شولتز، دوران پی؛ الن شولتز (1395). نظریه‌های شخصیت، ترجمة یحیی سید‌محمدی، تهران: نشر ویرایش.##[11] عباس‌زاده، محمد؛ بوداقی، علی؛ اقدسی علمداری، فران (1393). توانمندسازی زنان سرپرست خانوار با تأکید بر راهکارهای بومی، تهران: مجموعه مقالات برگزیدة همایش ملی توانمندسازی.##[12] فاضلی، محمد (1389). مصرف و سبک زندگی، قم: صبح صادق.##[13]  فقیری، مژگان؛ علی‌بیگی، امیرحسین؛ پور‌قاسم، فاطمه؛ تاتار، مریم (1393). «پیش‌بینی توانمندسازی زنان روستایی با استفاده از الگوی مبتنی بر تحلیل تشخیصی (مطالعة موردی: شهرستان کنگاور)»، فصل‌نامة فرهنگی‌ـ تربیتی زنان و خانواده، س 9، ش 27، ص 114ـ133.##[14] کاوه، زینب؛ صارم، اعظم؛ فراش، نورالدین (1396). «مقایسة سبک زندگی سلامت‌محور زنان شاغل و غیرشاغل شهر شیراز با تأکید بر متغیرهای جمعیتی»، نامة انجمن جمعیت‌شناسی ایران، س 12، ش 23، ص 177ـ205.##[15] کرمانی، مهدی؛ نوغانی دخت بهمنی؛ محسن؛ برادران کاشانی، زهرا(1397). «فراتحلیل کیفی مقالات پژوهشی حوزة توانمندسازی زنان روستایی و شهری در ایران»، مطالعات اجتماعی و روان‌شناختی، س 16، ش 2، ص33ـ54.##[16] کیمیایی، سید علی(1390). «شیوه‌های توانمندسازی زنان سرپرست خانوار رفاه اجتماعی»، دورة 11، ش 40، ص 63ـ92.##[17] گیدنز، آنتونی (1378). تجدد و تشخص، ترجمة ناصر موفقیان، تهران: نی.##[18] مطوف، شریف (1386). «بحران هویت و تشدید آن در زندگی اردوگاهی پس از زلزلة بم»، ماهنامة باغ نظر، دورة 3، ش 8، ص73ـ80.##[19] نیلی، محمدرضا (1388). نقش تلویزیون در تقویت خودگردانی و خودکارآمدی زنان سرپرست خانوارها، دومین همایش توانمندسازی زنان و توان‌افزایی زنان سرپرست خانوار، شهرداری تهران: امور بانوان.##[20] یزدانی، حمید (1381). نگرشی بر توانمندسازی، تهران: مطالعات بازرگانی، ص 28 و 33.## [21] Balabanovic, J., Ayers, B., &amp; Hunter, M. S. (2012). Women&#039;s experiences of Group Cognitive Behavior Therapy for hot flushes and night sweats following breast cancer treatment : An interpretative phenomenological analysis. Maturitas, 72(3), 236-42..##[22] Banato , E.J.(2016). Educational resilience:The relationship between school protective factors and student achievement. San Diego: state university.(Disseration phD).## [23] Bandura, A. (1997). Self-efficacy: The exercise of control. New York: W.H. Freeman and Company.##[24] Burt, R.S. (1987). &quot;Social contagion and innovation: Cohesion versus structural equivalence.&quot; American Journal of Sociology, 92: 1287–1335..##[25] Chen,M., Sebstad, J.,O&#039;connell, L. (1999). Counting the Invisible Workforce: The Case of Homebased Workers. World Development, 27(3), 603-610. 40##[26] Chio, M. C., Hsu , M. H. &amp; Wang, E. T.(2006). Understanding Knowledge sharing in virtual communities: An integration of social capital and social cognitive theories, Decision Support System, 42(8): 1872-1888.25##[27] Deci, E.L, Connel, J.P. Rayan, R.M.(1989). Self- Determination in a Work Organization Journal Applied Psychology 74. Vol3, pp577-586.##[28] Drury, J., &amp; Reicher, S. (2009). Collective psychological empowerment as a model of social change: researching crowds and power. Journal of Social Issues, 65(4), 707-725.##[29] Giuliano, P.(2014). The Role of Women in society: from Preindustrial to Modern Times. CESifo Economic Studies. N. 10.##  [30] Gloria ,M &amp; Steinhardt, T (2014). Relationships Among Positive Emotions, Coping, Resilience and Mental Health†. Stress and Health, 32, 2, 145–156. 19##[31] Hancer , Murat, George R.Thomas,(2003). Psychological Empowerment of Non-Supervisory Employees Working in Full-Service Restaurant, Hospitality Management, Vol 22. No1, pp3-16.## [32] Hancer , Murat, George R.Thomas,(2003). Psychological Empowerment of Non-Supervisory Employees Working in Full-Service Restaurant, Hospitality Management, Vol 22. No1, pp3-16.##[33] Kozlowski, A. (2013). &quot;Mindful mating: exploring the connection between mindfulness and relationship satisfaction&quot;. Sexual and Relationship Therapy, 28 (1–2), 92–104. doi: 10. 1080/ 146819.##[34]  Lee, Y.J.(2017). Subjective Quality of Life Measurement in Taipei, Building and Enviroment, 43(7),pp.1205-1215.## [35]  Mehling, W. E. Gopisetty, V. Daubenmier, J. Price, C. J. Hecht, F. M. &amp; Stewart, A. (2009).&quot;Body awareness: Construct and self-report measures&quot;. PloS One, 4(5), e5614..##[36]  Nash, R., Lemcke, P., &amp; Sacre, S. (2017). Enhancing transition: An enhanced model of clinical placement for final year nursing student. Nurse Educ. Today, 29(1), 48-56 .## [37]  Ongori, H., &amp; Shunda, J. P. W. (2008). Managing Behind the Scenes Employee Empowerment. The International Journal of Applied Economics and Finance, 2(2),84-94.##          [38] Rota, A. and Sidahmed, A. (2010). IFAD’s livestock position paper livestock planning. challenges and strategies for livestock development in IFAD. Available at: https://fcrn.org.uk/sites/default/files/IFAD_LivestockPaper.pdf (Retrieved at 12 June 2018).## [39] Siegel, Ronald D. (2010), The Mindfulness Solution: Everyday Practices for Everyday Problems, Guilford Press.##[40]   So,L &amp; Tang CA. (2003). Trajectory of traumatic stress symptoms in the aftermath of extreme natural disaster: a study of Adult Thai survivors of the 2004 Southeast Asian earthquake &amp; tsunami. Journal of Nervous Mental Diseases, 195(1): 54_59.##[41]  Spreitzer,G.M.(1995).Psychologycal empowerment in the workplace: Dimention, measurment, and validation. Academy of Management Journal,38(5):1442-1465.##[42] Tangka, F.K., Jabbar, M.A. and Shapiro, B.I. (2000). Gender roles and child, correct citation: gender roles and child, nutrition in livestock production systems in developing countries: a critical review. Socioeconomics and Policy Research Working Paper 27. ILRI (International Livestock Research Institute), Nairobi, Kenya. 64 pp.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>اثر حضور زنان در افزایش اثربخشی کمیتۀ حسابرسی: شواهدی از هزینه ‏های نمایندگی و خطر ورشکستگی در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The effect of female presence on increasing the effectiveness of the audit committee: Evidence from agency costs and bankruptcy risk in the Tehran Stock Exchange</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در سال‏های اخیر، حضور زنان در عرصه‏های راهبری شرکت‏ها، به‌ویژه در هیئت‏‏مدیره و کمیته‏های حسابرسی، رشد درخور ملاحظه‏ای داشته است. این پژوهش درصدد است با بررسی تأثیر حضور زنان در کمیتۀ حسابرسی بر هزینه‏های نمایندگی و خطر ورشکستگی به این پرسش پاسخ دهد که آیا زنان حاضر در کمیتۀ حسابرسی با افزایش اثربخشی آن در ارتباط‌اند یا خیر. برای این منظور، 662 مشاهدۀ سال‌‌ـ شرکت در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، طی سال‏های 1391 تا 1396، به روش داده‏های ترکیبی و رویکرد حداقل مربعات تعمیم‌یافته تجزیه و تحلیل شد. نتایج پژوهش نشان داد که حضور زنان در کمیتۀ حسابرسی رابطۀ منفی و معناداری با هزینه‏های نمایندگی و خطر ورشکستگی دارد. به سخن دیگر، حضور اعضای زن در کمیتۀ حسابرسی باعث کاهش هزینه‏های نمایندگی و خطر ورشکستگی شرکت‏ها می‏شود. در‌مجموع، نتایج از این دیدگاه حمایت می‏کند که زنان ناظران بهتری بوده و‌ خطر‏گریزترند و کمتر رفتارهای فرصت‏طلبانۀ مدیریت را تحمل می‏کنند و در‌نتیجه به افزایش اثربخشی کمیتۀ حسابرسی منجر می‏شوند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In recent years, the participation of women in corporate governance, especially on boards of directors and audit committees, has considerably increased. Examining the effect of female audit committee members on agency costs and bankruptcy risk, this study aims to answer the question of whether women on the audit committee are associated with the improvement of its effectiveness. In this respect, 662 firm-year observations of listed companies on the Tehran Stock Exchange for the period 2012-2017 were analyzed, employing the method of panel data and Generalized Least Squares (GLS). The research findings revealed that female presence on audit committees has a significant negative association with agency costs and bankruptcy risk. In other words, female presence on audit committees leads to the reduction in agency costs and bankruptcy risk. In sum, the results support the viewpoint that women make better monitors, and they are more risk-averse and less tolerant towards managers’ opportunistic behaviors and thus, lead to the enhancement of audit committee effectiveness.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>369</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>388</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خراشادی</Family>
						<NameE>mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>khorashadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری حسابداری، دانشکدة علوم انسانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، زاهدان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری حسابداری، دانشکدة علوم انسانی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mkhorashadi@tvu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مرادی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Moradi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه حسابداری، دانشکدة مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان، زاهدان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه حسابداری، دانشکدة مدیریت و</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m_ali_moradi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>پایان</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Payan</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه ریاضی، دانشکدة علوم پایه، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، زاهدان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه ریاضی، دانشکدة علوم پایه، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>payan_iauz@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جنسیت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کمیتۀ حسابرسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ورشکستگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هزینۀ نمایندگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1[ ارباب سلیمانی، عباس؛ نفری، محمود (1378). اصـول حـسابرسی، تهـران: سازمان حسابرسی.##]2[ اورادی، جواد؛ لاری دشت‌بیاض، محمود؛ سالاری فورگ، زینب (1395). «بررسی رابطة بین ویژگی‏های کمیتۀ حسابرسی و عملکرد شرکت‏»، دانش حسابداری مالی، ش 4، ص 111ـ131.##]3[ اسلامی بیدگل، غلامرضا، نیکومرام، هاشم و همکاران (1390). «محافظه‏کاری حسابداری و بحران مالی شرکت‏های پذیرفته‏شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران»، دانش مالی و تحلیل اوراق بهادار، دورة 4، ش 9، ص 125ـ146.##]4[ ایمانی برندقی، محمد؛ عبدی، مصطفی؛ کاظمی علوم، مهدی (1397). «بررسی تأثیر تنوع جنسیتی در کمیتۀ حسابرسی بر حق‏الزحمۀ حسابرسیِ شرکت‏های پذیرفته‏شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران»، بررسی‏های حسابداری و حسابرسی، ش 3، ص 303ـ322.##]5[ باباجانی، جعفر؛ بابایی، مسعود (1390). «تأثیر استقرار واحد حسابرسی داخلی و تشکیل کمیتۀ حسابرسی در ارتقای مسئولیت پاسخگویی مالی دانشگاه‏ها مؤسسات آموزش عالی و تحقیقاتی»، دانش حسابداری، ش 4، ص 7ـ27.##]6[ برزگر، قدرت‌الله؛ حسن نتاج کردی، محسن؛ ملکی، دنیا (1398). «بررسی اثر ویژگی‎های کمیتة حسابرسی بر افشای مسئولیت اجتماعی شرکت‎ها»، بررسی‏‏های حسابداری و حسابرسی، ش اول، ص 19ـ38.##]7[ رضائی پیته‏نوئی، یاسر؛ محسنی، خدیجه (1397). «بررسی ارتباط بین حضور زنان در هیئت‏مدیره و ضعف کنترل داخلی، شواهدی از شرکت‏های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران»، زن در توسعه و سیاست، ش 3، ص 439ـ456.##]8[ سپاسی، سحر؛ عبدلی، لیلا (1395). «تأثیرات حضور زنان در هیئت‌مدیره بر ارزش شرکت و عملکرد مالی»، پژوهش‌های حسابداری مالی و حسابرسی، ش 29، ص 39ـ58.##]9[ صالحی، مهدی؛ اورادی، جواد؛ سالاری فورگ، زینب (1395). «تأثیر وجود کمیتۀ حسابرسی و ویژگی‏های آن بر تأخیر گزارش حسابرسی»، دانش حسابداری، ش 26، ص 59ـ83.##]10[ عبدی، مصطفی؛ ثنایی محمدی، محمدحسین و همکاران (1398). «اثربخشی ویژگی‌های کمیتة حسابرسی بر عدم تقارن اطلاعاتی: دیدگاه نظریة نمایندگی»، دانش حسابرسی، ش، 74، ص ۲۰۹ـ۲۳۶.##]11[ عباسی، ابراهیم؛ خطیبی‏فر، فرزانه (1395). ارتباط بین ساختار حاکمیت شرکتی و درماندگی مالی، اولین همایش پژوهش‏های کاربردی در مدیریت صنعتی.##]12[ کاظمی علوم، مهدی؛ ایمانی برندق، محمد؛ عبدی، مصطفی (1398). «بررسی تأثیر تنوع جنسیتی در هیئت‌ مدیره و کمیتۀ حسابرسی بر کیفیت سود»، دانش حسابداری، ش 1، ص 137ـ168.##]13[ مشکی میاوقی، مهدی؛ هاشمی سعادت، مریم (1394). «بررسی رابطة حاکمیت شرکتی با احتمال ورشکستگی در شرکت‏های پذیرفته‏شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران»، پژوهش حسابداری، ش 17، ص 37ـ57.##[14] Abbott, L. J., Parker, S. &amp; Presley, T. J. (2012). “Female board presence and the likelihood of financial restatement”, Accounting Horizons, 26 (4), PP 607-629.##[15] Adams, R. B. &amp; Ferreira, D. (2009). “Women in the boardroom and their impact on governance and performance”, Journal of Financial Economics, 94 (2), PP 291-309.##[16] Ahmed, A.,.Monem, R., Delaney, D., and Ng, C. (2017). “Gender diversity in corporate boards and continuous disclosure: Evidence from Australia”, Journal of Contemporary Accounting &amp; Economics, 13 (2), PP 89-107.##[17] Ahmed, H, Kamardin, H,. (2015). Internal and External Audit Attributes, Audit Committee Characteristics, Ownership Concentration and Earnings Quality: Evidence from Malaysia, Mediterranean Journal of Social Sciences, Doi:10.5901/mjss.2015.v6n3p458.##[18] Alvarado, N., de Fuentes, P. and Laffarga, J. (2017). “Does board gender diversity influence financial performance?”, Evidence from Spain, Journal of Business Ethics, 141 (2), PP 337-350.##[19] Bansal. N, A, K.Sharma. (2016). Audit committee, corporate governance and firm performance. International Journal of Economics and Finance; Vol. 8, No. 3.##[20] Cadbury, A. (1992). Report on the Committee on the Financial Aspects of Corporate Governance, Gee, London.##[21] Cai, C, X,. David, H,. Gaoliang, T,. Qinghua, W,. (2015). Do audit committees reduce the agency costs of ownership structure?, Pacific-Basin Finance Journal, doi.org/10.1016/j.pacfin.2015.01.002.##[22] Carter, D. A., Souza, F. D., Simkins, B.J. &amp; Simpson, W.G. (2010). “The gender and ethnic diversity of US boards and board committees and firm financial performance”, Corporate Governance: An International Review, 18 (5), PP 396-414.##[23] Chen, Y., Eshleman, J, D. and Soileau, J, S. (2016). “Board Gender Diversity and Internal Control Weaknesses”, Advances in Accounting, 33, PP 11-19.##[24] Chuang, L.; Xiuhong, L.; and L. Zhang (2010). Earnings Quality and the Agency Costs of Controlling Shareholder International Conference on E-Business and E-Government, PP 5132-5135.##[25] Dawson, L. (1997), “Ethical Difference between men and women in sales profession”, Journal of Business Ethics, Vol. 16 No. 1, PP 1143-1152.##[26] Dey, A. (2008). “Corporate governance and agency conflicts”, Journal of Accounting Research, 46(5): PP 1143-1181.##[27] Eshleman, J. D., &amp; Lawson B. (2017). “Audit market structure and audit pricing”, Accounting Horizons, 31 (1), PP 57-81.##[28] Francis, B., Hasan, I., Park, J. C. and Wu, Q. (2015). “Gender Differences in Financial Reporting Decision Making: Evidence from Accounting Conservatism”, Contemporary Accounting Research, 32 (3), PP 1285-1318.##[29] Gul, F. A., Srinidhi, B. &amp; Ng, A. C. (2011). “Does gender diversity improve the informativeness of stock prices”, Journal of Accounting and Economics, 51, (3). PP 314-38.##[30] Ittonen, K., Miettinen, J. &amp; Vahamaa, S. (2010). “Does female representation on audit committees affect audit fees”, Quarterly Journal of Finance and Accounting, 49 (3/4), PP 113-139.##[31] Jensen, M., &amp; Meckling, W. (1976). “Theory of the firm: Managerial behavior, agency costs and ownership structure”, Journal of financial economics, 3: PP 305-360.##[32] Jia, J. (2019). Does risk management committee gender diversity matter? – A financial distress perspective, Managerial Auditing Journal, In Press.##[33] Kalbers, L., &amp; Fogarty, T.(1993). “Audit committee effectiveness: An empirical investigation of the contribution of power”, Auditing: A Journal of Practice and Theory, 12 (1), PP 24-49.##[34] Lai, K, M, Y., Srinidhi, B., Gul, F, A., and Tsui, J, S, L. (2017). “Board gender diversity, auditor fees, and auditor choice”, Contemporary Accounting Research, 34 (3), PP 1681-1714.##[35] Lakshan, A, M, I. W. M. H. N. Wijekoon. (2012). “Corporate governance and corporate failure”, Procedia Economics and Finance, 2 (1): PP 191-198.##[36] Lin, J. W., and Hwang, M. I. (2010). “Audit quality, corporate governance, and earnings management: a meta-analysis”, International Journal of Auditing, 14 (1), PP 57-77.##[37] Lopez, D. M., Rich, K. T., and Smith, P. (2013). “Auditor size and internal control reporting differences in nonprofit healthcare organizations”, Journal of Public Budgeting, Accounting and Financial Management, 25 (1), PP 41-68.##[38] Martinov,N.B, Dominic S.B. and Soh, D.T. (2015). “An investigation into the roles, characteristics, expectations and evaluation practices of audit committees”, Managerial Auditing Journal, Vol (30) Iss 8/9, PP 727 – 755.##[39] McMullen, D. A., and Raghunandan, K. (1996). “Enhancing audit committee effectiveness”, Journal of Accountancy, 182 (2), PP 79-81.##[40] Nadeem, M., De Silva, T., Gan, C., and Zaman, R. (2017). “Boardroom gender diversity and intellectual capital efficiency”, Evidence From China, Pacific Accounting Review, 29 (4), PP 590-615.##[41] Niederle, M., and Vesterlund, L. (2007). “Do women shy away from competition? Do men compete too much?”, The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 122 (3), PP 1067-1101.##[42] Post, C., and Byron, K. (2015). “Women on boards and firm financial performance”, A Meta-Analysis, Academy of Management Journal, 58 (5), PP 1546-1571.##[43] Oradi, J., and Izadi, Z, D, J. (2019). Audit committee gender diversity and financial reporting: evidence from restatements, Managerial Auditing Journal, In Press.##[44] Ray, D. M. (2005). “Corporate boards and corporate democracy”, Journal of Corporate Citizenship, 20, PP 93-105.##[45]Rashid, A. (2015). “Revisiting Agency Theory: Evidence of Board Independence and Agency Cost from Bangladesh”, Journal of Business Ethics, 130, PP 181–198##[46] Srinidhi, B., Gul. F. and Tsui, J. (2011). “Female directors and earnings quality”, Contemporary Accounting Research, 28 (5). PP 1610-1644.##[47] Stephen, O A, Iyoha, F, O, &amp; Obigbemi, I, F, (2014). Effectiveness of Audit Committee and Firm Financial Performance in Nigeria: An Empirical Analysis.Journal of Accounting and Auditing: Research &amp; Practice http://www.ibimapublishing.com/journals/JAARP/jaarp.html, DOI: 10.5171/2014.301176.##[48] Thiruvadi, S., &amp; Huang, H. W. (2011). “Audit committee gender differences and earnings management”, Gender in Management: An International Journal, 26 (7), PP 483-498.##[49] Usman, M, Farooq, M.U., Zhang, J., Makki, A.M.M., &amp; Khan, M. K. (2019). Female directors and the cost of debt: Does gender diversity in the boardroom matter to lenders?. Managerial Auditing Journal, In Press.##[50] Wahid, A. S. (2018). The Effects and the Mechanisms of Board Gender Diversity: Evidence from Financial Manipulation, Journal of Business Ethics, https://doi.org/10.1007/s10551-018-3785-6.##[51] Zahra, S.A., &amp; Pearce, J.A. (1989). “Boards of directors and corporate Financial Performance”, A Review and Interactive Model, Journal of Management, 15, (2), PP 291-334##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مهارت‌های تأثیرگذار بر تمایل به اشتغال و اشتغال‏پذیری بانوان دانش‏آموختة دانشگاهی در استان همدان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The skills affected on employment intention and employability of women&#039;s university graduated in Hamedan province</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>با توجه به اینکه سرمایه‏گذاری درخور توجهی برای رشد و ارتقای سطح دانش افراد تحصیل‌کرده، از جمله زنان، در قالب آموزش‏های دانشگاهی انجام می‏گیرد، اهمیت موضوع اشتغال آن‏ها بیش از پیش آشکار می‏شود، زیرا با افزایش اشتغال دانش‏آموختگان دانشگاهی می‏توان به نحو شایسته و مطلوب از سرمایه‏های انسانی کشور بهره‏برداری کرد. هدف این پژوهش شناسایی و بررسی مهارت‌های تأثیرگذار بر میزان اشتغال‏پذیری بانوان دانش‏آموختة دانشگاهی است. جامعة آماری پژوهش را بانوان دانش‏آموختة جویای کار در استان همدان تشکیل دادند. روش نمونه‏گیری به صورت تصادفی سهمیه‏ای بود که بر‌حسب جمعیت آماری موجود بانوان دانش‏آموخته (10431 نفر) 350 نفر به‌عنوان نمونه انتخاب شدند. پس از جمع‏آوری داده‏ها، تجزیه و تحلیل داده‏ها با استفاده از آماره‏های توصیفی و تحلیلی و کاربرد نرم‏افزارهای SPSS و PLS انجام شد. براساس نتایج تحقیق، ارتباط مشاغل موجود در بازار کار با رشتة تحصیلی و مهارت‌های کسب‌شدة بانوان دانش‏آموخته در استان همدان در حد ضعیف ارزیابی شد و محتوای آموزشی دانشگاه‏ها پیوستگی و همپوشانی ضعیفی با نیازهای بازار کار داشتند. نتایج ضریب همبستگی نیز نشان داد بین متغیرهای سازگاری، مهارت‌های ارتباطی، مهارت‌های فناوری اطلاعات، تمایل به اشتغال با اشتغال‏پذیری دانش‏آموختگان زن رابطة مثبت و معنا‏داری وجود دارد. سایر متغیرهای مستقل تحقیق رابطة معنا‏داری با اشتغال‏پذیری دانش‏آموختگان نداشتند. نتایج این تحقیق نشان داد بانوان دانش‏آموختة استان همدان برای احراز مشاغل موجود نیازمند کسب مهارت‌هایی از قبیل مهارت‌های فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات، مهارت‌های عمومی و ارتباطی، مهارت‌های فردی مثل تفکر انتقادی و حل مسئله، مهارت‌های فنی و تخصصی و مهارت‌های مدیریتی و برنامه‏ریزی‌اند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>With regard to significant investment on developing and enhancing the level of university graduates&#039; knowledge, including women, the importance of their employment becomes increasingly apparent. Because by increasing the employment of university graduates, the country&#039;s human resources can be appropriately and desirably used. The main purpose of this research is to identify and assess the skills affected on university graduated women who are seeking a job and their relationship with their employability. The statistical population of the study consisted of women seeking a work in Hamedan province. The sampling method was a proportional random method that according to the statistical population of the women (N=10431) a number of 350 women was selected. After data collection, data analysis was performed using descriptive and analytical statistics and application of software&#039;s SPSS and PLS. According to the results of the research, the relationship between the jobs in the labor market and the women’s education and skills was poorly assessed in Hamedan province and the educational content of the universities had a weak overlapping with the needs of the labor market. The results of correlation coefficient showed that there is a positive and significant relationship between the variables, women‘s compatibility, communication skills, IT skills, and willingness to work with the employability of the female graduates. The other independent variables did not show a significant relationship with the employability of the graduates. The results also showed that women in Hamedan province to acquire the current jobs need some skills such as ICT skills, public and communication skills, individual skills such as critical thinking and problem solving, technical and specialized skills, and management and planning skills.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>389</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>411</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>موحدی</Family>
						<NameE>Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Movahedi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری تخصصی، دانشیار و عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه بو علی سینا</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری تخصصی، دانشیار و عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>movahedi686@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>لیلا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>زلیخائی سیار</Family>
						<NameE>leila</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>zolikhaei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری دانشگاه بوعلی سینا</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری دانشگاه بوعلی سینا</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>la.zolikhai@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>معصومه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>باقری</Family>
						<NameE>Masoomeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Baghery</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>baghery1390@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>استان همدان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اشتغال‏پذیری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بانوان دانش‏آموخته</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مهارت‌های اشتغال</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] آقاپور، شهلا؛ موحدمحمدی، سیدحمید؛ علم‏بیگی، امیر (1393). «نقش مهارت‌های کلیدی در شکل‏گیری قابلیت اشتغال دانشجویان»، فصل‌نامةپژوهش و برنامه‏ریزی در آموزش عالی، ش 71، ص41ـ56.##[2] انتظاری، یعقوب (1388). «ارائة الگویی برای هماهنگ‏سازی نظام آموزش عالی با تحولات مبتنی بر دانش در نظام اشتغال؛ مورد برنامة پنجم توسعة اقتصادی، اجتماعی و فرهنگی جمهوری اسلامی ایران»، فصل‌نامه پژوهش و برنامه‏ریزی در آموزش عالی، ش53، ص1ـ27.##[3] پای‏خسته، پریسا؛ علم‏بیگی، امیر؛ بطحائی، سمیه (1396). «بررسی شایستگی‏های مورد نیاز توسعة کارآفرینی پایدار در آموزش عالی کشاورزی»، فصل‌نامة پژوهش مدیریت آموزش کشاورزی، ش 40، ص32ـ43.##[4] حاجی‏حیدری، فرزانه و سلیمانی، سمیرا (1395). «آموزش شایستگی و مهارت‌های کلیدی حین تحصیل از دیدگاه دانشجویان رشته‏های امداد و نجات و سوانح»، فصل‌نامة امداد و نجات، س 8، ش (1 و 2)، ص68ـ76.##[5] سعدوندی، مهسا؛ عباسی، عنایت؛ فرهادیان، همایون (1395). «صلاحیت‏های موردنیاز فراگیران در نظام آموزش عالی کشاورزی»، ششمین کنگرة ملی علوم ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی ایران، ملاحظات ترویج در پایداری کشاورزی، منابع طبیعی و محیط‏زیست در شرایط تغییرات اقلیمی، 5 و 6 آبان 1395، دانشگاه شیراز.##[6] صالحی‏عمران، ابراهیم؛ رحمانی قهدریجانی، الهه (1392). «مسئلة اشتغال دانش‌آموختگان آموزش عالی و ضرورت توجه به مهارت‌های اشتغال‌زای بازار کار در طرح آمایش آموزش عالی»، فصل‌نامة آموزش عالی ایران، س 5، ش 3، ص27ـ58.##[7] علوی‏راد، عباس (1391). «اشتغال زنان در ایران و آیندة اشتغال زنان دانش‏آموخته (1345ـ1385)». مجلةسیاسی و اقتصادی، ش 288، ص116ـ125.##[8] گرایی، احسان؛ حیدری، غلامرضا (1394). «نظریة شایستگی‏های کانونی: الگویی برای برنامه‏ریزی آموزش علم اطلاعات و دانش‏شناسی»، تحقیقات اطلاع‏رسانی و کتابخانه‏های عمومی، س 21، ش 3، ص467ـ490.##[9] محمودیان، ح.؛ رشوند، مرجان (1391). «اشتغال زنان فارغ‏التحصیل آموزش عالی و عوامل جمعیتی و اجتماعی مؤثر بر آن (مطالعة موردی شهر تهران»، مجلةزن در توسعه و سیاست، س 10، ش 1، ص83ـ104.##[10] میرجلیلی، فاطمه (1384). «اشتغال دانش‌آموختگان آموزش عالی و تأکید بر کارآفرینی به‌عنوان یک راهکار افزایش آن»، مجلس و پژوهش، س 12، ش (49ـ50)، ص77ـ91.##[11] نادری‏مهدیی، کریم؛ زلیخایی سیار، لیلا؛ پویا، مهرداد (1394). «واکاوی اشتغال‏پذیری دانشجویان زن: راهکاری جدید برای تقویت حضور زنان در بازار کار». فصل‌نامة پژوهش و برنامه‏ریزی در آموزش عالی، س 21، ش 4، ص21ـ50.##[12] نویدی، احد؛ محمودی کهریز، بهرام (1390). «ضرورت و راه‌های توسعة مهارت‌های عمومی برای اشتغال‏پذیری در جامعة دانش‌محور»، فصل‌نامةتعلیم و تربیت، س 112، ص15ـ35.##[13] یغموری، سعید (1388). «بررسی مهارت‌های اشتغال‏زای بازار کار در آموزش عالی»، پایان‏نامة کارشناسی ارشد رشتة علوم تربیتی، گرایش برنامه‏ریزی آموزشی، دانشگاه مازندران.##[14] Agbor Eta, E. (2017). “Enhancing Graduate Employability in Cameroonian Universities through Professionalization in the Context of the ‘Licence–Master–Doctorat’ Reform”, Higher Education Policy, 31 (3), PP 309-332.##[15] Andrew M. C. Mohammad, A. D. Stephanie, R. (2013). “Information Management graduates&#039; accounts of their employability: A case study from the University of Sheffield”, Education for Information, 30 (1, 2), PP 41-61.##[16] Argos, J., and Ezquerra, P. (2014). “Universities and skills for employability”, Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, 139, PP 290 – 296.##[17] Asonitou, S. (2015). “Employability Skills in Higher Education and the Case of Greece”, Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences,175, PP 283-290.##[18] Ayoubi, R. M., Alzarif, K., Khalifa, B. (2017). “The employability skills of business graduates in Syria: Do policymakers and employers speak the same language?”, Education + Training, 59(1), PP 61-75.##[19] Batistic, S. Tymon, A. (2017). “Networking behaviour, graduate employability: a social capital perspective”, Education + Training, 59(4), PP 374-388.##[20] Chhinzer, N. and Russo, A. M. (2018). “An exploration of employer perceptions of graduate student employability”, Education + Training, 60 (1), PP 104-120.##[21] Eivis, Q., Neal, M., Carol, S. (2014). “An empirical study of self-perceived employability: Improving the prospects for student employment success in an uncertain environment”, Active Learning in Higher Education, 15(3), PP 199-213.##[22] El-Temtamy,O., Kathleen O&#039;Neill, K., Midraj, S. (2016). “Undergraduate employability training and employment: a UAE study”, Higher Education, Skills and Work-Based Learning, 6 (1), PP 100-115.##[23] Falk, R.F. &amp; Miller, N.B. (1992). A Primer Soft Modeling. Akron, Ohio: University of Akron Press.##[24] Garrouste, C. L. &amp; Rodrigues, M. (2014). “Employability of young graduates in Europe”, International Journal of Manpower, 35 (4), PP 425-447.##[25] Hollister, J. M., Spears, L. I., Mardis, M. A., Lee, J., McClure, C. R., Liebman, E. (2017). “Employers’ perspectives on new information technology technicians’ employability in North Florida”, Education + Training, 59 (9), PP 929-945.##[26] Ishengoma, E., Vaaland, T. I. (2016). “Can university-industry linkages stimulate student employability?”, Education + Training, 58 (1), PP 18-44.##[27] Jackling, B. and Natoli, R. (2015). “Employability skills of international accounting graduates: Internship providers’ perspectives”, Education + Training, 57 (7), PP 757-773.##[28] McKeown, T.,&amp; Lindorff, M. (2011). “The graduate job search process – A lesson in persistence rather than good career management?”, Education and Training, 63, PP 301–320.##[29] Messer, D. (2018). “Work placements at 14-15 years and employability skills”, Education +Training, 60 (1), PP 16-26.##[30] Molla, T. and Cuthbert, D. (2015). “The Issue of Research Graduate Employability in Australia: An Analysis of the Policy Framing (1999–2013)”, Aust. Educ. Res. 42, PP 237–256.##[31] Pita, C. Eleftheriou, M. Ferna´ndez-Borra´s, J. Gonc¸alves, S. Mente, E. Santos, M. B. Seixas, S. and Graham J. Pierce, G. J. (2015). “Generic skills needs for graduate employment in the aquaculture, fisheries and related sectors in Europe”, Aquacult Int, 23, PP 767–786.##[32] Poon, J. (2016). “An investigation of characteristics affecting employment outcomes and patterns of real estate graduates”, Property Management, 34 (3), PP 180-198.##[33] Sermsuk, S. Triwichitkhun, D. Wongwanich, S. (2014). “Employment Conditions and Essential Employability Skills Required by Employers for Secondary School Graduate”, Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, 116, PP 1848-1854.##[34] Singh, R., Chawla, G., Agarwal, S., and Desai, A. (2017). “Employability and innovation: development of a scale”, International Journal of Innovation Science, 9 (1), PP 20-37.##[35] Thang, P. V. M. &amp; Wongsurawat, W. (2016). “Enhancing the employability of IT graduates in Vietnam”, Higher Education, Skills and Work-Based Learning, 6 (2), PP 146-161.##[36] Turner, N. K. (2014). “Development of self-belief for employability in higher education: Ability, efficacy and control in context”, Teaching in Higher Education, 19 (6), PP 592-602.##[37] Nilsson, S. (2010). “Enhancing individual employability: the perspective of engineering graduates”, Education + Training, 52 (6/7), PP 540-551.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>واکاوی پیامدهای مهاجرت مردان بر وضعیت زنان جامانده در نواحی روستایی (مطالعة موردی: شهرستان مشهد)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Examining the Implications of Men&#039;s Immigration on left-behind women in Rural area(Case study: Mashhad county)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>مهاجرت ماهیتاً فرایندی جنسیتی است، زیرا می‏تواند در ساختار جمعیتی مبدأ تغییر ایجاد کند و به تبع آن در بروز تحولات اقتصادی اجتماعی، به‌خصوص در ارتباط با جنسیت، تأثیر بسزایی داشته ‏باشد. هدف پژوهش تحلیل پیامدهای مهاجرت مردان سرپرست خانوار بر وضعیت اقتصادی و اجتماعی زنان جامانده در روستاست. روش تحقیق توصیفی‌ـ تحلیلی و حجم نمونه 289 زن سرپرست خانوار مهاجر در شهرستان مشهد بوده ‏است. تأثیرات مهاجرت در دو بعد اقتصادی و اجتماعی با 15 اثر مثبت و منفی در طیف لیکرت کمی شد. نتایج نشان داد از دیدگاه زنان، میانگین تأثیرات مثبت مهاجرت مردان با 88/2 بیشتر از تأثیرات منفی با 09/2 بوده‏ است. در بعد اجتماعی، میانگین تأثیرات مثبت مهاجرت با 26/3 بیشتر از تأثیرات منفی با 99/1 و در بعد اقتصادی میانگین تأثیرات مثبت با 54/2 بیشتر از تأثیرات منفی با 23/2 بوده‏ است. این امر با نوع غالب مهاجرت مردان در شهرستان مشهد، که عمدتاً روزانه است، قابل ‏توجیه است، زیرا میانگین تأثیرات منفی مهاجرت در خانوارهایی که مردان مهاجرت روزانه داشته‏اند 06/2 در مهاجرت کوتاه‏مدت 18/2 و در مهاجرت طولانی‏مدت به 53/2 افزایش می‏یابد. لذا مهاجرت انفرادی مردان از نواحی روستایی، در‌صورتی‏که روزانه باشد، تأثیرات مثبتی بر وضعیت اقتصادی و اجتماعی زنان جامانده در نواحی روستایی دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Migration is one of the most prevalent and effective social phenomenon that may cause some changes in origin’s population structure, consequently, lead to emerge of socioeconomic changes especially in relation to gender. So, the migration is a gender process naturally. The present research seeks to analyze the consequences of husband’s migration on socioeconomic status of left-behind women in rural areas. The research method is descriptive-analytical and sample size is 289 women in 22 sample villages of Mashhad County who their husband migrated to work. In this study, the examined women were identified by snowball method and participated in completing the questionnaire. The effects of men’s immigration on rural women were evaluated in term of economic and social dimensions with 15 positive and 15 negative effects separately. From the women perspective, the results of paired Sample t-test showed that men’s migration mainly had positive rather than negative effects; as in the social term, the average positive effects of migration of men is 3.26 that significantly more than the average 1.99 of negative effects; and in the economic dimension, the average 2.54 of positive effects were more than the average 2.23 of negative effects. In total, the average 2.88 of positive effects of men migration were more than the average 2.09 of negative effects. This is justified by the predominant type of men’s migration, which is mostly daily, across the mashhad county. The results of variance analysis also showed that the average of negative effects of households with daily migration of husband were 2.06 that this figure was increased to 2.18 in short-term migration and to 2.53 in long-term one. Therefore, if the migration of men from rural areas is daily, it will have a positive effect on the economic and social status of left-behind women in rural areas.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>413</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>438</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>آتنا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>وطن‌خواه نوغانی</Family>
						<NameE>Atena</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Vatankhah</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی روستایی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی روستایی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>at.vatankhahnoghani@stu-mail.um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مریم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قاسمی</Family>
						<NameE>Maryam</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ghasemi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار جغرافیا و برنامه ریزی روستایی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار جغرافیا و برنامه ریزی روستایی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>magh30@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تأثیرات مهاجرت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زنان روستایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شهرستان مشهد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مردان سرپرست خانوار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نوع مهاجرت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] ازکیا، مصطفی؛ ایمانی، علی (1378). توسعة پایدار روستایی، تهران: اطلاعات.##[2] اصغرپور ماسوله، احمدرضا (1392). آمار مقدماتی برای علوم اجتماعی، تهران: سنبله.##[3] جوان، جعفر (1391). جغرافیای جمعیت ایران، مشهد: جهاد دانشگاهی.##[4] حبیب‏پور گتابی، کرم؛ صفری شمالی، رضا (1391). راهنمای جامع کاربرد SPSS در تحقیقات پیمایشی (تحلیل داده‏های کمی)، چ 5، تهران: متفکران.##[5] خانی، فضیله (1383). «پی‏آمد مهاجرت انفرادی مردان بر کارکرد زنان در مناطق روستایی، مطالعة موردی روستاهای بندپی شرقی، مازندران»، مجلة مطالعات زنان، س 2، ش 4، ص 149ـ176‌.##[6] خانی، فضیله؛ چوبچیان، شهلا (1391). «مناسبات جنسیتی در فضاهای روستایی و تأثیر آن بر مشارکت زنان، مطالعة مقایسه‌ای دهستان مریدان شهرستان لنگرود و دهستان هولی شهرستان پاوه»، فصل‌نامة پژوهش‏های روستایی، س 3، ش 3، ص 138ـ162‌.##[7] خوش‏فر، غلامرضا؛ دانش، یونس؛ جوادی‌نیا، علی (1392). «مطالعة جریان‏های مهاجرتی و عوامل مؤثر بر آن در استان مازندران»، فصل‌نامة مطالعات توسعة اجتماعی‌ـ فرهنگی، س 1، ش 4، ص 147ـ176.##[8] زیاری، کرامت‌الله؛ اسدی، روح‌الله؛ صادقی، مجتبی (1392). «تحلیل، مدل‌سازی و پیش‌بینی نقش اشتغال در مهاجرت‌های منطقه، نمونه: استان سیستان و بلوچستان»، فصل‌نامة علمی‌ـ پژوهشی فضای جغرافیایی، س 13، ش 44، ص1ـ18.##[9] صادقی، رسول؛ ولدوند، لیلا (1394). «جنسیت و مهاجرت، تحلیل جامعه‌شناختی تفاوت‏های جنسیتی در مهاجرت‌های داخلی در ایران»، دوفصل‌نامة پژوهش‏های جامعه‌شناسی معاصر، س 4، ش 7، ص 55ـ78.##[10] عزیزیان، محمدصادق و کاظمی، فرهاد (1393). «بررسی و پیامدهای پدیده مهاجرت روستایی‌ـ شهری و عوامل موثر بر آن»، اولین کنفرانس ملی معماری و منظر شهری پایدار، ص 7‌ـ 1.##[11] عفتی، محمد (1382). «زنان روستایی و مهاجرت‌های فصلی مردان: با تاکید بر پیامدهای اجتماعی، فرهنگی»، نامه پژوهش فرهنگی، س 7، ش 6، ص 292‌ـ 245.##[12] علیرضانژاد، سهیلا و بنی هاشم، فروغ‌السادات (1391). «جنسیت و توسعه: نگاهی به تحولات جمعیت شناختی مناطق روستایی کشور»، مجله مطالعات اجتماعی ایران، س 4. ش 2، ص 93‌ـ 81.##[13] قاسمی سیانی، محمد (1386). «پیامدهای مهاجرت روستا‌ـ شهری نسل جوان روستایی»، پژوهش جوانان، فرهنگ و جامعه، ش 2، ص 145ـ165.##[14] مرکز آمار ایران، سالنامة آماری استان خراسان رضوی، 1390.##[15] مرکز آمار ایران، سرشماری عمومی نفوس و مسکن، شناسنامة آبادی‌ها، 1395.##[16] مقیمی‌زاده، ارسلان؛ اکبری، احمد؛ خدمتگذار، فرامرز (1391). «تأثیرات مهاجرت و شهرنشینی بر توسعة اقتصادی»، اولین همایش ملی توسعة پایدار کشاورزی و محیط زیست سالم، اسفند 1391، ص1ـ9.##[17] نقدی، اسدالله؛ بلالی، اسماعیل (1389). «مسئلة اجتماعی خاموش و نامرئی: کاهش شانس ازدواج برای دختران روستایی: با تأکید بر یافته‌هایی از نقاط روستایی همدان»، فصل‌نامة توسعة روستایی، س 2، ش 2، ص 77ـ94‌.##[18] وطن‌خواه نوغانی، آتنا؛ قاسمی، مریم؛ جوان، جعفر (1397). «شناسایی مهم‌ترین تأثیرات مهاجرت انفرادی مردان سرپرست خانوار بر زنان روستایی (مورد مطالعه: شهرستان مشهد)»، پژوهش‏های روستایی، س 9، ش 1، ص 58ـ71‌.##[19] همتی، رضا؛ گنجی، مریم (1395). «مهاجرت انفرادی مردان از روستاها و چالش‏های پیش روی زنان جامانده»، مجلة توسعة محلی (روستایی‌ـ شهری)، س 8، ش 1، ص 139ـ166.##[20] Binzel C, Assaad R. (2011). “Egyptian men working abroad: Labour supply responses by the women left behind”, Labour Economics. Vol,18. PP S98‌ـ 114.##[21] Campbell, H., &amp; Mayerfeld Bell, M. (2000). “The Question of Rural Masculinities”, Rural Sociology, Vol, 65. No, 4. PP 532‌ـ 546.##[22] Choi, S. Y. (2019). “Migration, masculinity, and family”, Journal of Ethnic and Migration Studies, Vol, 45. No, 1. PP 78‌ـ 94.##[23] Dahlberg, Å. &amp; Ahlin, S. (2010). Migration, remittances and the women left behind: A study on how women in Mali are affected by migration and remittances from their migrated husbands, G3‌ـ paper in Political Science, Linnaeus University, Institution of Social Sciences, PP 1‌ـ 42.##[24] De Haas H, Van Rooij A. (2010).“Migration as emancipation? The impact of internal and international migration on the position of women left behind in rural Morocco”, Oxford development studies. Vol, 38, NO,1. PP 43‌ـ 62.##[25] Desai, S &amp; Banerji, M. (2008). “Negotiated identities: Male migration and left‌ـ behind wives in India”, Journal of Population Research. Vol. 25, No. 3, PP 337‌ـ 55.##[26] Grimaldi AD. (2016). When the young men leave: Social implications of migration and remittances among the Tharu of Chitwan, Nepal.##[27] Haas, H &amp; Van Rooij, A. (2010). “Migration as Emancipation? The Impact of Internal and International Migration on the Position of Women Left Behind in Rural Morocco”, Oxford Development Studies, Vol. 38, No. 1, PP 43‌ـ 62.##[28] Holland, Steven M. (2006, January). Cluster Analysis. Department of Geology, University of Georgia, Athens, GA 30602‌ـ 2501.##[29] International Organization for Migration. (2008). World Migration 2008: Managing abor Mobility in the Evolving Global Economy. IOM World Migration Report Series. Vol 4. Geneva: IOM.##[30] Ismailbekova, A. (2013). “Migration and patrilineal descent: the effects of spatial male mobility on social female mobility in rural Kyrgyzstan”,Crossroads Asia Working Paper, Series, No, 12.##[31] Kakati BK. (2014). “Out‌ـ Migration and Its Bearing on Left‌ـ Behind Woman: Case in a Jharkhand village”, Vol. XI No.2, PP 83‌ـ 89.##[32] Kan, S., &amp; Aytimur, R. E. (2018). Labor force participation of women left behind in Tajikistan. Oxford Development Studies, 1‌ـ 25.##[33] Mahendra P, Agasty &amp; Dr.Rabi N, Patra (2014). “Migration of Labour and Left‌ـ behind Women: A Case Study of Rural Odisha. American International Journal of Research in Humanities”, Arts and Social Sciences, Vol, 7. No, 1. PP 28‌ـ 33.##[34] McEvoy, J. P. (2008). Male out‌ـmigration and the women left behind: A case study of a small farming community in southeastern Mexico, Master of Science thesis, Sociology, Utah State University.##[35] Menjívar, C., &amp; Agadjanian, V. (2007). “Men&#039;s migration and women&#039;s lives: Views from rural Armenia and Guatemala”, Social Science Quarterly, Vol, 88. No, 5. P 1243‌ـ 1262.##[36] Newland, K. (2009). Circular Migration and Human Development. Human Development Research Paper (HDRP) Series, Vol. 42.##[37] Rashid, S. R. (2013). “Bangladeshi Women’s Experiences of Their Men’s Migration”, Asian Survey, Vol, 53. No, 5. PP 883‌ـ 908.##[38] Saha, S., Goswami, R., &amp; Paul, S. K. (2018). “Recursive Male Out‌ـ migration and the Consequences at Source: A Systematic Review with Special Reference to the Left‌ـ behind Women”, Space and Culture, India, 5(3), 30‌ـ 53.##[39] Sarker, M., &amp; Islam, S. (2014). “Husbands’ International Labour Migration and the Change of Wives’ Position among the Left‌ـ Behind in Rural Bangladesh”, Research on Humanities and Social Sciences, Vol, 4. No 16. PP 2224‌ـ 5766.##[40] Somerville, W., &amp; Sumption, M. (2008). Immigration and the labour market. London: Migration Policy Institute/EHRC.##[41] Srivastava R, S K Sasikumari (2003). An Overview of migration in India, its impacts and key issues, Refugee and Migratory Movements Research Unit, University of Dhaka, Dhaka.##[42] Thapa, N., Paudel, M., Guragain, A. M., Thapa, P., Puri, R., Thapa, P., ... &amp; Stray‌ـ Pedersen, B. (2019). Status of migration and socio‌ـreproductive impacts on migrants and their families left behind in Nepal. Migration and Development, 1‌ـ 24.##[43] Ullah AA. (2017). “Male Migration and ‘Left–behind’Women: Bane or Boon?”, Environment and Urbanization ASIA. Vol, 8, NO,1. PP 59‌ـ73.##[44] Wu, H., &amp; Ye, J. (2016). “Hollow Lives: Women Left Behind in Rural C hina”, Journal of agrarian change, 16(1), 50‌ـ 69.##[45] Ye, J., Wu, H., Rao, J., Ding, B., &amp; Zhang, K. (2016). “Left‌ـ behind women: gender exclusion and inequality in rural‌ـ urban migration in China”, The Journal of Peasant Studies, 43(4), 910‌ـ941.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر موانع گرایش زنان روستایی به کارآفرینی گردشگری (مطالعة موردی: بخش اورامان شهرستان سروآباد)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Analysis of Effective Barriers on Women&#039;s Entrepreneurship Development in Rural Tourism (Case Study: Oraman Region, Sarvabad County)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>پژوهش حاضر در پی شناسایی موانع و مشکلات پیش‏روی ایجاد محیط مناسب و گرایش زنان روستایی شاغل در عرصة گردشگری منطقة اورامان شهرستان سروآباد به کارآفرینی است. جمع‏آوری داده‏ها در بخش نظری با استفاده از منابع اسنادی و در بخش عملی با روش پیمایشی و مبتنی بر توزیع پرسش‌نامه در میان 97 زن روستایی شاغل در عرصة گردشگری روستاهای بخش اورامان و 50 نفر از آگاهان و مختصصان توسعة روستایی است که به روش هدفمند انتخاب شدند. تجزیه و تحلیل داده‏های گردآوری‌شده با آزمون‏های آمار استنباطی (تحلیل عاملی و تحلیل مسیر) نشان دادند که در‌مجموع پنج عامل ضعف در برنامه‏ریزی، عملکرد اجرایی نهادهای دولتی و محدودیت‏های منابع مالی؛ ضعف در بازاریابی و نارسایی‏های خدماتی‌ـ زیرساختی؛ موانع اجتماعی و فرهنگی محیط روستایی؛ ضعف‎های فردی و محدودیت‏های آموزشی و موانع فنی و عملی از موانع مهم پیش‌روی کارآفرینی زنان روستایی شاغل در عرصة گردشگری روستاهای منطقه هستند که در این میان، عامل ضعف در برنامه‎ریزی، عملکرد اجرایی نهادهای دولتی و محدودیت‏های مالی بیشترین تأثیر را در تمایل زنان روستایی شاغل در عرصة گردشگری روستایی منطقة مطالعه‌شده به کارآفرینی داشت.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The present paper seeks to identify the obstacles and problems that women&#039;s rural entrepreneurs faced in the Oraman region of Sarvaba county, which is considered as one of the important hubs of rural tourism in the country. The aim is to remove the barriers to create an appropriate entrepreneurship environment for rural women to be employed in the field of tourism. Data gathering in the theoretical part was done by using documentary resources and in the practical section with survey method and based on distribution of questionnaire among 97 employed rural women in the tourism sector of the villages of Oraman section and 50 knowledgeable and specialized developers in rural issues who were chosen by using Snowy bullet method. Data analysis was performed by inferential statistics (factor analysis and path analysis) and indicates that in total, there are five factors including; weakness in planning, executive performance of public institutions and financial resources constraints, weaknesses in marketing and infrastructure service failures, social and cultural barriers of rural environment, individual weaknesses and educational constraints, and technical and practical barriers are the main obstacles that employed rural women entrepreneurs are facing in the rural tourism sector. Among them, the weakness of planning, the executive function of state institutions and financial constraints have the greatest impact on the inclination of employed rural women in the area of tourism to entrepreneurial.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>439</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>468</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سعدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمدی</Family>
						<NameE>s</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>m</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی روستایی دانشگاه پیام نور</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی روستایی دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>saadi@pnu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ژاله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمد شریفی</Family>
						<NameE>f</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>c</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناسی ارشد جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی روستایی، دانشگاه پیام نور</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناسی ارشد جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی روستایی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ornmanoochehri@chmail.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>روستاهای بخش اورامان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زنان روستایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کارآفرینی گردشگری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] آراستی، زهرا (1385). «ساختارهای فرهنگی‌ـ اجتماعی مؤثر در ایجاد کسب‌وکارهای کارآفرینانه»، پژوهش زنان، س 4، ش 1 و 2، ص‌93ـ119.##[2] امینی، عباس؛ طاهری، حسین (1395). «تحلیلی بر نقش‏پذیری زنان روستایی در فعالیت‏های اقتصادی و عوامل مؤثر بر آن: مورد مطالعه مناطق روستایی بخش سیمکان در شهرستان جهرم»، فصل‌نامة علوم ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی ایران، س 12، ش2، ص 37ـ48.##[3] بشیراحسن، مسلم؛ قربانی‌نژاد، ریباز ( 1396). «نقش زنان کارآفرین در توسعة اقتصادی روستایی (مطالعة موردی: دهستان خرم‏رود در شهرستان تویسرکان)»، فصل‌نامة جغرافیایی سرزمین، س 14، ش 53، ص 93ـ105.##[4] پاپلی یزدی، محمدحسین؛ ابراهیمی، محمد‌امیر (1387). نظریه‏های توسعة روستایی با تأکید بر ایران، تهران: سمت.##[5] جمعه‌پور، محمود (1387). مقدمه‏ای بر برنامه‏ریزی توسعة روستایی: دیدگاه‏ها و روش‏ها، تهران: سمت.##[6] حسینی‌نیا، غلامحسین؛ یعقوبی فرانی، احمد؛ سیدین، سید رضا (1393). «سنجش عوامل مؤثر بر عمکلرد کسب‌وکارهای زنان کارآفرین در روستاهای شهرستان میانه»، فصل‌نامة زن در توسعه و سیاست، س 12، ش 4، ص 545‌ـ558.##[7] رضوانی، محمدرضا (1388). مقدمه‏ای بر برنامه‏ریزی توسعة روستایی در ایران، تهران: قومس.##[8] سواری، مسلم؛ شعبانعلی فمی، حسین؛ شریف‌زاده، محمد‌شریف (1396). «موانع توسعة اشتغال زنان روستایی در صنایع دستی شهرستان دیواندره»، فصل‌نامة اقتصاد فضا و توسعة روستایی، س 6، ش 3، ص17ـ36.##[9] شاطریان، محسن؛ نصرآبادی، زهرا؛ منصوریان، فاطمه (1396). «تحلیل موانع کارآفرینی زنان روستایی در شهرستان کاشان»، فصل‌نامة اقتصاد فضا و توسعة روستایی، س 6، ش 3، ص 181ـ196.##[10] شریفی، امید؛ عادلی، محسن (1389). «تحلیل عاملی موانع موجود در زمینة کارآفرینی زنان کشاورز از دیدگاه زنان نمونة کشاورز منطقة جیرفت و کهنوج»، فصل‌نامة تحقیقات زنان، س 5، ش 1، ص112ـ125.##[11] غنیان، منصور؛ فتوتی، هستی (1392). «گردشگری راهکاری جهت توسعة کارآفرینی زنان روستایی»، ماهنامةاجتماعی، اقتصادی، فرهنگی کار و جامعه، س 1، ش 159، ص 29ـ39.##[12] کریمی، سعید (1394). «کارآفرینی گردشگری کشاورزی، راهبردی نوین برای توسعة روستایی»، نشریة کارآفرینی در کشاورزی، س 1، ش 4، ص96ـ104.##[13] گلرد، پروانه (1384). «عوامل مؤثر در توسعة کارآفرینی زنان»، فصل‌نامة پژوهش زنان، س 3، ش 1، ص101ـ123.##[14] مکرری، حیدر؛ سارانی، افسانه (1394). «تحلیل عوامل مؤثر بر توسعة کارآفرینی زنان در مناطق روستایی»، همایش ملی عمران و معماری با رویکرد توسعة پایدار، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد فومن.##[15] ممیز، آیت‌الله؛ قاسمی، عاطفه (1392). «بررسی عوامل مؤثر در توسعة کارآفرینی زنان»، فصل‌نامه رشد فناری، س 9، ش 35، ص 15ـ22.##[16] منوچهری، سوارن (1393). «تحلیل عوامل مؤثر بر گسترش فعالیت‏های گردشگری جهت تحقق توسعة پایدار روستایی، مطالعة موردی: بخش خاوومیرآباد شهرستان مریوان»، پایان‏نامة کارشناسی ارشد جغرافیا و برنامه‏ریزی روستایی به راهنمایی دکتر حسین فراهانی، دانشگاه زنجان.##[17] موحدی، رضا؛ گلی، فائزه؛ محمدی، مریم (1395). «توسعة آموزش عالی کشاورزی با تأکید بر کارآفرینی پایدار»، نشریة کارآفرینی در کشاورزی، س 3، ش 1، ص55ـ77‌.##[18] یعقوبی فرانی، احمد؛ سلیمانی، عطیه؛ موحدی، رضا (1393). «تحلیل عوامل مؤثر بر کارآفرینی زنان روستایی»، فصل‌نامة روان‌شناختی زنان، س 12، ش 4، ص 7ـ42.##[19] Ball, S. (2005). The Importance of Entrepreneurship to Hospitality, Leisure, Sport and Tourism, Hospitality, Leisure, Sport and Tourism Network, 2‌ـ 15.at: http://citeseerx.ist. psu.edu viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.542.3486&amp;rep=rep1&amp;type=pdf.##[20]Filion, L.J. (2011). Defining the entrepreneur Complexity and Multi‌ـ Dimensional Systems Some Reflections, World Encyclopedia of Entrepreneurship. Cheltenham, England: Edward Elgar.##[21] Fallatah, H. (2012). Women Entrepreneurs in Saudi Arabia: Investigating strategies used by successful Saudi women entrepreneurs, A thesis submitted in partial fulfilment of the requirements for the Degree of Master of Business Management at Lincoln University.##[22] Gnyawali, D.R and Fogel, D.S. (1994). “Environments for entrepreneurship development: Key dimensions, and research implications”, Journal Entrepreneurship Theory and Practice ( SAGE Journals ), 18 (4): PP 43–62.##[23] Heaton,J. (2005). “Developing entrepreneurs: an examination of systematic approaches to Entrepreneurial development for rural Areas”, Rural Research Report, 16 (1): PP 1‌ـ 11.##[24] International Labour Organization. (2016). Sustainable Enterprise Programme Women’s Entrepreneurship Development, at: http://www.ilo.org /wcmsp5/groups/public /‌ـ ‌ـ ‌ـ ed_emp/‌ـ ‌ـ ‌ـ emp_ent/‌ـ ‌ـ ‌ـ ifp_seed /documents /publication/wcms_175471.pdf.##[25] Jurdana, S and Dadić, L. (2015). “Entrepreneurship in tourism as a factor of rural development”,  journal of wei business and economics.4 (2): PP 1-9‌.##[26] kaburi, S. (2012). “Entrepreneurship challenges in developing economies: a case of kenyan economy”, International journal of arts and commerce, 4 (1): PP 27-264.##[27] Lordkipanidze, M., Backman, M &amp; Brezet, H. (2005). “The entrepreneurship factor in sustainable tourism development”, Journal of Cleaner Production, 13 (3): PP 787‌ـ 798.##[28] Lordkipanidze, M. (2002). Enhancing Entrepreneurship in Rural Tourism for Sustainable Regional Development, The case of Söderslätt region, Sweden, The International Institute for Industrial Environmental Economics, Lund University, Sweden.##[29] Mkubukeli, Z, Tengeh, R. (2016). “Prospects and Challenges for Small‌ـ Scale Mining Entrepreneurs in South Africa”, J Entrepren Organiz Manag , 5 (4): PP 2‌ـ 10.##[30] Mokaya, S. (2012). “The concept of entrepreneurship; in pursuit of a universally acceptable definition”, International Journal of Arts and Commerce, 6 (1): PP 125‌ـ 137.##[31] Mrema, A. (2015). “Tourism and women empowerment in Monduli District, Arusha‌ـ Tanzania”, African Journal of Hospitality, Tourism and Leisure, 4 (2): PP 1‌ـ13.##[32] Nedelcheva, S. (2012). Female Entrepreneurship in Denmark. MSc Thesis. Denmark: International Business, Aarhus University, Business and Social Sciences.##[33] Nemirschi, A. (2010). “Entrepreneurship and tourism development in rural areas: case of Romania”, Romanian Economic and Business Review , 5 (1): PP 138‌ـ149.##[34] Niethammer,N. (2013). Women, Entrepreneurship and the Opportunity to Promote Development and Business Carmen, The 2013 Brookings Blum Roundtable Policy Briefs Enterprising Solutions: The Role of the Private Sector in Eradicating Global Poverty. At: https://www.brookings.edu/wp‌ـ content/uploads/2016/06/2013‌ـ BBR‌ـ Women‌ـ Entrepreneurship.pdf.##[35] Omerzel, G. (2012). “The Impact of Entrepreneurial Characteristics and Organisational Culture on Innovativeness in Tourism Firms”, Managing Global Transitions,14 (1): PP 93–110.##[36] Petridou, E and Glaveli, N. (2008). “Rural women entrepreneurship within co‌ـ operatives: training support”, Gender in Management: An International Journal, 23 (4): PP 262‌ـ277.##[37] Roberts, L., Hall, D. (2001). Rural Tourism and Recreation: Principles to Practice, Oxfordshire, England: CABI (Centre for Agriculture and Bioscience Internationa).##[38] Roig, S.,Ribeiro, D and Cuervo, A. (2011). Introduction Entrepreneurship: Concepts, Theory and Perspective. Berlin, : Springer.##[39] Sharma, M., Chaudhary, V., Bala, R and Chauhan, R. (2013). “Rural Entrepreneurship in Developing Countries: Challenges, Problems and Performance Appraisal, Global”, Journal of Management and Business Studies, 9 (3): PP 1035‌ـ 1040.##[40] Sheikh, R. (2015). Tourism entrepreneurship challenges and possibilities in small tourism businesses, bachelor’s thesis centria university of applied sciences Degree programme in Tourism, centeria University of applied science Finland.##[41] Singh, R. (2012). “Women Entrepreneurship Issues, Challenges and Empowerment through Self Help Groups: An Overview of Himachal Pradesh”, International journal of democratic and development studies (ijdds), 1 (1): PP 45‌ـ58.##[42] Sharif, N.M and Tuan, A. (2014). Entrepreneurship as a catalyst for rural tourism development, SHS Web of Conferences. DOI: 10.1051/ shsconf/20141201087##[43] Vinesh,M. (2014). “Role of Women Entrepreneurs in India”, Global Journal of Finance and Management,6 (5): PP 473‌ـ480.##[44] Wube, M. (2010). Factors affecting the performance of women entrepreneurs in micro and small enterprises (the case of dessie town), A Thesis Presented in Partial Fulfillment of the Requirements for Degree of Master of Arts in Technical and Vocational Education Management, faculty of education and behavioral sciences department of educational planning and management, Bahir Dar university.##[45] Yadav, V and Unni ,J. (2016). “Women entrepreneurship: research review and future directions”, Journal of Global Entrepreneurship Research,12 (6): PP 1-12.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>رابطة گرایش‌های فمنیستی با خودشیءانگاری، درونی‏ سازی لاغری ایدئال و هویت جنسی (مطالعة موردی دانشجویان دختر دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی سبزوار)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The relationship between Feminism tendencies with Self _objectification ,Thin ideal internalization and Gender identity(Case study of female students of Islamic Azad University of Sabzevar)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی رابطة گرایش‌های فمنیستی با خودشیء‏انگاری، درونی‌سازی لاغری ایدئال و هویت جنسی دانشجویان دختر دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی سبزوار انجام شد. این پژوهش از نوع توصیفی‌ـ همبستگی بود. جامعة آماری پژوهش شامل 1856 نفر دانشجویان دختر دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی سبزوار در سال تحصیلی 1396ـ1397 بود که با استفاده از جدول مورگان 318 نفر به روش نمونه‏گیری تصادفی طبقه‏ای نسبتی به‏عنوان نمونه انتخاب شدند. برای گردآوری داده‏ها از پرسش‌نامه‏های گرایش‌های فمنیستی برگاد و هاید (1991)، خودشیءانگاری نل و فردریکسون (1997)، درونی‌سازی لاغری استیک و گراس (1998) و هویت نقش جنسیتی شرتزر، لوفر، سیلورا و مک براید (2008) استفاده شد. داده‏های گردآوری‏شده با استفاده از نرم‏افزار SPSS20 و روش‏های آمار توصیفی، همبستگی و رگرسیون تک‌متغیره تجزیه ‏و تحلیل شد. یافته‏های پژوهش نشان داد که بین گرایش‌های فمنیستی با خودشیءانگاری رابطة معناداری وجود ندارد؛ اما با درونی‌سازی لاغری ایدئال همبستگی منفی و معنادار و با هویت جنسی رابطۀ مثبت و معناداری وجود دارد. همچنین، بر‌اساس نتایج تحقیق مشخص شد که گرایش‌های فمنیستی توانست حدود 4/5 درصد واریانس درونی‌سازی لاغری ایدئال و 6/5 درصد واریانس هویت جنسی را تبیین کند. بنابراین، افزایش گرایش‌های فمنیستی می‏تواند سبب کاهش درونی‌سازی لاغری ایدئال و افزایش هویت جنسی دانشجویان دختر شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The current study aims to investigate the relationship between Feminism tendencies, Self- objectification, Thin ideal internalization and Gender identity in female students Islamic Azad University of Sabzebvar (2018). This study was correlation-descriptive. The population of this study included 1856 emale students Islamic Azad University of Sabzebvar that Using Morgan table 318 persons were selected through Relative stratified random sampling method. The data was collected using Questionnaires of Burgad &amp; Hides Feminism (1991), Neil and Fredrickson&#039;s self-objectification (1997), Stick and Grass thin-idealization (1998) and Schertzer, Laufer, Silvera, &amp; Brad McBride Gender identity (2008). The collected data were analyzed using Spss20 software and descriptive statistics, Pearson correlation and Univariate regression methods. The results showed that there was no significant relationship between feminist tendencies and Self- objectification; But there was a significant negative correlation with Thin ideal internalization and a significant positive relationship with Gender identity. In addition, it was found that Feminism tendencies accounted for about 5.4% of the variance in Thin ideal internalization and 5.6% of the variance in Gender identity. Therefore, increasing Feminism tendencies can reduce Thin ideal internalization and increase the Gender identity of female students.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>469</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>486</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ندا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نصر</Family>
						<NameE>Neda</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nasr</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی سابق کارشناسی ارشد روانشناسی تربیتی، گروه علوم تربیتی، واحد سبزوار، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی سبزوار، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی سابق کارشناسی ارشد روانشناسی تربیتی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>nasrneda95@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ناعمی</Family>
						<NameE>Ali mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Naemi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه علوم تربیتی، واحد سبزوار، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، سبزوار، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه علوم تربیتی، واحد سبزوار، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>amnaemi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خود‌شیءانگاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>درونی‌سازی لاغری ایدئال</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فمنیسم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هویت جنسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] بهشتی، سعید؛ احمدی‏نیا و مریم (1385). «تبیین و بررسی نظریة تربیتی فمنیسم و نقد آن از منظر تعلیم و تربیت اسلامی»، دو فصل‌نامة علمی پژوهشی تربیت اسلامی، س 2، ش 3، ص41ـ88.##[2] پورعزت، علی‌اصغر؛ خالقی، امیر‌حسین (1394). «فمنیسم در مطالعات سازمان»، مجلة مدیریت دولتی، س 7، ش3، ص437ـ458.##[3] پیشگاهی‌فرد، زهرا؛ قدسی، امیر (1389). «نظریه‌های فرهنگی فمنیسم و دلالت‏های آن بر جامعة ایران»، نشریةزن در فرهنگ و هنر، س اول، ش 3، ص 109ـ132.##[4] دادستان، پریرخ (1382). روان‌شناسی مرضی تحولی: از کودکی تا بزرگسالی، ج اول، تهران: سمت.##[5] ذکایی، محمد‌سعید؛ قاراخانی، معصومه (1386). «دختران جوان و تجربة زنانگی (مطالعة موردی در میان دختران دبیرستانی شهر تهران»، فصل‌نامة زن در توسعه و سیاست، س 5، ش اول، ص 59ـ82.##[6] راتوس، اسپنسر (1378). روان‌شناسی عمومی، ترجمة حمزه گنجی، تهران: ویرایش.##[7] رضایی، مریم؛ افلاک‌سیر، عبدالعزیز و همکاران (1394). «طراحی و آزمون مدلی از متغیرهای درونی‌سازی لاغری، خودشیءانگاری و نارضایتی بدنی به‏عنوان پیش‌آیندهای خطر اختلالات خوردن در دختران دانشجو»، مجلة علوم تغذیه و صنایع غذایی ایران، س 10، ش 2، ص 11ـ18.##[8] رودگر، نرجس؛ محبی، فاطمه (1388). تاریخچه، نظریات، گرایش‏ها و نقد فمنیسم، تهران: دفتر مطالعات و تحقیقات زنان.##[9] ریاحی، محمد‌اسماعیل (1390). «بررسی تفاوت‌های جنسیتی در میزان رضایت‌مندی از تصویر بدن»، فصل‌نامة زن در توسعه و سیاست، س 9، ش 3، ص 5ـ33.##[10] عطارزاده، مجتبی؛ مصفا، نسرین (1384). «جنبش زنان ایران؛ از ایستایی تا پویایی»، فصل‌نامه مطالعات زنان، س3، ش 7، ص 105ـ128.##[11] علمی، محمود؛ علیزاده، محمود (1388). «عوامل اجتماعی مؤثر بر هویت جنسی دختران دانشجوی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تبریز»، فصل‌نامة زن و مطالعات خانواده، س اول، ش 3، ص 75ـ90.##[12] علیوردی‌نیا، اکبر؛ رضی، داوود؛ آیینی، صدیقه (1392). «تبیین جامعه‌شناختی خشونت علیه زنان: آزمون تجربی نظریه‏های منابع در دسترس زنان و فمنیسم رادیکال»، فصل‌نامةعلمی‌ـپژوهشی رفاه اجتماعی، س 13، ش 49، ص 85ـ115.##[13] فریدمن، جین (1381). فمنیسم. ترجمة فیروزه مهاجر، تهران: آشیان.##[14] ناعمی، علی‌محمد (1395). «رابطة خودشیءانگاری با تاب‏آوری و خوددلسوزی دانشجویان دختر (مطالعة موردی: دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی سبزوار)». فصل‌نامة زن در توسعه و سیاست، س 14، ش1، ص 125ـ139.##[15] وینست، آندره (1378). ایدئولوژی‏های مدرن سیاسی قرن بیستم، ترجمة مرتضی ثابت‌فر، تهران: ققنوس.##[16] American Psychological Association, Task Force on the Sexualization of Girls. (2010). Report of the APA Task Force on the Sexualization of Girls. Retrieved from http://www.apa.org/pi/women/programs/girls/report-full.pdf.##[17] Bargad, A., &amp; Hyde, J. S. (1991).“Women&#039;s studies: A study of feminist identity development in women”, Psychology of Women Quarterly, Vol. 15, No. 2, PP181–201.##[18] Bem, S. L. (1993). The lenses of gender (Vol. 40). New Haven, CT: Yale University Press.##[19] Brennan, J. (2005). A selective prevention study: Decreasing body dissatisfaction and eating disorder symptomatology in sorority women using psych education, social norms, and social marketing strategies (Doctoral dissertation, The Ohio State University).##[20] Brinkman, B. G., Khan, A., Edner, B., &amp; Rosén, L. A. (2014). “Self-objectification, feminist activism and conformity to feminine norms among female vegetarians, semi-vegetarians, and non-vegetarians”, Eating behaviors, Vol. 15, No. 1, PP 171-174.##[21] Calogero, R. M., Tylka, T. L., Donnelly, L. C., McGetrick, A., &amp; Leger, A. M. (2017). “Trappings of femininity: A test of the “beauty as currency” hypothesis in shaping college women’s gender activism”, Body Image, Vol. 21, PP 66–70.##[22] Cash, T. F. (2011). Cognitive-behavioral perspectives on body image. In T. F. Cash &amp; L. Smolak (Eds.), Body image: A handbook of science, practice, and prevention (PP 39–47). New York: Guilford Press.##[23] Coyne, C. A., Demian-Popescu, C., &amp; Friend, D. (2006). “Peer Reviewed: Social and Cultural Factors Influencing Health in Southern West Virginia: A Qualitative Study”, Preventing Chronic Disease, Vol. 13, No. 4.##[24] Daniel, S., &amp; Bridges, S. K. (2010). “The drive for muscularity in men: Media influences and objectification theory”, Body Image, Vol. 7, No. 1, PP 32-38.##[25] Delmar, R.(1986). What is Feminism? New York: Pantheon Books.##[26] Dohnt, H. K., &amp; Tiggemann, M. (2006). “The contribution of peer and media influences to the development of body satisfaction and self-esteem in young girls: A prospective study”, Developmental Psychology, No. 42, PP 929-936.##[27] Feltman, C. E., &amp; Szymanski, D. M. (2018). “Instagram Use and Self-Objectification: The Roles of Internalization, Comparison, Appearance Commentary, and Feminism”, Sex Roles, PP 1-14.##[28] Ferrier, A. G., &amp; Martens, M. P. (2008). “Perceived incompetence and disordered eating among college students”, Eating behaviors, Vol. 19, No. 1, PP 111-119.##[29] Fredrickson, B. L., &amp; Roberts, T.-A. (1997). “Objectification theory: Toward understanding women’s lived experiences and mental health risks”, Psychology of Women Quarterly, Vol. 21, PP 173-206.##[30] Grippo, K. P., &amp; Hill, M. S. (2008). “Self-objectification, habitual body monitoring, and body dissatisfaction in older European American women: Exploring age and feminism as moderators”, Body Image, Vol. 5, No. 2, PP 173-182.##[31] Harding, S. &amp; Hintikka, M. B. (1983). Introduction. In S. Harding, &amp; M. B. Hintikka (Eds.) Discovering reality, Feminist Perspectives on Epistemology, Metaphysics, Methodology, and Philosophy of Science (pp. ix-xix). Dordrecht, Holland: Kluwer Academic Publishers.##[32] Iwamoto, D. K., Corbin, W., Takamatsu, S., &amp; Castellanos, J. (2018). “The association between multidimensional feminine forms, binge drinking, and alcohol related problems among young adult college women”, Addictive Behaviors, Vol. 76, PP 243–249.##[33] Kinsaul, J. A., Curtin, L., Bazzini, D., &amp; Martz, D. (2014). “Empowerment, feminism, and self-efficacy: Relationships to body image and disordered eating. Body image”, Coyne, C. A., Demian-Popescu, C., &amp; Friend, D. (2006). Peer Reviewed: Social and Cultural Factors Influencing Health in Southern West Virginia: A Qualitative Study. Preventing Chronic Disease, Vol. 11, No. 1, PP, 63-67.##[34] Lloyd, G. (2002). The man of reason: Male and female in western philosophy, Routledge.##[35] Lorber, J., &amp; Farrell, S. A. (1991). “Principles of gender construction”, The social construction of gender, PP 7-11.##[36] Mahalik, J., Morray, E. B., Coonerty-Femiano, A., Ludlow, L. H., Slattery, S. M., &amp; Smiler, A. (2005). “Development of the Conformity to Feminine Norms Inventory”, Sex Roles, Vol. 52, PP 417–435.##[37] Marine, S. B., &amp; Lewis, R. (2014, November). “I&#039;m in this for real”: Revisiting young women&#039;s feminist becoming. In Women&#039;s Studies International Forum (Vol. 47, pp. 11-22). Pergamon.##[38] Miller, J. B. (2012). Toward a new psychology of women. Beacon Press.##[39] Murnen, S. K., &amp; Smolak, L. (2009). “Are feminist women protected from body image problems?”, A meta-analytic review of relevant research. Sex Roles, Coyne, C. A., Demian-Popescu, C., &amp; Friend, D. (2006). Peer Reviewed: Social and Cultural Factors Influencing Health in Southern West Virginia: A Qualitative Study. Preventing Chronic Disease, Vol. 60, No. 34, PP 181-215.##[40] Palan, K. M. (2001). “Gender identity in consumer behavior research: A literature review and research agenda”, Academy of Marketing Science Review, Vol. 10, No. 1, PP 1-25.##[41] Parnt, M. C., Moradi, B. (2001). “An abbreviate tool for assessing feminine conformity: Psychometric Properties of the Conformity to Feminine Norms Inventory”, Psychological Assessment, Vol. 23, 958- 969.##[42] Piaget, J. (1952). Play, dreams and imitation in childhood. New York: W. W. Norton &amp; Company, Inc.##[43] Ricciardelli, L. A. (2012). “Body Image Development—Adolescent Boys”, In, T. Cash, Encyclopedia of Body Image and Human Appearance. (PP 180-186)##[44] Schertzer, S., Laufer, D., Silvera, D. and Brad McBride, J. (2008), “A cross‐cultural validation of a gender role identity scale in marketing”, International Marketing Review, Vol. 25 No. 3, PP 312-323.##[45] Siegel, J.A. Calogero, R.M. (2019). “Conformity to feminine norms and self-bjectification in self-identified feminist and non-feminist women”, Body Image, Vol. 28, PP 115–118.##[46] Tong, R. (2009). Feminist Thought: A Comprehensive Introduction. 3th Edition ed. Colorado: Westview Press.##[47] Tylka, T. L., Russell, H. L., &amp; Neal, A. A. (2015). “Self-compassion as a moderator ofthinness-related pressures’ associations with thin-ideal internalization and dis-ordered eating”, Eating Behaviors, Vol. 17, PP 23–26.##[48] Vandenbosch, L., Muise, A., Eggermont, S., &amp; Impett, E.A. (2015). “Sexualizing reality television: Associations with trait and state self-objectification”, Body Image, Vol. 13, PP 62–66.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر کوتاه‌مدت و بلندمدت متغیرهای اقتصادی بر روند ازدواج و طلاق در ایران با تأکید بر کانال‌های کنترلی جنسی و آموزشی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Analysis of short-term and long-term economic variables on marriage and divorce trend with an emphasis on sexual and educational control channels</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>تحولات ازدواج و وقوع طلاق می‏تواند با مسائل جنسی، نهادی و اقتصادی‌ـ که امکان تشکیل یا ادامة زندگی مشترک را تسهیل یا دشوار می‏کنند‌ـ ارتباط داشته باشد. در این پژوهش، تأثیر متغیرهای اقتصادی بر روند ساختاری (پایدار) و روند تصادفی ازدواج و طلاق با بهره‏گیری از فیلتر کالمن (KF)، با تأکید بر کانال‏های کنترلی نسبت جنسیتی و نرخ باسوادی در ایران طی دورة 1348ـ1395 در دو الگوی کوتاه‏مدت و بلندمدت مبتنی بر مدل خودرگرسیون با وقفه‏های توزیعی (ARDL) بررسی شده است. نتایج نشان می‏دهد میان روند ساختاری (پایدار) متغیر طلاق و متغیرهای اقتصادی رابطة معنا‏دار و مثبتی وجود دارد. نکتة حائز اهمیت این است که کانال‏های کنترلیِ نسبت جنسی و نرخ باسوادی هستند که امکان تأثیرگذاری و تفسیر دقیق و معنا‏دار بیکاری و تورم بر روند ساختاری (پایدار) طلاق را فراهم می‏آورند. به‌علاوه، نسبت جنسی و نرخ باسوادی خود نیز تأثیر مثبت و معنا‏داری بر روند ساختاری (پایدار) ازدواج دارند. از‌این‌رو، تأکید و توجه ویژه به مکانیسمِ هشدار نسبت جنسی و برنامه‏ریزی در‌خصوص نرخ باسوادی می‏تواند تأثیری مضاعف و هم‏افزا بر بهبود روند ازدواج در ایران داشته باشد. بنابراین، تشکیل خانواده در ایران به‌طور ویژه تحت‌تأثیر زمینه‏های جنسی (به‌ویژه نسبت جنسی) و زمینه‏های آموزشی (به‌ویژه نرخ باسوادی) است، ولی تصمیم به طلاق می‏تواند علاوه بر متغیرهای جنسی و آموزشی، تحت‌تأثیر تورم و بیکاری نیز باشد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Marriage and divorce can be related to economic, sexual and institutional issues that make it easier or more difficult to create or maintain a new married life. In this study, the impact of economic variables on smooth and stochastic trends of marriage and divorce, with emphasis on sexual ratio and literacy rate control channels has been analyzed during 1969-2016 in Iran, using Autoregressive Distributed Lag model and Kalman filter. The results show that there is a significant and positive relationship between smooth divorce process and economic variables. Importantly, sexual ratio and literacy rate control channels are the channels that allow for accurate interpretations of unemployment and inflation on the smooth divorce process. In addition, sexual ratio and literacy rate have a positive and significant effect on the smooth marriage process. Therefore, the emphasis on gender-based alerting mechanism and literacy rate planning can have a double and synergic effect on improving the marriage process in Iran. Therefore, family formation in Iran is particularly influenced by gender control channels (especially sexual ratio) and institutional control channels (especially literacy rates) but the decision to divorce can be influenced by inflation and unemployment in addition to gender and institutional variables.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>487</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>511</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قائمی اصل</Family>
						<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ghaemi Asl</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشکدة اقتصاد دانشگاه خوارزمی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشکدة اقتصاد دانشگاه خوارزمی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.ghaemi84@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نصر اصفهانی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nasr Isfahani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت‌علمی دانشکدة اقتصاد، دانشگاه خوارزمی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت‌علمی دانشکدة اقتصاد، دانشگاه خوارزمی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mnasr121@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>الهه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شاه پرست</Family>
						<NameE>Elahe</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Shahparast</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد اقتصاد انرژی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد اقتصاد انرژی، دانشگاه فردوسی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>eli_shahparast@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نیره</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>توسلی عبدل‌آبادی</Family>
						<NameE>Nayereh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Tavassoli Abdolabadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد اقتصاد انرژی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد اقتصاد انرژی، دانشگاه فردوسی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>nayeretavasoli1990@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ازدواج</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بیکاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>طلاق</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فلیتر کالمن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نسبت جنسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] آستین‏فشان، پروانه (1380). «بررسی روند تحولات سن ازدواج و عوامل اجتماعی‌ـ جمعیتی مؤثر بر آن طی سال‏های 77-1355»، پایان‏نامة کارشناسی ارشد، جمعیت‌شناسی دانشکدة علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه تهران.##[2] اسحاقی، محمد؛ محبی، سیده فاطمه؛ ستار، پروین؛ محمدی، فریبرز (1391). «سنجش عوامل اجتماعی مؤثر بر درخواست طلاق زنان در شهر تهران»، زن در توسعه و سیاست (پژوهش زنان)، ش 3، ص 97ـ124.##[3] التجائی، ابراهیم؛ عزیززاده، مینا (1395). «بررسی عوامل اقتصادی و فرهنگی مؤثر بر سن ازدواج در ایران، یک مطالعة میان استانی»، جامعه‏پژوهی فرهنگی، ش 3، ص 1ـ23.##[4] بانکی‏پور فرد، امیر‌حسین؛ کلانتری، مهدی؛ مسعودی‏نیا، زهرا (1390). «درآمدی بر آمار ازدواج زنان در ایران»، معرفت در دانشگاه اسلامی، ش3، ص 26ـ47.##[5] تمنا، سعید (1380)، مبانی جمعیت‏شناسی، تهران: دانشگاه پیام نور.##[6] تیماجچی، فاطمه (1377). «علل و عوامل طلاق در تهران»، پایان‏نامة کارشناسی ارشد، دانشکدة علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه تهران.##[7] درگاهی، حسین؛ قاسمی، مجتبی؛ بیرانوند، امین (1397). «عوامل اقتصادی و اجتماعی مؤثر بر طلاق در ایران با تأکید بر ادوار تجاری، آموزش و اشتغال زنان»، فصل‌نامة اقتصاد و الگوسازی دانشگاه شهید بهشتی. ش 17 و 18، ص 120ـ195.##[8] صادقی، رسول (1395). «عوامل اقتصادی‌ـ اجتماعی مؤثر بر طلاق جوانان در ایران»، نشریة مطالعات راهبردی ورزش و جوانان، ش 32، ص 189ـ205.##[9] صادقی، رسول؛ شکفته‌گوهری، محمد (1395). «مطالعة پیامدهای بیکاری بر تأخیر در ازدواج جوانان در شهر تهران»، فصل‌نامة برنامه‏ریزی رفاه و توسعة اجتماعی، ش 30، ص 142ـ175.##[10] صدرالاشرفی، مسعود؛ خنکدار طارسی، معصومه؛ شمخانی، اژدر؛ یوسفی افراشته، مجید (1391). «آسیب‏شناسی طلاق و راه‏های پیشگیری از آن»، مجلة مهندسی فرهنگی، ش 73 و 74، ص 26ـ53.##[11] ضرابی، وحید؛ مصطفوی، سید فرخ (1390). «بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر سن ازدواج در ایران؛ یک رویکرد اقتصادی»، فصل‌نامة پژوهش‏های اقتصادی، ش 4، ص 33ـ64.##[12] عسکری ندوشن، عباس؛ ساسانی‏پور، محمد؛ کوششی، مجید؛ خسروی، اردشیر (1397). «الگوی تفاوت جنسی مرگ‌ومیر در ایران طی سال‏های 1385ـ1394»، زن در توسعه و سیاست، ش 3، ص 415ـ438.##[13] علی‏مندگاری، ملیحه؛ رازقی نصرآبادی، حجیه بی‏بی (1395). «بسترهای اقتصادی مؤثر در تصمیم‏گیری زوجین به طلاق مطالعة موردی شهر تهران»، پژوهش‏نامة زنان، ش 3، ص 109ـ135.##[14] عیسی‌زاده، سعید؛ بلالی، اسماعیل؛ قدسی، علی محمد (1389). «تحلیل اقتصادی طلاق بررسی ارتباط بیکاری و طلاق در ایران طی دورة 1385ـ1345»، مطالعة راهبردی زنان، ش 50، ص 7ـ28.##[15] کاظمی‏پور، شهلا (1388). «سنجش نگرش جوانان نسبت به ازدواج و شناخت آثار و پیامدهای این نوع ازدواج با تأکید بر ازدواج‏های دانشجویی»، فصل‌نامة علمی‌ـ ترویجی دانشگاه اسلامی، ش42، ص 75ـ95.##[16] کاظمی‏پور، شهلا (1371). روش‌های مقدماتی تحلیل جمعیت، تهران: دانشگاه پیام نور.##[17] کاملی، محمدجواد (1386). «بررسی توصیفی علل و عوامل مؤثر در بروز آسیب اجتماعی طلاق در جامعة ایران با توجه به آمار و اسناد موجود»، فصل‌نامة دانش انتظامی، ش 53، ص 180ـ198.##[18] کاوه فیروز، زینب؛ کاظمی‏پور، شهلا؛ رنجبر، مرتضی (1393). «تعیین‏کننده‏های اجتماعی‌ـ جمعیتی افزایش سن ازدواج (دانشجویان زن تحصیلات تکمیلی دانشگاه‏های تهران»، زن در توسعه و سیاست (پژوهش زنان)، ش 3، ص 449ـ468.##[19] کلانتری، صمد (1375). مبانی جمعیت‏شناسی، تهران: مانی.##[20] میرمحمدصادقی، جواد؛ توکلی، اکبر؛ واحدسعید، فریبا (1389). «عوامل اجتماعی‌ـ اقتصادی و جمعیت‏شناختی مؤثر بر باروری در مناطق روستایی شهرستان نجف‏آباد»، زن در توسعه و سیاست (پژوهش زنان)، ش 1، ص 143ـ159.##[21] هزارجریبی، جعفر؛ آستین‏فشان، پروانه (1388). «بررسی عوامل اجتماعی، اقتصادی مؤثر بر میانگین سن ازدواج زنان در سه دهة گذشته 1355ـ1385»، نشریة برنامه‏ریزی رفاه و توسعة اجتماعی، ش 1، ص 13ـ32.##[22] Ackley, Gardner. 1978. “The goals of stabilization policy: The costs of inflation”, American Economics Review, 68: PP 149-154.##[23] Arnaldo, Carlos (2004). “Ethnicity and Marriage Patterns in Mozambique”, African .##[24] Banerjee, A., J.J. Dolado &amp; R. Mester. (1992). “On Some Simple Test for Cointegration: The Cost of Simpilicity”, Bank of Spain Working Paper, 9302.##[25] Becker, S. Gary; Landes, M.Elisabeth and Michael Robert T. (1977). “An Economic Analysis of Marital Instability”, Journal of Political Economy, Vol. 85, No. 6 (Dec., 1977), PP 1141-1187.##[26] Blau, Francine D.; Lawrence M. Kahn and Jane Waldfogel. (2000). “Understanding Young Women’s Marriage Decisions: The Role of Labor and Marriage Market Conditions”, Industrial and Labor Relations Review, 4, PP 624-647.##[27] Bracher, Michael and Gigi Santow. (1998). “Economic independence and union formation in Sweden”, Population Studies,3, PP 275-294.##[28] Brien, Michael J. (1997). “Racial Differences in Marriage and the Role of Marriage Markets”, Journal of Human Resources, 4,PP 74178.##[29] Charles K. and Stevens, M. (2004). “Job displacement, Disability, and divorce”, Journal of Labour Economics,22, PP 522–489.##[30] Choe, Minja K., ShymaThapa and VinodMistra. (2004). “Early marriage and early motherhood in Nepal”, Journal of Biosocial Sciences (First published on line, 20, PP 1-20.##[31] Edlund, L. (1999). “Son preference, sex ratios, and marriage patterns”, Journal of political Economy, 107(6), PP 1275-1304.##[32] Ehiemua, S. (2014). “Gender longevity: Male/female disparity”, International Journal of Academic Research and Reflection, 2(3), PP 32-38.##[33] Elias, J.Julio. (2003). “The Link between Unemployment and the Marriage Rate: Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1980-1999”, Cuad. Econ, 121.##[34] Goode, W. J. (1971). “Family disorganization, in Contemporary Social Problems (Eds) R”, Merton and R. Nisbet, Harcourt, Brace, Jovanovich, New York, PP 476–544.##[35] Harvey, A. (1997). “Trends, cycles, and autoregressions”, Economic Journal, 107, PP 192–201.##[36] Harvey, A. (1989). “Forecasting Structural Time Series Models and the Kalman Filter”, Cambridge University Press, Cambridge.##[37] Hess, G. D؛ (2004). “Marriage and Consumption Insurance: What’s Love Got to do with it?”, Journal of Political Economy, 112, PP 290–318.##[38] Ikamari, Lawrence D.E. (2005). “The Effect of Education on the Timing of Marriage in Kenya”, Demographic Research, 12.##[39] Kalmijn, Matthijs &amp; Jansen, M. (2004). “Interaction between Cultural and Economic Determinates of Divorce in the Netherlands”, Marriage andFamily, 1, PP 75-89.##[40] Koopman, S., Harvey, A., Doornik, J. and Shephard, N. (2000). Stamp: Structural Time Series Analyser, Modeller, and Predictor, Timberlake Consultants Press, London.##[41] Kwiatkowski, D.; Phillips, P.; Schmidt, P. and Shin, Y. (1992). “Testing the null hypothesis of stationarity against the alternative of a unit root: how sure are we that economic time series have a unit root?”, Journal of Econometrics, 54, PP 159–78.##[42] Lopez, A. D. (1984). “Sex differentials in mortality”, WHO Chronicle, 38, PP 217-224.##[43] Loughran, David S. (1998). “Does Variance Matter? The Effect of Rising Male Wage Inequality on Female Age at First Marriage Unpublished manuscript”,##[44] Luy, M. (2003). “Causes of male excess mortality: insights from cloistered populations. Population and Development Review, 29(4), PP 647-676.##[45] Nathanson, C. A. (1984). “Sex differences in mortality”, Annual review of sociology, 10(1), PP 191-213.##[46] Norton, A. and Glick, P. (1979). “Marital instability in America: past, present, and future”, in Divorce and Separation (Eds) G. Levinger and O. C. Moles, Basic Books, New York, PP 6–19.##[47] Nunley, J. M. (2009). “Inflation and other aggregate determinants of the trend in US divorce rates since the 1960s”, Applied Economics, 42:26, PP 3367-3381.##[48] Nunley, J. M; M.John and Seals, Alan؛ (2010). “The Effects of Household Income Volatility on Divorce”, American Journal of Economics and Sociology, 69.##[49] Ogburn, W. and Thomas, D. (1922). “The influence of the business cycle on certain social conditions”, Journal of the American Statistical Association, 18, pp 324–40.##[50] Population Studies,19(1), PP 164-143.  ##[51] Schellekens, Jona and Gliksberg, David. (2012). “Inflation and Marriage in Israe&quot;l”, Journal of Family History, 00(0), PP 1-16.##[52] Smith, D. W. (1989). “Is greater female longevity a general finding among animals?”, Biological Reviews, 64(1), PP 1-12.##[53] South, S. (1985). “Economic conditions and the divorce rate: a time-series analysis of postwar United States”, Journal of Marriage and the Family, 47, PP 31–41.##[54] Waldron I. (1995). “Contributions of biological and behavioural factors to changing sex differences in ischemic heart disease mortality”, in: Lopez A. D., Caselli G., Valkonen T. (Ed.): Adult Mortality in Developed Countries. From Description to Explanation, Oxford: Clarendon Press: PP 161-178##[55] Weiss, Yoram and Willis, J.Robert. (1997). “Match Quality، New information and Marital Dissolution”, Journal of Labor Economic, 15.##[56] Wilson, William J. And Neckerman, Kathryn M. (1986). “Poverty and Family Structure: The Widening Gap between Evidence and Policy Issues, in Sheldon H”,##[57] Wingard, D. L. (1984). “The sex differential in morbidity, mortality, and lifestyle”, Annual review of public health, 5(1), PP 433-458.##[58] Wood, Robert G. (1995). “Marriage Rates and Marriageable Men: A Test of the Wilson Hypothesis”, Journal of Human Resources, 30(1), P 16393.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				