<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Localization Branding of Training and Social Personal Entrepreneurship for Model Presentation ( A Case Study: Educational Department Mazandaran Province).</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارائه مدل بومی سازی برندینگ مهارت آموزی و کارآفرینی فردی و اجتماعی در نظام آموزشی ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>20</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">61472</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>میترا</FirstName>
					<LastName>ناصری آلاشتی</LastName>
<Affiliation>مدریت دبیرستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعید</FirstName>
					<LastName>صفاریان همدانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه مدیریت آموزشی،دانشکده علوم انسانی،دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد ساری، ساری،ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>هاشم نژاد آبرسی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه علوم تربیتی، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، ساری، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>31</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This research aims to develop a localizing model of branding skill training and individual and social entrepreneurship in Educational system of Iran. The research method is combination and research design is also a mixed explorative research method. In qualitative section, twenty professors of educational management, entrepreneurship and public management disciplines in Islamic Azad University of Mazandaran and Senior and middle managers of Mazandaran Province Education Department were interviewed by using &quot;samples containing rich information&quot; with Delphi method and by using semi-structured questionnaires. The results suggested that the internal factors underlying the brand had dimensions of: manager&#039;s risk-taking, financial, social and legal infrastructures, strategic planning, support of senior managers of the organization, educational quality and culture and environment of the schools, external factors underlying the brand had dimension of: the brand power of the organization, government support, motivational plans of Upstream institutions and macro strategies, Internal Consequences of Branding had dimensions of: students motivation, entrepreneurial trend in school, encouragement and support of talent students and their creation and innovation and external consequences of branding had the dimensions of: brand equity of the organization, community and Public Opinion Satisfaction, attracting talented and innovative students, total desirable performance and the social responsibility of the organization. In the quantitative part of research, a researcher-made questionnaire by multi-stage relative classified sampling method has been distributed among 364 teachers of girls&#039; and boys&#039; secondary schools of Mazandaran and data were analyzed explorative and confirmatory factor analysis with SPSS and AMOS software. The results from quantitative section showed that the effect of all the internal and external factors underlying brand on branding skill-learning and individual and social entrepreneurship and this variable on internal and external consequences of branding has been confirmed.&lt;br /&gt; AhmadPour Daryani. M, Azizi. M. (2013), Entrepreneurship, Tehran: Mehrab Qalam. [in Persian] &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Ahmadpour, M., Salamzadeh, Y., Salamzadeh, A., Farzad, F., (2011), An analysis of the current gaps in social entrepreneurship in Iran: shackled feet, 1st International Conference on Management, Innovation and Entrepreneurship, Shiraz, Iran [in Persian]&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Ali- Choudhury, R., Bennett, R., &amp; Savani, S. (2009). University marketing directors’ views on the components of a university brand. Intern Rev Publ Nonprofit Mark, 6(1), 11-33.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Alvani. Seyyed Mahdi (2011); Entrepreneurship, Synergy of individual, culture and society, 20 (134), 5-9. [in Persian]&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Asarian. R (2019), identification and prioritization of the success factors in social entrepreneurship, fourth national conference of management, accounting and economy with emphasis on regional and global marketing, Tehran- Shahid Beheshti University, Permanent Secretariat of the Conference. [in Persian]&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Atwi, S. (2009).Evaluation of open and distance learning System with a specific focus on academic performance. Presented in the 23rd Annual Conference of Asian Association of Open Universities Was Held at Payame Noor University in November 3 to 5, 62-68.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; AzizPour, A. A, Mahdivand. M (2011), social capital and its role on Entrepreneurial orientation of organizations, Specialized Monthly of Nab Karafarin, No. 10 and 11, p. 15-23. [in Persian]&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Azma. F, Nouri. Abed, M. Seyyed Davoud, Panahi. M, (2018), &quot;the effect of training entrepreneurship on the tendency to entrepreneurship in Agriculture students&quot;, National Management Conference, Accounting and Business Development, Qaemshahr, Farvardin Institute of Higher Education. [in Persian]&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Bozhikin I, Macke J, da Costa L. F, (2019), The role of government and key non-state actors in social entrepreneurship: A systematic literature review, Journal of Cleaner Production, doi: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2019.04.076.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Brunzel, D. L. (2007). Universities sell their brands. Journal of Product &amp; Brand Management, 16(2), 152-153.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Cassia,L &amp; Massis,A &amp; Meoli,M &amp; Minola,T (2013). Entrpreneurship Research Centers Around the World: Research Orientation, Knowledge Transfer and Performance. J Technol Transf, . PP.1-17.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Ekhlasi. A &amp; Giyah Chin. M. (2013), &quot;A model for measuring the brand equity in the service area; Test and Implementation of a Virtual University, Modern Marketing Research Quarterly, 3 (2), 189 – 204. [in Persian]&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Dinari. F, (2012), &quot;the comparison of Technical and vocational education and Official skill system of Iranian with some of world&#039;s successful countries, national entrepreneurship conference and management of knowledge-based business. [in Persian]&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Duarte, P. O., Alves, H. B., &amp; Raposo, M. B. (2010). Understanding university image: A structural equation model approach. International Review on Public and Nonprofit Marketing, 7(1), 21-36.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Dvorak, D. (2010). Build your own brand. Gretna, LA: Pelican.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Enzebati. A, Valipour. M, (2011), &quot;the study of the relation between job training and Entrepreneurship and its role in the youth attitude about self-employment, identifying and simulating the entrepreneurship talents and skills&quot;, National Conference on Knowledge-Based Entrepreneurship and Business Management. [in Persian]&lt;br /&gt; Nasr Esfahani. H, Fazlollah. R, Arash. S, Hekmat Panah. M (2018), studying the effective factors and barriers on individual entrepreneurship of Members of Trade and Commerce, industries and tourism Commissions of Chamber of Commerce, Mines and Agriculture in Isfahan, first international conference of management and engineering/ elementary, Tehran, management research institute of Modabber. [in Persian]&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Palacios-Marques D, Guijarro Garcia M, Sanchez M. M, Alguacil Mari M. P, (2019), Social entrepreneurship and organizational performance: A study of the mediating role of distinctive competencies in marketing, Journal of Business Research, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jbusres.2019.02.004&lt;br /&gt; Salehi O. E (2010), society, labor and jobs: a review on job creation in labor market, Tehran: the publication of organization of study and compilation of humanities textbooks of universities (SAMT). [in Persian]&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Sang-Hoon, K and others, (2005). Entrepreneurship in Japan and Silicon Valley: a comparative study. Technovation, vol 22, Issue 10, June, pp. 598&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Sadiku-Dushi N, Dana L. P, Ramadani V, (2019), Entrepreneurial marketing dimensions and SMEs performance, Journal of Business Research 100 (2019) 86–99.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Sharma, A. A., Rao, V. R., &amp; Popli, S. (2013). Measuring customer-based brand equity for Indian business schools. Journal of Marketing for Higher Education, 23(2), 175-203.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Shaw, E., &amp; Carter, S. (2007). Social entrepreneurship: Theoretical antecedents and empirical analysis of entrepreneurial processes and outcomes. Journal of Small Business and Enterprise Development, 14(3), 418—434.&lt;br /&gt; Sheikhifar R, Koknar J, (2016), The Interplay of Work Culture and Learning Skills Based on Resistance Economics Using DEMATEL Model (Case Study: Industrial City of Abyek Arak), The 5th National Conference and the Fourth International Conference on Training and Employment, Tehran, Technical and Vocational Training Organization In partnership with UNESCO and Protection of Ministry of Cooperatives, Labour, and Social Welfare. [in Persian]&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Shepherd, D; Covin, G.F; Kuratko F.D. (2008). Project Failure fromCorporate Entrepreneurship: Managing the Grief Process, Journal of Business Venturing, 24 (6): 588-600.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از پژوهش حاضر، ارائه مدل‌ بومی‌سازی برندینگ مهارت آموزی و کارآفرینی فردی و اجتماعی در نظام آموزش و پرورش ایران بوده، روش تحقیق ترکیبی و طرح تحقیق نیز از نوع طرح تحقیق آمیخته اکتشافی است. در بخش کیفی با استفاده از روش &quot;نمونه‌های حاوی اطلاعات غنی&quot; با 20 نفر از اساتید رشته‌های مدیریت آموزشی، کارآفرینی و مدیریت دولتی در دانشگاه‌های آزاد استان مازندران و مدیران ارشد و میانی اداره آموزش و پرورش استان مازندران، با روش دلفی و استفاده از پرسشنامه‌های نیمه‌ساختاریافته؛ مصاحبه گردید. نتایج حاکی از آن بوده که عوامل داخلی زمینه‌ساز برند دارای ابعاد: ریسک‌پذیری مدیران، زیرساختهای مالی، اجتماعی و قانونی، برنامه‌ریزی استراتژیک، حمایت مدیران ارشد سازمان، کیفیت آموزشی و فرهنگ و محیط مدارس، عوامل خارجی: قدرت برند سازمان، حمایت دولت، طرح های تشویقی، پیامدهای داخلی: انگیزش ، گرایش کارآفرینانه در مدرسه، تشویق و حمایت و پیامدهای خارجی: ارزش ویژه برند سازمان، رضایت جامعه و افکار عمومی، جذب دانش آموزان مستعد و نوآور، عملکرد کلی مطلوب و مسئولیت اجتماعی سازمان، بود. در بخش کمی تحقیق، پرسشنامه محقق ساخته‌ای با روش نمونه‌گیری طبقه‌ای نسبی چندمرحله‌ای در بین 364 تن از معلمان مدارس دخترانه و پسرانه دوره دوم متوسطه استان مازندران توزیع و داده‌ها با روش تحلیل عاملی اکتشافی و تائیدی با نرم افزارهای SPSS و AMOSتحلیل گردید. نتایج بخش کمی نشان داد که تاثیر تمامی ابعاد عوامل داخلی و خارجی زمینه‌ساز برند بر برندسازی مهارت‌آموزی و کارآفرینی فردی و اجتماعی و این متغیر هم بر پیامدهای داخلی و خارجی برندسازی مورد تائید واقع شدند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">برندینگ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مهارت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارآفرینی فردی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
