<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Introducing and developing reflective leadership at schools
And its role in improving teachers&#039; self-efficacy beliefs</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رهبری تأملی در مدارس و نقش آن در بهبود باورهای خودکارآمدی معلمان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>19</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60979</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.34785/J010.2019.143</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجتبی</FirstName>
					<LastName>طاهری</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت آموزشی، دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>هویدا</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار مدیریت آموزشی، دانشگاه اصفهان،اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of present research was to investigate the relationship between principals&#039; reflective leadership with teachers&#039; self-efficacy. The research method was descriptive – correlational. The population consisted of the whole high schools’ teachers nearly 2165 people in the academic year of 1395-96. 327 teachers were selected as a sample using Krejcie and Morgan table through proportionate Stratified random sampling method. The tools used in this research were researcher-made Reflective Leadership Questionnaire based on Castelli’s (2012, 2016) integrated model of RL and the Teachers’ Efficacy Questionnaire (Tschannen-Moran &amp; Woolfolk Hoy,2001). Their face and content validity was confirmed by experts. The instruments’ reliability coefficients were estimated 0/96 and 0/92 respectively. The data, at the descriptive statistics (frequency, percentage, mean and standard deviation) and inferential statistics level (Pearson correlation coefficient, regression analysis, t-Test, ANOVA and Tukey Test) were analyzed by SPSS 23. The findings showed a positive and significant relationship between principals&#039; reflective leadership and teachers&#039; self-efficacy (r = 0.81, p≤0.05). Moreover 77 percent of teaching strategies, 28 percent of classroom management and 71 percent of student engagement were predicted by principals&#039; reflective leadership. And finally, education and work experience on principals&#039; reflective leadership and teachers&#039; self-efficacy were significant. The principals&#039; reflective leadership can raise the teachers’ self-efficacy belief through the knowledge and experience connection.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">  این پژوهش توصیفی - همبستگی با مشارکت ۳۲۷ نفر از معلمان دوره اول متوسطه شهر اصفهان از طریق نمونه گیری طبقه ای متناسب با حجم انجام شد. داده‌ها با استفاده از پرسشنامه محقق ساخته رهبری تأملی مدیران مدارس بر اساس الگوی یکپارچه رهبری تأملی (Castelli,2016) و پرسشنامه خودکارآمدی معلم (Tschannen-Moran &amp; Hoy,2001) گردآوری شد. روایی محتوایی پرسشنامه‌ها تعیین گردید و پایایی پرسشنامه‌های رهبری تأملی مدیران و خودکارآمدی معلمان با استفاده از آلفای کرونباخ به ترتیب ۹۶/۰ و ۹۲/۰ بدست آمد. از نرم افزار آماری SPSS و آزمون های تحلیل رگرسیون، آزمون تی تک نمونه ای، تحلیل واریانس یکراهه، ضریب همبستگی پیرسون و آزمون توکی جهت تجزیه و تحلیل داده ها بهره گرفته شد. یافته‌های پژوهش نشان داد که بین رهبری تأملی مدیران مدارس با خودکارآمدی معلمان رابطه مستقیم و معناداری وجود دارد. همچنین از بین مولفه‌های رهبری تأملی مدیران، مولفه های هدف و معناداری بهترین پیش‌بینی کننده خودکارآمدی معلمان بود. ضمناً ابعاد رهبری تأملی مدیران می تواند ۷۴ درصد تغییرات خودکارآمدی معلمان را پیش بینی کند. رهبری تأملی عاملی اساسی در جهت تغییر پارادایم آموزشی در مدارس است که از طریق پیوند دانش و تجربه می‌تواند باور به خودکارآمدی را در معلمان تقویت کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رهبری تأملی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خودکارآمدی معلم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رویه‌های تأملی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدارس متوسطه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_60979_642c3f91675eb9f92817c5e5a3dd0f2b.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
