<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identification of Components and indicators of non-governmental schools ranking from the perspective of strategic factors</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی معیارها و شاخص‌های رتبه‌بندی مدارس غیردولتی از دیدگاه عوامل راهبردی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>415</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>396</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">61461</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>خدیجه</FirstName>
					<LastName>بزرگی نژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دوره دکتری مدیریت آموزشی، واحد مرودشت، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، مرودشت، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>زارعی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت آموزشی، واحد مرودشت، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، مرودشت، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مژگان</FirstName>
					<LastName>امیریان زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه مدیریت آموزشی، واحد مرودشت، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، مرودشت، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>خیّر</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه مدیریت آموزشی، واحد مرودشت، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، مرودشت، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study was to identify the components and indicators of non-governmental theoretical secondary schools from the perspective of strategic factors through a qualitative method and case study in Shiraz. One of the major strategies of the fundamental transformation document of education, is the development of educational capacities and capabilities for an active and constructive presence on international and regional scene in pursuit of the goals and missions of the constitution, document of future perspective, general policies of the Supreme Leader and five-year plans. Non-governmental schools that work as one of the educational capitals to achieve two important goals of increasing people&#039;s participation and educational justice can enhance  the position Iran in assessing the quality of the world and the introduction of the pattern of Islamic education by improving the quality of services and providing a variety of educational opportunities. Improving the quality and creating the opportunities for students and society depends on the goals, motivation and performance of the founders of these schools.
According to the fundamental transformation document of education, the strategy for improving performance, enhancing the quality and strengthening the incentives for rational and scientific competition between schools is creating a ranking system in schools and educational institutions. In order to create and formulate an appropriate ranking system, one can identify the essential components and indicators. Meanwhile, although the economic, political, social, and technological components of society and the environments of far from school can play a determinative role in introducing opportunities and even create sudden changes in schools, But the contributors of the action field and stakeholders who feel the challenges faced by schools to upgrade, are able to provide researchers with useful information about school ranking components.
The present research also aims to collect and analyze the views of the strategic factors of schools in order to identify and introduce the components and indicators of school ranking. The method of this study was qualitative case study. The potential contributors to this study were nongovernmental school experts and five elementary school members, including: the director, the council of school, the council of teachers, the council of parents association and coaches and the council of student who were selected through targeted sampling and a criterion-centered technique.
In order to determine the sample size, according to the multilevel approach of sampling, the task of collecting information up to the stage of the emergence of order and non-proliferation, was taken with the participation of 28 of the above strategic factors. The data collection tools was an open interview with the participants, which was conducted with the question &quot;What are the components and Indicators for ranking of nongovernmental schools?&quot;. Data analysis method with interpretive analysis approach was done by the method of thematic analysis. So initially, by assigning the initial codes derived from the quotes of the contributors, the basic themes were extracted and categorized with the organizer and inclusive themes and finally thematic network was drawn up by the researcher. To validate data, feedback methods to participators, researcher&#039;s review and positioning and aligning them with scientific resources, educational plans, endpoints, style sheets, documents and other related organizations were used. The reliability of the findings was also examined by using the opinions of the committee members including experts of non-governmental schools and the committee of the dissertation.
The findings of the research show that from the perspective of strategic factors there are nine major components in the ranking of non-governmental theoretical secondary schools, including: student ergonomics, school equipment and facilities, educational services, social services, humanity capital management, school management, data base, participation of strategic factors and outputs. In these nine components, 28 indicators were obtained for the ranking which their fields are briefly summarized below.
Ergonomics is an interdisciplinary science that establishes the mutual connection of technology, environment, and human physical needs. Students&#039; ergonomics focus on the level of health, safety, conducive and comfort of students and the quality of the conditions for doing school activities and learning. It tries to make school conditions more conducive to the physical conditions of the students so they do not have to adapt themselves to inappropriate conditions. Ergonomic of students includes school design, physical school design and designing the conditions for student’s activities.
Equipment and facilities affect learning indirectly and include library equipment, specialized laboratories, saloons, buffets, smart and sports equipment./ Educational services are the main tasks of educational organizations. School is the most basic center for providing these services. The school tries to create more academic and practical opportunities for students to improve their life skills and capabilities. Educational services include educating, training, and technology using./ Social services are carried out in accordance with the social responsibility of the organization and have a significant impact on the loyalty of customers and stakeholders to the organization and include scholarships and discounts, employment and physical and psychological care./ Human capital management is one of the major issues of organizations in the third millennium, including salaries and benefits, employee maintenance and staff training./ School management includes manager status and management functions, is the most important factor in school changes. The success of managers&#039; performance depends on their skills, knowledge, attitudes, abilities and competencies./ Database holds the organization&#039;s information set and includes organizational documentation and knowledge./ Participation and satisfaction of strategic factors in decision making is one of the major discussions of nongovernmental schools, including fivefold school pillars, educational experts, local officials and graduates./ Outputs include intermediate and final outputs which sensitize managers and stakeholders to shortcomings, bottlenecks, and pitfalls of the organization&#039;s perennial movements.
The results of this study show that from the perspective of strategic factors, school as the main focus of the provision of educational services and opportunities has important responsibilities to students and society. Each of these components has a particular function at the school, but in coordination with them, the local school will be a suitable place for education and training of adolescents. Therefore, in the ranking of nongovernmental schools, these components need to be considered in terms of their impact on student learning and the expectations of the beneficiaries of the school.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر به روش کیفی و با مطالعه موردی در شهر شیراز انجام شد. مشارکت‌کنندگان بالقوه این پژوهش، کارشناسان مدارس غیردولتی و اعضای ارکان پنج‌گانه مدرسه بود. انتخاب افراد به روش نمونه‌گیری هدفمند و تکنیک ملاک محور انجام گردید. با توجه به رویکرد چند سطحی بودن نمونه‌گیری با مشارکت 28 نفر از ذی‌نفعان فوق صورت گرفت. ابزار جمع‌آوری داده‌ها، مصاحبه باز با مشارکت‌کنندگان بود. تجزیه‌وتحلیل دادها بر اساس تحلیل مضمون انجام شد. برای اعتبار یابی داده‌ها از روش‌های بازخورد به مشارکت‌کنندگان، بازبینی و موضع‌گیری پژوهشگر و همسوسازی با منابع علمی و اسناد کلیدی آموزش‌وپرورش استفاده گردید. اعتمادپذیری یافته‌ها نیز با استفاده از نظرات اعضای کمیته راهنما انجام شد. یافته‌های پژوهش نشان داد که از دیدگاه عوامل راهبردی تعداد 9 معیار و 28 شاخص در رتبه‌بندی مدارس غیردولتی دوره دوم متوسطه نظری مؤثر است. معیارها شامل: ارگونومی دانش‌آموزان، امکانات و تجهیزات، خدمات آموزشی&lt;strong&gt;- &lt;/strong&gt;پرورشی، خدمات اجتماعی، مدیریت سرمایه انسانی، مدیریت مدرسه، بانک اطلاعاتی، مشارکت و رضایت عوامل راهبردی و بروندادها بود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارکان پنج‌گانه مدرسه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ذی‌نفعان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدارس غیردولتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سند تحول بنیادین آموزش‌وپرورش</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_61461_976475ce2f471691a25ef42ac2015e45.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
