<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The study of the relationship between leadership styles  school principals with organizational skills of time management</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی رابطۀ بین سبک‌های رهبری مدیران مدارس با مهارت‌های سازمانی مدیریت زمان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>18</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60945</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>اصغری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی آموخته کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه کاشان، کاشان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>یزدخواستی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، دانشکده علوم انسانی ، دانشگاه کاشان ،کاشان ، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید احمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>مدنی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکده علوم انسانی ، دانشگاه کاشان ،کاشان ، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>04</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Optimal allocation of organizational resources such as capital, human, information and time resource is one of the prerequisite the efficient management of educational organizations. In addition, time management controls interruptions, identifies lost time, recognizes and adjusts the limits and subsequently increases the efficiency of the works. Time management plays as an important role in the effective leadership of educational organizations, including schools and educational sections. School management is a complex activity which requires attention to the various issues and problems. The manager is responsible for supervising all the teachers and staff. He or she should follow the right instructions to guide the staff for the efficient educations. Efficient managing of the times makes it possible to create the opportunity for success and development. This study focused on the examination of time management and leadership styles of the school principals. Since the main pillar of the society development is the expert human resources, education and training is also the main pillar of human resource educations. Desired leadership results in relative satisfaction of the teacher and subsequently increases the efficiency of education. On the other hand, education plays an important role in training of future generation. One of the important tasks of each leader is his decision methods that the available time plays an important role in the decisions of the leader. In fact, it is the decision method determines his leadership styles. If the manager don’t manage his time properly he will be forced to make hasty decisions, which in most cases, due to lack of time, cannot use the advises of others. This may lead the leader to an autocratic leadership (Arami, 2006). Undoubtedly, if time is not used efficiently and people do not know its influences, they can never have a desired outcome. If people do not have control over their time and do not set their task properly, they will never be succeed. Time management control lags, identify the main waste of time, set limits and maximize the efficiency practically. In education, time is scarce, which is rarely planned for optimal use and is often inadequate to perform tasks. While the use of time influences all of school activities and the project managers does not predict use their time efficiently, they always lead to a shortage of time in their work and teachers and resulted in displeasuring the subordinates. Teacher for teaching, student for doing his/her tasks and family for helping students deal with time. Skill of time management consists of individual time management and organization time management. Organizational skill of time management is dedicated only to people who manage an organization which means applying the skills of a manager in the optimal use of time and direction for achieving goals in the organization and in relation to their duties. Also, the organizational and administrative environment of the manager is the environment which this kind of skill is used. Time management organization skills include six components: targeting, prioritizing, operational planning, delegation, communication management, and meeting management. Fault of managers working with the available times causes stress into them and subsequently waste time, and making stress of chief, which results in reducing the efficiency and effectiveness of the organization. Therefore, considering the key role of managers in the development of an organization, as well as the country, it is very important to pay attention to this issue. The director of the school is considered as the manager of an educational organization, with relationships to many people (students, teachers, teachers, etc.), should be responsible for answering to the senior managers in education and for the implementation of school affairs. Since school teachers may be in higher scientific level than school management, leadership may be difficult for school leadership, which may influence the school performances at the right time. This problem is more pronounced in populated schools. School administrators or administrators should have the ability to lead beside the management and the time can also play a role in determining leadership style. Considering the importance of this subject and the organizational benefits of time management skills, the main objective of this study is to examine the status of time management and leadership style and the relationship between them in school principals so that all managers, both educational and executive, can take advantage of their results. &lt;br /&gt;Research Method: The research type was descriptive-correlational. The statistical population consisted of all male and female male and female primary school students, first and second middle schools of Amol city. A sample of 132 school administrators was selected randomly. The hypotheses of this research were analyzed by one-sample t-test, independent t-test, analysis of variance, Spearman correlation test. Data collection tools were two organizational time management skills questionnaires with six components (targeting, prioritizing goals and activities, planning of operations, delegation of authority, communication management, management of meetings) and with a reliability coefficient (83/0) based on the Likert scale of 5 points (I highly agree I strongly disagree) and the standard LBDQ leadership style questionnaire in two dimensions of orbital and orbital duties in terms of four components (libertarian leadership, government leadership, integrated leadership and unbridled leadership) with a coefficient of reliability (76/0) and a five-level spectrum Likert (never, rarely, sometimes, often and always). To determine the validity, the content and formal review method was used. &lt;br /&gt;Findings: The results showed that there is a relationship between the components of leadership style and the organizational skills of time management. Only the authoritative and authoritative leadership styles have a significant relationship with organizational skills of time management, which this relationship is efficient to free leadership style and negative time management and to the style of leadership and organizational skills of time management. The findings also showed that the liberal style of leadership, his organizational performance in time management will decrease and the forced managing style resulted in better time management. The average of time management skill in the forced management style was also higher than other styles. In addition, the status of organizational skills of AMOL school administrators is in a favorable situation.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف این تحقیق بررسی رابطه بین سبک رهبری با مهارت‌های سازمانی مدیریت زمان مدیران مقطع ابتدایی، متوسطه اول و دوم مدارس شهرستان آمل بوده است. نوع تحقیق، توصیفی همبستگی بوده است. جامعه آماری شامل تمامی مدیران مرد و زن مقطع ابتدایی، متوسطه اول و دوم مدارس دولتی شهرستان آمل بوده است که نمونه‌ای به حجم 132 نفر از مدیران مدارس به صورت تصادفی انتخاب شد. فرضیه‌های این تحقیق از طریق آزمون‌ های t تک نمونه‌ ای، t مستقل، تحلیل واریانس، آزمون همبستگی اسپیرمن تجزیه‌ و تحلیل شد. ابزار گردآوری داده‌ ها دو پرسشنامه‌ی مهارت سازمانی مدیریت زمان با ضریب پایایی (83/0) و پرسشنامه استاندارد سبک رهبری LBDQ با ضریب پایایی (76/0) بوده است. برای تعیین روایی نیز از روش بررسی محتوایی و صوری استفاده گردید. یافته‌ ها نشان داد بین سبک رهبری و مهارت سازمانی مدیریت زمان مدیران مدارس ارتباط معناداری وجود دارد که میانگین مهارت سازمانی مدیریت زمان در سبک آمرانه نسبت به سایر سبک‌ها بیشتر بوده است. رابطه بین سبک رهبری آزادمنشانه و مهارت سازمانی مدیریت زمان منفی و بین سبک رهبری آمرانه و مهارت سازمانی مدیریت زمان مثبت و معنادار بوده است و همچنین وضعیت مهارت سازمانی مدیریت زمان مدیران مدارس آمل در وضعیت مطلوبی قرار دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رهبری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سبک رهبری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مهارت مدیریت زمان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مهارت سازمانی مدیریت زمان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_60945_94085e8b768f2c414e35ecb5b0959c5f.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Seeking to Understand the Schools’ Principals of Their Functional and Professional Nature</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>درک مدیران مدارس از ماهیت و کارکرد تخصصی و حرفه ای خود</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>19</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>39</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60942</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فریبا</FirstName>
					<LastName>عدلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه الزهرا، تهران- ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ابوطالب</FirstName>
					<LastName>مطللبی ورکانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه امام خمینی نوشهر، مازندران- ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In the last decade, schools’ principals and leadership professionalism, has been the main agenda of educational policy and attention to the quality of schools’ principals and leaders have been priority of educational system. Mangers and leaders pay attention to all school’s issues and they are in charge of the performances of school; they create a positive culture at school, their impact is beyond the boundaries of the school and the success of other systems in creating a sustainable environment depend on their performance. Many countries, including members of Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD), have held training course in School Leadership. According to these courses, School Leadership should be entrusted to the schools’ principals, so they must have a responsibility and a considerable freedom and independence. In fact, decision making is a task that schools principals should carry out independently. Therefore, higher education degree, passing various training courses and having experience in teaching and managing are absolute necessities for being a school’s principals. However, Iranian school’s principals mostly be chosen from the employees of the Ministry of Education and do not involved in decision making. As finding researches show Iranian school’s principals engage in ordinary tasks such as making sure that, when school finishes, all electronic equipment are off, the laboratory and library door is locked and etc. Our school’s principals are only responsible for the Ministry circulars and do not involve in decision making. As researches mention in 21&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century every effort to improve the quality of educational system should begin from school’s principals. Hence the purpose of this study was to identifying and understanding the tasks and activities of schools’ principals to achieve effective educational systems. To understand what the schools’ principals do and how do these activities, this research did qualitative method. Population of research were schools’ principals in Tehran that were selected theoretical sampling method. The tools for collecting data: we interviewed with 16 public schools’ principals. This schools’ principal had Bachelor and master degree. Also, we observed schools (observation without participation). We saw the activities of schools’ principals for a week at per schools. We studied the policies which reflect expectations, roles, and responsibilities of school’s principals and determine the scope of their powers. By observation, interviewing and studying documents, we did triangulation data. To analyze was used qualitative content analysis method. &lt;br /&gt;The content analysis of the findings observations, interviews and official documents show our schools’ principals are based on Mintzberg’s 10 Managerial Roles, respectively from high to low, Informational, Interpersonal and Decisional Roles. This schools’ principal was playing important role of decisional less frequently. Also, the content analysis of their job description shows the schools’ principals must perform codes set of Iranian Ministry of Education. Findings show that the appointment conditions of schools’ principals did not reflect the importance and complexity of schools as a unit of analysis. Job description is defined principals as controller not agent. we are facing with principals in our schools that control teachers and pupils’ actions instead of helping them to make decision and they are affected instead of affecting. While school’s principals must take decision about vital subjects, for example increase educational quality, decrease inequality and etc. Schools administers do tasks such as &lt;em&gt;a security guard&lt;/em&gt; and a &lt;em&gt;police officer&lt;/em&gt;. As security guards, they were treating with teachers and pupils like &lt;em&gt;things&lt;/em&gt;, as they were protecting the properties, the facilities, rooms, equipment, news, classified documents even people from damage at their schools. Moreover, they were behaving like a police officer at their schools. They were similar to an officer who supervised to perform the rules of the school. They were performing the rules of educational system and were controlling teachers and pupils at their school. Also, the content analysis of job description of schools’ principals is showed schools’ principals were tasked in a closed system. School’s principals must do everything that central office want to. Weakness emerges in the schools because of schools’ principals do not know management and leadership. Schools’ principals who do not know about administration and management and they do not try for learning how can help to teachers and pupils? Although, management and leadership learning is very important; but our schools’ principals perform it to trial and error method. That is very important problem for our educational system. As our recent research shows Iranian schools’ principals urgently need preparation and training, so we should organize a precise program to prepare them. Teaching and learning are often planed for pupils, students and sometimes for teachers, but this rarely discuss that school or university managers and leaders learn about school principal or do they participate in a training sessions? Our schools’ principals are never taught or trained for management and leadership. Despite this fact that there are disciplines of education and educational administration in Iranian higher education institutions, it seems “managers were born manager” here. Learning leadership is dependent on leadership learning. There are several theories about school’s leadership and management and the relationship between theory and practice of management has been confirmed. However, in our schools, schools’ principals were not taught about managing and leading of schools. Therefore, it is essential to redefine the role of the school’s principals, selection criteria and job description, in order to achieve effective educational system. Also, principals and leadership training courses for schools’ principals will be designed and implemented. Based on the findings of this study, it is suggested to change the existing situation of school principal: &quot;School selection conditions&quot; are reviewed and developed by schools’ principals. The duties of school principals are rewritten according to the management literature and educational leadership. In order to empower managers, leadership training and leadership courses will be held in schools. &lt;br /&gt; </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">چکیده&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; در یک دهه گذشته، حرفه گرایی رهبری مدرسه، دستورکار اصلی سیاست گذاری آموزشی شده و توجه به کیفیت مدیران و رهبران مدارس در صدر موضوعات نظام آموزشی قرار گرفته است. با توجه به اهمیت این موضوع، هدف این پژوهش، شناسایی و درک وظایف و فعالیت های مدیران مدارس برای دستیابی به نظام آموزشی اثربخش بود. لذا، برای درک آنچه مدیران مدارس انجام می دهند، این پژوهش به روش کیفی انجام شد. جامعه مورد مطالعه، مدیران مدارس شهر تهران بودند که به روش نمونه گیری نظری انتخاب شدند. ابزار گردآوری داده ها، مشاهده، مصاحبه و مطالعه اسناد مربوطه بود. برای تحلیل داده ها، از روش تحلیل محتوای کیفی استفاده شد. یافته های پژوهش نشان می دهد شرایط انتصاب مدیران مدارس، اهمیت و پیچیدگی مدارس را به عنوان واحد تحلیل منعکس نمی کند و شرح وظیفه، مدیران مدارس را ناظر فعالیت های اعضای مدرسه نه کارگزار تعریف می کند. لذا، ضروری است برای دستیابی به نظام آموزشی اثربخش، مدیر مدرسه، شرایط انتخاب و شرح وظیفه مدیران مدارس بازتعریف شود. همچنین، دوره های مهارت آموزی مدیریت و رهبری برای مدیران مدارس طراحی و برگزار شود. &lt;br /&gt; کلمات کلیدی: آئین نامه انتصاب مدیران مدارس، شرح وظیفه مدیر مدرسه، حرفه گرایی، آموزش مدیریت، مهارت آموزی رهبری</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آئین نامه انتصاب مدیران مدارس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شرح وظیفه مدیر مدرسه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حرفه گرایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آموزش مدیریت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مهارت آموزی رهبری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_60942_3aa9319ac6aee6d2cb3984f3bba32ffb.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>the mediator role of career plateau in relationship between teachers&#039; individual characteristics and organizational laziness among teachers</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رابطۀ بین ویژگی های فردی و تنبلی سازمانی در بین معلمان مدارس ابتدایی: نقش میانجی سکون‏ زدگی شغلی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>40</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>55</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60946</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>غفار</FirstName>
					<LastName>کریمیان پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>باشگاه پژوهشگران جوان و نخبگان، واحد کرمانشاه، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، کرمانشاه، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عادل</FirstName>
					<LastName>زاهد بابلان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، مدیریت آموزشی، گروه علوم تربیتی، دانشکده علوم تربیتی وروانشناسی، دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی، اردبیل، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>خالق خواه</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، فلسفه تعلیم و تربیت، گروه علوم تربیتی، دانشکده علوم تربیتی وروانشناسی، دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی، اردبیل</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضایی شریف</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار ، روانشناسی تربیتی، گروه علوم تربیتی، دانشکده علوم تربیتی وروانشناسی، دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی، اردبیل، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>31</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Social laziness has attracted researchers in recent years. A person can be called lazy, who has no tenderness and enthusiasm for mobility and is fleeing from the dynamism and search. . In fact, laziness is a pain that can affect people in all activities and organizations and has been raised as a challenge in organizations called &quot;Organizational laziness.&quot; Organizational laziness In a simple definition, the laziness of employees in their work is in a collective form and is the result of a lazy group of people working in the organization. Organizations that suffer from organizational laziness are in a situation where, even with the best forces, they are in slippery situatio. One of the factors affecting organizational laziness is job plataeu, which has long been considered and addressed in management literature. The phrase &quot;job plateau&quot; refers to the feeling of failure or disappointment that people experience temporarily or permanently during their career process. Definition of job plateau in two aspects of hierarchy and occupational content. And it is a point in the person&#039;s career path, where the probability of hierarchical upgrading for the individual is very small. And employees reach a point that they are reluctant to attain higher organizational levels. In fact, in terms of these employees, the opportunities for individual growth in the organization are very limited, and they are not looking for higher job titles. It&#039;s not challenging for employees to stay in content, Therefore, they do not have any meaning for competition in business, Duties and occupational activities for ordinary and recurring employees, and usually there is no opportunity to learn and grow in the desired job. Research has shown that occupational stagnation is associated with negative outcomes such as emotional exhaustion and positive emotional exhaustion goals, attitude and reduction of staff performance, depression and stress, and decreased job satisfaction. &lt;br /&gt; One of the factors affecting job plateau, is the individual characteristics of the employees. Individuals are different in many respects due to individual characteristics. In fact, the individual characteristics of the various individuals indicate the strengths and weaknesses of individuals that can be improved some of them during their lifetimes. Individual characteristics include a wide range of characteristics. In this study, according to the interviewed codes, the characteristics of age, sex, work experience, communication skill weakness, lack of disability in class management, problems and illnesses, study rate, beliefs and attitudes Teachers are presented as individual features. Since these features have always had an impact on individual performance, consideration of them as factors affecting organizational laziness can also be important. &lt;br /&gt;One of the most important organizations in every country is education, which has its own special significance. The importance of education is due to the expansion of its functions, which has increasingly placed it at the heart of the community, has attracted particular attention. . Teachers play the most important role in the education system, and they are seen as the starting point for education. With compassionate and educated teachers, society can create a fundamental transformation. On the other hand, organizational laziness is not limited to a specific society and includes all occupational and organizational environments. Although every job has its own stress, But teachers for reasons of low salaries, lack of administrative support, negative attitudes towards jobs, lack of public support, Planning for diverse courses, diverse learners, inadequate income, conflicts with colleagues and managers, and lack of bilateral ties, unfavorable conditions and pressure for promotion, bureaucratic structure, Lack of participation in decision making, management disregard for welfare issues of employees, teaching in multi-level classes, teaching a subject in multiple classes (repetitive work), Values ​​and different cultures of students They are subject to special stresses that can provide a platform for organizational laziness. Because this phenomenon results from laziness of the staff of the organization, which can have long negative consequences in the long run. This phenomenon can happen in the current state of education. Therefore, individual laziness of teachers can lead to the formation of organizational laziness. Research conducted in this area suggests that this negative phenomenon has been neglected among teachers. And identifying the effective factors on it can help relevant authorities to take effective measures to reduce this ominous phenomenon. On the other hand, considering the important and vital role of teachers in the educational system, addressing this phenomenon and studying the factors among teachers in terms of their key role and position is of great importance. Therefore, to cope with it, recognizing the effects, consequences and factors affecting it is of particular importance. &lt;br /&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;The purpose of this study was to investigate the relationship between teachers&#039; individual characteristics and organizational laziness with the mediator role of career plateau. The research method was descriptive and correlated by structural equation method (SEM). The statistical population of this study consisted of all elementary school teachers in Awramanat district, that by Using multistage cluster sampling, according to the Cochran formula, 350 people (222 male and 128 female) were selected. A researcher-made questionnaire was used to collect the data. In order to measure individual characteristics, 10 questions, 6 questions were used to measure career plateau and 5 questions for measuring organizational laziness. The content validity of the questionnaires was approved by the Relevant specialists and Their reliability of them respectively was 0.81 for individual characteristics questionnaire, 0.91 for career plateau questionnaire and 0.95 for organizational laziness questionnaire. Data were analyzed using SPSS (Mean, standard deviation, Pearson correlation coefficient, KMO and Bartlett, slope and elongation) and LISREL softwares. The results of the data analysis showed that the positive and direct effects of individual characteristics on career plateau and the direct effect of career plateau on organizational laziness are significant. Also, the indirect effect of individual characteristics was significant on organizational laziness through career plateau. &lt;br /&gt; Therefore, it can be concluded that individual traits and job stagnation are one of the important variables related to the organizational laziness of teachers, and these two variables should be paid more attention by the authorities and managers of education.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر، پژوهشی توصیفی و از نوع همبستگی بوده که با کمک روش معادلات ساختاری (SEM) انجام شد. جامعه آماری پژوهش شامل تمام معلمان مقطع ابتدایی منطقه اورامانات بود که با استفاده از روش نمونه‌گیری خوشه‌ای چندمرحله‌ای و با توجه به فرمول کوکران، تعداد 350 نفر (222 نفر مرد و 128 نفر زن) به‌عنوان نمونه انتخاب شدند. برای جمع‌آوری داده‏های پژوهش از پرسشنامه محقق ساخته استفاده شد. برای سنجش ویژگی‌های فردی 10 سئوال، برای سنجش سکون‏زدگی شغلی 6 سئوال و برای سنجش تنبلی سازمانی 5 سئوال طراحی شد. روایی محتوایی پرسشنامه‏ها مورد تایید متخصصان مربوطه قرار گرفته و پایایی آن‌ها با استفاده از روش محاسبه آلفای کرونباخ به ترتیب برای ویژگی‌های فردی 81/0، برای پرسشنامه سکون‏زدگی شغلی 91/0 و برای پرسشنامه تنبلی سازمانی 85/0 به دست آمد. داده‏ها با استفاده از نرم‌افزارهایSPSS و روش‌های (میانگین،انحراف استاندارد، ضریب همبستگی پیرسون، کایمو و بارتلت، چولگی و کشیدگی) و نرم‌افزار LISREL تجزیه و تحلیل شدند. نتایج تحلیل داده‏ها نشان داد که اثر مثبت و مستقیم ویژگی‌های فردی بر سکون‏زدگی شغلی و اثر مستقیم سکون‏زدگی شغلی بر تنبلی سازمانی معنی‏دار است. همچنین اثر غیرمستقیم ویژگی‌های فردی از طریق سکون‌زدگی شغلی بر تنبلی سازمانی معنی‏دار بود.&lt;br /&gt;  </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ویژگیهای فردی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سکون‏زدگی شغلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تنبلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معلمان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_60946_1697d42494ccc3fac722c6473954e69e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Evaluation of School Management Excellence Program with Goal free Model</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزشیابی برنامۀ تعالی مدیریت مدرسه برمبنای الگوی هدف آزاد</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>56</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>77</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60940</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شهین</FirstName>
					<LastName>بنی اسد</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت آموزشی، دانشگاه فردوسی، مشهد- ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضوان</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسینقلی زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت آموزشی و توسعۀ منابع انسانی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد- ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مقصود</FirstName>
					<LastName>امین خندقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه برنامه درسی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد- ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this research was to identify the real effects of the school management excellence program in the junior secondary school, to assess the extent to which the objectives of the excellence program are realized. In order to achieve this aim, Scrivens Goal Free Evaluation model was used. The study domains consisted of two girls junior secondary schools in the first and fourth district of Mashhad during the school year 2017. Multiple tools of observation, interviewing, analyzing a documentary, and researcher-made checklist were used for data collection. The process of data analysis was done using the coding process and interpretation. Based on the findings of this research, the actual results of the implementation of the school management excellence program were consisted of the main categories of &quot;extracurricular activities&quot;, &quot;evaluation&quot;, &quot;class management&quot;, &quot;executive activities&quot;, &quot;educational issues&quot; and &quot;educational issues&quot; with considering its positive and negative experiences and by evaluating the checklist resulting from actual results that was found to be in the medium range. Also, the results of the evaluation of the intended goals of the excellence program showed that the first goal of this program, entitled &quot;Contextualization for the promotion of school education qualification&quot; is at the dynamic level of evaluation. This goal was not desirable and other goals were not attained by the level of evaluation of the expected level. In addition, by scoring a checklist, it was determined that the current situation is based on the intended goals at a weak level. Considering that the two checklist of the actual result and intended goals graded with two different spectra.The purpose of this research was to identify the real effects of the school management excellence program in the junior secondary school, to assess the extent to which the objectives of the excellence program are realized. In order to achieve this aim, Scrivens Goal Free Evaluation model was used. The study domains consisted of two girls junior secondary schools in the first and fourth district of Mashhad during the school year 2017. Multiple tools of observation, interviewing, analyzing a documentary, and researcher-made checklist were used for data collection. The process of data analysis was done using the coding process and interpretation. Based on the findings of this research, the actual results of the implementation of the school management excellence program were consisted of the main categories of &quot;extracurricular activities&quot;, &quot;evaluation&quot;, &quot;class management&quot;, &quot;executive activities&quot;, &quot;educational issues&quot; and &quot;educational issues&quot; with considering its positive and negative experiences and by evaluating the checklist resulting from actual results that was found to be in the medium range. Also, the results of the evaluation of the intended goals of the excellence program showed that the first goal of this program, entitled &quot;Contextualization for the promotion of school education qualification&quot; is at the dynamic level of evaluation. This goal was not desirable and other goals were not attained by the level of evaluation of the expected level. In addition, by scoring a checklist, it was determined that the current situation is based on the intended goals at a weak level. Considering that the two checklist of the actual result and intended goals graded with two different spectra.The purpose of this research was to identify the real effects of the school management excellence program in the junior secondary school, to assess the extent to which the objectives of the excellence program are realized. In order to achieve this aim, Scrivens Goal Free Evaluation model was used. The study domains consisted of two girls junior secondary schools in the first and fourth district of Mashhad during the school year 2017. Multiple tools of observation, interviewing, analyzing a documentary, and researcher-made checklist were used for data collection. The process of data analysis was done using the coding process and interpretation. Based on the findings of this research, the actual results of the implementation of the school management excellence program were consisted of the main categories of &quot;extracurricular activities&quot;, &quot;evaluation&quot;, &quot;class management&quot;, &quot;executive activities&quot;, &quot;educational issues&quot; and &quot;educational issues&quot; with considering its positive and negative experiences and by evaluating the checklist resulting from actual results that was found to be in the medium range. Also, the results of the evaluation of the intended goals of the excellence program showed that the first goal of this program, entitled &quot;Contextualization for the promotion of school education qualification&quot; is at the dynamic level of evaluation. This goal was not desirable and other goals were not attained by the level of evaluation of the expected level. In addition, by scoring a checklist, it was determined that the current situation is based on the intended goals at a weak level. Considering that the two checklist of the actual result and intended goals graded with two different spectra.The purpose of this research was to identify the real effects of the school management excellence program in the junior secondary school, to assess the extent to which the objectives of the excellence program are realized. In order to achieve this aim, Scrivens Goal Free Evaluation model was used. The study domains consisted of two girls junior secondary schools in the first and fourth district of Mashhad during the school year 2017. Multiple tools of observation, interviewing, analyzing a documentary, and researcher-made checklist were used for data collection. The process of data analysis was done using the coding process and interpretation. Based on the findings of this research, the actual results of the implementation of the school management excellence program were consisted of the main categories of &quot;extracurricular activities&quot;, &quot;evaluation&quot;, &quot;class management&quot;, &quot;executive activities&quot;, &quot;educational issues&quot; and &quot;educational issues&quot; with considering its positive and negative experiences and by evaluating the checklist resulting from actual results that was found to be in the medium range. Also, the results of the evaluation of the intended goals of the excellence program showed that the first goal of this program, entitled &quot;Contextualization for the promotion of school education qualification&quot; is at the dynamic level of evaluation. This goal was not desirable and other goals were not attained by the level of evaluation of the expected level. In addition, by scoring a checklist, it was determined that the current situation is based on the intended goals at a weak level. Considering that the two checklist of the actual result and intended goals graded with two different spectra.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در پژوهش حاضر از روش ارزشیابی هدف آزاد اسکریون بهره گرفته شد. دو مدرسه دخترانه مقطع متوسطه اول در ناحیه 1 و 4 مشهد در بازه زمانی سال تحصیلی 96-1395 قلمرو این مطالعه را تشکیل دادند. جهت گردآوری داده­های موردنیاز، از ابزار­های چندگانه مشاهده، مصاحبه، تحلیل برنامه تعالی و چک‌لیست محقق ساخته استفاده شد. فرایند تحلیل داده­ها با استفاده از فرایند کدگذاری و به شیوه تفسیری انجام شد. براساس یافته‌های  این پژوهش، نتایج واقعی حاصل از اجرای برنامه تعالی مدیریت آموزشگاهی در شش مقوله اصلی «فعالیت­های فوق‌برنامه»، «ارزشیابی»، «مدیریت کلاس»، «فعالیت­های اجرایی»، «مسائل آموزشی» و «مسائل تربیتی» با نظر به تجارب مثبت و منفی آن مشاهده شد و با ارزش‌گذاری چک‌لیست حاصل از نتایج واقعی مشخص گردید که در طیف متوسط قرار دارد. همچنین، نتایج حاصل از ارزشیابی اهداف قصد شده در برنامه تعالی نشان داد هدف  اول این برنامه با عنوان «زمینه­سازی به منظور ارتقای کیفیت آموزشی و پرورشی مدارس» در سطح ارزشیابی پویا قرار دارد. با این توضیح که این هدف در حد مطلوب و سایر اهداف با قرار گرفتن در سطح ارزشیابی کمتر از حدانتظار، محقق نشدند. علاوه براین با نمره­گذاری چک‌لیست مشخص شد که وضعیت موجود مبتنی بر اهداف قصدشده در سطح ضعیف قرار دارد با نظر به اینکه دو چک‌لیست نتایج واقعی و اهداف قصد­شده با دو طیف­بندی متفاوت نمره­گذاری­ شدند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">برنامه تعالی مدیریت آموزشگاهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جنبش مدارس اثربخش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوی ارزشیابی هدف آزاد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نتایج واقعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اهداف قصدشده</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_60940_f90cf12659287d1e1286db5e6bd60714.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Phenomenological Approach in Identifying Effective Factors in Performance Evaluation of Primary School principals</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی عوامل مؤثر در ارزیابی عملکرد مدیران مدارس ابتدایی با راهبرد پدیدار شناسی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>78</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>99</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60943</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهره</FirstName>
					<LastName>صادقی نیا</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد تحقیقات آموزشی، تهران-ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کیوان</FirstName>
					<LastName>صالحی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکده روان‌شناسی و علوم تربیتی دانشگاه تهران، تهران-ایران.</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8673-4248</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>مقدم زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکده روان‌شناسی و علوم تربیتی دانشگاه تهران، تهران-ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>27</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>One of the most important factors of the sublimity or destruction in any organization is the quality of evaluation system of its Managers performance. If we properly study the mission of the school about of educating the people in the community and recognize its importance, we will find that the lack of effective leadership and management may have irreparable consequences. Progressing and sub limiting is the result of successful performance of the principle and poor performance due to the weakness of the school organization and, ultimately, the weakness of the educational system. Considering that the elementary period plays an important role in the public education process of the country, and given the importance of the principal&#039;s role in achieving the objectives and the advancement of teaching and learning, principles need to have special properties and abilities.Since identification of the basic factors and indicators of the performance evaluation tool for primary school principals can be one of the solutions for improving the professional development of principles, and in order to improve the educational conditions of the schools, to ensure that the educational system have primary school principals with competencies and essential functions of the profession, the researcher decided to do this research. Therefore, the purpose of this study is identifying these effective factors in evaluating the performance of primary school principals.A qualitative and descriptive-phenomenological approach was used to examine the factors and indicators affecting the quality of school principals&#039; performance. The research was done in primary schools of 2nd District of Tehran in the academic year 2017-18. The number and method of selecting participants in qualitative studies, such as quantitative methods, is not predetermined and depends on the process of research and emerging categories. And its size depends on the level of theoretical saturation of the research questions. Therefore, semi-structured interviewing techniques was used, to study of experiences of 15 people(9 managers and 6 teachers) who have been selected as criterion-oriented and as informant, have been deeply examined And their views on the designation of indicators and components of performance evaluation were analyzed. Data were analyzed on basing of seven step strategy. This decision was done to identify new and obvious indicators from the managers&#039; point of view about their performance, which was necessary in their work. In this study, 12 semi-structured deep interviews have been reached to theoretical saturation level and validate the findings in order to perform this analysis, firstly, we read all the descriptions provided by the participant in the study usually called the protocol, in order to gain a sense and to get accustomed to it. Then, in the second step, we refer to each of the protocols and derive sentences and phrases directly related to the phenomenon studied. This stage is known as &quot;extraction of important sentences&quot;. In the third step, we try to understand each of the important sentences, and this stage is known as the (formulation of meanings). In the fourth step, the steps above are for each protocol repeats and formulates meaningful and related meanings in clusters of themes (main themes). In the next step, we combine the results in a comprehensive description of the subject matter. Then, in the sixth stage, we formulate a comprehensive description of the phenomenon under study as a clear statement of the basic structure of the phenomenon under study, often referred to as (The intrinsic structure of the phenomenon), and in the final stage, by referring to each participant and asked them by conducting a single interview or conducting multiple interviews, for final validation of findings. After implementing of interviews and doing depth analysis of data, 120 indicators, 27 criteria and 8 main factors that include &quot;morality and values&quot;, &quot;personality properties&quot;, &quot;role expectations&quot;, &quot;ability and skill&quot;, &quot;knowledge and cognition&quot;, &quot;accounting and financial affairs&quot;, administrative and executive &quot;and&quot; educational affairs &quot;were identified and classified. The results indicate that just having (technical, human, perceptual) skills for management, and especially the management of educational organizations that have their own characteristics and are less visible in other organizations are not enough. The type of organizational relationship and kind of clientele, dealing with teachers, the existence of various stakeholders (parents, students, teachers, etc.) and many other special features have led to the management of schools with their own special features and skills. The first and most important factor identified from the viewpoint of teachers and ethical values ​​managers was mentioned. Justice and fairness, commitment and accountability, appreciation, and trust are some of the characteristics that affect the performance of the manager in terms of the participants. in this research, tried to identify and introduce all effective factors in a semi-structured interview with the managers and teachers of the elementary schools in view of the various biases and factors affecting the performance of managers, and ultimately, A total and comprehensive framework for evaluating the performance of executives can be ensured through the use and consideration of these factors, which are the first and most important step in the selection and assignment of important school leadership responsibilities, in their qualifications. Evaluation based on scientific research with considering important and influential indicators can lead to evaluation in its main direction, namely, increasing individual capabilities and efficiency, developing managerial skills and, consequently, increasing school efficiency and ultimately the success of guidance students. Since in evaluating the performance of managers, neglected the factors identified in the current research and in managers&#039; evaluation forms individuals with these characteristics have not been allocated a score. Therefore in fundamental revision in this case and consider scores to these factors, can be useful in influencing performance evaluation. It seems that the use of these factors can provide a suitable basis for accurate and fair assessment of the performance of primary school principals and can improve their performance and the quality of schools and the growth and prosperity of the country as it seems to be contributing to Improving the performance of managers, schools are driving more towards their mission, which is the achievement of a knowledgeable society. &lt;br /&gt;  &lt;br /&gt; </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">از مهم‌ترین عوامل تعالی یا تباهی هر سازمانی، کیفیت نظام ارزشیابی عملکرد مدیران آن است. پژوهش حاضر با هدف شناسایی عوامل مؤثر در ارزیابی عملکرد مدیران مدارس ابتدایی انجام‌شده است. به منظور واکاوی عمیق و شناسایی عوامل و نشانگرهای اثرگذار بر کیفیت عملکرد مدیران مدارس، از رویکرد کیفی و به شیوه پدیدارشناسی از نوع توصیفی استفاده شد. تلاش شد تا با استفاده از فن مصاحبه عمیق نیمه ساختار‌یافته، ادراک و تجربه‌زیسته 15 نفر (9 مدیر و 6 معلم) که به‌صورت ملاک محور و به‌عنوان اطلاع‌رسان انتخاب شدند، مورد بررسی عمیق قرار گیرد. داده‌ها مبتنی بر راهبرد کُلایزی تحلیل گردید؛ پس از پیاده‌سازی مصاحبه‌ها و تحلیل عمیق داده‌ها، 120نشانگر، 27 ملاک و 8 عامل اصلی که شامل &quot;اخلاق و ارزش‌ها&quot;، &quot;ویژگی‌های شخصیتی&quot;، &quot;انتظارات نقش&quot;، &quot;توانایی و مهارت‌&quot;، &quot;دانش و شناخت&quot;، &quot;امور حسابداری و مالی&quot;، &quot;امور اجرایی و اداری&quot; و &quot; امور تربیتی&quot;، شناسایی و طبقه‌بندی گردید. از آنجاکه در ارزیابی عملکرد مدیران به این عوامل توجهی نگردیده و در فرم‌های ارزشیابی مدیران به افراد دارای این ویژگی‌ها امتیازی اختصاص نیافته است، در صورت تجدیدنظر اساسی در این زمینه و در نظر گرفتن امتیاز به این عوامل می‌تواند در تأثیرگذاری ارزیابی عملکرد مفید واقع شود. به‌نظر می‌رسد، استفاده از این عوامل بتواند زمینه مناسب برای ارزیابی دقیق و منصفانه از عملکرد مدیران مدارس ابتدایی را فراهم نماید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">"ارزیابی عملکرد"</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">"مدارس ابتدایی"</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">"پدیدار شناسی"</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">"عوامل موثر"</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">&amp;quot;مدیران مدارس&amp;quot;</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_60943_7702ab55bb5e42678fd8ca0fb5c626b3.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Managing Green School:  Introduction to Paradigm of Association of Primary Schools and Local Parks</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مدیریت مدارس سبز: الگوی همنشینی دبستان ها و بوستان ها</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>100</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>122</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60833</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آزاده</FirstName>
					<LastName>خاکی قصر</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه معماری، دانشکده معماری و شهرسازی، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی،تهران،ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The quality and size of school yards are so important While there are some primary schools which have small yards. In other hand, there are some local parks which are empty during weak day in academic year. It seems if in allocation process of schools and local parks, association of them would be considered the decision will optimize both of them. Research method is descriptive-analytical through studies. &lt;br /&gt; The physical model through systems theory are based on five alternatives: near model, connected model, far model, unit model and intersection model. By analysis, three of them are acceptable: near, connected and jointed models&lt;br /&gt; The paradigm is useful in three positions: to land allocation of both primary school and local parks, schools’ relation to existing local parks and local parks’ relation to existing primary schools.&lt;br /&gt; The important condition of approach to Paradigm of Association of Primary Schools and Local Parks is to save frontage of primary schools not to unsuitable intercourse by local parks. also the usage of local parks by people mustn’t be confused.&lt;br /&gt; in result in urban planning scale, there are some usage in neighbor of schools which must be changed. in design scale, saving origins in nature is base for both architectures and landscape designers. making potentials to understand during play is very useful in design of open spaces of primary schools. In other hand landscape designers should support social sustainability in neiberhood by effective presence of old in local parks who can help the children in primary schools.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">کیفیت و اندازه فضای باز دبستان ها مهم است، اما تعداد قابل توجهی از دبستان ها در ایران حیاط کوچکی دارند. از سوی دیگر تعدادی از بوستان های محله ای در روزهای کاری هفته در سال تحصیلی، مخاطبان کمی دارند. لذا تامین مناسبتر فضای باز دبستان ها و استفاده بهینه از بوستان های محلی برای هم افزایی توامان مورد سوال است. روش تحقیق از باب هدف، کاربردی و از لحاظ ماهیت و روش، توصیفی-تحلیلی بر مبنای مطالعات کتابخانه ای است. در تحقیق حاضر، همنشینی دبستان ها و بوستان ها الگویی است که بر اساس قواعد و مدلهای همنشینی با اولویت متصل، مرتبط و دارای فصل مشترک برای موقعیتهای متنوع در سه قسم برنامه ریزی مکانیابی دبستانها و بوستانها کاربرد دارد: مکانیابی توامان مجموعه دبستان و بوستان، مکانیابی دبستانها در مجاورت بوستانهای موجود و مکانیابی بوستانها در مجاورت دبستانهای موجود. از قاعده های تقرب به همنشینی مناسب، حفظ حریم دبستانها و عدم مختل نمودن فعالیت بوستان هاست. موانعی برای تحقق الگوی همنشینی وجود دارد و آفت هایی نیز در همنشینی نامناسب نهفته است که در متن آمده است. از نتایج تحقیق حاضر، در مقیاس برنامه ریزی، مطالعه برای تغییر کاربری برخی از فضاهای مجاور دبستانها به سمت بوستانها و مکانیابی برخی زمینها در مجاورت بوستانها برای دبستان است. در مقیاس طراحی، اتخاذ رویکرد مناسب در نزد معماران و طراحان منظر بر مبنای حفظ اصالت طبیعت و ایجاد قابلیت در فضای باز برای توسعه فهمیدن دانش آموزان از یک سو و از سوی دیگر امکان حضور موثر مردم محله به خصوص افراد سالمند در بوستانهای محلی می باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدرسه سبز</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دبستان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بوستان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مکان یابی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوی همنشینی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بسط فضای باز</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_60833_156b7e8f27be85b542ec2cbe75027294.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The relationship between Spirituality in Workplace with Organizational Health and principals Organizational Commitment of the High Schools  of Ahvaz</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>معنویت در محیط کار و رابطۀ آن با تعهد سازمانی و سلامت سازمانی مدیران مدارس متوسطۀ دوم شهر اهواز</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>123</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>142</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60955</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حجت الله</FirstName>
					<LastName>درفش</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه علوم تربیتی دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، خوزستان، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرجان</FirstName>
					<LastName>گلشن پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد علوم تربیتی دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز،خوزستان،ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Abstract&lt;br /&gt; The aim of this study was aware of The relationship between Workplace Spirituality with Organizational Health and Organizational Commitment of the High School Administrators of Ahwaz Educational administrate. The method of study was descriptive-correlation. The population were all High School Administrators of second term of Ahwaz Education in the second semester of the academic year 2017-2018 that using simple random sampling 155 person were selected. The data gathering tool were questionnaires of spirituality in the workplace of Milimin (2003), Organizational commitment of Allen and Meyer (1996) and School Organizational Health of Hoy and Feldman (1987). Data were analyzed using statistical tests pearson correlation coefficient and multiple regression analysis. The results showed that between Workplace Spirituality with Organizational Commitment and Organizational Health there was simple and multiple correlation of positive and significant (P&lt; 0/01). Also Multiple regression analysis with stepwise method showed that of between predictor variables the components of meaningful work and alignment with the organizations values to have predictive power of Organizational Commitment, so that 0/52 of the total variance of Organizational Commitment was explained by this components. Also from between predictor variables, only components of alignment with the organizations values to have predictive power of Organizational Health, so that 0/31 of the total variance of Organizational Health was explained by this component.&lt;br /&gt; Abstract&lt;br /&gt; The aim of this study was aware of The relationship between Workplace Spirituality with Organizational Health and Organizational Commitment of the High School Administrators of Ahwaz Educational administrate. The method of study was descriptive-correlation. The population were all High School Administrators of second term of Ahwaz Education in the second semester of the academic year 2017-2018 that using simple random sampling 155 person were selected. The data gathering tool were questionnaires of spirituality in the workplace of Milimin (2003), Organizational commitment of Allen and Meyer (1996) and School Organizational Health of Hoy and Feldman (1987). Data were analyzed using statistical tests pearson correlation coefficient and multiple regression analysis. The results showed that between Workplace Spirituality with Organizational Commitment and Organizational Health there was simple and multiple correlation of positive and significant (P&lt; 0/01). Also Multiple regression analysis with stepwise method showed that of between predictor variables the components of meaningful work and alignment with the organizations values to have predictive power of Organizational Commitment, so that 0/52 of the total variance of Organizational Commitment was explained by this components. Also from between predictor variables, only components of alignment with the organizations values to have predictive power of Organizational Health, so that 0/31 of the total variance of Organizational Health was explained by this component.&lt;br /&gt; Abstract&lt;br /&gt; The aim of this study was aware of The relationship between Workplace Spirituality with Organizational Health and Organizational Commitment of the High School Administrators of Ahwaz Educational administrate. The method of study was descriptive-correlation. The population were all High School Administrators of second term of Ahwaz Education in the second semester of the academic year 2017-2018 that using simple random sampling 155 person were selected. The data gathering tool were questionnaires of spirituality in the workplace of Milimin (2003), Organizational commitment of Allen and Meyer (1996) and School Organizational Health of Hoy and Feldman (1987). Data were analyzed using statistical tests pearson correlation coefficient and multiple regression analysis. The results showed that between Workplace Spirituality with Organizational Commitment and Organizational Health there was simple and multiple correlation of positive and significant (P&lt; 0/01). Also Multiple regression analysis with stepwise method showed that of between predictor variables the components of meaningful work and alignment with the organizations values to have predictive power of Organizational Commitment, so that 0/52 of the total variance of Organizational Commitment was explained by this components. Also from between predictor variables, only components of alignment with the organizations values to have predictive power of Organizational Health, so that 0/31 of the total variance of Organizational Health was explained by this component.&lt;br /&gt; Abstract&lt;br /&gt; The aim of this study was aware of The relationship between Workplace Spirituality with Organizational Health and Organizational Commitment of the High School Administrators of Ahwaz Educational administrate. The method of study was descriptive-correlation. The population were all High School Administrators of second term of Ahwaz Education in the second semester of the academic year 2017-2018 that using simple random sampling 155 person were selected. The data gathering tool were questionnaires of spirituality in the workplace of Milimin (2003), Organizational commitment of Allen and Meyer (1996) and School Organizational Health of Hoy and Feldman (1987). Data were analyzed using statistical tests pearson correlation coefficient and multiple regression analysis. The results showed that between Workplace Spirituality with Organizational Commitment and Organizational Health there was simple and multiple correlation of positive and significant (P&lt; 0/01). Also Multiple regression analysis with stepwise method showed that of between predictor variables the components of meaningful work and alignment with the organizations values to have predictive power of Organizational Commitment, so that 0/52 of the total variance of Organizational Commitment was explained by this components. Also from between predictor variables, only components of alignment with the organizations values to have predictive power of Organizational Health, so that 0/31 of the total variance of Organizational Health was explained by this component.&lt;br /&gt; Abstract&lt;br /&gt; The aim of this study was aware of The relationship between Workplace Spirituality with Organizational Health and Organizational Commitment of the High School Administrators of Ahwaz Educational administrate. The method of study was descriptive-correlation. The population were all High School Administrators of second term of Ahwaz Education in the second semester of the academic year 2017-2018 that using simple random sampling 155 person were selected. The data gathering tool were questionnaires of spirituality in the workplace of Milimin (2003), Organizational commitment of Allen and Meyer (1996) and School Organizational Health of Hoy and Feldman (1987). Data were analyzed using statistical tests pearson correlation coefficient and multiple regression analysis. &lt;br /&gt; Abstract&lt;br /&gt; The aim of this study was aware of The relationship between Workplace Spirituality with Organizational Health and Organizational Commitment of the High School Administrators of Ahwaz Educational administrate. The method of study was descriptive-correlation. The population were all High School Administrators of second term of Ahwaz Education in the second semester of the academic year 2017-2018 that using simple random sampling 155 person were selected.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">چکیده&lt;br /&gt; هدف پژوهش حاضر، بررسی رابطه بین معنویت در محیط کار با تعهد سازمانی و سلامت سازمانی مدیران مدارس متوسطه دوم آموزش‌وپرورش شهرستان اهواز بود. روش پژوهش توصیفی و از نوع همبستگی بود. جامعه‌ آماری پژوهش شامل کلیه مدیران مدارس متوسطه دوم آموزش‌وپرورش شهرستان اهواز در سال تحصیلی 97-1396 بود که با استفاده از روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی ساده 140 نفر به‌عنوان نمونه پژوهش انتخاب شدند. ابزار گردآوری داده‌ها، پرسشنامه‌های معنویت در محیط کار میلیمن و همکاران (Milliman et al, 2003)، تعهد سازمانی آلن و می‌یر (Meyer &amp; Allen, 1996) و سلامت سازمانی مدرسه هوی و فیلدمن (Hoy &amp; Feldman, 1987)بود. داده‌ها با استفاده از آزمون‌های آماری ضریب همبستگی پیرسون و تحلیل رگرسیون چندگانه تحلیل شدند. نتایج نشان داد که بین معنویت در محیط کار با تعهد سازمانی و سلامت سازمانی همبستگی ساده و چندگانۀ مثبت و معنی‌دار وجود داشت (01/0 &gt;P). همچنین نتایج تحلیل رگرسیون با روش مرحله‌ای نشان داد که از بین مؤلفه‌های معنویت در محیط کار، (کار معنادار و همسویی با ارزش‌های سازمان) توان پیش‌بینی تعهد سازمانی را داشتند، به‌طوری‌که 52/0 از واریانس تعهد سازمانی مدیران توسط این مؤلفه‌ها قابل تبیین بود. همچنین از بین مؤلفه‌های متغیر پیش‌بین (معنویت در محیط کار) فقط ‌ همسویی با ارزش‌های سازمان توان پیش‌بینی سلامت سازمانی را داشت، به‌طوری‌که 31/0 از واریانس سلامت سازمانی مدیران توسط این مؤلفه قابل تبیین بود.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; کلیدواژه‌ها: معنویت در محیط کار، تعهد سازمانی، سلامت سازمانی، مدیران مدارس، آموزش‌وپرورش</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معنویت در محیط کار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تعهد سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سلامت سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیران مدارس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آموزش و پرورش</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_60955_b6ac6fd70816af351263b9abed3c0672.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The relationship between spiritual intelligence and organizational excellence with the mediating role of organizational trust among principals</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>نقش میانجی اعتماد سازمانی مدیران مدارس در رابطه بین هوش معنوی و تعالی سازمانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>143</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>162</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60967</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید حمیدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>شاوران</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت آموزشی، دانشکده علوم تربیتی و روانشناسی، دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجتبی</FirstName>
					<LastName>طاهری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت آموزشی، دانشگاه شهید چمران، اهواز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حامد</FirstName>
					<LastName>براتیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت آموزشی، دانشکده علوم تربیتی و روانشناسی، دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Due to the world&#039;s remarkable changes and today&#039;s social needs, the excellence and quality of education in the educational organization is undeniable. So, the school principals have to strive to achieve it. Excellence means organizational commitment to sustainable development, participation in customer satisfaction, and continuous increase of profitability of the organization in a comprehensive and supportive national environment for achieving total quality. Applying total quality management to organizations requires managers and staff who have the potential to move towards transcendental goals and also have an appropriate level of intelligence. One of the important types of intelligence in humans is spiritual intelligence. Spiritual intelligence is an instrument that integrates the external aspects of intelligence with the inner aspects of spirituality and creates an extraordinary capacity in person to use spirituality in an applied way. However, the individual efforts are not sufficient by themselves to optimize the organization&#039;s work, especially at schools, which requires teamwork. To organize their teams, the principals must be able to strengthen the cooperation and create a spirit of trust. There are mutual expectations in social relations, but the structure of unequal power against the subordinate usually causes distrust. The school principals need to create a climate of trust and benevolence among teachers, students and parents so that the effective and efficient education in Schools will be achieved. Therefore, the purpose of this study was to investigate the relationship between spiritual intelligence and organizational excellence with the mediating role of organizational trust among the high school principals in Isfahan. In this context, the paper also examines the research model underlying the variables of the study. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Research method: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;A descriptive-correlation research method was utilized. The statistical population included all 222 principals of high and secondary schools in 2015-2016 academic years. The sample size (128 participants) was selected based on Krejcie &amp; Morgan (1970) table through multiplecluster random sampling. The research instruments included: King (2008) spiritual intelligence questionnaire with four dimentions of critical existential thinking, personal meaning production, transcendental awareness, conscious state expansion,Bruce (2008) organizational excellence and Sztompka (2002) organizational trust respectively. Their face and content validity was confirmed by a number of respondents and five experts in educational administration area. The reliability of the tools was calculated through Cronbach&#039;s alpha coefficient of 0.93, 0.81 and 0.88 for Bruce&#039;s Spiritual Intelligence Questionnaire (2008), King&#039;s Excellence Questionnaire (2008), and Ztompka&#039;s Organizational Trust Inventory (2002). To analysis the data’s SEM, correlation coefficient and regression were utilized. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Findings:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Data analysis was performed using statistical methods of structural equation model, regression analysis and Pearson correlation coefficient. The findings revealed a positive and significant relationship generally between spiritual intelligence, organizational trust and organizational excellence. Also, among the components of spiritual intelligence of principals, only transcendental awareness predicted organizational excellence. Moreover, the finding showed a significant relationship between organizational trust and organizational excellence, and the obtained data fits the presented model through direct and indirect effects (p≤0/05, t≥1/96). The results of the coefficients of direct effects of variables on each other show that spiritual intelligence with the effect coefficient of 0.22 and 0.75 directly affects organizational excellence and organizational trust. Also, organizational trust with the coefficient of 0.35 directly affects organizational excellence. The indirect effect of spiritual intelligence on organizational excellence is significant and the role of mediator of organizational trust is confirmed. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Spirituality makes life meaningful as long as rational behaviors and trust in others are flourished based on the mutual respect and equality. Therefore, it is possible to say that principals who have high spiritual intelligence at school may lead to the formation of a sense of trust and a healthy and logical environment in the organization, using the rational existence in order to thought awareness about the nature of the realities, the purpose and the reason for schools’ existence, and lead people in a conscious and purposeful way for its excellence. So, it can be concluded that relying on creating group relationships and using the spiritual intelligence of principals in its development can increase the sense of trust and also the sense of responsibility of individuals to the work and organizational tasks. This process follows by the principal&#039;s efforts in achieving the goals of the school and, consequently, the pursuit of excellence and the growth of the organization. School principals can focus on the excellence of the organization and the concept of quality through the demonstration of the usage of the spiritual intelligence capacity in understanding the meanings of collaboration, participation and collective work, and establishing group communication in its portfolio. Spiritual intelligence strengthens the basis of individual beliefs and influences its performance and school principals who have enough of it, in their beliefs, relationships and behaviors enhance the aspects that affect the level of organizational trust and strengthen them. &lt;br /&gt;According to the findings of the main hypothesis and the research model as well as the relationship between spiritual intelligence of principals and organizational excellence and trust, the practitioners, policy makers and senior administrators in educational organization are suggested: &lt;br /&gt;- Hold workshops on customer-orientation, organizational decision making, goal-recognition and organizational ethics for school principals and other staff. &lt;br /&gt;- School principals, while establishing meaningful relationships in schools, especially with teachers, should strengthen the competencies of teachers and promote their critical thinking in different ways, such as holding creativity and self-awareness courses. They can explain the nature of the reality of education, the purpose and reason of its existence, and the responsibility of different people to excel in the education system. &lt;br /&gt;- Finally, it is suggested that, while emphasizing the discussion and gathering sessions for the principals and staff of the organization, hold workshops on job skills training, human relationships, teamwork and participation, in order to increase the organizational trust and the organization will be on the path of excellence. Also, by strengthening the parents and teachers’ community, connecting with cultural and social institutions as well as student councils, the interactions and relationships between the organization, school staff, students, parents ae well as related social and cultural institutions will be flourished with the goal of education excellence. In brief, the organizations should focus on training principals, by understanding the complexities of the environment and establishing friendly rational relationships in schools especially with teachers, strive to strengthen their competencies and promote their critical thinking.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">روش پژوهش حاضر توصیفی- همبستگی و جامعه آماری شامل کلیه مدیران مدارس متوسطه اول و دوم شهر اصفهان در سال تحصیلی 95-1394 و تعداد آن‌ها ۲۲۲ نفر بود. حجم نمونه بر اساس جدول (Krejcie &amp; Morgan, 1970) برابر با ۱۲۸ نفر برآورد شد که به روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی خوشه‌ای چندمرحله‌ای انتخاب شدند. ابزارهای اندازه‌گیری شامل پرسشنامه‌های هوش معنوی King, 2008))، استاندارد تعالی سازمانی (Bruce, 2008) و اعتماد سازمانی (Sztompka, 2002) بود که روایی صوری آن‌ها توسط تعدادی از پاسخ‌دهندگان و روایی محتوایی آن‌ها به‌وسیله پنج نفر از متخصصان و اساتید مدیریت آموزشی مورد تأیید قرار گرفت. پایایی ابزارها نیز از طریق ضریب آلفای کرونباخ به ترتیب ۹۳/۰، برای پرسشنامه هوش معنوی، ۸۱/۰ برای پرسشنامه تعالی سازمانی و ۸۸/۰ برای پرسشنامه اعتماد سازمانی محاسبه گردید. تجزیه‌وتحلیل داده‌ها با استفاده از روش‌های آماری مدل معادلات ساختاری، تحلیل رگرسیون و ضریب همبستگی پیرسون انجام شد. نتایج نشان داد اعتماد سازمانی مدیران نقش میانجی مثبت و معناداری بین هوش معنوی با تعالی سازمانی مدارس دوره متوسطه شهر اصفهان دارد. همچنین از میان مؤلفه‌های هوش معنوی مدیران تنها آگاهی متعالی تعالی سازمانی را پیش‌بینی می‌نمود. بین اعتماد سازمانی مدیران با تعالی سازمانی مدارس نیز همبستگی مثبت و معناداری مشاهده شد و مدل پژوهش از برازش مناسبی برخوردار بود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هوش معنوی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اعتماد سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تعالی سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیران مدارس متوسطه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_60967_43858b26ac11e7fde50aa9be9959d6d1.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The causal model of relationship Between the Components of Authentic Leadership Style and Positive  Excitements of Teaching: Mediating Role of Psychological Capital</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رابطۀ مؤلفه های سبک رهبری اصیل مدیران مدارس با هیجان های مثبت تدریس معلمان: نقش میانجی سرمایۀ روان شناختی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>163</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>185</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60944</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>رستگار</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه علوم تربیتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>صیف</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، گروه علوم تربیتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>علی محمدی معدنویی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد آموزش و بهسازی منابع انسانی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>27</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Abstract&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; The purpose of this study was to the effect of authentic leadership style on Positive Excitements of Teaching with mediating role of psychological capital in the High Secondary School Teachers of in Shiraz Province, The research method is descriptive survey and the population of this study included 345 teachers of high secondary school teachers in Shiraz has been selected by using the cluster multistage sampling and they responded to Authentic Leadership Questionnaire of Olive and Gardner (2005) , Psychological Capital Questionnaire of Luthans , Olive and Avi (2007) and excitements of teaching questionnaire of Frinzl (2010). Obtained data of sample were analyzed by using the statistical software LISREL and by path analysis. In whole , results showed that perception dimensions of authentic leadership has a direct and positive effect on psychological capital . In addition, psychological capital has a direct , positive and meaningful effect on positive teaching excitements . According to the findings, consciousness, ethical-oriented , processing balance and relational transparent through the mediating role of optimism , self-efficacy , hope and resilience has a indirect and meaningful effect on the positive teaching excitements.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Keywords : Perception of Authentic Leadership ; Psychological Capital ; Positive Teaching Excitements .</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر با روش روش تحقیق توصیفی و از نوع همبستگی انجام یافته  است. جامعه آماری این تحقیق شامل 345 نفر از معلمان مقطع متوسطه دوم شهر شیراز است که با استفاده از روش نمونه گیری خوشه­ای چند مرحله­ای انتخاب و به پرسشنامه رهبری اصیل آوولیو و گاردنر (2005)، پرسشنامه سرمایه روان شناختی لوتانز، آوولیو و آوی (2007) و پرسشنامه هیجانات تدریس فرینزل (2014) پاسخ دادند. داده­های به دست آمده از نمونه با استفاده از نرم افزار آماری LISREL و به روش تحلیل مسیر مورد تحلیل قرار گرفت. نتایج پژوهش به شکل کلی نشان داد که ابعاد ادراک از رهبری اصیل دارای اثر مستقیم و مثبت بر سرمایه­های روان شناختی هستند. به علاوه، سرمایه­های روان شناختی بر هیجان­های مثبت تدریس دارای اثر مستقیم، مثبت و معنادار بودند. مطابق با یافته­ها، خودآگاهی، اخلاق مداری، پردازش متوازن و شفافیت رابطه ای از طریق نقش واسطه خوش بینی، خودکارآمدی، امیدواری و تاب آوری بر هیجان­های مثبت تدریس دارای اثر غیرمستقیم و معنادار بودند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رهبری اصیل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه روان‌شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هیجان‌های مثبت تدریس</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_60944_f3095dc3398f99b826a66d68fb78f82b.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Relationship between job Involvement with Organizational Learning and Organizational Innovation among Public School Principals</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رابطه بین درگیری شغلی با یادگیری سازمانی و نوآوری سازمانی مدیران مدارس</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>186</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>203</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60947</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>منصور</FirstName>
					<LastName>دهقان منشادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیأت علمی دانشگاه فرهنگیان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>31</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The aim of this study was to determine the relationship between job involvement with organizational learning and organizational innovation among public school principals in Meybod city. This was a quantitative paradigm and a descriptive correlation study. The population of the study included all 151 school principals in Meybod city in the academic year of 2016-17. 108 people were selected by stratified random sampling. The modified standard questionnaire of job involvement, organizational learning and organizational innovation questionnaires were used. The face and content validity of the questionnaires was confirmed in a pilot study by a number of principals. Reliability of the questionnaires calculated according to Cronbach&#039;s alpha for job involvement, organizational learning and organizational innovation questionnaires was respectively 0.89, 0.87 and 0.86. Data analysis took place in two levels of descriptive and inferential statistic contain Pearson correlation coefficient and simple linear regression. Findings showed that the relationship between job involvement with organizational learning and organizational innovation variables was significant at r= 0.33, r= 0.38 respectively. The main variable of research (job involvement) has the ability to predict organizational learning and organizational innovation. It is suggested that job involvement promotion programs are run to enhance principals active participation in the work. It will help increase the effectiveness of the organization with changes in their attitude and will lead to organizational learning and innovation of principals.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر با روش توصیفی و از نوع همبستگی انجام گردید. جامعه­ی آماری شامل کلیه مدیران مدارس دوره‌های تحصیلی شهرستان میبد در سال تحصیلی 96-95 به تعداد 151 نفر بوده که با استفاده از جدول نمونه­گیری کرجسی و مورگان (1971) حجم نمونه‌ معادل 108 نفر تعیین گردید که با روش تصادفی طبقه‌ای متناسب با حجم، نمونه­گیری شدند. ابزار مورد سنجش پرسش­نامه درگیری شغلی (Lodahl &amp; Kejnar, 1965)  ، یادگیری سازمانی (Neefe, 2001) و نوآوری سازمانی (Ettlie &amp; Okeefe, 1982) بود. روایی صوری و محتوایی پرسش­نامه­ها در یک اجرای مقدماتی توسط تعدادی از مدیران مورد تأیید قرار گرفت. پایایی پرسش­نامه­ها بر حسب ضریب آلفای کرونباخ برای پرسش نامه درگیری شغلی 89/0، یادگیری سازمانی 87/0 و نوآوری سازمانی 86/0 برآورد گردید. تحلیل داده­ها در دو سطح آمار توصیفی و استنباطی شامل آزمون ضریب همبستگی پیرسون، رگرسیون خطی ساده و تحلیل واریانس چند راهه صورت گرفت. یافته­ها نشان داد که رابطه هر یک از متغیرهای یادگیری سازمانی و نوآوری سازمانی با درگیری شغلی رابطه­­ای معنادار است. متغیر اصلی پژوهش (درگیری شغلی) توان پیش­بینی یادگیری سازمانی و نوآوری سازمانی را دارد.&lt;br /&gt;  </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">درگیری شغلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیران مدارس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوآوری سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">یادگیری سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_60947_4104105d637b0bc990eab31222855be0.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Presenting a model of Empowering primary school managers</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارائه مدلی برای توانمندسازی مدیران مدارس ابتدایی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>204</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>223</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60950</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی اصفهان(خوراسگان)</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محبوبه سادات</FirstName>
					<LastName>فدوی</LastName>
<Affiliation>مدیر گروه مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی اصفهان(خوراسگان)</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>هادی</FirstName>
					<LastName>فرهادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>مدیر گروه روان شناسی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی اصفهان(خوراسگان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>27</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study has been done with the aims of providing the model of Empowering primary school managers in the country.The statistical community comprised all independent primary school managers with the number of 30900.The statistical sample was chosen randomly on the basis of a clustering method during a number of stages with the proportionate number of 336. The main instrument for this phase was a structured questionnaire made in the first comparative phase of the stud. Face validity of the questionnaire was ensured by a number of respondents and the content validity on the basis of 15 practitioners&#039; viewpoints of experts in educational management. The reliability of the instrument was calculated by distributing the questionnaire and the calculation of Cronbach&#039;s alpha coefficient (0.921). Data analysis was performed by using SPSS18 and LISREL 8.8 based on exploratory statistic analysis methods, structural equations, factor loadings and identifying variances. This model is based on five approaches obtained by, sequentially, managerial-technical (0.98), (meta)motivational ( 0.97 ), personal and spiritual abilities ( 0.96 ), psychological-meta cognitive (0.95) and structural communicative ( 0.94 )dimensions. In this model,five approaches and 15 components were identified as the most important component of Empowering primary school managers. Therefore, regarding the results, also supported by previous research, and along with the available theories, it could be concluded that the suggested model enjoys theoretical and empirical validity and adequacy. This model can be used as a local, comparative model in the regions of the country.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این پژوهش کاربردی و روش آن توصیفی از نوع زمینه‌یابی است. جامعه آماری آن را کلیه مدیران مستقل مدارس ابتدایی کشور به تعداد (30900) نفر تشکیل می‌دهند. نمونه آماری به شیوه‌ی نمونه‌گیری خوشه‌ای، طی چند مرحله به تعداد 336 نفر به‌صورت تصادفی متناسب با حجم انتخاب شدند. ابزار اصلی مورداستفاده در این پژوهش، پرسشنامه‌ی محقق ساخته‌ای بوده که بر اساس نتایج یک مطالعه تطبیقی تهیه‌شده بود. روایی صوری توسط تعدادی از پاسخ‌دهندگان و روایی محتوایی بر اساس نظرات پانزده نفر از متخصصان مدیریت آموزشی انجام گرفت. پایایی این ابزار با پیش توزیع پرسشنامه و محاسبه ضریب آلفای کرون باخ به میزان (0.921) محاسبه شد. تحلیل آماری داده‌ها مبتنی بر روش‌های تحلیل عاملی (اکتشافی و تأییدی)، معادلات ساختاری، محاسبه بار عاملی‌ها و تبیین واریانس‌ها انجام شد، الگوی ارائه‌شده در پنج رویکرد با بار عاملی‌های به‌دست‌آمده به ترتیب مدیریتی-تکنیکی، انگیزشی-فوق انگیزشی، توانمندی‌های شخصی و معنوی ، شناختی- فراشناختی و ساختاری-ارتباطی تدوین گردید. در این الگو 5 رویکرد و 15 مؤلفه به‌عنوان مهم‌ترین مؤلفه‌های توانمندسازی مدیران مدارس ابتدایی شناسایی شدند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توانمندسازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیران مدارس ابتدایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کیفیت‌بخشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مؤلفه‌های توانمندسازی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_60950_eeb1ccec85b9c037197ff775f8e25953.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>How teachers and school administrators of Kurdistan province perceive teachers&#039; well-fare</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>چگونگی ادراک معلمان و مدیران مدارس استان کردستان از رفاه معلم</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>224</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>242</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60969</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>صلاح الدین</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت آموزشی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نعمت اله</FirstName>
					<LastName>عزیزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه علوم تربیتی، دانشکده ی علوم انسانی و اجتماعی، دانشگاه کردستان، سنندح- ایران.</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8637-397X</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>خلیل</FirstName>
					<LastName>غلامی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه دکتری مدیریت آموزشی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پریوش</FirstName>
					<LastName>جعفری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت آموزشی دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه علوم و تحقیقات تهران. ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study aims to investigate teachers&#039; perception of their own welfare, identifying its affecting factors and suggesting mechanisms to improve teachers&#039; welfare. As a an exploratory mixed method research both qualitative (grounded theory and quantitative (survey and correlational study) were applied simultaneously. Participants for qualitative study composed of 12 teachers in Sannadaj who were selected purposefully using theoretical sampling. Moreover, using cluster sampling 416 teachers were selected for the survey study. In order to collect data, deep interview and questionnaire were applied. &lt;br /&gt; The qualitative findings showed that from the participants view point welfare is a comprehensive concept and has material and mental dimensions which can be influenced by political (state policy), social (values, attitude), economic (quantitative and cost attitude), organizational (management and process), individual (teachers&#039; role), professional (professional identity) factors. The qualitative findings also revealed that teachers welfare can be improved through comprehensive social efforts, teachers own will and efforts, recognizing and supporting teachers professional association.&lt;br /&gt; Quantitative findings showed a significant relation between teachers’ gender and material and mental welfare (t = 0.498). Additionally, positive relationship between teachers’ level of education and their perception of welfare was confirmed (t = 2.55). salary and incomes are among the most important welfare indicators. Furthermore, teachers have pointed out that the teachers’ welfare can be improved by creating a quality mechanism in education.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر در حوزه تحقیقات کیفی و با بهره­گیری از روش نظره­ی برخواسته از داده­ها انجام شد. مشارکت کنندگان این پژوهش، 12 نفر از معلمان و 10 نفر از مدیران بودند که با استفاده از روش نمونه گیری هدفمند و با تاکید بر رویکرد اشباع نظری، انتخاب گردیدند. گردآوری داده ها با استفاده از مصاحبه های نیمه ساختارمند به عمل آمد. داده های پژوهش با استفاده از راهبردهای کدگذاری، در سه سطح کدگذاری باز، محوری و گزینشی مورد تحلیل قرار گرفتند. نتایج کدگذاری‌های چندگانه و تحلیل محتوای مصاحبه‌ها نشان داد که اولاً رفاه از نگاه مشارکت‌کنندگان یک مفهوم جامع و دارای ابعاد مادی و روانی می‌باشد؛ ثانیاً این مقوله متأثر از عوامل گوناگونی نظیر سیاسی، اجتماعی، اقتصادی، عوامل سازمانی مانند مدیریت، فرایندها و اقدامات اداری، نقش مدیر مدرسه به عنوان رهبر آموزشی، عوامل فردی مانند نقش خود معلمان و ویژگی‌های شخصیتی آن‌ها، و همچنین صفات شخسیتی مدیران مدارس،(مهارت انسانی مدیران)،  عوامل حرفه‌ای مانند هویت شغلی و پرستیژ حرفه‌ای بر رفاه معلمان می‌باشد.  </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفاه معلمان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل رفاه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ادراک از رفاه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عوامل موثر بر رفاه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_60969_646da89fc7b76c9c4a091baf0e2b6df6.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identify the entrepreneurial teacher&#039;s mentality about factors related to the promotion of entrepreneurship culture in schools</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی ذهنیت معلمان کارآفرین نسبت به عوامل مرتبط با ترویج فرهنگ کارآفرینی در مدارس</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>243</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>263</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60968</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شادی</FirstName>
					<LastName>شاکری سیه کمری</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت آموزشی- گروه علوم تربیتی- دانشگاه شهید مدنی آذربایجان- تبریز- ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پیمان</FirstName>
					<LastName>یارمحمدزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکده علوم تربیتی و روانشناسی دانشگاه شهید مدنی آذربایجان ، تبریز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهبود</FirstName>
					<LastName>یاریقلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکده علوم تربیتی و روانشناسی دانشگاه شهید مدنی آذربایجان ، تبریز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present research seeks to answer the following questions: what factors affect the promotion of entrepreneurial culture in second high schools of Tabriz City? What is the entrepreneurial mentality about the factors creating entrepreneurial culture? And what is the significance of each of them? In this regard, the Q-methodology (a mixed-methods of qualitative-quantitative approaches) and exploratory research method were employed; first, to prepare Q items, participants were selected from among the teachers from the second high schools or entrepreneurs who somehow were connected with the schools. It was tried that interviews be conducted with participants who have different and practical ideas and mentalities about the entrepreneurial culture in schools. Reviewing theoretical literature; conducting interviews with eleven entrepreneurs, experts and experts; reviewing bulletins and school publications; and reviewing the documents, films, cartoons, paintings and essays related to the subject, were used to compile Q items. The number of the participants depended on the saturation of Q items. In this research, after the 9th interview, the saturation of Q items were obtained, and the interviews of the tenth and eleventh were also conducted to ensure the validity of the items. Then, in order to sort the Q for second high school teachers in active entrepreneurship in Tabriz, their number was estimated to be around 260 individuals, from among whom 152 individuals were selected via the purposive sampling method. by entrepreneur teachers, this research means those who have been educated in entrepreneurship, teach entrepreneurship, have completed entrepreneurial courses, created new businesses, selected as entrepreneurs, patented their own patents, or worked in knowledge-based companies. In the implementation of the research, the initial data on the participants (entrepreneur teachers) were obtained and recorded. Data such as age, gender, years of service, field of study and education. In response to this question, what are the factors affecting the promotion of entrepreneurship culture in secondary schools in the second theoretical part of Tabriz city?, it should be clarified that 65 factors derived from the evaluation of the discourse space of the research were obtained as follows: assignment-oriented assessment, parent-sponsored partnership with students, launch of the weekend start-up competition in schools, student participation in solving school problems, offering apprenticeships for students in the field of study, team-building training in schools, having a library of new business books, prioritizing funding for research activities in schools, creating centers for growth in schools, familiarizing students with important organizations and institutions of the country such as the labor office, the autonomy and independence of schools in attracting, employing, rewarding and making decisions, school interaction with the social, economic, production and service environment, giving freedom to act in the content of learning and autonomy of students, teaching managers, experts, teachers and students to change and development, the formation of a number of education and entrepreneurship experts for designing systematic schools programs, attractive and creative physical atmosphere of the school, emphasizing educational content on self-esteem, creativity and innovation, the fitting of educational content to the needs of the students day, paying attention to the individual differences of students in the teaching process, crating think tanks in schools, organizing school-based school malls, identifying entrepreneurship opportunities in schools, identifying the threats of entrepreneurship in schools, providing incentive mechanisms for teachers and students, promoting scholarly and exploratory camps in schools, from school ownership, identifying drawbacks and failures of schools with the help of students, offering entrepreneurship courses in all disciplines, providing workshops for students&#039; parents to institutionalize entrepreneurial beliefs, valuing different creativity and thought, students’ freedom in selecting disciplines, private sector support from schools, providing entrepreneurship units at cultural universities, using documentaries, holding exhibitions, festivals, and publishing journals of entrepreneurship in schools, introducing and using different curriculum resources, designing entrepreneurship training courses in high schools, flexibility in schools-inspired rules, research-based propositions, creative and pragmatic curriculum, informing students about out-of-school opportunities, familiarizing students with labor market problems in their city, using active teaching models, using cyberspace and the presentation of teachers&#039; and school staff proposals to promote entrepreneurship, emphasizing the student problem solving process in the teaching process, development and advancement of human resources, recruitment of job and career entrepreneur counselors, the increased risk-taking opportunities for teachers and students, the participation of students in the teaching process Providing student self-taught classes, teaching brain training, developing case studies about successful businesses, emphasizing the self-assessment of managers, teachers and students, using day-training technology, E-learning and web-based learning, accountability and responsibility in schools, participatory management, continuous improvement and continuation of educational content, increasing the collective spirit of managers, teachers and students, emphasizing the quality of teaching, learning methods, teaching-learning activities and processes, monitoring and continuous evaluation of school activities, promoting teamwork culture and networking in schools, paying attention to entrepreneurs&#039; teachers in the promotion and ranking of teachers, increasing facilities and resources available to teachers and students, providing diverse and stimulating entertainment for students, paying attention to personal differences in evaluation of flexible and dynamic structure of schools. After the participants were asked to prioritize Q cards, which were composed of statements, on a scale of -5 to +5, according to their research and beliefs and their current feelings. The subject of the research and the question was prepared in writing with all the conditions, as well as a summary of the stages of the work, and was made available to the contributor. The interval cards with numbers from -5 to +5 on them were arranged on a table for the participants who sort them based on the significance of the items inserted on the Q cards. To create validity in the research, Q items were submitted to a number of expert professors and participants to be reviewed. After collecting their comments and removing ambiguities about statements, Q options were finalized. In order to determine the reliability of the Cronbach&#039;s alpha coefficient, the SPSS statistical software calculated it as 0.89, indicating that the Q sort has the required reliability and reliability. According to research findings, eight different perspectives on the promotion of entrepreneurial culture in schools were obtained. These views indicate that the promotion of entrepreneurial culture in schools is affected by factors such as the creation of entrepreneurial infrastructure, development of practical training, improvement of school resources and facilities, empowerment of human actors, teacher-centered management, acceptance of differences, communication with society and industry, and creative education and curriculum.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در پژوهش حاضر از روش‌شناسی آمیخته کیو استفاده شد. ابتدا از رویکرد کیفی و سپس رویکرد کمی با اجرای کارت‌ها، برای گردآوری داده‌ها بهره گرفته شد. مرحله نخست، با مرور ادبیات موضوع و مراجعه به منابع مختلف و با 11 نفر از نخبگان کارآفرین مطلع مصاحبه انجام شد؛ سپس فضای گفتمان جمع‌بندی و ارزیابی شد، در مرحله بعد 65 گزاره برای نمونه کیو انتخاب شدند و دسته کیو ایجاد شد؛ بعد از انتخاب مشارکت‌کنندگان که شامل معلمان کارآفرین شهرستان تبریز که حدوداً تعداد 260 نفر بود، مرتب‌سازی گزاره‌ها توسط 152 نفر که به شکل نمونه هدفمند انتخاب شدند، آغاز شد و پس از ثبت داده‌ها، تحلیل آماری داده‌ها با استفاده از نرم‌افزار آماری Spss به روش تحلیل عاملی کیو انجام گردید. طبق یافته‌های پژوهش در نهایت 8 دیدگاه مختلف در خصوص ترویج فرهنگ کارآفرینی در مدارس، به دست آمد. این دیدگاهها حاکی از آن است که ترویج فرهنگ کارآفرینی در مدارس به ترتیب تحت تأثیر عواملی از قبیل ایجاد زیرساخت‌های کارآفرینی، توسعه آموزش‌های کاربردی، بهبود منابع و امکانات مدارس، توانمندسازی کنشگران انسانی، مدیریت مدرسه‌محور، پذیرش تفاوت‌ها، ارتباط با جامعه و صنعت، آموزش و برنامه درسی خلاق، قرار دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارآفرینی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرهنگ کارآفرینی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدارس متوسطه دوره دوم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش‌شناسی کیو</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_60968_e534e71e26c024994eda0d6dadcca13a.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Pathology of Administrators performance evaluation system: The results of Qualitative research</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>آسیب شناسی نظام ارزشیابی عملکرد مدیران مدارس: پژوهشی کیفی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>264</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>284</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60827</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>سرچهانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری مدیریت آموزشی، مدرس دانشگاه فرهنگیان فارس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رحیم</FirstName>
					<LastName>زارع</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیروس</FirstName>
					<LastName>قنبری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکده علوم تربیتی دانشگاه همدان، همدان،ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>قلتاش</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه علوم تربیتی، واحد مرودشت، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>   Performance evaluation in facilitating organizational effectiveness is considered as an important task of human resource management, through evaluation, deficiencies and staffing weaknesses, and is addressed through guidance and training to address them. Since school leadership and management are often recognized as a key element in raising the quality of school activities, assessment of the performance of school principals is very important and should be of the highest quality (Branch et al, 2009). Performance evaluation in facilitating organizational effectiveness important tasks of human resource management is seen, in recent years the role of performance evaluation much attention has been paid, according to experts, an effective system of performance evaluation can be a huge advantage for organizations and their employees grant (Abdollahi &amp; Raisi, 2018). Performance evaluation has led to strengthening working groups, active participation in the activities of the organization and the right people, motivate employees to perform better activities, improving communication within the organization and the successful achievement of the objectives (Capko, 2003). Professional assessment and timely feedback enable managers to be aware of their strengths and weaknesses, to recognize the organization&#039;s values and develop leadership (Bedford, 2013). An assessment of the performance of the staff shows that the employee has performed the tasks assigned to him according to the job description. Through evaluation, the inadequacies and weaknesses of the service are identified and handled and directed to eliminate them (Sobhani Fard et al., 2011). With all the scientific and rational importance for staff evaluation, unfortunately today, in schools and educational institutions, like other devices, it has become a ceremonial act that is being addressed with the least care and importance, and this It has caused employee dissatisfaction. In addition to the above, it is worth noting that despite the importance of school management and leadership in improving educational processes, education and achievements of students, assessment of the performance of school principals has been a minor focus on research. This study aimed to evaluate the performance of school principals’ pathology system with qualitative approach was used. Potential participants consisted of primary and secondary schools of the city with a history of more than ten years of management. In order to select the participants of theoretical sampling was used in a purposeful way, the aim of the researcher was to select the items that were rich in information according to the purpose of the research. Data were collected using semi-structured interviews and analyzed by content analysis method. The time for each interview was between 40 and 50 minutes. After 16 interviews, data saturation was achieved, in order to further ensure two complementary interviews. Validity and reliability were checked and verified by using feedback loops and re-interviewing. The main questions of the research were: 1- Do school administrators consider the current system of performance evaluation appropriate? 2. What is the most important damage caused by the performance evaluation system of school administrators? To answer the above questions, the data were collected by semi-structured interviews. After the implementation of the interviews, the content was analyzed by means of content analysis method. Then, based on similarity, conceptual relationship, common characteristics between the codes and the integration of the cases that were overlapping, classification was made and, finally, four main categories 27 sub-categories were extracted in two main axes: 1. Problems and failures of the performance appraisal system and 2. Damage caused by performance evaluation system. Data analysis showed that school principals were dissatisfied with their performance evaluation system and major Problems and failures caused by inappropriate evaluation practices These justification meetings before the evaluation and signing of the evaluation contract, the failure to carry out a continuous evaluation, the lack of evaluators, the presentation of formal documents, the special conditions governing the managerial environment, the inappropriate feedback at the end of the course, the absence of a meeting, the end of the course, Inappropriate monitoring of the evaluation process, unrealistic self-assessment) and developed indicators (lack of attention to ethical behavior and the spread of spirituality in the home, lack of creativity and innovation, insufficient research culture, insufficient attention to school and community relationships , Ignoring, managing information technology) know, On the damage caused by the performance evaluation system administrators extracted concepts and categories of interviews, including two major ones affected individual (the obvious lack of strengths and weaknesses, job performance poor, burnout, lower satisfaction and employee engagement, reduce motivation and Change Post, lack of development of personal and professional) and organizational (create stillness in the process of teaching and learning, low productivity, growing distrust and ability to create a system of punishment and reward efficient ability to identify employees are hard workers, growing organizational silence, Organizational injustice, organizational growth, organizational divorce). The results from judging or valuing human factors in the evaluations of an organization can be a place for managers and policymakers to stop using the results obtained to refine and improve the performance appraisal system of their organization. Regarding the results of the study, it is suggested that instead of performance evaluation, the term &quot;performance management&quot; should be used, because performance management is a strategic and comprehensive process that provides the organization with a sustained success through performance improvement, while positively evaluating the performance Often faced with a negative reaction from employees, indicating the importance of addressing Improve the performance of employees by management as a basic duty. A slight shift towards a performance evaluation process in favor of participatory qualitative approaches is another useful tool, which involves stakeholder participation in all stages of the management of the performance from setting goals to providing end-to-end process feedback and describing qualitative descriptions of employee performance. Describe any decision to promote, maintain or retrain. Suggestions based on research findings &lt;br /&gt;• Review and review the indexes developed to evaluate the performance of school principals by provincial and ministerial experts in the field of performance evaluation &lt;br /&gt;• Briefing sessions organized by experts from education departments with school principals before signing a Performance Evaluation Form &lt;br /&gt;• Continuous assessment of the performance of school principals and providing corrective feedback &lt;br /&gt;• Selection of committed, competent and dominant individuals on the indicators and evaluation methods for continuous and final assessment of the performance of school principals and continuous monitoring of the departments on the process of assessing the performance of school principals. &lt;br /&gt;• Conduct a reflection session with managers after an annual evaluation of their performance in order to examine the strengths and weaknesses of the managers&#039; performance and review the whole process of assessing the performance of school principals.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر با رویکرد کیفی انجام گرفت. مشارکت کنندگان بالقوۀ پژوهش مدیران مدارس دوره های ابتدایی و متوسطه شهر شیراز با سابقه مدیریت بیش از ده سال بودند. بمنظور انتخاب مشارکت کنندگان از نمونه گیری نظری به شیوه هدفمند استفاده شد، داده ها با استفاده از مصاحبه نیمه ساختار یافته با 16 نفر از  مدیران جمع آوری و به شیوه تحلیل محتوا مورد تجزیه و تحلیل قرار گرفت. روایی و پایایی با استفاده از حلقه های باز خورد و انجام مصاحبه مجدد توسط پژوهشگر همکار بررسی و مورد تایید قرار گرفت. تجزیه و تحلیل اطلاعات نشان داد مدیران مدارس از نظام ارزیابی عملکرد خویش ناراضی بوده و عمده مشکلات و نارسایی ها را ناشی از شیوه ارزیابی نامناسب و شاخص های تدوین شده می دانند، که این موضوع خود باعث به وجود آمدن مسائلی از قبیل ایجاد نفاق و بدبینی سازمانی، بهره وری پایین، ایجاد سکون در فرایند یاددهی و یادگیری، رشد بی عدالتی و بی اعتمادی سازمانی، کاهش انگیزه و تغییر پست، فرسودگی شغلی و.... می شود که در دو مقوله آسیب های فردی و سازمانی طبقه بندی گردید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزیابی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیران مدارس</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_60827_11ecce7dec6119567f47cc2ba8c90457.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Phenomenological Study of Financial Empowerment from the Point of View of School Managers</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی پدیدار‌شناسانه توانمندسازی مالی از دیدگاه مدیران مدارس</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>285</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>304</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60970</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رقیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>فاضل</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت آموزشی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سمیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>ابراهیمی کوشک مهدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت آموزشی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>آهنچیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study aimed to investigate the phenomenological lived experience of financial empowerment through deep-interviews with school principals used the phenomenological method. Participants in this study were 10 principals from different district of Mashhad were selected with Purposive sampling. Participants were selected due to managerial work experience from a variety of schools and regions.&lt;br /&gt; The analysis of results was done with interpretation analysis through Strauss and Corbin coding.&lt;br /&gt; The findings were in three categories: concept of financial empowerment from the viewpoint of principals, principals feel about the school&#039;s financial management and stimulus of financial empowerment from the viewpoint of principals. Also, the stimulus of financial empowerment was in three categories related to the individual characteristics, organizational supports, and institutional- social macro relationships. We can summarize that financial empowerment of school administrators concerns is not a within organization concern and is not in micro level in educational system. For organizing this important issue, should be established broader volition in policymaking level.&lt;br /&gt; We can summarize that financial empowerment of school administrators concerns is not a within organization concern and is not in micro level in educational system. For organizing this important issue, should be established broader volition in policymaking level.&lt;br /&gt; should be established broader volition in policymaking level.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این مطالعه با هدف بررسی پدیدارشناسانه تجربه زیسته مدیران مدارس از توانمندسازی مالی با استفاده از مصاحبه عمیق با روش پدیدارشناسی انجام شد. مشارکت‌کنندگان در این پژوهش ده نفر از مدیران مدارس نواحی مختلف شهر مشهد بودند که به صورت هدفمند با توجه به سابقه کار مدیریتی از انواع مدارس و نواحی، در مصاحبه شرکت کردند.&lt;br /&gt; تحلیل یافته‌ها به صورت تحلیل تفسیری و با کدگذاری به روش اشتراس و کوربین انجام شد. &lt;br /&gt; یافته‌های حاصل از این مطالعه در سه دسته مفهوم توانمندسازی مالی از نظر مدیران، احساس مدیران نسبت به مدیریت مالی در مدرسه و محرک‌های توانمندسازی مالی از نظر مدیران بیان شده است. همچنین محرک‌های توانمندسازی مالی در سه دسته توانمندسازی ناظر به ویژگی‌های فردی، توانمندسازی ناظر به حمایت‌های سازمانی و توانمندسازی ناظر به روابط کلان نهادی- اجتماعی جای گرفتند. در نتیجه این مطالعه به‌طور خلاصه می‌توان گفت دغدغه توانمندسازی مالی مدیران مدارس، دغدغه‌ای درون سازمانی و خرد نبوده و برای سامان دادن به این مسئله مهم، عزمی گسترده‌تر در سطح سیاستگذاری‌ها باید ایجاد شود.&lt;br /&gt; در نتیجه این مطالعه به‌طور خلاصه می‌توان گفت دغدغه توانمندسازی مالی مدیران مدارس، دغدغه‌ای درون سازمانی و خرد نبوده و برای سامان دادن به این مسئله مهم، عزمی گسترده‌تر در سطح سیاستگذاری‌ها باید ایجاد شود.&lt;br /&gt; در نتیجه این مطالعه به‌طور خلاصه می‌توان گفت دغدغه توانمندسازی مالی مدیران مدارس، دغدغه‌ای درون سازمانی و خرد نبوده و برای سامان دادن به این مسئله مهم، عزمی گسترده‌تر در سطح سیاستگذاری‌ها باید ایجاد شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توانمندسازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توانمندسازی مدیران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت مالی مدرسه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_60970_f922d6c10b7735fddee76f4da2af2f3d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Caring Leadership of School Principals: A qualitative study</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رهبری مراقبتی مدیران مدارس: پژوهشی کیفی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>305</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>324</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60957</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>نظری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت آموزشی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد سنندج، سنندج، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رفیق</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسنی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه علوم تربیتی، واحد سنندج، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، سنندج، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ناصر</FirstName>
					<LastName>شیربگی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه کردستان، سنندج، ایران.</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8770-4227</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The realization of school goals and, consequently, the realization of the goals of the education system require special attention to school principals and, in particular, their leadership role.Lambert (2006) believes that a successful leader can be a factor in making positive changes in the success of the students, teachers and school he leads.Some of these goals include general development and the well-being of others, meeting the special needs of individuals, and developing the capacity of care between themselves and others (Lewis, Murphy and Smilley, 2016).Weyl (1951) takes care as consideration for others And he understands, senses and acts in the interests of others.The common denominator of these researchers is that care is part of the relationships that emerge through activity and engagement.Care is something that occurs with the carer and is taken care of by the person being cared for. Therefore, leadership can be used as a school environment that suggests the need for the discipline of school management is based on the principles of care (Start, 1997).Carter (2012) argues that a school-based care principle that emphasizes respectful and trustworthy relationships as well as academic discipline will increase student participation, social and emotional competence, progress and academic success, and reduce their expulsion.School care communities focus on teaching and leadership, organizational structures, and promoting school culture based on the principle of care, emphasizing relationships based on features such as civility, care for others, friendship, respect and trust. . . Rely on (Lehmann, 2000).Nadings (2005) suggests three types of care under the heading of aesthetic care and reliable and careful care in the field of education.In this research, we have tried to develop and present a model of native and relevant culture and education system of the leadership of the school principals.&lt;br /&gt; Therefore, the main objectives of the present research are to identify the main components of the caring leadership of high school principals and provide a native model of caring leadership among high school principals.&lt;br /&gt; Research methodology&lt;br /&gt; Since the main objective of the research is to identify the main components of the leadership of the school principals and provide a native model of the leadership of the school principals,the qualitative research approach and the methodology of the data theory of the foundation have been used in this research.This is a developmental goal in terms of purpose. The process of implementation of the research is that firstly, the components of the leadership of the school principals were developed, then the school leadership model was designed for school administrators.The two main stages of the process of this study were identifying the leadership indicators of Sanandaj middle school principals and providing a model for caring leadership among Sanandaj high school principals.In the first part of the study, based on theoretical and research bases and the use of purposeful sampling and semi-structured interviews with the number of 25 high school principals and teachers, the primary indicators of the leadership of the school administrators were identified.To analyze andthe analysis of the data extracted from the interviews was done using qualitative data analysis (qualitative content analysis and coding process).&lt;br /&gt; Findings&lt;br /&gt; Regarding the analysis of the results of the interviews and the responses of the contributors to the causal conditions in this research, which influences the main category (leadership of high school administrators), includes the category of goals, vision and mission of the school, the characteristicsEthical and professional managers, environmental, family and economic conditions of students and teachers, philanthropy, empathy, motivation and dynamics of the school community, the support of senior executives of the organization, commitment and responsibility, and the mission of the teacher.&lt;br /&gt; The central phenomenon of the proposed model is the leadership of the school principals, which includes three main categories and 11 sub-categories that are: Objectives (prevention and protection, involvement of the school community, creating a safe and uplifting environment). Characteristics (personality and professional characteristics,Relationships based on justice and goodness, encouragement, supportive and supportive (implementation practices (care measures, ethical model, use of communication skills, trust and mutual understanding. (Subjective conditions include the educational needs, the social and emotional needs of individuals, the daily care activities of managers and teachers, the acceptance and welcoming and support of families and the intimate relationship between the parents and the school, the philosophy of religious education, religious beliefs and beliefs of individuals, the existenceThe document is the fundamental transformation of education, the personal and human characteristics of the director and co-workers.&lt;br /&gt; Four categories of influence on the political, social and religious issues of the local community, the allocation of financial and material resources and equipment for schools, an effective training program for teachers and school partners, the welfare and livelihood of school administrators and teachers.&lt;br /&gt; The proposed model strategies include modeling the fundamental values of care for the school community, identifying the mechanisms of participation and effective communication, based on justice and goodwill in the school community, developing insight into the school community, creating a nurturing, safe and vibrant environment. At the school, adopting effective leadership and implementing organizational behavior based on trust and mutual understanding in school, developing educational goals and teaching content tailored to the needs of students and diversity of the local community, creating a decentralized management structure of the educational system, managing communication processesinside and out of school.&lt;br /&gt; The implications of caring leadership for school principals can be related to students&#039; academic achievement, social and emotional learning, the institutionalization of care culture, prevention and protection, increased sense of belonging and participation, increased social status of teachers and managers. In this way, school administrators will be able to better carry out their duties and responsibilities, and provide a boost to their school, if they achieve a caretaker leadership.&lt;br /&gt; Discussion and conclusion&lt;br /&gt; According to the results of the coding of documents and interviews, after reviewing the experts, the components of the leadership of the school principals in the six main categories of causative conditions, the pivotal phenomenon, the leadership strategies of managers, the mediating conditions, the conditions of intervention, and the consequences of the leadership of the managers of the compilationAnd presented</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از انجام این پژوهش شناسایی مؤلفه‌های رهبری مراقبتی به‌منظور ارائۀ الگوی رهبری مراقبتی مدیران مدارس بوده است. رویکرد پژوهش کیفی و از روش نظریۀ برخاسته از داده‌ها (طرح سامانمند) در این پژوهش استفاده‌شده است. جامعۀ آماری شامل تمامی مدیران مدارس دورۀ متوسطۀ سنندج بوده است. برای گردآوری داده‌های کیفی با ۲۵ نفراز مدیران مجرب مدارس مصاحبه صورت پذیرفت. در این پژوهش، از روش نمونه‌گیری هدفمند برای انتخاب نفر اول و از فن گلوله برفی برای انتخاب نفرات بعدی استفاده شد. روش نمونه‌گیری به‌صورت هدفمند تا جایی ادامه یافت که پژوهشگر با استفاده از مصاحبۀ نیمه ساختاریافته با ۲۵ نفر از اعضای نمونه به اشباع نظری رسید.با استفاده از نتایج حاصل از بررسی مبانی نظری و پیشینۀ پژوهش و تجزیه‌وتحلیل محتوای مصاحبه‌های انجام‌گرفته، شاخص‌های اولیۀ رهبری مراقبتی مدیران مدارس شناسایی‌شده و طی سه مرحلۀ کدگذاری باز،کدگذاری محوری و کدگذاری انتخابی، مدل رهبری مراقبتی مدیران مدارس در شش مقولۀ اصلی شرایط علی،پدیدۀ محوری (رهبری مراقبتی مدیران مدارس)، راهبردهای رهبری مراقبتی مدیران، شرایط واسطه‌ای، شرایط مداخله‌گر و پیامدهای رهبری مراقبتی مدیران تدوین و ارائه‌شده است.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; با انجام این پژوهش، شاخص‌های رهبری مراقبتی مدیران مدارس شناسایی‌شده و الگوی رهبری مراقبتی مدیران مدارس طراحی می‌شود. بنابراین الگوی قابل‌اعتمادی را از رهبری مراقبتی مدیران مدارس دورۀ متوسطه ارائه خواهد کرد تا مدیران و برنامه ریزان آموزش‌وپرورش بتوانند در جهت بهبود وضعیت موجود از آن استفاده نمایند&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; کلیدواژگان: رهبری مراقبتی، مدیران مدار، دورۀ متوسطه</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رهبری مراقبتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیران مدارس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رهبری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل کیفی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_60957_f3b495860532e544faf4208bcf26ef96.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
