<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The role of Organizational Culture at Adoption of Management Excellence Plan among Education Principals</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>نقش فرهنگ سازمانی در پذیرش طرح تعالی مدیریت در میان مدیران مدارس</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>41</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>59</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60978</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهاره</FirstName>
					<LastName>عزیزی نژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشگاه پیام نور ارومیه- ارومیه-ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ابراهیم</FirstName>
					<LastName>ملکوتی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشگاه پیام نور ارومیه- ارومیه-ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract> The research’s method is applied and it has descriptive-correlational method. The statistical population comprises all of the schools’ principals in district 1 and 2 of Urmia City, counting 143 individuals that 104 pricipals were selected in accordance with Cochran Formula and using random stratified sampling proportional to volume. The required data were collected using 2 questionnaires of Organizational Culture and Management Excellence Plan. The validity of questionnaires were approved using content analysis. The reliability of questionnaires were determined as follow: 0.91 and 0.88. The data was analyzed in 2 levels which are descriptive and inferential (Pearson’s coefficient of correlation and step by step regression). The main results showed that there is a meaningful and positive relationship between organizational culture and its four components (Consensus, Rational, Hierachical, and Ideological culture) with Management Excellence Plan. The variable of organizational culture has the ability to predict the variance of the variable of acceptance of the Management Excellence Plan. Among the components of organizational culture, the ideological culture has the biggest share. Finally in line of resuts, applied suggestions have been presented.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">روش پژوهش ازنظر هدف، کاربردی و به لحاظ شیوه تحلیل از نوع توصیفی- همبستگی است. جامعه­ آماری مشتمل بر مدیران مدارس آموزش‌وپرورش ناحیه 1 و 2  ارومیه به تعداد 143 نفر بود که از میان آن‌ها 104 نفر با فرمول کوکران و به شیوه­ تصادفی طبقه‌ای متناسب با حجم به‌عنوان نمونه آماری انتخاب شدند. ابزار تحقیق شامل دو پرسشنامه فرهنگ‌سازمانی و پذیرش طرح تعالی مدیریت بود که روایی آن‌ها به روش محتوایی مورد تائید قرار گرفت و پایایی آن‌ها به ترتیب، 91/0 و 88/0 تعیین گردید؛ داده‌ها در سطوح توصیفی و استنباطی (ضریب همبستگی پیرسون و رگرسیون گام‌به‌گام) تحلیل شدند. اهم نتایج حاصله نشان داد که بین فرهنگ‌سازمانی و مؤلفه‌های آن (توافقی، عقلایی، سلسله مراتبی و ایدئولوژیک) با پذیرش طرح تعالی مدیریت رابطه مثبت و معنی­دار وجود دارد. متغیر فرهنگ‌سازمانی از توان پیش­بینی واریانس متغیر پذیرش طرح تعالی مدیریت برخوردار است و از بین مؤلفه‌های فرهنگ‌سازمانی، فرهنگ ایدئولوژیک بیشترین سهم را بر عهده دارد. در پایان پیشنهادهای کاربردی در راستای نتایج به‌دست‌آمده ارائه‌شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرهنگ سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ابعاد فرهنگ سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پذیرش طرح تعالی مدیریت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدارس دوره ابتدایی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_60978_139c8e4b214ee547deb2181eb66edea4.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
