<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The study of the relationship between leadership styles  school principals with organizational skills of time management</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی رابطۀ بین سبک‌های رهبری مدیران مدارس با مهارت‌های سازمانی مدیریت زمان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>18</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60945</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>اصغری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی آموخته کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه کاشان، کاشان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>یزدخواستی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، دانشکده علوم انسانی ، دانشگاه کاشان ،کاشان ، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید احمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>مدنی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکده علوم انسانی ، دانشگاه کاشان ،کاشان ، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>04</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Optimal allocation of organizational resources such as capital, human, information and time resource is one of the prerequisite the efficient management of educational organizations. In addition, time management controls interruptions, identifies lost time, recognizes and adjusts the limits and subsequently increases the efficiency of the works. Time management plays as an important role in the effective leadership of educational organizations, including schools and educational sections. School management is a complex activity which requires attention to the various issues and problems. The manager is responsible for supervising all the teachers and staff. He or she should follow the right instructions to guide the staff for the efficient educations. Efficient managing of the times makes it possible to create the opportunity for success and development. This study focused on the examination of time management and leadership styles of the school principals. Since the main pillar of the society development is the expert human resources, education and training is also the main pillar of human resource educations. Desired leadership results in relative satisfaction of the teacher and subsequently increases the efficiency of education. On the other hand, education plays an important role in training of future generation. One of the important tasks of each leader is his decision methods that the available time plays an important role in the decisions of the leader. In fact, it is the decision method determines his leadership styles. If the manager don’t manage his time properly he will be forced to make hasty decisions, which in most cases, due to lack of time, cannot use the advises of others. This may lead the leader to an autocratic leadership (Arami, 2006). Undoubtedly, if time is not used efficiently and people do not know its influences, they can never have a desired outcome. If people do not have control over their time and do not set their task properly, they will never be succeed. Time management control lags, identify the main waste of time, set limits and maximize the efficiency practically. In education, time is scarce, which is rarely planned for optimal use and is often inadequate to perform tasks. While the use of time influences all of school activities and the project managers does not predict use their time efficiently, they always lead to a shortage of time in their work and teachers and resulted in displeasuring the subordinates. Teacher for teaching, student for doing his/her tasks and family for helping students deal with time. Skill of time management consists of individual time management and organization time management. Organizational skill of time management is dedicated only to people who manage an organization which means applying the skills of a manager in the optimal use of time and direction for achieving goals in the organization and in relation to their duties. Also, the organizational and administrative environment of the manager is the environment which this kind of skill is used. Time management organization skills include six components: targeting, prioritizing, operational planning, delegation, communication management, and meeting management. Fault of managers working with the available times causes stress into them and subsequently waste time, and making stress of chief, which results in reducing the efficiency and effectiveness of the organization. Therefore, considering the key role of managers in the development of an organization, as well as the country, it is very important to pay attention to this issue. The director of the school is considered as the manager of an educational organization, with relationships to many people (students, teachers, teachers, etc.), should be responsible for answering to the senior managers in education and for the implementation of school affairs. Since school teachers may be in higher scientific level than school management, leadership may be difficult for school leadership, which may influence the school performances at the right time. This problem is more pronounced in populated schools. School administrators or administrators should have the ability to lead beside the management and the time can also play a role in determining leadership style. Considering the importance of this subject and the organizational benefits of time management skills, the main objective of this study is to examine the status of time management and leadership style and the relationship between them in school principals so that all managers, both educational and executive, can take advantage of their results. &lt;br /&gt;Research Method: The research type was descriptive-correlational. The statistical population consisted of all male and female male and female primary school students, first and second middle schools of Amol city. A sample of 132 school administrators was selected randomly. The hypotheses of this research were analyzed by one-sample t-test, independent t-test, analysis of variance, Spearman correlation test. Data collection tools were two organizational time management skills questionnaires with six components (targeting, prioritizing goals and activities, planning of operations, delegation of authority, communication management, management of meetings) and with a reliability coefficient (83/0) based on the Likert scale of 5 points (I highly agree I strongly disagree) and the standard LBDQ leadership style questionnaire in two dimensions of orbital and orbital duties in terms of four components (libertarian leadership, government leadership, integrated leadership and unbridled leadership) with a coefficient of reliability (76/0) and a five-level spectrum Likert (never, rarely, sometimes, often and always). To determine the validity, the content and formal review method was used. &lt;br /&gt;Findings: The results showed that there is a relationship between the components of leadership style and the organizational skills of time management. Only the authoritative and authoritative leadership styles have a significant relationship with organizational skills of time management, which this relationship is efficient to free leadership style and negative time management and to the style of leadership and organizational skills of time management. The findings also showed that the liberal style of leadership, his organizational performance in time management will decrease and the forced managing style resulted in better time management. The average of time management skill in the forced management style was also higher than other styles. In addition, the status of organizational skills of AMOL school administrators is in a favorable situation.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف این تحقیق بررسی رابطه بین سبک رهبری با مهارت‌های سازمانی مدیریت زمان مدیران مقطع ابتدایی، متوسطه اول و دوم مدارس شهرستان آمل بوده است. نوع تحقیق، توصیفی همبستگی بوده است. جامعه آماری شامل تمامی مدیران مرد و زن مقطع ابتدایی، متوسطه اول و دوم مدارس دولتی شهرستان آمل بوده است که نمونه‌ای به حجم 132 نفر از مدیران مدارس به صورت تصادفی انتخاب شد. فرضیه‌های این تحقیق از طریق آزمون‌ های t تک نمونه‌ ای، t مستقل، تحلیل واریانس، آزمون همبستگی اسپیرمن تجزیه‌ و تحلیل شد. ابزار گردآوری داده‌ ها دو پرسشنامه‌ی مهارت سازمانی مدیریت زمان با ضریب پایایی (83/0) و پرسشنامه استاندارد سبک رهبری LBDQ با ضریب پایایی (76/0) بوده است. برای تعیین روایی نیز از روش بررسی محتوایی و صوری استفاده گردید. یافته‌ ها نشان داد بین سبک رهبری و مهارت سازمانی مدیریت زمان مدیران مدارس ارتباط معناداری وجود دارد که میانگین مهارت سازمانی مدیریت زمان در سبک آمرانه نسبت به سایر سبک‌ها بیشتر بوده است. رابطه بین سبک رهبری آزادمنشانه و مهارت سازمانی مدیریت زمان منفی و بین سبک رهبری آمرانه و مهارت سازمانی مدیریت زمان مثبت و معنادار بوده است و همچنین وضعیت مهارت سازمانی مدیریت زمان مدیران مدارس آمل در وضعیت مطلوبی قرار دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رهبری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سبک رهبری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مهارت مدیریت زمان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مهارت سازمانی مدیریت زمان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_60945_94085e8b768f2c414e35ecb5b0959c5f.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
