<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Influence of Spirituality training on the Organizational commitment, Employee Retention and Employee Engagement of Primary school principals</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر آموزش معنویت بر تعهد سازمانی، نگهداشت نیروی انسانی و اشتیاق شغلی مدیران مدارس ابتدایی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>153</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>168</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">58071</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>ناعمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه روانشناسی و علوم تربیتی واحد سبزوار،  دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، سبزوار، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Education is essential for sustainability and development of any society. Reaching to this goal could not be possible, except with using effective management of educational organizations. Commitment is one of the important issues of management and leadership in organizations that has a significant impact on the quality of services, popularity of organization and its success. Therefore, any organization tries to increase the organizational commitment of its employees because the organizational commitment affects the employee retention. On the other words, the employee retention and organizational commitment with a similar manner have emphasis on creating, keeping and improving relationship between individuals and organization. One of the factors can influence employee retention is job engagement in educational organizations. Organizational commitment, employee retention and employee job engagement, productivity and efficiency are among the most important issues of organizational management. Spiritual values at work means that the individuals and organizations consider working in a spiritual path, in an opportunity to grow and contribute to the society in a meaningful way, attempting to develop their values more fully in the work. This study was done to determine the effectiveness of spirituality training on organizational commitment, employee retention and employee job engagement of the administrators of primary schools of Sabzevar city. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research Method:&lt;/strong&gt; This study was semi -experimental and pretest-posttest with control group. The statistical population of this research was all administrators of primary schools of Sabzevar in the academic year 2015-2016 that 30 administrators of primary schools were selected by available sampling method and randomly assigned to two experimental group (15 persons) and control group (15 persons), then both groups were given pre-test. The experimental group received spirituality training during 10 sessions (each session 90 minutes), while the control group received no intervention. After completing the training program, the two groups were given a post-test. Data was collected using questionnaires of organizational commitment, employee retention and employee job engagement that their validity and reliability have been reported to be desirable. The organizational commitment questionnaire was developed by (Meyer, Allen &amp; Smith, 1993). This questionnaire has three ty­­pes of ethical, normative and continuous commitment with 24 items (each component is 8 questions). Meyer et al. (1993) reported the reliability of this questionnaire by Cronbach&#039;s alpha for emotional commitment of 0.88, normative commitment 0.81 and continuous commitment of 0.84. (Jazayeri, Neami, Shokrkon, &amp; Taghipour, 2006), the reliability and validity coefficients of this questionnaire were 0.85 and 0.45, respectively. In this study, the reliability coefficients of this questionnaire were calculated using Cronbach&#039;s alpha method for emotional commitment of 0.82, normative commitment 0.82 for continuous commitment 0.81 and for the whole scale of 0.85. The employee retention questionnaire was developed by (Potter, 1983) and consists of 24 questions in the five-point Likert scale (very low = 1, low = 2, average = 3, high = 4 and very much = 5). The reliability of this questionnaire was reported by (Salanova, Agut, &amp; Peiro, 2005) 0.88 and its validity was 0.73. (Hasani, 2012). The reliability of this questionnaire was 0.72 for Iranian employees and 0.69 for Cronbach&#039;s alpha. Employee job engagement was measured using Schaufeli &amp; Bakker 2003 scale. This scale has 17 questions with a Likert scale of 7 degrees. The components of this scale include professional energy (6 questions), professional sacrifice (5 questions) and professional fascination (6 questions). The reliability of the components was reported by Cronbach&#039;s alpha from 0.68 to 0.91 (Schaufeli &amp; Bakker, 2003) and for the whole scale of 0.92 (Mauno, Kinnunen, Ruokolainen, 2007). The convergent validity of this scale was reported in the Canengo Job Involvement Questionnaire (1982), 0.71 and its reliability was 0.87 in the Iranian society (Ghanbari, Ardalan, Zandi, &amp; Seif-Panahi, 2015). The reliability coefficient of this scale in this study was 0.89. &lt;br /&gt;After selecting 30 primary managers and replacing them, they were randomly divided into two experimental groups (15 people) and control (15 people), all participants were pre-test. Then, the experimental group received 10-week sessions (10 sessions per week) for an Islamic-based spiritual training intervention program by a specialist and the control group for the purpose of maintaining ethical issues until the end of the study in the list waiting remained. One week after the end of the educational program, both groups were subjected to post-test. Educational sessions were developed based on psychological and spiritual interventions by Richard &amp; Bergin (2005) and with the help of the spiritual skills training package (Boulahari 2012) with an Islamic approach. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Findings: &lt;/strong&gt;The collected data was analyzed using descriptive statistics methods (including percentage, mean and standard deviation) and inferential statistics (covariance analysis with consideration of prerequisites, including Kolmogorov-Smirnov test, homogeneity of variances and regression slope) with the help of SPSS&lt;sub&gt;23&lt;/sub&gt;. The results showed that spirituality training had a positive and significant effect on organizational commitment of primary school managers and predicts 37% of organizational commitment variance. Also, the results of the study showed that spirituality training has a positive and significant effect on employee retention levels of primary school managers and predicts 41% of the variance in human resources sustainability. In addition, the present study showed that spirituality training has a positive and significant effect on employee job engagement of primary school managers and predicts 26 percent of variance in on employee engagement. Therefore, spirituality training has a significant effect on of organizational commitment, employee retention and employee job engagement of the administrators of primary schools. The limitations of this study emphasized spiritual training with an Islamic approach to organizational commitment to employee retention and employee job engagement, while factors such as age, family status, career opportunities, learning, good benefits, promotion, labor market, title occupation, organizational justice and effective communication with senior managers can affect these variables that were not addressed in this study. In addition, the findings of this study belong to primary school managers of Sabzevar, which may have different results in other sections and locations. It is suggested that future research should look at the variables that can influence the organizational commitment, employee retention and employee job engagement of teachers in different sections and locations.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این پژوهش بر اساس هدف، از نوع پژوهش‌های کاربردی بوده و بر اساس ماهیت و روش انجام کار، نیمه آزمایشی از نوع پیش­آزمون- پس­آزمون با گروه کنترل بود. جامعه­ی آماری را تمامی مدیران مدارس ابتدایی سبزوار در سال  94-1395 به تعداد 73 نفر تشکیل دادند که تعداد 30 نفر با استفاده از روش نمونه­گیری در دسترس انتخاب و به­صورت گمارش تصادفی در دو گروه آزمایش و کنترل  جایگزین شدند.  گروه آزمایش، آموزش معنویت را طی 10 جلسه90 دقیقه­ای دریافت کرد و گروه کنترل هیچ مداخله­ای نداشت. بعد از اتمام آموزش از هر دو گروه پس­آزمون به عمل آمد. گردآوری داده­ها با پرسشنامه­های تعهد سازمانی، نگهداشت نیروی انسانی و اشتیاق شغلی انجام شد که روایی و پایایی آن­ها مطلوب گزارش‌شده است. تجزیه‌وتحلیل داده­ها با استفاده از روش‌های آمار توصیفی و تحلیل کواریانس با کمک نرم‌افزار SPSS&lt;sub&gt;21&lt;/sub&gt; انجام شد. یافته­های پژوهش نشان داد که آموزش معنویت بر تعهد سازمانی، نگهداشت نیروی انسانی و اشتیاق شغلی مؤثر است. همچنین آموزش معنویت واریانس تعهد سازمانی، نگهداشت نیروی انسانی و اشتیاق شغلی را تبیین کرد. بنابراین، آموزش معنویت بر تعهد سازمانی، نگهداشت نیروی انسانی و اشتیاق شغلی مدیران ابتدایی تأثیر معناداری دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آموزش معنویت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تعهد سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نگهداشت نیروی انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اشتیاق شغلی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_58071_1673b20082b39a18b9d5caa41bbe77db.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
