<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue></Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identification and Prioritization of Key Performance Indicators in Elementary Schools</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسائی و اولویت‌بندی نشانگرهای کلیدی عملکرد در مدارس ابتدایی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>34</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">61291</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید روح الله</FirstName>
					<LastName>تیموری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، تهران ، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>عباس پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی،تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمید</FirstName>
					<LastName>رحیمیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی،تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>عبداللهی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی،تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study was to identify and prioritize key performance indicators in elementary schools using fuzzy Delphi and SWARA methods. Experts (statistical population), including faculty members and specialists in the Ministry of Education, were selected through a purposive sampling method to reach the theoretical saturation of 15 people. The data collection tool is a structured interview. At first, by reviewing the existing literature, effective components and indicators were selected and a list of identified components and indicators was provided to the experts, and then the desired components and indicators were selected based on the expert opinion. Fuzzy Delphi method was used to identify and screen the indicators. Research findings showed that elementary schools have 102 indicators in 6 components of human relations development, strategic planning, growth and learning, instruction and evaluation, management and leadership, and environment and community. In the end, the final weight of the key components and indicators was determined by the SWARA method. The most important components of management and leadership, growth and learning, and environment and community were introduced.&lt;br /&gt; There are several definitions of performance. According to Lockett (1992), performance is defined as “a multidimensional construct and the common factors that are frequently associated with organizational performance are efficiency, quality, responsiveness, cos, and overall effectiveness”. In 2017, Armstrong has extended the definition to a “Performance management” as “a means of getting better results from the organization, teams, and individuals by understanding and managing performance within an agreed framework of planned goals, objectives, and standards of achievement and competence.” More recently, Neely et al. (2002, pp. xiii) defined a “performance metric” as the scope, content, and component parts of a broadly-based performance measure (Marson &amp; et al, 2012).&lt;br /&gt; In today’s competitive scenario, organizations are forced to monitor their performance on a sustained basis, across several dimensions. However, developing an effective performance management system (PMS) remains a challenge. Several problems regarding the building of a performance management system, such as the accuracy of data, the definition of meaningful metrics to support decision-making processes, and the measurement of the company’s intangible aspects, continue to represent challenges for managers. In order to be useful, performance management systems should ensure that performance is clearly defined and metrics accurately measure performance. Closely related to this subject is the selection of valuable performance indicators Any effective performance management system has to adopt a limited number of indicators, i.e., key performance indicators (KPIs), capable of providing an integrated and complete view of company’s performance and to measure progress toward organizational goals(Carlucci, 2010). In many organizations, the basic issue is that performance appraisal should be done with what criteria and indicators. Because if an appropriate indicator is introduced, they can better manage their resources in particular and guide the sectors to the strategic goals of the organization in general (Kaplan &amp; Norton, 2004).&lt;br /&gt; The selection of performance indicators is one of the major challenges of organizations developing and implementing a performance management system. The performance indicators represent the means for monitoring processes and related outcomes to drive management actions. Therefore, the selection of performance indicators has to be addressed: limiting the number of indicators to prevent information overload, to avoid confusion for their potential users, to provide a clear picture of the critical organizational competitive factors and to facilitate the overall measurement (Carlucci, 2010). Measurement of performance allows to make clear performance issues, compare the current situation to the goals and to provide exact steps towards the elimination of the problems (Graham, 2012).&lt;br /&gt; Good indicators share two characteristics: first, they are well-founded in theory, having an explanation for the assumption that they correctly represent a given feature of reality and second, they are robust against limitations in the underlying data. After adding a few more important characteristics, quality indicators should be cost-effective, timely, reliable, valid and specific (Markic, 2014). According to Parmenter (2015) “key performance indicators (KPIs) represent a set of measures focusing on those aspects of organizational performance that are the most critical for the current and future success of the organization” (p. 4). KPIs are a set of measures that should be measured frequently and tie directly to the success of an organization. KPIs need to be tracked on a regular basis, and if they are not meeting the target then processes or systems need to be modified (Arif &amp; Smiley, 2004). Lyddon and McComb (2008) state every KPI measure should include several components: “(1) the actual results of the indicator; (2) the target for which the indicator is striving; (3) the difference between actual results and target results; and 4) signal values, or benchmarks” (p. 139). KPIs allow gathering knowledge and exploring the best way to achieve organization goals (Badawy &amp; et al, 2018). In today’s world KPIs are essential for planning and controlling (Meier &amp; et al, 2013) through consolidating information (Gladen, 2005), creating transparency and thereby supporting decision making of the management. KPIs are also known as Key Performance Index, Key Process Indicators, Balanced Scorecards, Business Dashboards, Scoreboard, Key Result Areas, Key Success Indicators or a number of other identifications depending on the consultant and management experts you are talking with (Ismail &amp; Yu, 2007). The Key Performance indicators are the modern tools that help to keep the performance in the production on a high level (Kaganski &amp; et al, 2018). KPIs are financial and non-financial indicators that organizations use in order to estimate and fortify how successful they are; aiming previously established long-lasting goals (Velimirović &amp; et al, 2011)&lt;br /&gt; In this identification, the component of human relations management has 13 indicators, the strategic planning component has 20 indicators, the component of education and assessment has 13 indicators, the component of growth and learning has 21 indicators, the component of the environment and society has 11 indicators, and finally, the component of the management and leadership has 24 indicators. Six indicators are rejected by experts. With Swara&#039;s method, key indicators of leaders&#039; performance in elementary schools were prioritized. The results of this method show that management and leadership &amp; growth and learning components are of the highest importance for improving the performance of schools.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">  این به روش اکتشافی و با بهره‌گیری از روش‌های دلفی فازی و سوآرا انجام شده است. خبرگان(جامعه آماری پژوهش)، شامل اساتید مدیریت آموزشی و متخصصان تعلیم و تربیت در وزارت آموزش و پرورش هستند که از طریق روش نمونه‌گیری هدفمند تعداد 15 نفر تا رسیدن به اشباع نظری انتخاب شدند. ابزار گردآوری داده‌ها، مصاحبه ساختاریافته است. از مولفه‌ها و نشانگرهای استخراج شده از ادبیات پژوهش به عنوان پایه و اساس طراحی مصاحبه ساختاریافته استفاده شد. در ابتدا با بررسی پژوهش‌های انجام شده و ادبیات موجود، مولفه‌ها و نشانگرهای موثر انتخاب و فهرستی از مولفه‌ها و نشانگرهای شناسایی شده در اختیار خبرگان قرار گرفت، سپس مولفه‌ها و نشانگرهای موردنظر بر اساس نظر خبرگان انتخاب شدند. برای شناسائی و غربالگری نشانگرها، از روش دلفی فازی استفاده شد. یافته‌های پژوهش نشان داد که مدارس دوره ابتدایی دارای 102 نشانگر در 6 مولفه توسعه روابط انسانی، برنامه‌ریزی استراتژیک، رشد و یادگیری، آموزش و ارزشیابی، مدیریت و رهبری و محیط و جامعه هستند. در پایان با روش سوآرا وزن نهایی مولفه‌ها و نشانگرهای کلیدی موردنظر به دست آمد که مولفه‌های مدیریت و رهبری، رشد و یادگیری و محیط و جامعه با اهمیت‌ترین مولفه‌ها معرفی شدند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نشانگرهای کلیدی عملکرد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدارس ابتدایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش دلفی فازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش سوآرا</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_61291_dc5b753f5a2ef7fa74091fb73676c943.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
