<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه کردستان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت مدرسه</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-4724</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>the mediator role of career plateau in relationship between teachers&#039; individual characteristics and organizational laziness among teachers</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رابطۀ بین ویژگی های فردی و تنبلی سازمانی در بین معلمان مدارس ابتدایی: نقش میانجی سکون‏ زدگی شغلی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>40</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>55</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60946</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>غفار</FirstName>
					<LastName>کریمیان پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>باشگاه پژوهشگران جوان و نخبگان، واحد کرمانشاه، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، کرمانشاه، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عادل</FirstName>
					<LastName>زاهد بابلان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، مدیریت آموزشی، گروه علوم تربیتی، دانشکده علوم تربیتی وروانشناسی، دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی، اردبیل، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>خالق خواه</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، فلسفه تعلیم و تربیت، گروه علوم تربیتی، دانشکده علوم تربیتی وروانشناسی، دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی، اردبیل</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضایی شریف</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار ، روانشناسی تربیتی، گروه علوم تربیتی، دانشکده علوم تربیتی وروانشناسی، دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی، اردبیل، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>31</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Social laziness has attracted researchers in recent years. A person can be called lazy, who has no tenderness and enthusiasm for mobility and is fleeing from the dynamism and search. . In fact, laziness is a pain that can affect people in all activities and organizations and has been raised as a challenge in organizations called &quot;Organizational laziness.&quot; Organizational laziness In a simple definition, the laziness of employees in their work is in a collective form and is the result of a lazy group of people working in the organization. Organizations that suffer from organizational laziness are in a situation where, even with the best forces, they are in slippery situatio. One of the factors affecting organizational laziness is job plataeu, which has long been considered and addressed in management literature. The phrase &quot;job plateau&quot; refers to the feeling of failure or disappointment that people experience temporarily or permanently during their career process. Definition of job plateau in two aspects of hierarchy and occupational content. And it is a point in the person&#039;s career path, where the probability of hierarchical upgrading for the individual is very small. And employees reach a point that they are reluctant to attain higher organizational levels. In fact, in terms of these employees, the opportunities for individual growth in the organization are very limited, and they are not looking for higher job titles. It&#039;s not challenging for employees to stay in content, Therefore, they do not have any meaning for competition in business, Duties and occupational activities for ordinary and recurring employees, and usually there is no opportunity to learn and grow in the desired job. Research has shown that occupational stagnation is associated with negative outcomes such as emotional exhaustion and positive emotional exhaustion goals, attitude and reduction of staff performance, depression and stress, and decreased job satisfaction. &lt;br /&gt; One of the factors affecting job plateau, is the individual characteristics of the employees. Individuals are different in many respects due to individual characteristics. In fact, the individual characteristics of the various individuals indicate the strengths and weaknesses of individuals that can be improved some of them during their lifetimes. Individual characteristics include a wide range of characteristics. In this study, according to the interviewed codes, the characteristics of age, sex, work experience, communication skill weakness, lack of disability in class management, problems and illnesses, study rate, beliefs and attitudes Teachers are presented as individual features. Since these features have always had an impact on individual performance, consideration of them as factors affecting organizational laziness can also be important. &lt;br /&gt;One of the most important organizations in every country is education, which has its own special significance. The importance of education is due to the expansion of its functions, which has increasingly placed it at the heart of the community, has attracted particular attention. . Teachers play the most important role in the education system, and they are seen as the starting point for education. With compassionate and educated teachers, society can create a fundamental transformation. On the other hand, organizational laziness is not limited to a specific society and includes all occupational and organizational environments. Although every job has its own stress, But teachers for reasons of low salaries, lack of administrative support, negative attitudes towards jobs, lack of public support, Planning for diverse courses, diverse learners, inadequate income, conflicts with colleagues and managers, and lack of bilateral ties, unfavorable conditions and pressure for promotion, bureaucratic structure, Lack of participation in decision making, management disregard for welfare issues of employees, teaching in multi-level classes, teaching a subject in multiple classes (repetitive work), Values ​​and different cultures of students They are subject to special stresses that can provide a platform for organizational laziness. Because this phenomenon results from laziness of the staff of the organization, which can have long negative consequences in the long run. This phenomenon can happen in the current state of education. Therefore, individual laziness of teachers can lead to the formation of organizational laziness. Research conducted in this area suggests that this negative phenomenon has been neglected among teachers. And identifying the effective factors on it can help relevant authorities to take effective measures to reduce this ominous phenomenon. On the other hand, considering the important and vital role of teachers in the educational system, addressing this phenomenon and studying the factors among teachers in terms of their key role and position is of great importance. Therefore, to cope with it, recognizing the effects, consequences and factors affecting it is of particular importance. &lt;br /&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;The purpose of this study was to investigate the relationship between teachers&#039; individual characteristics and organizational laziness with the mediator role of career plateau. The research method was descriptive and correlated by structural equation method (SEM). The statistical population of this study consisted of all elementary school teachers in Awramanat district, that by Using multistage cluster sampling, according to the Cochran formula, 350 people (222 male and 128 female) were selected. A researcher-made questionnaire was used to collect the data. In order to measure individual characteristics, 10 questions, 6 questions were used to measure career plateau and 5 questions for measuring organizational laziness. The content validity of the questionnaires was approved by the Relevant specialists and Their reliability of them respectively was 0.81 for individual characteristics questionnaire, 0.91 for career plateau questionnaire and 0.95 for organizational laziness questionnaire. Data were analyzed using SPSS (Mean, standard deviation, Pearson correlation coefficient, KMO and Bartlett, slope and elongation) and LISREL softwares. The results of the data analysis showed that the positive and direct effects of individual characteristics on career plateau and the direct effect of career plateau on organizational laziness are significant. Also, the indirect effect of individual characteristics was significant on organizational laziness through career plateau. &lt;br /&gt; Therefore, it can be concluded that individual traits and job stagnation are one of the important variables related to the organizational laziness of teachers, and these two variables should be paid more attention by the authorities and managers of education.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر، پژوهشی توصیفی و از نوع همبستگی بوده که با کمک روش معادلات ساختاری (SEM) انجام شد. جامعه آماری پژوهش شامل تمام معلمان مقطع ابتدایی منطقه اورامانات بود که با استفاده از روش نمونه‌گیری خوشه‌ای چندمرحله‌ای و با توجه به فرمول کوکران، تعداد 350 نفر (222 نفر مرد و 128 نفر زن) به‌عنوان نمونه انتخاب شدند. برای جمع‌آوری داده‏های پژوهش از پرسشنامه محقق ساخته استفاده شد. برای سنجش ویژگی‌های فردی 10 سئوال، برای سنجش سکون‏زدگی شغلی 6 سئوال و برای سنجش تنبلی سازمانی 5 سئوال طراحی شد. روایی محتوایی پرسشنامه‏ها مورد تایید متخصصان مربوطه قرار گرفته و پایایی آن‌ها با استفاده از روش محاسبه آلفای کرونباخ به ترتیب برای ویژگی‌های فردی 81/0، برای پرسشنامه سکون‏زدگی شغلی 91/0 و برای پرسشنامه تنبلی سازمانی 85/0 به دست آمد. داده‏ها با استفاده از نرم‌افزارهایSPSS و روش‌های (میانگین،انحراف استاندارد، ضریب همبستگی پیرسون، کایمو و بارتلت، چولگی و کشیدگی) و نرم‌افزار LISREL تجزیه و تحلیل شدند. نتایج تحلیل داده‏ها نشان داد که اثر مثبت و مستقیم ویژگی‌های فردی بر سکون‏زدگی شغلی و اثر مستقیم سکون‏زدگی شغلی بر تنبلی سازمانی معنی‏دار است. همچنین اثر غیرمستقیم ویژگی‌های فردی از طریق سکون‌زدگی شغلی بر تنبلی سازمانی معنی‏دار بود.&lt;br /&gt;  </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ویژگیهای فردی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سکون‏زدگی شغلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تنبلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معلمان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jsa.uok.ac.ir/article_60946_1697d42494ccc3fac722c6473954e69e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
