<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 (پیاپی 17)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Designing and Explaining Entrepreneurial Government Model for Public Organizations of Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی مدل دولت کارآفرین برای سازمان های اداری ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>91</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>106</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">3482</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>نصیری زنگ آباد</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>رسولی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>الوداری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>4دانشیارگروه روانشناسی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Although the term Entrepreneurship has been shaped &lt;br /&gt; and nurtured first time in the business area in the literarature, but today we can see it’s entering to the area of public services. One of the promotion of this attitude, is the creating of reinventing government theory. In the present study, we decided to test the effect of injecting the mentioned theory in the public sector of Iran. For doing this, a fundamental research approach and Delphi techniqe, as well as confirmatory factor analysis and structural equation modeling to assess construct validity was used. Delphi panels formed of 15 executives from administrative division population and academic faculty, consists of 15 members. For designing the primary questionnaire design, dimensions and variables was extracted from the theory. after 3 rounds of the Delphi, by eliminating the 5 variables of the 10 variables and adding 3 local variables, the 8 variables and 67 indicators of the final model were defined Variables include: community-opened, market orientated, mission-oriented, customer-driven, decentralized, promoting professional ethics, development the social justice and Jihadian management.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">با وجودی که واژه کارآفرینی نخستین بار در ادبیات کسب و کار و تجارت شکل گرفته و پرورش یافته است، اما امروزه شاهد ورود آن به فضای خدمات عمومی هستیم.. یکی از نتایج اشاعه این نگرش، ایجاد نظریه باز آفرینی دولت است. پژوهش حاضر بر آن است تا اثر تزریق تئوری بازآفرین دولت را بر محیط اداری بخش دولتی کشور مورد بررسی قرار دهد. این امر از طریق یک رویکرد تحقیقی بنیادی و روش توصیفی پیمایشی دلفی و نیز مدل یابی معادلات ساختاری برای تحلیل عاملی تاییدی و سنجش روایی سازه انجام گردید. پانل دلفی از دو بخش اداری با 15 نفر مدیر اجرایی جامعه آماری و علمی شامل 15 نفر عضو هیات علمی دانشگاه تشکیل یافت. برای طراحی پرسشنامه اولیه، متغیّرهای 10 گانه مدل دولت کارآفرین به همراه ابعاد استخراجی آنها وارد و پس از 3 دور اجرای دلفی، با حذف 5 متغیّر از این 10 متغیر و نیز افزوده شدن 3 متغیّر بومی، 8 متغیّر نهایی مدل شناسایی و مجموعا 67 شاخص بومی برای این 8 متغیّر تعریف گردید. متغیّرها عبارتند از: تعلق به مردم، بازارگرایی، رسالت محوری، مشتری مداری، تمرکز زدایی، اشاعه اخلاق حرفه ای، توسعه مدیریت جهادی و برقراری عدالت اجتماعی. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دولت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظریه بازآفرینی دولت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دولت کارآفرین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فن دلفی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بومی سازی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_3482_e9a6a9d752cf0e60dcb12e9ee443cc42.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
