<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 2 (پیاپی 14)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Criticizing Governmental Supportive Programs for Home-based Business Growth; Viewpoint of Home-based Businesses&#039; House Wifes</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>آسیب‌شناسی برنامه‌های حمایتی دولت از رشد کسب‌وکارهای خانگی از دیدگاه زنان صاحب کسب‌وکارهای خانگی در ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>31</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>50</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2744</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>میثم</FirstName>
					<LastName>مدرسی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری کارآفرینی گرایش عمومی، دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>آراستی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه کارآفرینی، دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کامبیز</FirstName>
					<LastName>طالبی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه کارآفرینی، دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مقصود</FirstName>
					<LastName>فراستخواه</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه برنامه ریزی و آموزش عالی، موسسه پژوهش و برنامه ریزی آموزش عالی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>24</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Calibri; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;In under-developing societies and even developed economies, home-based enterprises have been used as a device for economical growth and solving the problem of unemployment particularly for women. The role of these kinds of businesses in national and regional development causes government&#039;s attention to this subject and establishing special supporting policies for these kinds of businesses the more. According to the increasing predicaments of unemployment in Iran, especially for women, some actions have been taken for supporting home-based enterprise and their growth; but difficulties of these businesses still continue to be valid. Present research has dealt with the pathlogy of the government&#039;s supporting programs for home-based enterprise. For this, qualitative research method and 20 deep interviews with owner of home-based enterprises have been done. In addition, interview analysis was done through thematic analysis. Research results was presented in two groups of pathologies related to designing programs and pathologies related to executing programs. At the end, helpful diplomatic solutions were suggested to improve the government&#039;s supporting programs for home-based enterprises.&lt;/span&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &#039;B Lotus&#039;; font-size: 10pt; mso-bidi-language: FA; mso-ansi-font-weight: bold;&quot; lang=&quot;FA&quot;&gt;در جوامع درحال‌توسعه و حتی اقتصادهای توسعه‌یافته، کسب‌وکارهای خانگی به‌عنوان یکی از ابزارهای رشد اقتصادی و حل مشکل بیکاری به‌ویژه برای زنان به کار گرفته‌شده است. نقش این نوع از کسب‌وکارها در توسعه منطقه‌ای و ملی سبب توجه بیش‌ازپیش دولت‌ها به این مقوله و تدوین خط‌مشی‌های حمایتی خاص از این نوع از کسب‌وکارهاست. در ایران نیز با توجه به معضل بیکاری فزاینده به‌خصوص برای زنان، اقداماتی در راستای حمایت از کسب‌وکارهای خانگی و رشد آن‌ها صورت گرفته است اما مشکلات این نوع از کسب‌وکارها همچنان به قوت خود باقی است. پژوهش حاضر به آسیب‌شناسی برنامه‌های حمایتی دولت از کسب‌وکارهای خانگی پرداخت. در این راستا از روش پژوهش کیفی و انجام 20 مصاحبه عمیق با صاحبان کسب‌وکارهای خانگی استفاده‌ شد. همچنین تحلیل مصاحبه‌ها از طریق تحلیل تماتیک صورت گرفت. نتایج پژوهش در دودسته اصلی آسیب‌های مربوط به تدوین برنامه‌ها و آسیب‌های مربوط به اجرای برنامه‌ها ارائه و در پایان راهکارهای سیاستی مفیدی برای ارتقاء برنامه‌های حمایتی دولت از کسب‌وکارهای خانگی پیشنهاد شد.&lt;/span&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کسب‌وکار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کسب‌وکار خانگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خط‌مشی‌</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خط‌مشی‌های حمایتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دولت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_2744_2901666f6fee1312b41d46469c662202.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
