<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 3 (پیاپی 23)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Discourse Analysis of public administration:
“Education Sphere in Iran&quot;</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل گفتمان مدیریت دولتی ایران در بخش آموزش و پرورش</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>99</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>114</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">4801</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>الوانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد مدیریت، دانشگاه علامه ﻃﺒﺎﻃﺒﺎﺋﯽ، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهرداد</FirstName>
					<LastName>صباغی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجو دکتری مدیریت، دانشگاه علامه ﻃﺒﺎﻃﺒﺎﺋﯽ، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>To be democratic, transparent, and publicly-engaged are of integral qualities to administrate public affairs in modern era by the organizations. The survey suggests that at verbal stage and superficial structure, the language of governmental senior officials is close to this discourse. However, one of the key setbacks in interactions of public organizations providing public services is language hinders. This study is to characterize the discourse of public administration concerning education in between 1989- 2013 to assess the extent they concur with modern paradigm in public administration. To conduct the survey, Fairclough ‘s approach has been applied. The findings indicate that, although senior officials in Education Ministry are largely inclined to use conceptions as well as variations of modern paradigm of management, their usage is highly superficial and less genuine. In fact, what really occurs is language gaming, blurring their intentions through insisting on bureaucratic mechanism and expertization of reference language in public interactions, poor inclusiveness, and slogan-oriented approach versus practice-oriented one play the central role in their discourse</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">رویکردهای نوین اداره امورعمومی برویژگی هایی همچون دموکراتیک بودن، شفافیت، مشارکت عامه مردم وغیره، به عنوان شاخص های سازمانها درعصر پست مدرن اشاره دارد. در سطح گفتاری و سازه های صوری، زبان مدیران دولتی به این ادبیات نزدیک است. اما یکی از موانع مهم در تعاملات بین سازمانهای دولتی (ارائه دهنده خدمات عمومی) با مردم (گیرندگان خدمات) موانع زبانی است. درتحقیق حاضرمحققین کوشیده اند تا مختصات گفتمان مدیریت دولتی در سه دوره حاکمیت دولتهای مختلف طی 24 سال از 1368 تاپایان سال 1391 را بررسی نموده و میزان دوری و نزدیکی آن به پارادایم های نوین مدیریت دولتی مورد تحلیل قرار دهند. روش تحقیق تحلیل گفتمان انتقادی فرکلاف گویای آنست که به رغم استعمال زیاد مدیران دولتی از مفاهیم و متغیرهای پارادایم های نوین مدیریت،این کاربرد درحد قابل توجهی جنبه صوری وظاهری داشته و درعمل استفاده از بازیهای زبانی، مجهول نگه داشتن نیت ازطریق تاکید بر قواعد بوروکراتیک و استعمال زبان معیار تخصصی در تعامل با عامه مردم، شعارزدگی و شمول معنایی پائین از مختصات گفتمان مدیریت دولتی در جامعه مورد بررسی می باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل گفتمان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شمول معنایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مجهول سازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت دولتی نوین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزش عمومی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_4801_d7d98518d28f7110cfb1defe09bb6c05.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
