<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 2 (پیاپی 26)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Designing a Trust Building Model in the Humanitarian Services Network(Case study: Plasco building fire, Shahran explosion, Metro flooding in Tehran)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی مدل اعتمادسازی در شبکة تأمین خدمات بشردوستانه (مطالعه موردی: آتش‌سوزی ساختمان پلاسکو ، انفجار شهران، آب‌گرفتگی مترو تهران)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>59</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>82</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">5638</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.30473/ipom.2019.42091.3307</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمیدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>طلایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری گروه مدیریت تولید و عملیات، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>جعفرنژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عالیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>کاظمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حنانه</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی کنگرانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مرتع و آبخیزداری، دانشگاه هرمزگان، هرمزگان، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study is to provide a model of trust building process in the country&#039;s relief network considering the importance of establishing trust in the supply chain of humanitarian services as well as theoretical poverty in the field of trust building. To perform this study, three major recent events in Tehran province have been selected as a case study. Due to the lack of qualitative research in the field of trust building, using the grounded Theory, 2015 version of Corbin and Strauss, the model of trust building process in the relief network is designed and edited based on interview with 8 experts and members involved in the relief network. Given the importance of establishing trust between the members present in the relief network and the lack of a comprehensive model in this area, the present study aims to design a trust building model among members of the relief network and to examine the critical role of trust in the successful relief process and its reflection.The research findings are classified in three phases of conditions, actions and outcomes. The weak structures of the society and the community management system are a major obstacle to building trust. And insufficient funding, lack of certainty, unsuccessful performance, lack of coordination and cooperation between responsible groups and lack of preparation are the main sources of distrust. The most important finding of this research is the lack of trust in the humanitarian supply chain due to the reliance on public assistance.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از این پژوهش با توجه به اهمیت مسئله ایجاد اعتماد در زنجیرة تأمین خدمات بشردوستانه و نیز فقر نظری در حوزة اعتمادسازی، ارائه مدلی از فرایند اعتمادسازی در شبکة امداد کشور است. برای انجام این مطالعه، سه حادثة بزرگ اخیر استان تهران  مورد مطالعه انتخاب ‌شده است و با توجه به کمبود تحقیقات کیفی در حوزة اعتمادسازی، با استفاده از روش نظریة داده ­بنیاد نسخه 2015 کوربین و استراوس، مدل فرایند اعتمادسازی در شبکة امداد براساس مصاحبه با 8 نفر از خبرگان حاضر در شبکة امداد، طراحی ‌شده است. با توجه به اهمیت ایجاد اعتماد میان اعضای حاضر در شبکة امدادرسانی و فقدان مدلی جامع در این حیطه، پژوهش حاضر به طراحی مدل ساخت اعتماد و بررسی نقش حساس اعتماد در فرایند امدادرسانی موفق  و بازتاب آن می­پردازد. یافته­های پژوهش در 3 فاز شرایط، اقدامات و پیامدها طبقه‌بندی ‌شده‌اند. ساختارهای ضعیف جامعه و سیستم مدیریت جامعه مانع بزرگ ایجاد اعتماد است و کافی نبودن بودجه، نامشخص بودن متولی امر، عملکرد ناموفق، عدم هماهنگی و همکاری کارگروه­های مسئول و آمادگی نداشتن از عوامل اصلی بی­اعتمادی تعیین‌ شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اعتماد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنجیرة تأمین بشردوستانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظریة داده‌بنیاد</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_5638_147103548dedc05011841be7f547b4ae.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
