<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 3  (پیاپی 11)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Mechanism of organizational abilities, improvement in public sector</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>سازوکارهای ارتقای قابلیت‌های سازمانی در بخش دولتی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>91</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>106</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2073</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ﺣﺴﻦ</FirstName>
					<LastName>داﻧﺎﯾﯽ فرد</LastName>
<Affiliation>اﺳﺘﺎد داﻧﺸﮕﺎه ﺗﺮﺑﯿﺖ ﻣﺪرس؛ داﻧﺸﮑﺪه ﻣﺪﯾﺮﯾﺖ و اﻗﺘﺼﺎد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ﻓﺎﻃﻤﻪ</FirstName>
					<LastName>برزﮔﺮ</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارﺷﻨﺎﺳﯽ ارﺷﺪ ﻣﺪﯾﺮﯾﺖ دوﻟﺘﯽ؛ داﻧﺸﮕﺎه ﺗﺮﺑﯿﺖ ﻣﺪرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>هاﻧﯿﻪ</FirstName>
					<LastName>اﺣﻤﺪی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشچوی دوره دﮐﺘﺮی ﺳﯿﺎﺳﺘﮕﺬاری ﺑﺨﺶ ﻋﻤﻮﻣﯽ؛ داﻧﺸﮕﺎه ﺗﺮﺑﯿﺖ ﻣﺪرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 115%; font-size: 12pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Calibri;&quot;&gt;Organizations require different resources to keep up their survival and for optimum usage of these resources; they should become equipped to some abilities and fortify them. In viewpoint of managers, ability is organization&#039;s power for expanding capacities and tolerating limitations and inadequacy to achieve determined goals. The aim of this research is counting mechanisms that lead to organizational abilities improvement in public sector of Iran and prioritizing them according to their importance. The research is a mixed research; the means of interview has been used at the qualitative phase and the questionnaire was used at the quantitative phase. These mechanisms were ranked in terms of importance level by presenting a kind of classification of organizational abilities&#039; improvement mechanisms. These mechanisms are as below in the manner of priority: mechanisms of psychological, processing, political and financial at the first rank: Mechanisms of human, culture, social and technological at the second rank and structural mechanisms at the third rank.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 107%; font-family: &#039;B Lotus&#039;; font-size: 10pt;&quot; lang=&quot;AR-SA&quot;&gt;سازمان‌ها برای ادامه بقای خود به منابع مختلفی نیاز دارند و برای استفاده بهینه از &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 107%; font-family: &#039;B Lotus&#039;; font-size: 10pt; mso-bidi-language: FA;&quot; lang=&quot;FA&quot;&gt;این &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 107%; font-family: &#039;B Lotus&#039;; font-size: 10pt;&quot; lang=&quot;AR-SA&quot;&gt;منابع باید به قابلیت‌هایی مجهز شوند و آنها را تقویت کنند. قابلیت از نظر مدیران، توان سازمان برای ایجاد ظرفیت‌ها و تحمل محدودیت‌ها و نارسایی‌ها برای رسیدن به اهداف معین است. هدف این پژوهش، احصاء سازوکارهایی است که منجر به ارتقای قابلیت‌های سازمانی در بخش دولتی ایران می‌شود و اولویت‌بندی این سازوکارها براساس میزان اهمیت آنهاست. پژوهش به صورت ترکیبی انجام شده که در مرحله کیفی از ابزار مصاحبه و در مرحله کمی از ابزار پرسشنامه استفاده شده است.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 107%; font-family: &#039;B Lotus&#039;; font-size: 10pt;&quot; lang=&quot;AR-SA&quot;&gt;با ارائه نوعی طبقه‌بندی از سازوکارهای ارتقای قابلیت‌های سازمانی، این سازوکارها از نظر درجه اهمیت نیز رتبه‌بندی شدند. این سازوکارها به ترتیب اولویت عبارتند از: سازوکارهای روانشناختی، فرایندی، سیاسی و مالی در رتبه اول. سازوکارهای انسانی، فرهنگی اجتماعی و فناورانه در رتبه دوم و سازوکار ساختاری در رتبه سوم.&lt;/span&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قابلیتهای سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازمان‌های بخش دولتی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_2073_5665955e818d7920de621bb8f242e971.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
