<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 (پیاپی 25)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A comparative study of the structure and function of Payame Noor University with five open universities in the world</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تطبیقی ساختار و کارکرد دانشگاه پیام نور با پنج دانشگاه باز جهان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>89</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>110</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">5384</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.30473/ipom.2018.5384</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نجاری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جواد</FirstName>
					<LastName>معدنی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This research aims to provide a comparative study on the structure and functioning of Payame Noor University with open universities abroad and to know about similarities and differentiate them in order to design the optimal structure in the future. The research method of this study is a comparative study method that has been studied by the Payam Noor University and five open universities in the world (England, Canada, Malaysia, China and Indonesia) based on components and indicators of structure and operation. All universities studied use open and distance education. The Open University of China, due to its high population, has the largest number of students, and equally has the largest number of staff and faculty. In this comparison, the UK University ranked 313 in the world&#039;s best position, and then the Payame Noir University of Iran ranked second in the study. : In terms of the structure of Payam Noor University, it has a hybrid structure. But other open universities studied more than two-part structure. Payam Noor University, with a high degree of recognition, has relative concentration and complexity compared with five open universities. All universities have more organizational agility than Payam Noor University, given the number of centers, faculty and staff, staff ratios, and levels of hierarchy. Therefore, it is suggested that the design of a desirable structure be tailored to the needs of the university in line with its mission and objectives and tasks.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این پژوهش به بررسی تطبیقی ساختار و کارکرد دانشگاه پیام نور با دانشگاه های باز خارج کشور و آگاهی از نقاط تشابه و افتراق آنها برای طراحی ساختار مطلوب در آینده برخی اطلاعات لازم فراهم شود . روش تحقیق طرح حاضر، روش مطالعه تطبیقی است که به بررسی و تحلیل دانشگاه پیام نور و پنج دانشگاه باز جهان (انگلیس، کانادا، مالزی، چین و اندونزی) بر اساس مولفه ها و شاخص های ساختار و کارکرد پرداخته است.  کلیه دانشگاه های مورد مطالعه  از روش آموزش باز و از راه دور  استفاده می کنند. دانشگاه باز چین به دلیل جمعیت بالا، بیشترین تعداد دانشجو را به خود اختصاص داده است و به همان نسبت بیشترین تعداد کارمند و هیأت علمی را داراست. در این مقایسه دانشگاه انگلیس با رتبه 313 بهترین جایگاه را در رتبه جهانی دارد و سپس دانشگاه پیام نور ایران در مقام دوم این مطالعه قرار گرفته است. : از نظر نوع ساختار دانشگاه پیام نور، ساختار ترکیبی دارد. ولی سایر دانشگاه های باز مورد مطالعه بیشتر ساختار چند بخشی (دو بخشی) دارند. دانشگاه پیام نور در مقایسه با پنج دانشگاه باز خارجی دارای رسمیت بالا، تمرکز نسبی و  پیچیدگی بیشتری است. همه دانشگاه ها  با توجه به تعداد مراکز، اساتید و کارکنان و نسبت های پرسنلی و سطوح سلسه مراتب از چابکی سازمانی بیشتری نسبت به دانشگاه پیام نور برخودار ند. بنابراین پیشنهاد می شود به  طراحی ساختار مطلوب و متناسب با نیاز دانشگاه در راستای ماموریت و اهداف و وظایف محوله پرداخته شود. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دانشگاه باز</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آموزش از راه دور</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">یادگیری الکترونیکی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_5384_340981c414c352c880de80b4270eda76.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
