<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 (پیاپی 21)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Processing the Theory of Management by Reactions: To Comes and Comes On</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>پردازش نظریه مدیریت واکنشی: پیش‌آیندها و پسایندها</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>25</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>34</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">4340</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدعلی</FirstName>
					<LastName>سرلک</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد/ پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جهان</FirstName>
					<LastName>عبدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترا</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>25</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The lack of futurism of some managers of public and private organizations and their surprise against various events, such as ‎natural disasters, indicates a specific management style that is called reaction management. The use of such a lightness, due ‎to reduced trust of the stakeholders and the reduction of social capital, causes the destruction of the organization&#039;s brand and ‎its brand. therefore, the purpose of this research is to achieve a theory on identifying the causes of reaction management in ‎the organization, determining the results and solutions, and also understanding this phenomenon. In organizations and ‎change in behaviors. the research approach is qualitative and the research strategy is based on the data theory of the ‎foundation. To collect the data, the present study The semi-structured interview was conducted and to analyze the data, ‎binomial statistical tests And Friedman were used. A theoretical and purposeful sampling (judgment and snowball) was ‎used to based on this, there were 15 interviews with managers, faculty members and organizational experts They had ‎experience and knowledge about the cause of the response management and its outcomes. According to the findings of the ‎research, it was found that the lack of Strategic thinking, lack of merit, lack of crisis management training, lack of ‎management expertise, managers&#039; daily routine, lack of information systems, and ignoring time are the cause of reaction ‎management of organizations that cause the destruction of the organization&#039;s face.‎‎</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">عدم آینده نگری برخی از مدیران سازمانهای دولتی و خصوصی و غافلگیری آنها در برابر رویدادهای مختلف نظیر حوادث طبیعی، بیانگر سبک مدیریتی خاصی است ‏که به آن مدیریت واکنشی گفته می شود. استفاده ازچنین سبکی، به دلیل کاهش اعتماد ذینفعان و کاهش سرمایه اجتماعی ، باعث تخریب چهره سازمان و برند آن ‏می‌گردد.‏&lt;br /&gt;لذا هدف این پژوهش‎ ‎دستیا‌‌بی‎ ‎به‎ ‎نظریه‌ای‎ ‎در‎ ‎خصوص شناسایی علت های مدیریت واکنشی درسازمان‌ها ، تعیین نتایج وارائه راهکارها، وهمچنین‎ ‎درک‎ ‎این‎ ‎پدیده‎ ‎در‎ ‎سازمان‎ ‎ها و تغییر در رفتارها انجام‎ ‎شده‎ ‎است‎.‎‏ ‏&lt;br /&gt;رهیافت‎ ‎پژوهش‎ ‎به‎ ‎صورت‎ ‎کیفی‎ ‎و استراتژی‎ ‎پژوهش‎ ‎مبتنی‌بر‎ ‎نظریه‌پردازی‎ ‎داده بنیاد‎ ‎است‎ .‎جهت‎ ‎گردآوری‎ ‎اطلاعات‎ ‎پژوهش‎ ‎حاضر‎ ‎از‎ ‎مصاحبه‎ ‎نیمه‌ساختار‎ ‎یافته و‎ ‎به‎ ‎منظور‎ ‎تجزیه‎ ‎وتحلیل‎ ‎داده‎ ‎ها‎ ‎ازآزمون‎ ‎های‎ ‎آماری‎ ‎دو‎ ‎جمله‎ ‎ای‎ ‎و‎ ‎فریدمن‎ ‎استفاده‎ ‎شد.‏‎ ‎نمونه‌گیری‎ ‎به روش نظری‎ ‎و‎ ‎هدفمند (قضاوتی‎ ‎و گلوله‎ ‎برفی) انجام‎ ‎شده‎ ‎است‎ ‎که‎ ‎بر‎ ‎مبنای‎ ‎آن تعداد‎ 15‎مصاحبه‎ ‎با مدیران،‎ ‎اعضاء‎ ‎هیأت‎ ‎علمی‎ ‎و‎ ‎خبرگان سازمانی که‎ ‎دارای‎ ‎تجربه‎ ‎و دانش در مورد علت مدیریت واکنشی ونتایج آن بودند،‎ ‎صورت‎ ‎گرفته‎ ‎است‎.‎‏ باتوجه‎ ‎به‎ ‎یافته‎ ‎های‎ ‎تحقیق، مشخص گردید که فقدان تفکراستراتژیک، عدم شایسته سالاری، عدم آموزش مدیریت بحران، عدم تخصص ‏مدیریتی، روزمرگی مدیران، فقدان سیستم های اطلاعاتی، و نادیده انگاشتن زمان علت مدیریت واکنشی سازمان ها می‌باشند که باعث تخریب چهره سازمان می-‏گردند.‏&lt;br /&gt;‏</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">&amp;quot;مدیریت واکنشی&amp;quot;</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">&amp;quot;پنجره های شکسته&amp;quot;</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">&amp;quot;چهرة سازمانی&amp;quot;</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">&amp;quot; رویدادهای مختلف&amp;quot;.‏</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_4340_2abf67c83933b6c00750689d96df9637.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
