<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 4 (پیاپی 20)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The relationship between customer mistreatment, emotional dissonance and emotional exhaustion with employee retaliation: Moderator role of supervisory support climate (Case of: Mellat Bank customers in Mashhad)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رابطه میان بدرفتاری مشتریان، ناهمسانی هیجانی و فزسودگی عاطفی با رفتارهای تالفی جویانه کارکنان: نقش تعدیلگر جو حمایت سرپرست</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>81</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>94</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">4194</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدمهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>پرهیزگار</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>صدیقه</FirstName>
					<LastName>باقری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study aimed to investigate the impact of customer mistreatment on Mallet Bank employees’ retaliation in Mashhad, Iran. In this regard, the impact of customer mistreatment on emotional dissonance and emotional exhaustion was investigated. Also, the influence of these variables on employee retaliation by considering the moderator role of supervisory support climate in the relationship between emotional exhaustion and employee retaliation were evaluated. This study is applicable, descriptive and analytic survey. In this respect, a questionnaire was used to collect data. Confirmatory factor analysis and Cronbach&#039;s alpha coefficient were used to assess validity and the internal consistency of the instrument, respectively. To investigate the effect of independent variables on the dependent variable, the method of structural equation modeling in AMOS software was used. Subsequently, multiple regression analysis was conducted to investigate the effect of moderator role of supervisory support climate. Findings revealed that customer mistreatment has a significant influence on both emotional dissonance and emotional exhaustion. Emotional exhaustion has a crucial effect on employees’ retaliation. On the other hand, emotional dissonance on employees’ retaliation has an insignificant impact. The moderating role of supervisory support climate in the relationship between emotional exhaustion and employee retaliation is also confirmed in this study.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از این مطالعه بررسی تاثیر بدرفتاری مشتریان بر رفتارهای تلافی‌جویانه کارکنان شعب بانک ملت مشهد است. در این راستا تاثیر بدرفتاری مشتریان بر ایجاد ناهمسانی هیجانی و فرسودگی عاطفی در کارکنان بررسی شده است. همچنین تاثیر این متغیرها بر رفتارهای تلافی‌جویانه کارکنان با درنظرگرفتن تعدیل‌گری جو حمایت سرپرست در رابطه بین فرسودگی عاطفی و رفتارهای تلافی‌جویانه ارزیابی شده است. پژوهش حاضر از نظر هدف کاربردی و به‌لحاظ روش، پیمایشی تحلیلی است. برای جمع آوری اطلاعات از پرسشنامه استفاده شده است. تکنیک تحلیل عاملی تاییدی جهت بررسی روایی سازه و ضریب آلفای کرونباخ جهت سنجش انسجام درونی ابزارها مورد استفاده قرار گرفته است. جهت بررسی تاثیر متغیرهای مستقل بر وابسته، از روش مدل‌یابی معادلات ساختاری بااستفاده از نرم‌افزار آموس و به‌منظور بررسی نقش تعدیل‌گر جو حمات سرپرست، از تحلیل رگرسیون چندگانه سلسله‌مراتبی استفاده شده‌‌است. یافته‌ها نشان‌ می‌دهد که بدرفتاری مشتریان بر فرسودگی عاطفی و ناهمسانی هیجانی کارکنان تاثیر مثبت و معناداری دارد. فرسودگی عاطفی بر رفتارهای تلافی‌جویانه کارکنان تاثیر قابل‌توجهی دارد. درحالی‌که تاثیر مستقیم ناهمسانی هیجانی بر رفتارهای تلافی‌جویانه کارکنان معنادار نیست. از سوی دیگر نقش تعدیل‌گر جو حمایت سرپرست در رابطه بین فرسودگی عاطفی و رفتارهای تلافی‌جویانه نیز در این مطالعه تایید شده است .</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفتارهای تلافی‌جویانه کارکنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جو حمایت سرپرست</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بدرفتاری مشتریان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ناهمسانی هیجانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرسودگی عاطفی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_4194_882cbb7f978ca8f9a91e2a7c8a3b99e1.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
