<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 4 (پیاپی 20)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Explaining the Model of Factors Affecting the Promotion of the Tourism Brand of the Islamic Republic of Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تبیین مدل عوامل موثر بر ارتقاء برند گردشگری جمهوری اسلامی ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>95</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>106</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">4196</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>نساجی کامرانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اوژن</FirstName>
					<LastName>کریمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمودی میمند</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>درویش</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The rapid growth of tourism as an industry has led many countries to consider tourism as an important component in the growth and development of the national economy and for this reason, from the perspective of development, today, based on gross domestic product, exports and employment, tourism is the largest industry in the world. On the other hand, it is noted that tourists, based on their mental images of different places, are determined to determine the destination of their travel, and this is where the importance of the brand&#039;s role in tourism appears. Therefore, in this research, along with the study of upstream documents; based on Delphi methodology, the opinion of experts from the field of tourism, especially policy makers in this field as well as university researchers in the field of brand and tourism, have been compiled to develop a model for promotion of tourism brand of the Islamic Republic of Iran. Also, cognitive mapping is used to draw and understand the relationships between model components. In the model obtained from the research, four main factors affecting the promotion of the tourism brand in Iran, including the factors of the tourism industry, the factors of the tourism destination, the factors of the state and government and the factors of the international environment, are identified and the relationship between them and their 16 sub-factors are analyzed together.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">رشد سریع گردشگری به مثابه صنعت، موجب شده تا بسیاری از کشورها گردشگری را مولفه مهمی در رشد و توسعه اقتصاد ملی بنگرند و به همین دلیل از منظر توسعه، امروزه بر اساس درآمد ناخالص داخلی، صادرات و اشتغال، گردشگری بزرگ ترین صنعت در جهان است. از طرفی ملاحظه می شود که گردشگران بر اساس تصاویر ذهنی خود از مکان های مختلف، اقدام به تعیین مقصد گردشگری مورد نظر خود می نمایتد و در اینجاست که اهمیت نقش برند در گردشگری نمایان می شود. لذا در این پژوهش ضمن مطالعه اسناد بالادستی، بر اساس فن دلفی نظر متخصصین حوزه گردشگری خصوصا مدیران سیاست‌گذار در این حوزه و همچنین محققین دانشگاهی در زمینه برند و گردشگری به منظور تدوین مدل ارتقاء برند گردشگری جمهوری اسلامی ایران گردآوری شده است. همچنین از نگاشت‌های شناختی برای ترسیم و درک بهتر روابط بین اجزای مدل استفاده شده است. در مدل حاصل از پژوهش، چهار مجموعه عامل اصلی موثر بر ارتقاء برند گردشگری ایران در سطح بین المللی شامل عوامل صنعت گردشگری، عوامل مقصد گردشگری، عوامل دولت و عوامل محیط بین المللی شناسایی و ارتباط بین آنها و 16 عامل فرعی زیر مجموعه آنها با یکدیگر مورد تحلیل قرار گرفته است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گردشگری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">برند</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">برند گردشگری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل برند گردشگری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_4196_7986d9c42b920cc969e5660be8e949ea.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
