<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 (پیاپی 29)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Designing and Explaining the Model of Strategic Control with Self-Controlling Approach Based on Data-Based Theorizing</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی و تبیین الگوی راهبردی کنترل استراتژیک با رویکرد خود کنترلی بر مبنای نظریه پردازی داده بنیاد</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>11</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>32</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">6338</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.30473/ipom.2019.42938.3370</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعیده</FirstName>
					<LastName>سیادت</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدتقی</FirstName>
					<LastName>امینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدمهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>پرهیزگار</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جمشید</FirstName>
					<LastName>سالار</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Nowadays, competition in various business environments requires confrontation with plenty of opportunities and challenges. It is therefore necessary for the managers to apply some strategic control model for the purpose of predicting, effective strategic guidance of the organization as well as timely control and response to the movements of the rivals and environmental developments. Such a strategic control model should be able to turn the strategic control to a continuous, internal and ongoing stream in addition to guaranteeing the survival of the organization and realization of the organizational goals. The present research is an attempt to explain the pattern of strategic control with a self-control approach using qualitative research method and grounded theory. Data sampling has been made using purposeful and snowball sampling methods. Semi-structured interviews have been used as the tool for gathering data and data analysis has been carried out using grounded theory paradigmatic model. The results confirm that the main category is &quot;implementation of strategic control in the organization with an internal look at strategic control (self-control)&quot; which has been developed by the causal factors and a set of contextual and intervening elements that lead to two main organizational and individual outcomes through strategies.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه رقابت در فضای کسب‌وکارهای مختلف مستلزم مواجهه با فرصت‌ها و چالش‌های فروانی است. ازاین‌رو، ضروری است تا مدیران به‌منظور پیش‌بینی و هدایت راهبردی اثربخش سازمان‌های خود، همچنین کنترل و پاسخگویی به -موقع در واکنش به تحرکات رقبا و تحولات محیطی، از نوعی الگوی کنترل -استراتژیک استفاده نمایند که علاوه‌بر ضمانت حفظ حیات و بقای سازمان و تحقق اهداف سازمان، کنترل را به امری مستمر، درونی و جاری در سازمان تبدیل نماید. بنابراین؛ پژوهش حاضر با بهره‌گیری از شیوة پژوهشی کیفی و روش داده بنیاد به تبیین الگوی کنترل استراتژیک با رویکرد خودکنترلی پرداخته است. در این پژوهش نمونه‌گیری به روش‌های هدفمند، نظری و گلوله برفی انجام شده، ابزار گردآوری داده‌ها در این پژوهش، مصاحبه‌های نیمه ساختاریافته و شیوة تجزیه و تحلیل آن با استفاده از مدل پارادیمی داده بنیاد انجام شده است. نتایج حاصله مؤید آن -است که مقولة اصلی «پیاده‌سازی کنترل استراتژیک در سازمان و نگاهی -درونی به کنترل استراتژیک» است که با توجه به عوامل علّی، عوامل زمینه‌ای و عوامل مداخله‌گر شکل گرفته است و از طریق راهبردها، به دودسته پیامد اصلی شامل پیامدهای سازمانی و پیامدهای فردی منجر می‌شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کنترل استراتژیک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خودکنترلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظریة داده بنیاد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگو</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_6338_46daa1663ba8b09fd474cd3f826f9d29.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 (پیاپی 29)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Conceptual Modeling of the Entrepreneurial Government in Iran With the Qualitative Meta-Analysis Approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ترسیم الگوی مفهومی دولت کارآفرین در ایران با رویکرد فراتحلیل کیفی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>33</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>50</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">6343</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.30473/ipom.2019.48893.3817</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رحمان</FirstName>
					<LastName>رنجبر</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری گروه علوم سیاسی، سیاست‌گذاری عمومی، واحد تهران مرکزی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بابک</FirstName>
					<LastName>نادرپور</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه علوم سیاسی، واحد تهران مرکزی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>غلامحسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسینی‌نیا</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه کسب‌وکار جدید، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نادر</FirstName>
					<LastName>هوشمندیار</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه علوم سیاسی، واحد تهران مرکزی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The recreating government with the entrepreneurial approach is not a simple reconsideration or partial interpretation of management, but a comprehensive change in the role of community management and the relationship between government and citizens that replaces directing leadership with enterprise. This qualitative meta-analysis study investigates the studies on the field of entrepreneurial government and provides a regular formulation of them. To accomplish this, 68 articles and reports on the entrepreneurial government have been searched through scientific databases of the country and abroad over the past 10 years (2008-2018) and were reviewd in two sections of &quot;Descriptive meta-analysis findings&quot; and &quot;Qualitative evaluation of articles&quot;. A meta-analysis of the Entrepreneurial Government papers shows that studies in this field are less focused on operational aspects and more dealt with theoretical discussions and general concepts. In most of these studies, the indices concerning the entrepreneurial government theory have not been explained in accordance with the indigenous conditions of Iran. In this study, however, the conceptual model of the entrepreneurial government has been outlined in terms of the Iranian indigenous conditions including the macro policies, good governance, social justice, mission orientation, social-cultural values, decentralization, customer orientation, market orientation, and advocacy.
 </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">بازآفرینی دولت با رویکرد کارآفرینی تجدیدنظر ساده یا تفسیر جزئی در شیوة مدیریت نیست، بلکه تغییری همه‌جانبه در نقش مدیریت جامعه و رابطة بین دولت و شهروندان است که هدایت‌گری را جایگزین تصدی‌گری می‌کند. این پژوهش با روش فراتحلیل کیفی به بررسی پژوهش‌های حوزۀ دولت کارآفرین پرداخته و صورت‌بندی منظمی از آن‌ها ارائه می‌‌دهد. 68 مقاله و گزارش درزمینۀ دولت کارآفرین با جست‌وجو در پایگاه اطلاعات علمی داخلی و خارجی در بازۀ زمانی 10 سال (1387-1397) و در دو بخش «یافته‌های توصیفی فراتحلیل» و «ارزیابی کیفی مقاله‌ها» بررسی شده‌اند. مطالعات فراتحلیل مقاله‌های دولت کارآفرین نشان می‎دهد پژوهش‌های این حوزه کمتر ناظر بر جنبه‌های عملیاتی بوده و بیشتر بر بحث‌های نظری و ارائۀ مفاهیم کلی تمرکز کرده‌اند. در اغلب پژوهش‌های صورت پذیرفته؛ شاخص‌های نظریۀ دولت کارآفرین متناسب با شرایط بومی ایران تبیین نشده است، لیکن در این مطالعه مدل مفهومی دولت کارآفرین با لحاظ شرایط بومی ایران ترسیم شده که ابعاد آن شامل سیاست‌های کلان، حکمرانی خوب، عدالت اجتماعی، رسالت محوری، عوامل فرهنگی- اجتماعی، تمرکز‌زدایی، مشتری مداری، بازارگرایی و حمایت و پشتیبانی است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوی مفهومی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارآفرینی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارآفرینی دولتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دولت کارآفرین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش فراتحلیل کیفی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_6343_8539ac94b325d854c128bcef02b4b6bb.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 (پیاپی 29)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Monitoring the Role of Organizational Citizenship Behavior on the Performance of Staff and Professors of Payame Noor University</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>پایش نقش رفتار شهروندی سازمانی بر عملکرد کارکنان و استادان دانشگاه پیام نور</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>51</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>58</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">6366</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.30473/ipom.2019.6366</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجید</FirstName>
					<LastName>واحدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت آموزشی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پروانه</FirstName>
					<LastName>صادقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد گروه مدیریت، واحد تبریز، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تبریز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>17</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study aimed to investigate the impact of organizational citizenship behavior and organizational performance of faculty members and staff of Payame Noor University of East Azarbaijan province. The statistical population of the study consisted of 806 teachers and staff of Payame Noor University of East Azarbaijan. Among them, 225 are faculty members and 581 are staff. The data collection instrument in this study were standard questionnaires of organizational citizenship behavior (OCB) and Organizational Performance of Hershey and Goldsmiths. Descriptive and inferential statistical methods were used to analyze the collected data. At the inferential level, to test the research hypotheses, Pearson&#039;s r test and linear regression test were used via SPSS software after determining the distribution of the data related to the research variables through Kolmogorov-Smirnov test. The results confirmed the main and sub-hypotheses of the research at 95% confidence level based on statistical tests. In other words, it was found that there is a positive significant relationship between all components of organizational citizenship behavior and organizational performance of teachers and staff of Payame Noor University of East Azarbaijan.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این تحقیق که به بررسی تأثیر رفتار شهروندی سازمانی، عملکرد سازمانی استادان و کارکنان دانشگاه پیام نور استان آذربایجان شرقی، پرداخته شد. جامعة آماری تحقیق کلیة استادان و کارکنان دانشگاه پیام نور استان آذربایجان شرقی بوده که تعداد آن‌ها 806 نفر است. که از این تعداد 225 نفر هیئت‌علمی و 581 نفر شامل کارکنان است. ابزار جمع‌آوری اطلاعات در تحقیق حاضر، پرسشنامه بوده که شامل پرسشنامه استاندارد رفتار شهروندی سازمانی پادساکف (&lt;strong&gt;OCB&lt;/strong&gt;) است. همچنین پرسشنامه استاندارد عملکرد سازمانی هرسی و گلداسمیت بود. به‌منظور تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌های به دست آمده از پرسشنامه‌های جمع‌آوری شده از روش‌های آماری توصیفی و استنباطی استفاده شد و در سطح استنباطی برای آزمون فرضیه‌های تحقیق، پس از تعیین توزیع داده‌های مربوط به متغیرهای تحقیق براساس آزمون کولوموگروف اسمیرنف و آزمون &lt;strong&gt;r&lt;/strong&gt; پیرسون و آزمون رگرسیون خطی با استفاده از نرم‌افزار &lt;strong&gt;SPSS&lt;/strong&gt; تعیین گردید. نتایج به دست آمده حاکی از آن است که فرضیات اصلی و فرعی تحقیق، با توجه به آزمون‌های آماری، در سطح اطمینان 95% تأیید می‌گردند. به‌عبارت‌دیگر، مشخص شد که رابطة مثبت و معنی‌داری میان همه مؤلفه‌های رفتار شهروندی سازمانی و عملکرد سازمانی استادان و کارکنان دانشگاه پیام نور استان آذربایجان شرقی وجود دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفتار شهروندی سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد سازمان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_6366_4921a2b7cd37ad034db3c227acf20d63.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 (پیاپی 29)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Disruptive Behaviors of Staff at Payame Noor University of Alborz Province and Its Causing Factors with a Mixed Approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رفتارهای مخرب‌ کاری کارکنان در دانشگاه پیام نور استان البرز و عوامل به وجودآورنده آن با رویکرد آمیخته</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>59</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>78</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">6375</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.30473/ipom.2019.48575.3800</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مینا</FirstName>
					<LastName>مسلمی کویری</LastName>
<Affiliation>مربی،گروه مدیریت، واحد اشکذر، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، اشکذر، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5609-2387</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اوژن</FirstName>
					<LastName>کریمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شمس‌الدین</FirstName>
					<LastName>نیک‌منش</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه مدیریت دولتی،دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Malicious behaviors, which are rapidly increasing in the modern era, will have irreparable negative consequences for organizations, so it has attracted researchers&#039; attention in recent decades. In this regard, the present study was conducted to identify the factors that cause destructive behaviors of staff at Payam Noor University of Karaj. This study is a descriptive survey in terms of purpose and method of data collection. In addition, the present study has been done using a qualitative-quantitative research methodology. In the first stage, to identify the factors causing malicious behaviors, 10 professors, faculty members and experts were interviewd face-to-face. A qualitative content analysis was used to design a questionnaire for quantitative part. The statistical population of the study consisted of 245 employees of Payam-e-Noor University of Alborz. The sample size was 150 individuals selected using Cochran formula. The instrument for collecting data was standard questionnairs. The reliability of these questionnaires which was calculated through Cronbach&#039;s alpha coefficient formula was 0.91. Structural equation modeling software was used to analyze the collected data. The results indicate that emotional intelligence and leader-member interaction have the opposite effect on malicious behaviors, and in contrast, injustice, stress, and personality features, including introversion, incompatibility, lack of conscientiousness, neuroticism, and inattention to experience have direct impact on destructive behaviors.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">رفتارهای مخرب که در عصر حاضر با سرعت زیادی در حال افزایش است، پیامدها و آثار منفی جبران ناپذیری برای سازمان‌ها در پی خواهند داشت. لذا، در طی دهه‌های اخیر توجه محققان را به خود جلب کرده است. در همین راستا پژوهش حاضر با هدف شناخت عوامل به وجودآورنده رفتارهای مخرب کاری کارکنان در دانشگاه پیام نور کرج صورت گرفت. این پژوهش از لحاظ هدف کاربردی و از نظر شیوة جمع‌آوری داده‌ها توصیفی پیمایشی است. همچنین پژوهش حاضر با استفاده از روش‌شناسی پژوهش آمیخته (کیفی- کمی) مورد تحلیل قرار گرفته است. در مرحلة اول جهت شناسایی عوامل به وجودآورنده رفتارهای مخرب، مصاحبه با تعداد 10 نفر از اعضای هیئت‌علمی و خبرگـان در حوزة رفتار کارکنان صورت گرفت و با استفاده از روش تحلیـل محتوای کیفی تجزیه و تحلیل و پرسشنامه‌ای طراحی شد که مبنای پژوهش کمی قرار گرفته است. جامعۀ آماری مربوط به مطالعۀ کمی، شامل کارکنان دانشگاه پیام نور استان البرز به تعداد 245 نفر بوده است که حجم نمونه با استفاده از فرمول کوکران، 150 نفر محاسبه شد. ابزار گردآوری در این پژوهش، پرسشنامة استاندارد بوده که پایایی این پرسشنامه‌ها با استفاده از ضریب آلفای کرونباخ 91/0 تأیید شد. جهت تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌های جمع‌آوری شده از نرم‌افزار مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری اسمارت پی ال اس استفاده شد. نتایج یافته‌ها حاکی از آن است که هوش عاطفی و تعامل رهبر – عضو دارای تأثیر معکوس بر رفتارهای مخرب کاری هستند و در مقابل بی‌عدالتی، استرس و ویژگی شخصیت شامل درون‌گرایی، عدم توافق‌پذیری، عدم وظیفه‌شناسی، روان‌رنجوری و عدم‌گشودگی به تجارب تأثیر مستقیم بر رفتارهای مخرب کاری دارند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفتارهای مخرب‌ کاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هوش عاطفی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بی‌عدالتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استرس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ویژگی شخصیت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_6375_e003fb196d7a75b4f27c0bcafef8455c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 (پیاپی 29)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Pathology of the Oil Ministry Intellectual Capital</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>آسیب‌شناسی سرمایةفکری وزارت نفت</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>79</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>92</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">6617</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.30473/ipom.2019.48129.3765</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فریدون</FirstName>
					<LastName>قاسمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری گروه مدیریت دولتی، مرکز آموزش بین‌ا‌لملل قشم، واحد علوم و تحقیقات، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، قشم، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کرم اله</FirstName>
					<LastName>دانش‌فرد</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه مدیربت دولتی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نجف بیگی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه مدیربت دولتی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدعلی</FirstName>
					<LastName>افشارکاظمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه مدیریت صنعتی، واحد تهران مرکزی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>17</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The main purpose of the research is the pathology of the Ministry of Oil intellectual capital. The present study is of applied purpose and of descriptive survey method. The statistical population consists of 900 oil ministry research managers and the sample is estimated to be 269. The tool was a questionnaire and its validity was estimated to be 94%. The results showed that human capital constituents ranked first in order of importance of experience and expertise in the first rank, competence and skills second, staff motivation and satisfaction, teamwork morale, creativity And problem-solving and decision-making innovation ranks third to sixth. The components of Structural Capital are the processes and processes ranked first, organizational structure ranked second, organizational culture ranked third, information systems ranked fourth, organizational knowledge management ranked fifth, human resource management practices ranked sixth, intellectual property ranked Seventh, R&amp;D ranked eighth, and product and process innovation ninth. The constituent components of social capital are ranked first, shared language second, trust, commitment, reciprocity, reciprocal interactions, and interactions ranging from third to seventh. And all three aspects of human capital, structural capital and social capital have a good status in the Ministry of Oil and structural capital is better than the other two dimensions.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف اصلی تحقیق آسیب‌شناسی سرمایة فکری وزارت نفت است. پژوهش حاضر از نظر هدف کاربردی و از نظر روش توصیفی پیمایشی است. جامعة آماری 900 نفر از مدیران محققان وزارت نفت بوده و نمونة آماری 269 نفر برآورد شده است. ابزار پژوهش پرسشنامه بوده و میزان اعتبار آن 94 درصد تخمین‌زده شد. نتایج نشان داد، شاخص‌های تشکیل‌دهندة سرمایة انسانی به ترتیب اهمیت تجربه و تخصص در رتبة اول، شایستگی و مهارت‌ها در رتبة دوم، انگیزش و رضایت کارکنان، روحیة کار تیمی، خلاقیت و نوآوری قابلیت حل مسئله و تصمیم‌گیری در رتبه‌های سوم تا ششم قرار دارند. مؤلفه‌های تشکیل‌دهندة سرمایة ساختاری به ترتیب روند‌ها و فرایندها در رتبة اول، ساختار سازمانی در رتبة دوم، فرهنگ سازمانی رتبة سوم، سیستم‌ اطلاعاتی در رتبة چهارم، مدیریت دانش سازمانی در رتبة پنجم، اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی در رتبة ششم، مالکیت معنوی در رتبة هفتم، تحقیق و توسعه در رتبة هشتم و نوآوری در محصولات و فرایندها در رتبة نهم قرار دارند. مؤلفه‌های تشکیل‌دهندة سرمایة اجتماعی ترتیب ارزش‌های مشترک در رتبة اول، زبان مشترک در رتبة دوم، اعتماد، تعهد، عمل متقابل و دوجانبه، تعاملات موجود در شبکه و تعدد تعاملات در رتبة سوم تا هفتم قرار دارند و نیز هر سه بعد سرمایة انسانی، سرمایة ساختاری و سرمایة اجتماعی از وضعیت مناسبی در وزات نفت برخوردار بوده و سرمایة ساختاری در مقایسه با دو بعد دیگر وضعیت بهتری را داراست.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">واژه‌های کلیدی: سرمایة فکری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة ساختاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">وزارت نفت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_6617_a26db31e45f215418d25bfa799e3635e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 (پیاپی 29)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Designing and Explaining a Pattern to Manage Imbalance Between Manager’s Responsibility and Authority in Public Organizations</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی و تبیین الگویی برای مدیریت عدم تعادل میان مسئولیت و اختیار مدیران در سازمان‌های دولتی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>93</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>112</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">6340</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.30473/ipom.2019.44639.3500</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سولماز</FirstName>
					<LastName>الهامی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>رسولی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدمهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>فراحی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The imbalance between responsibility and authority means disregarding one of the most important principles of delegation that, given the implications of this issue for the individual and the present research organization, seeks to identify its various dimensions and explain the balancing strategies by analyzing this phenomenon. The strategy used in this study is grounded theory based on emerging approach. The study population consisted of managers of public organizations in Mashhad, among whom 19 were selected through targeted sampling method to reach the theoretical saturation.The research tool was a semi-structured interview. MAXQDA qualitative analysis software was utilized to analyze the data, and open, axial and selective coding processes were usesd in this regard. The accomplished analysis using continuous comparisons in the actual and theoretical coding process showed 193 codes, 72 concepts, 16 classes, and 6 categories, which led to the final model of research on the axial category, named the imbalance between responsibility and authority. Then, the final model of imbalance management which is lucrative to decline negative imbalance consequences and empower its positive results was designed with the help of individual and organizational strategies.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">عدم تعادل میان مسئولیت و اختیارات به معنای در نظر نگرفتن یکی از مهم‌ترین اصول تفویض اختیار است که با توجه به پیامدهای این موضوع برای فرد و سازمان پژوهش حاضر در تلاش است تا با واکاوی این پدیده، زوایای گوناگون آن را شناسایی و راهکارهای متعادل&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;سازی را تبیین کند. استراتژی مورد استفاده تحقیق داده‌بنیاد و مبتنی‌بر رویکرد ظاهر شونده است. جامعه مورد مطالعه مدیران سازمان‌های دولتی در شهر مشهد می‌باشند که 19 نفر تا رسیدن به اشباع نظری با استفاده از روش نمونه‌گیری هدفمند انتخاب شدند. ابزار پژوهش، مصاحبة نیمه ساختاریافته بود. در تحلیل داده‌ها از نرم‌افزار تحلیل کیفی MAXQDA کمک گرفته شد و فرایند‌های کدگذاری باز، محوری و انتخابی در این خصوص انجام شد. تجزیه و تحلیل انجام شده از طریق مقایسه مستمر در فرایند کدگذاری حقیقی و نظری، 193 کد، 72 مفهوم، 16 طبقه و 6 مقوله را نشان داد که منجر به ظهور مدل نهایی پژوهش پیرامون مقوله محوری، با عنوان عدم تعادل مسئولیت و اختیارات شد. پس از آن مدل نهایی مدیریت عدم تعادل که می‌تواند به کمک استراتژی‌های سازمانی و فردی اثرات منفی عدم تعادل را کاهش داده و اثرات مثبت آن را تقویت نماید ترسیم شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اختیار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مسئولیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عدم تعادل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظریة داده‌بنیاد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رویکرد ظاهرشونده</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_6340_ca1ed1c66f7d1ac32f237dbc10786f37.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 (پیاپی 29)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Strategic Commitment for Middle Managers: Investigating the Impact of Organizational Justice, Senior Management Support for Change, and Participation in Decision Making</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تعهد استراتژیک مدیران میانی: بررسی تأثیر عدالت سازمانی، حمایت مدیریت ارشد از تغییر و مشارکت در تصمیم‎گیری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>113</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>124</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">6339</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.30473/ipom.2019.47772.3737</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ناصر</FirstName>
					<LastName>صنوبر</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت، دانشگاه تبریز، تبریز، ایران.</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7354-0222</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید صمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت ، دانشگاه تبریز، تبریز، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پویا</FirstName>
					<LastName>بهزادنیا</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانش آموخته کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت کسب و کار، دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت، دانشگاه تبریز، تبریز، ایران.</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6728-1500</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>یونس پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانش آموخته مدیریت کسب و کار، گروه مدیریت دانشگاه تبریز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>30</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>   One of the key issues for governmental organizations is the proper implementation of change strategy and organizational improvement programs, and middle managers, especially their relationship quality, play a key role in implementing the strategy. The present study aims to investigate the impact of organizational justice, senior managers’ support for change, and participation in decision making on strategic commitment of middle managers. Data were analyzed using SPSS, AMOS 21 software and regression analysis. The findings show that there is a positive relationship between organizational justice and high quality relationships and the presence of perceived organizational justice leads to high relationships quality and commitment to organizational goals. Also, according to the results of this study, no specific relationship between senior manager management and commitment to change was demonstrated without considering the ongoing role of high quality relationships.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">یکی از مسایل مهم  سازمان‎های دولتی اجرای صحیح استراتژی تغییر و برنامه های بهبود سازمانی است و مدیران میانی و به‌ویژه کیفیت روابط بین آن‌ها، نقش کلیدی در اجرای استراتژی دارد.  پژوهش حاضر در نظر دارد تأثیر عدالت سازمانی، حمایت مدیریت ارشد از تغییر و مشارکت در تصمیم‎گیری را بر تعهد استراتژیک مدیران میانی بررسی کند.در این پژوهش با جمع‎آوری پرسشنامه از میان 77 نفر از مدیران دستگاه‎های اجرایی استان آذربایجان شرقی به روش تصادفی در دسترس و  پردازش و بررسی فرضیه‌ها و تجزیه ‌و تحلیل داده‌ها از روش رگرسیون توسط نرم‌افزارهای SPSS&lt;strong&gt;،&lt;/strong&gt;MOS 21  استفاده شده است. یافته‌ها نشان می‎دهد بین عدالت سازمانی و روابط با کیفیت بالا رابطة مثبتی وجود داشته و حضور عدالت سازمانی درک‎شده باعث ایجاد روابط با کیفیت بالا می‎شود، تعهد به اهداف سازمانی نیز افزایش می‎یابد. همچنین طبق نتایج این تحقیق، ارتباط خاصی بین مدیریت مدیران ارشد و تعهد به تغییر بدون در نظر گرفتن نقش مستمر روابط با کیفیت بالا اثبات نشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">واژه‌های کلیدی: روابط با کیفیت بالا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تعهد استراتژیک مدیران میانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حمایت مدیریت ارشد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عدالت سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشارکت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_6339_f85fd589b6ddb435a867609d4adfec77.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 (پیاپی 29)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Analyzing the Behavior Pattern of Invisible Employees in the Organization</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>واکاوی الگوی رفتاری کارکنان نامرئی در سازمان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>125</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>140</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">6360</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.30473/ipom.2019.49228.3839</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>منطقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه مدیریت، موسسه آموزشی و پژوهشی امام خمینی (ره)، قم، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Organizations seek to accomplish their goals by hiring their staff. Organizational conditions in terms of physical space, workplace and laws, as well as the ethical and behavioral characteristics of employees provide the context for some employees to elude from work and absent in performance while they are present physically at work. Investigating the behavioral pattern of invisible employees is the aim of this research which has been done based on the foundation data method. The study, which was conducted in cultural organizations and educational centers in Qom, was based on limited theoretical literature and mainly based on interviews with 12 people (snowball method) from professors and experts in the humanities. The propositions of the study were obtained in the form of open coding, selective coding, and axial coding. Internal validity coefficient was used to ensure the validity of research and three stage-qualitative reliability was used to calculate research reliability. The results of this study show that proper staff selection, reforming structures and laws, reinforcing religious and spiritual beliefs, making employees aware of the consequences of their actions, and reforming socio-political relationships can greatly reduce the phenomenon of invisible employees.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">سازمان‌ها، با استخدام و به‌کارگیری کارکنان، درصدد تحقق اهداف خود هستند. شرایط سازمان‌ها ازنظر فضای فیزیکی، کاری و قوانین و همچنین خصوصیات اخلاقی و رفتاری کارکنان زمینه‌ای را فراهم می‌سازد که برخی از کارکنان، از زیر کار شانه خالی کنند و در عین حضور، ازنظر عملکرد غایب باشند. بررسی الگوی رفتاری کارکنان نامرئی، موضوع این پژوهش است که با روش داده بنیاد انجام شده است. این پژوهش که در سازمان‌های فرهنگی و مراکز آموزشی شهر قم انجام شده است؛ بر مبنای ادبیات نظری محدود و عمدتاً با تکیه‌بر مصاحبه با 12 نفر (به صورت گلوله برفی) از استادان و خبرگان در حوزه‌های علوم انسانی انجام شده است. گزاره‌های به دست آمده از مطالعات نظری و مصاحبه‌ها در قالب کدگذاری باز، کدگذاری انتخابی و کدگذاری محوری انجام شد. برای روایی تحقیق، از ضریب توافق درونی و برای شناسایی پایایی تحقیق از سه مرحلة پایایی کیفی استفاده شده است. نتایج این تحقیق نشان می‌دهد که گزینش مناسب کارکنان، اصلاح ساختارها و قوانین، تقویت باورهای مذهبی و معنوی، آشناسازی کارکنان از پیامدهای عملکرد خود و اصلاح روابط سیاسی – اجتماعی می‌تواند کمک شایانی به کاهش پدیدة کارکنان نامرئی کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارکنان نامرئی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">از زیرکاردرروی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">داده‌بنیاد</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_6360_2493b20260699993e283a41310e4baf0.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 (پیاپی 29)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Designing a philanthropic leadership model in organization management</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی مدل رهبری نوع دوستانه در مدیریت سازمان دولتی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>140</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>154</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">6486</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.30473/ipom.2020.50196.3919</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>عماری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، واحد بناب، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، بناب، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سارا</FirstName>
					<LastName>امیرحصاری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت بازرگانی، گرایش بازاریابی، واحد عجب‌شیر، دانشگاه آزاد، عجب‌شیر، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>قره بیگلو</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، واحد عجب‌شیر، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>بوداقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، ‌واحد تبریز، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تبریز، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>11</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Abstract
&lt;span&gt;The main purpose of this research is to conceptualize and implement &quot;altruistic leadership&quot; in the management of government organizations. The method of this research is mixed. The statistical population of this research in the qualitative section was the professors working in the seminaries of East Azerbaijan province, and in quantitative section was the students studying in the seminaries of East Azerbaijan province. For data analysis, hidden content analysis was used in the qualitative part and confirmatory factor analysis was used in the quantitative section. After analyzing the data for this structure, five categories of social norms, taboos, inappropriate social behaviors, human rights and improper individual behaviors along with 24 items were identified based on the relevant verses and hadiths. Re-conceptualizing the structure of altruistic leadership based on the teachings of Islam is an aspect of innovation in this research.&lt;/span&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;span lang=&quot;FA&quot;&gt;نیت اصلی این پژوهش مفهوم‌سازی و عملیاتی کردن &quot;رهبری نوع‌دوستانه&quot; در مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی است. روش این پژوهش آمیخته است. جامعة آماری پژوهش در بخش کیفی &quot; اساتید شاغل در حوزه‌های علمیه استان آذربایجان شرقی&quot; و در بخش کمی &quot;دانشجویان حوزه‌های علمیة استان آذربایجان شرقی&quot; است. برای تحلیل داده‌ها در بخش کیفی از تحلیل محتوای پنهان و در بخش کمی از تحلیل عامل تأییدی استفاده شده است. بعد از تحلیل داده‌ها برای این سازه، با استناد به آیات و احادیث مرتبط، پنج مقوله هنجارهای اجتماعی، تابوها، رفتارهای ناشایست اجتماعی، حقوق انسانی و رفتارهای ناشایست فردی به همراه 24 آیتم شناسایی شدند. مفهوم‌سازی مجدد سازه رهبری نوع‌دوستانه بر اساس آموزه‌های دین اسلام، جنبه نوآوری این پژوهش محسوب می‌شود.&lt;/span&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">واژگان کلیدی: رهبری نوع‌دوستانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازاریابی خیرخواهانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازاریابی اسلامی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حس نوع‌دوستی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_6486_42c4f4199ea0fbea46116a6bed4f4cd6.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 (پیاپی 29)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigating the Effect of Quentum Management Skills on Employees&#039; Performance Based On the Role of Knowledge Capacity and Knowledge Sharing
 (Case Study: Beheshti University of Medical Sciences(</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر مهارت‌های کوانتومی مدیریت بر عملکرد نوآورانه کارکنان با توجه به نقش ظرفیت جذب دانش و تسهیم دانش (مطالعه موردی: کارکنان دانشگاه علوم پزشکی بهشتی)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>155</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>168</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">6784</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.30473/ipom.2020.50177.3917</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>قربانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه پیام نور،  تهران،ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>متینه</FirstName>
					<LastName>مقدم</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه پیام نور، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آزین</FirstName>
					<LastName>هرندی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه پیام نور ، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Nowadays, with the formation of complex competitive environments, only organizations can continue to work to enhance their prominent organizational capabilities such as innovation. In this age, one of the ways to enhance innovation is to use quantum management skills. In this study, the relationship between quantum skills and the innovative performance of the staff of the University of Medical Sciences has been addressed. This research is descriptive-applied. To analyze the factors, correlation analysis and regression analysis were used to analyze the relationship between them. The samples were selected using a Morgan table and a stratified random sampling of 92 people. The SEM structural equation modeling and smart pls software were used. The results showed that between quantum skills and innovative performance with path coefficient of 0.212 with a significant level of 6,931 and between quantum skills and knowledge sharing with path coefficient of 0.613 with a significant amount of 20.782 and between knowledge sharing and innovative performance with the coefficient of path is 0.778 with a significant amount of 30.097. Finally, it can be concluded that one of the most important tasks of managers and leaders of Shahid Beheshti University is to identify and strengthen quantum skills among employees and motivate and tend to transfer Knowledge is among the different levels of the staff of the university, in order to enable the innovative performance of the staff of the university The better.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه با شکل‌گیری محیط‌های پیچیده رقابتی، تنها سازمان‌هایی می‌توانند به فعالیت خود ادامه دهند که عملکرد خود را در قابلیت‌های مهم سازمانی همچون نوآوری تقویت کنند. در عصر حاضر یکی از راه‌های تقویت نوآوری به‌کارگیری مهارت‌های کوانتومی مدیریت است که در این پژوهش به چگونگی ارتباط میان مهارت‌های کوانتومی و عملکرد نوآورانه کارکنان دانشگاه علوم پزشکی پرداخته ‌شده است. برای تجزیه‌وتحلیل داده‌ها از آزمون‌های تحلیل همبستگی و تحلیل رگرسیون برای تحلیل رابطه بین آن‌ها بکار گرفته شد. نمونه با استفاده از جدول مورگان و روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی طبقه‌ای 92 نفر انتخاب و از الگو‌سازی معادلات ساختاری SEM و از نرم‌افزار Smart pls استفاده شد. نتایج نشان داد که ضریب مسیر بین مهارت‌های کوانتومی و عملکرد نوآورانه 212/0 با میزان معنی‌داری 931/6 و بین مهارت‌های کوانتومی و تسهیم دانش با ضریب مسیر 613/0 با میزان معناداری 782/20 و بین تسهیم دانش و عملکرد نوآورانه با ضریب مسیر 778/0 با میزان معنی‌داری 097/30 ارتباط معنی‌دار و مثبتی وجود دارد، درنهایت می‌توان نتیجه گرفت که یکی از وظایف بسیار مهم مدیران و رهبران دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، شناسایی و تقویت مهارت‌های کوانتومی در میان کارکنان و ایجاد انگیزه و تمایل به انتقال دانش در میان سطوح مختلف کارکنان دانشگاه است تا از این طریق بتوانند عملکرد نوآورانه کارکنان دانشگاه را بهبود بخشند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مهارت‌های کوانتومی مدیریت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد نوآورانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تسهیم دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دانشگاه علوم پزشکی بهشتی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_6784_cd67568d57fa48f214745839a028c6f0.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
