<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 2 (پیاپی 30)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Performance Evaluation of Child and Adolescent Health Centers  in the Welfare Organization by AHP and ARAS Method (Case study: Semnan, Golestan and North Khorasan Provinces)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی عملکرد مراکزنگهداری نوجوانان بی سرپرست سازمان بهزیستی کشور با روش AHP و ARAS (مورد مطالعه: استان های سمنان، گلستان و خراسان شمالی)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>113</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>128</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">6654</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.30473/ipom.2020.42806.3355</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>فراتی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی اکبر</FirstName>
					<LastName>جوکار</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>لیلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>هراتی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت دولتی، واحد شاهرود، دانشگاه آزاداسلامی، شاهرود، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>04</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The aim of this study was to evaluate the performance of child and adolescent health centers over 13 years old in Semnan, Golestan and North Khorasan provinces. The present study is applied in terms of purpose, and is descriptive-survey in terms of data collection. The statistical population of the study is the managers and experts of the child centers in the provinces of Semnan, Golestan and North Khorasan to prioritize the performance evaluation indicators. A sample of 20 individuals was selected. Adolescent care centers over 13 years of age were also selected as performance evaluation samples. A questionnaire was used to collect data. AHP technique was used to prioritize the performance evaluation indicators of adolescent care centers and ARAS technique was used for comparative evaluation of selected centers in this study. The results of paired comparisons showed that the index of specialist force with the weight of 234/0 was in the first rank, the empowerment and future supply of children with a weight of 221/0 in the second rank, the atmosphere and environment of the maintenance center of children with a weight of 0/188 Third place. Similarly, the weight of each of the sub-indicators was characterized by a hierarchical process analysis technique, which was ranked below the high experience of employees with a weight of 0.071, the skill of working with adolescents weighing 0.65 and the future insurance contracts Third is located. Based on the results of the ARAS technique, center number four has the highest performance.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف پژوهش ارزیابی عملکرد مراکز نگداری نوجوانان بالای 13 سال در استان های سمنان، گلستان و خراسان شمالی می باشد. پژوهش حاضر از نظر هدف، کاربردی و از نظر جمع‌آوری داده‌ها، توصیفی- پیمایشی است. جامعه آماری پژوهش مدیران و کارشناسان مجرب مراکز نگهداری نوجوانان در استان های سمنان، گلستان و خراسان شمالی برای اولویت بندی شاخص های ارزیابی عملکرد است  و نمونه‌ای به حجم 20 نفر انتخاب شدند. همچنین مراکز نگهداری نوجوانان بالای 13 سال این استان ها به عنوان نمونه‌های ارزیابی عملکرد انتخاب شدند. برای گردآوری داده‌های پژوهش از پرسشنامه استفاده شد. جهت اولویت‌بندی شاخص‌های ارزیابی عملکرد مراکز نگهداری نوجوانان از تکنیک AHP و برای بررسی تطبیقی مراکز منتخب در پژوهش حاضر، از تکنیک ARAS استفاده شد. نتایج مقایسه‌های زوجی انجام شده نشان داد که شاخص وجود نیروی متخصص با وزن 234/0 در رتبه نخست، توانمندسازی و تامین آتیه فرزندان با وزن 221/0 در رتبه دوم، جو و محیط مرکز نگهداری فرزندان با وزن 188/0 در رتبه سوم قرار گرفته است. به همین ترتیب وزن هریک از زیر شاخص‌ها با تکنیک فرایند تحلیل سلسه‌مراتبی مشخص گردید که زیر شاخص تجربه بالای کارکنان با وزن 071/0 در رتبه نخست، مهارت کار با نوجوانان با وزن 065/0 در رتبه دوم و قراردادهای تامین آتیه بیمه در رتبه سوم قرار گرفته است. بر اساس نتایج تکنیک ARAS، مرکز شماره چهار بالاترین عملکرد را به خود اختصاص داد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خدمات بهداشتی مناسب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آموزش فرزندان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جلب مشارکت مردمی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توانمندسازی و تأمین آتیه فرزندان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_6654_19d55709de7b5b6c5f844fe2764349f0.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
