<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 2 (پیاپی 14)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Designing a Model of Performance Evaluation of the Subsidiaries Urban Management using the Balanced Score Card</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی الگوی ارزیابی عملکرد سازمان های تابعه مدیریت شهری با استفاده از توسعه کارت امتیازی متوازن</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>99</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>116</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2747</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>موسوی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیارگروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Calibri;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: small;&quot;&gt; in present research, balanced scored card has been developed to assess affiliate organizations to municipality. In spite of various designed models to assess performance of the sub-departments of Mashhad municipality, there is not a model that can consider the organization&#039;s natural differences sides together with their performance sides. Hence, the aim of this research is designing a model that considers the factors which are out of control of affiliate organizations that are effective on their performance besides presenting performance indices. In another words, the research is intended to answer the question that which internal and external factors affect on performance of affiliate organizations to Mashhad municipality indeed and what is the part of each one? The research is an applied research in terms of purpose and is a qualitative one in terms of gatherind data. In order to take the experts&#039; ideas that included managers of all organizations and affiliate organizations to Mashhad municipality (14 organizations and 6 affiliate agency), Delphi method was utilized. The ultimate designed model included 7 indices of financial clustering, 2 indices of customer clustering, 5 indices of process clustering, 2 indices of growth clustering, 7 indices of financial performance, 4 indices of customer performance, 7 indices of process performance and 7 indices of growth performance. This research helps top managers of Mashhad municipality that how they can monitor the performance of affiliate organizations regarding natural characteristics of each of them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این پژوهش، کارت امتیازی متوازن، جهت ارزیابی سازمان های وابسته به شهرداری، توسعه داده شد. با وجود الگوهای متعدد طراحی شده جهت ارزیابی عملکرد واحدهای زیر مجموعه شهرداری مشهد، الگویی که وجوه افتراق ذاتی سازمان ها را توأمان با وجوه عملکردی آنها را مورد توجه قرار دهد، ارایه نشد. از این رو، هدف از این پژوهش، تدوین الگویی است که مضاف بر ارائه ی  شاخص های عملکردی، عوامل خارج از اراده سازمان های تابعه که بر عملکرد آنها تأثیر گذار است را نیز مورد توجه قرار دهد. به عبارت دیگر این پژوهش در پی آن بوده تا به این سئوال مهم پاسخ دهد که براستی چه عوامل درونی و بیرونی بر عملکرد سازمان های تابعه شهرداری مشهد اثر گذار است و سهم هریک از این عوامل به چه میزان بوده است. این تحقیق، از حیث هدف، کاربردی و از نظر نحوه گردآوری اطلاعات، کیفی محسوب می شود. در این تحقیق، از روش دلفی برای احصای نظر خبرگان که شامل مدیران کلیه سازمان ها و شرکت های تابعه شهرداری مشهد (14 سازمان و 6 شرکت تابعه)، بوده اند، استفاده شد. الگوی طراحی شده نهایی مشتمل بر7 شاخص خوشه بندی  مالی، 2 شاخص خوشه بندی  مشتری، 5 شاخص خوشه بندی  فرایند، 2 شاخص خوشه بندی رشد، 7 شاخص عملکردی مالی، 4 شاخص عملکردی مشتری، 7 شاخص عملکردی فرایند و 7 شاخص عملکردی رشد بود. این پژوهش به مدیران ارشد شهرداری مشهد یاری می رساند که چگونه عملکرد سازمان های تابعه را با لحاظ قراردادن ویژگی های ذاتی هر یک از آنها، مورد پایش قرار دهند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خوشه بندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رتبه بندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارت امتیازی متوازن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شهرداری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_2747_92849f3f53a9bc613c8b4ac4c0aa21f7.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
