<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1  (پیاپی 9)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Managerial Competencies for Effective Management in Iranian Governmental Organizations; Grounded Data Theory</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مدیریت دولتی اثربخش در سازمان‌های ایرانی؛ نظریه‌پردازی داده‌بنیاد</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>55</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>70</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1682</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>فرهادی نژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>. استادیار گروه مدیریت دانشگاه سمنان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>لگزیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>یزدان</FirstName>
					<LastName>منصوریان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه علوم کتابداری و اطلاع‌رسانی دانشگاه خوارزمی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آذر</FirstName>
					<LastName>کفاشپور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>One of the major challenges in managing organizational effectiveness, especially in the public sector, is ensuring the availability of qualified managers at the top of the organizational pyramid. Such managers can have limited resources sector amid countless other government agencies surrounds the handle to the desired shape. The aim of this study was to explore the key competencies required for effective administration of the public sector. Since explore the subjective world, and experience has been mining their attitude requires the use of qualitative methods, on the other hand, one of the best qualitative methods for the purpose of this study is consistent examination, is grounded theory, this method was used for research. In order to collect data, semi-structured interviews that finally, after reaching theoretical saturation, with interviews with 25 managers are eligible to collect the necessary data were analyzed. After comparing the data sets collected continuous data and coding of open, axial and selective, in the form of 430 primary codes, 27 concept, and the 9 categories and 3 floors, were organized. Data analysis resulted in a grounded theory of the &quot;theory of effective management in government agencies&quot; were presented. This theory seeks to set personality traits, attitudes, behaviors, skills and competencies of a public administrator who attempts to operate effectively in Iranian governmental bodies, according to the environmental conditions of their experiences. According to this theory, effective public administration in order to achieve the desired level of effectiveness must have a series of merit, interactive and organizational. In fact, these findings suggest the effectiveness of public administration in the face of Iranian organizations which can be used as an indicator for managers and organizations that intend to evaluate the degree of their effectiveness and their managers used.
&lt;br /&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">یکی از چالش‌های جدّی در ادارۀ اثربخش سازمان‌ها به ویژه در بخش دولتی، حصول اطمینان از وجود مدیرانی شایسته در بالای هرم سازمانی است. وجود چنین مدیرانی می‌تواند منابع محدود این بخش را در میان محدودیت‌های بی‌شمار دیگری که سازمان‌های دولتی را احاطه کرده است، به شکل مطلوب اداره کند. لذا هدف این پژوهش، کشف کلیدی‌ترین شایستگی‌های مورد نیاز برای ادارۀ اثربخش امور در بخش دولتی می‌باشد. از آنجا که کاوش در دنیای ذهنی و تجارب افراد و استخراج نگرش آنها مستلزم بهره‌گیری از روش‌های کیفی پژوهش بوده و از سویی، یکی از بهترین روش‌های کیفی که با هدف و سؤال این مطالعه سازگاری دارد، نظریۀ داده‌بنیاد است، از این روش برای انجام تحقیق بهره‌گیری شد. به منظور جمع‌آوری داده‌ها نیز از مصاحبه‎های نیمه ساختاریافته استفاده شد که در نهایت و پس از رسیدن به اشباع نظری، با انجام مصاحبه با 25 نفر از مدیران واجد شرایط، داده‌های لازم گردآوری و تحلیل شد. مجموعه داده‌های جمع‌آوری شده پس از طی فرایند مقایسۀ مستمر داده‌ها و کدگذاری‌های باز، محوری و انتخابی، در قالب 430 کد اولیه، 27 مفهوم، 9 مقوله و سه طبقه، سازماندهی شدند. حاصل نهایی تحلیل داده‌های گردآوری شده، در قالب یک نظریة داده بنیاد اولیه با عنوان «نظریة مدیریت اثربخش در سازمان‌های دولتی ایران» ارائه شد. این نظریه به دنبال آن است تا مجموعه ویژگی‌های شخصیتی، نگرشی، رفتاری، مهارت‌ها و شایستگی‌های یک مدیر دولتی را که می‌کوشد به گونه‌ای اثربخش در سازمان‌های دولتی ایران فعالیت کند، با توجه به شرایط محیطی تبیین کند. بر اساس این نظریه، مدیران دولتی اثربخش به منظور دستیابی به سطح مطلوب اثربخشی، باید دارای مجموعه‌ای از شایستگی‌های فردی، تعاملی و سازمانی باشند. در واقع؛ این یافته‌ها بیانگر سیمای مدیریت دولتی اثربخش در سازمان‌های ایرانی است که می‌تواند به عنوان یک شاخص برای مدیران و سازمان‌هایی که قصد دارند درجة اثربخشی خود و مدیران خود را ارزیابی کنند نیز مورد استفاده قرار گیرد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شایستگی‌های مدیران دولتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت اثربخش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظام اداری ایران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظریه‌پردازی داده‌بنیاد</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_1682_fd91082a7d7b32e6431ea4abe6869be4.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
