<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 2 (پیاپی 26)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Application of Grounded Theory in Assessing the Economic Policies of the Islamic Parliament</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی‌ خط‌مشی‌های اقتصادی مصوب مجلس شورای اسلامی با استفاده از نظریة داده‌بنیاد</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>135</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>148</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">5779</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.30473/ipom.2019.42898.3367</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>داوود</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسین‌پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فتاح</FirstName>
					<LastName>شریف‌زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>روح الله</FirstName>
					<LastName>نوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امید</FirstName>
					<LastName>کریمیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانش‌آموخته دکتری مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>08</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present paper seeks to use the grounded theory to assess the economic policies of the Islamic Parliament. Research method is based on the qualitative method of grounded theory. Depth interviews were conducted with 16 representatives in the Islamic Parliament using snowball sampling. After open, selective, and axial coding of collected data, 159 primary concepts, 45 subcategories and 8 main categories were extracted. The final outcome of this study is the design of a 5-dimensional model whose dimensions are categorized into four bases of the ground, input, process components, and products. The findings of this study indicate the domination of the political climate of Iran over the policy climate, the rule of politics over economy, followed by the confrontation of legislative, administrative and executive sectors with institutional, structural and cultural challenges in the policy-making process. Therefore, it is suggested that legislators emphasize national interests by adopting a holistic approach and avoid the involvement of political approaches with the policy-making process. Also, it is necessary to form special committees in the Islamic Parliament in order to align policies with high-level documents.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مقاله حاضر درصدد است با استفاده از نظریه‌ زمینه‌ای به ارزیابی‌ خط‌مشی‌های اقتصادی مجلس شورای اسلامی بپردازد. روش تحقیق مبتنی بر روش کیفی، نظریه زمینه‌ای، است. همچنین با استفاده از نمونه‌گیری گلوله برفی و فن مصاحبه با 16 نفر از خبرگان حوزه قانونگذاری در مجلس شورای اسلامی مصاحبههای عمیقی صورت گرفت. پس از کدگذاری باز، محوری و انتخابیِ داده‌های گردآوری شده تعداد 159 مفهوم اولیه، 45 مقوله فرعی و 8 مقوله اصلی استخراج شدند. برآیند نهایی این مطالعه طراحی مدلی 5 بُعدی است که ابعاد پنج‌گانه‌ی آن در قالب چهار رُکن زمینه، ورودی، مؤلفه‌های فرایندی و محصولات طبقه‌بندی شده است. یافته‌های این مطالعه حکایت از تسلط فضای سیاسی کشور بر فضای خط‌مشی‌گذاری، حاکمیت سیاست بر اقتصاد و به دنبال آن مواجه بودن بخش تقنینی، اداری و اجرایی با چالش‌ها و مشکلات نهادی، ساختاری و فرهنگی در فرایند خط‌مشی‌گذاری است. بنابراین پیشنهاد می‌شود قانونگذاران با اتخاذ رویکردی کل‌نگرانه بر منافع ملی تأکید ورزند و از دخالت رویکردهای سیاسی در فرایند خط‌مشی‌گذاری اجتناب نمایند. همچنن به منظور همسوسازی خط‌مشی‌ها با اسناد بالادستی تشکیل هیأت‌هایی ویژه در مجلس ضروری است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خط‌مشی‌های اقتصادی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزیابی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مجلس شورای اسلامی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظریة‌ داده‌بنیاد</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_5779_c64d3a78a4f2324978ea82f4e150a480.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
