<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 (پیاپی 29)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Conceptual Modeling of the Entrepreneurial Government in Iran With the Qualitative Meta-Analysis Approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ترسیم الگوی مفهومی دولت کارآفرین در ایران با رویکرد فراتحلیل کیفی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>33</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>50</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">6343</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.30473/ipom.2019.48893.3817</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رحمان</FirstName>
					<LastName>رنجبر</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری گروه علوم سیاسی، سیاست‌گذاری عمومی، واحد تهران مرکزی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بابک</FirstName>
					<LastName>نادرپور</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه علوم سیاسی، واحد تهران مرکزی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>غلامحسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسینی‌نیا</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه کسب‌وکار جدید، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نادر</FirstName>
					<LastName>هوشمندیار</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه علوم سیاسی، واحد تهران مرکزی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The recreating government with the entrepreneurial approach is not a simple reconsideration or partial interpretation of management, but a comprehensive change in the role of community management and the relationship between government and citizens that replaces directing leadership with enterprise. This qualitative meta-analysis study investigates the studies on the field of entrepreneurial government and provides a regular formulation of them. To accomplish this, 68 articles and reports on the entrepreneurial government have been searched through scientific databases of the country and abroad over the past 10 years (2008-2018) and were reviewd in two sections of &quot;Descriptive meta-analysis findings&quot; and &quot;Qualitative evaluation of articles&quot;. A meta-analysis of the Entrepreneurial Government papers shows that studies in this field are less focused on operational aspects and more dealt with theoretical discussions and general concepts. In most of these studies, the indices concerning the entrepreneurial government theory have not been explained in accordance with the indigenous conditions of Iran. In this study, however, the conceptual model of the entrepreneurial government has been outlined in terms of the Iranian indigenous conditions including the macro policies, good governance, social justice, mission orientation, social-cultural values, decentralization, customer orientation, market orientation, and advocacy.
 </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">بازآفرینی دولت با رویکرد کارآفرینی تجدیدنظر ساده یا تفسیر جزئی در شیوة مدیریت نیست، بلکه تغییری همه‌جانبه در نقش مدیریت جامعه و رابطة بین دولت و شهروندان است که هدایت‌گری را جایگزین تصدی‌گری می‌کند. این پژوهش با روش فراتحلیل کیفی به بررسی پژوهش‌های حوزۀ دولت کارآفرین پرداخته و صورت‌بندی منظمی از آن‌ها ارائه می‌‌دهد. 68 مقاله و گزارش درزمینۀ دولت کارآفرین با جست‌وجو در پایگاه اطلاعات علمی داخلی و خارجی در بازۀ زمانی 10 سال (1387-1397) و در دو بخش «یافته‌های توصیفی فراتحلیل» و «ارزیابی کیفی مقاله‌ها» بررسی شده‌اند. مطالعات فراتحلیل مقاله‌های دولت کارآفرین نشان می‎دهد پژوهش‌های این حوزه کمتر ناظر بر جنبه‌های عملیاتی بوده و بیشتر بر بحث‌های نظری و ارائۀ مفاهیم کلی تمرکز کرده‌اند. در اغلب پژوهش‌های صورت پذیرفته؛ شاخص‌های نظریۀ دولت کارآفرین متناسب با شرایط بومی ایران تبیین نشده است، لیکن در این مطالعه مدل مفهومی دولت کارآفرین با لحاظ شرایط بومی ایران ترسیم شده که ابعاد آن شامل سیاست‌های کلان، حکمرانی خوب، عدالت اجتماعی، رسالت محوری، عوامل فرهنگی- اجتماعی، تمرکز‌زدایی، مشتری مداری، بازارگرایی و حمایت و پشتیبانی است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوی مفهومی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارآفرینی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارآفرینی دولتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دولت کارآفرین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش فراتحلیل کیفی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_6343_8539ac94b325d854c128bcef02b4b6bb.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
