<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 2 (پیاپی 30)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identification and Ranking of Causes of Employee Resignation in Organization with Exploratory Factor Analysis Approach and Fuzzy AHP Method (Studied Case Mehr Eghtesad Bank)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی و رتبه‌بندی علل استعفای پرسنل در سازمان با رویکرد تحلیل عاملی اکتشافی و روش AHP فازی (مورد مطالعه: بانک مهر اقتصاد)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>129</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>142</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">6791</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.30473/ipom.2020.50990.3994</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امیر</FirstName>
					<LastName>بهبودی گل خطمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری گروه مدیریت دولتی، واحد تبریز، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تبریز، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>هوشنگ</FirstName>
					<LastName>تقی زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه مدیریت، واحد تبریز، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تبریز، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>بافنده زنده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت، واحد تبریز، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تبریز، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Today, the resignation of employees, especially skilled and skilled personnel, is one of the problems of organizations that has focused on a large part of the measures and attention of human resources management. The purpose of this research is to identify and rank employee resignation factors. The method of research is a combination of qualitative and quantitative factors that were identified in the qualitative section of the factors affecting resignation through interviewing ten of the bankers and academics, and in the small part of the resignation factors, the questionnaires were interviewed by the staff, then the factors were ranked by Fuzzy AHP. The statistical population consists of 6000 employees of Mehr Eghtesad bank. The sample size was determined by using two-stage sampling method and cluster sampling methods proportional to the sample size using 384 people and Krejcie and Morgan tables. In order to analyze the data, one-sample t-test, exploratory factor analysis and Fuzzy AHP were used. The results show that financial requirements, individual factors, job factors and organizational factors are the first to fourth factors of factors affecting employee resignation, respectively. It is also important from the perspective of employees that earnings from employment are more important than other indicators.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه استعفای کارکنان به‌ویژه پرسنل کارآمد و ماهر یکی از معضلات سازمان‌ها بوده که قسمت عمده‌ای از تدابیر و توجه مدیریت منابع انسانی را به خود معطوف داشته است. هدف این پژوهش شناسایی و رتبه‌بندی عوامل استعفای پرسنل است. روش پژوهش ترکیبی از کیفی و کمی است که در بخش کیفی عوامل مؤثر بر استعفا از طریق مصاحبه با ده تن از خبرگان بانکی و دانشگاهی شناسایی شد و در بخش کمی عوامل استعفا از طریق پرسشنامه از کارکنان نظرخواهی شد؛ سپس عوامل به AHP فازی رتبه‌بندی شد. جامعة آماری شامل 6000 نفر از کارکنان وسیله بانک مهر اقتصاد است. حجم نمونة آماری به روش نمونه‌گیری دومرحله‌ای و شیوه‌های نمونه‌گیری طبقه‌ای و خوشه‌ای متناسب با حجم نمونه با استفاده از جدول کرجسی و مورگان 384 نفر تعیین شد. به‌منظور تجزیه و تحلیل داده­ها از آزمون t تک نمونه­ای، تحلیل عاملی اکتشافی و AHP فازی استفاده شده است. نتایج حاصل نشان می‌دهد الزامات مالی، عوامل فردی، عوامل شغلی و عوامل سازمانی به ترتیب در اولویت­های اول تا چهارم عوامل مؤثر بر استعفا پرسنل هستند. همچنین از دیدگاه کارکنان منابع درآمدی حاصل از شغل نسبت به سایر شاخص‌ها از اهمیت ویژه‌ای برخوردار است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استعفاء پرسنل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الزامات مالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عوامل فردی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عوامل شغلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عوامل سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
