<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 3 (پیاپی 7)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Citizen participation model in public management based on Nahjolbalaghe&#039;s teachings</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>الگوی مشارکت شهروندی در مدیریت دولتی مبتنی بر تعالیم نهج البلاغه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>25</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>48</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1316</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>هادی</FirstName>
					<LastName>خان محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجو دکتری مدیریت دولتی،‌ دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>واعظی</LastName>
<Affiliation>.دانشیار مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName>
					<LastName>دلشاد تهرانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار علوم حدیث  ، دانشگاه قرآن و حدیث</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The subject of citizen&#039;s Participation in government and reign affairs or the interactions between people and government is one of the important issues that should be paid attentionby scholars and statesmen. This is while the subject got an important place in recent quasi paradigm of public management i.e. new public service so that different theories and models have been stated in this area since the 50&#039;s. In a logical and rational approach, each country&#039;s citizen participation model take different shape according to the culture and environment of the country; Although experiences of other countries can also be used in this field.Accordingly, given the importance of people&#039;s participation in government and reign, Followingresearchaimsto identifycitizen participation&#039;s model in viewpoint of NahjolBalaghe&#039;s teachings regarding practical and theoretical method of Imam Ali (greeting to him) totakea step in theproductionof Islamic  model.Therefore, themain research questionis thatwhat the model of citizen participation inpublic managementlooks like based on theteachings of theNahjolBalagheh? Tocarry out the research,contentanalysis method by Maxqdaqualitative analysis softwarehas been used. The results showthatcitizenparticipationmodel is formedbased onbasic and fundamentalvalues ofthe Islamic government andhave an interactivemodel according to the rule of both parties&#039; reconciliation in order to achieve mutual right and duty&#039;s performance with ultimate good cooperation and interaction. According to this model, citizen-government interactive process and other partly models are created.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">موضوع مشارکت شهروندان در امور دولت و حکومت و یا تعاملات بین مردم  ودولت از موضوعات بسیار مهمی است که باید مورد توجه اندیشمندان و دولتمردان قرار بگیرد. این در حالی است که این موضوع در شبه پارادیم­های اخیر مدیریت دولتی یعنی خدمات عمومی نوین بسیار حائز اهمیت گشته تا آنجا که در این زمینه مدل­ها و تئوری­های مختلفی از دهه 50 میلادی تاکنون بیان شده است­. در یک رویکرد منطقی و عقلایی، الگوی مشارکت شهروندان هر کشور متناسب با فرهنگ و محیط آن کشور شکل متفاوتی به خود می­گیرد؛ هرچند می­توان از تجربیات دیگر کشور­ها در این زمینه نیز استفاده نمود. بر این اساس با توجه به درجه اهمیت مشارکت مردم در حکومت و دولت، این تحقیق بدنبال آن است که الگوی مشارکت شهروندی از منظر تعالیم نهج البلاغه را متناسب با سیره نظری و عملی امام علی &lt;sup&gt;علیه السلام&lt;/sup&gt; شناسایی نماید تا گامی در تولید الگویی اسلامی برداشته شود. بنابراین سوال اصلی پژوهش آن است که مشارکت شهروندی در مدیریت دولتی مبتنی بر تعالیم نهج البلاغه چه الگویی دارد؟ جهت انجام پژوهش نیز از روش تحلیل مضمون با استفاده از نرم افزار تحلیل کیفی Maxqda استفاده گردید. نتایج تحقیق حاکی از  آن است که الگوی مشارکت شهروندی بر اساس ارزش­های بنیادین و اساسی حکومت اسلامی شکل می­گیرد و دارای  الگویی تعاملی براساس قاعده اصلاح طرفینی جهت تحقق اداء حق و تکلیف متقابل با نهایت حسن تعامل و همکاری می­باشد و براساس آن الگو  فرایند تعاملی دولت­– شهروند و سایر الگو­های بخشی دیگر ایجاد می­گردد. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نهج البلاغه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دولت اسلامی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مردم سالاری دینی‌</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حقوق شهروندان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشارکت شهروندان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_1316_12699b979e9778adf487996601bcad16.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
