<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانـشـگـاه پــیــام نـــور</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه علمی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-522X</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 3 (پیاپی 3)</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Designing an Intellectual Capital Measuring Model for Iranian Cultural Public Organizations</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی الگوی اندازه گیری سرمایه فکری در سازمان های فرهنگی دولتی ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>43</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>63</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1110</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شمس السادات</FirstName>
					<LastName>زاهدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهروز</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضایی منش</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسلامبولچی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکترای مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>27</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;Intellectual capital is a knowledge that can create value. Nowadays, attention to intellectual capital is an approach that provides instrument for efficiency and effectiveness fulfilment for public departments&#039; managers and hence, intangible elements are paid attention intensively in public departments, in spite of the emphasis, there is a place for intellectual capital in public organizations hardly ever and so far, a few number of public organizations attempts to measure, manage and report their intangible assets. To deal with managing these capitals better, this research intends to present a model for measuring and evaluating intellectual capitals level in Iranian public cultural organization and testing the model through evaluating intellectual capitals in the ministry of culture and Islamic guidance as the largest and main organization, custadian of culture in Iran. In this study, the research primary model was designed after a review on intellectual capital literature and particularly measurment models and evaluation of intellectual capital in public organizations, then by using focus group and delphi techniques and ideas of a panel of experts, model&#039;s criteria were adjusted and reformed and the resulted questionnaire was examined in the ministry of culture and Islamic guidance. Findings analysis confirmed research hypotheses and the validity of presented model for meadsuring and evaluating intellectual capital in public cultural organizations.&lt;/span&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;سرمایه فکری دانشی است که می تواند تولید ارزش کند. امروزه توجّه به سرمایه های فکری، رویکردی است که ابزار تحقّق کارایی و کارآمدی را در اختیار مدیران بخش دولتی می گذارد و از این رو مؤلفه های ناملموس مورد توجّه شدید در بخش دولتی قرار گرفته است، علیرغم این میزان اهمّیت، سرمایه فکری در سازمان های دولتی به ندرت جایگاه خود را یافته است و  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;تا کنون تعداد کمی از سازمان های دولتی برای اندازه گیری و مدیریت و گزارش داراییهای ناملموس خود تلاش کرده اند&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Times New Roman;&quot;&gt; .&lt;/span&gt;این تحقیق در پی ارائه مدلی برای اندازه گیری و ارزیابی سطح سرمایه های فکری در سازمان های فرهنگی-دولتی کشور و آزمون مدل از طریق ارزیابی سرمایه های فکری وزارت فرهنگ و ارشاد اسلامی به عنوان بزرگترین و اصلی ترین سازمان متولی فرهنگ در ایران می باشد، تا از این رهگذر در جهت مدیریت هر چه بهتر این سرمایه ها گام برداشته شود.در این تحقیق پس از مروری بر ادبیات سرمایه های فکری و به خصوص مدل های اندازه گیری و ارزیابی سرمایه فکری در سازمان های دولتی، مدل اولیه تحقیق طراحی شد، با استفاده از تکنیک گروه کانونی و دلفی و استفاده از نظرات خبرگان شاخص های مدل تعدیل و اصلاح شدند و پرسشنامه حاصله در وزارت فرهنگ و ارشاد اسلامی مورد آزمون قرار گرفت.تجزیه و تحلیل یافته های حاصله از پیمایش، فرضیه های تحقیق و روایی مدل ارائه شده برای اندازه گیری و ارزیابی سرمایه های فکری سازمان های فرهنگی-دولتی را مورد تأیید قرار داد.&lt;/span&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه فکری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">داراییهای ناملموس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه ساختاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه ارتباطی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://ipom.journals.pnu.ac.ir/article_1110_4b66a5b8c353ff3ecd717905a48ec80c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
