<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Review of the Effects of Factors which are Vital in the Implementation of Knowledge Management</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی عوامل حیاتی موفقیت در پیاده‌سازی مدیریت دانش</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>149</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>184</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">35322</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2013.35322</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>حیدری</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت دولتی پردیس قم، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>مقیمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>خنیفر</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد دانشکده مدیریت پردیس قم دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>15</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>KM&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, as a new approach and modern means and as a systematic and deliberate effort to expand, cultivate, and apply knowledge in ways that add value to the entity, has positive results in accomplishing objectives and fulfilling arganizortion’s purpose.   
The present study tries to review critical factors in which affect implementation of KM in agri caltural organization according to the conceptual model of Huang and his colleagues, based on ten key factors.
Including organization’s culture, commitment of senior managers, employee involvement, employee training, teamwork, empowerment, information system infrastructure, performance measurement, benchmarking, and knowledge structure.
The results in 95% confidence level, show that all selected factors affect implementing knowledge management. The Friedman test showed that the influences of all factors are not equal and each has its rate.
&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot; /&gt;

[1]. Knowledge Management</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مدیریت دانش، به عنوان یک رویکرد جدید و نوین به معنای تلاش آگاهانه و نظام‌مند یک نهاد برای نشر، پرورش و کاربرد دانش به نحوی که به ارزش آن نهاد بیفزاید و نتایج مثبتی را در دستیابی به آرمان‌ها به وجود آورد، می‌باشد.
پژوهش حاضر سعی دارد تا میزان تأثیرگذاری عوامل حیاتی را در پیاده سازی مدیریت دانش سازمان جهاد کشاورزی بر طبق مدل مفهومی هونگ و همکارانش که مبتنی بر ده عامل اساسی یعنی فرهنگ سازمانی، تعهد مدیران ارشد، مشارکت، آموزش، کار تیمی، توانمند سازی، سیستم‌های اطلاعاتی، سنجش عملکرد، الگو سازی و ساختار دانش می‌باشد بررسی نماید.
نتایج تحقیق در سطح اطمینان 95% حاکی از آن است که تمامی عوامل انتخاب شده منجر به پیاده سازی مدیریت دانش می‌شوند. هم چنین با آزمون فریدمن نشان دادیم که  میزان تأثیرگذاری همه عوامل بر مدیریت دانش برابر نیست و هر یک در رتبه‌ای قرار می‌گیرند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جهاد کشاورزی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عوامل موثر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازمان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_35322_773891afc9220490dd03f9863873bc19.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
