<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>15</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigating the Effect of Employee Empowerment on Organizational Development with Emphasis on Perceived Organizational Support</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر توانمندسازی کارکنان بر توسعة سازمانی با تأکیدبر حمایت سازمانی ادراک شده</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>69</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>91</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">61278</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2017.61278</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سکینه</FirstName>
					<LastName>جعفری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکدة روان‌شناسی و علوم تربیتی، دانشگاه سمنان، سمنان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>داریوش</FirstName>
					<LastName>احمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ‌ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی- مالی، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نوروزی کوهدشتی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت آموزشی، دانشگاه شیراز، شیراز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>27</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The goal of this study was investigating the effect of employee empowerment on organizational development with emphasis on perceived organizational support. This research is applied and the research method is descriptive - correlational. The Statistical population was all female and male personnel (1044) at Shiraz University and the method of Simple random sampling. In order to do research, a sample of 122 people was selected from the staff of the university. The instrument to collect data consisted of three questionnaire of organizational development, organizational support questionnaire and an employee empowerment questionnaire, which after computing validity and reliability distributed between the samples and gathered. Data were analyzed by SPSS and Lisrel softwares using Pearson correlation coefficient and path analysis. The results indicated: There is a meaningful relationship between employee empowerment, perceived organizational support and organizational development. Employee empowerment has significant impact of organizational development. Employee empowerment has significant impact of organizational support. Employee empowerment has significant impact of organizational development with mediator&#039;s organizational support. Employee empowerment can directly affect organizational development. But the employee empowerment indirectly and by organizational support can affect organizational development. Practical implications of the findings were discussed.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف پژوهش حاضر، بررسی تأثیر توانمندسازی کارکنان بر توسعة سازمانی با نقش میانجی‌گری حمایت سازمانی ادراک‌شده در دانشگاه شیراز بود. روش تحقیق توصیفی ـ همبستگی و مبتنی بر مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری بود. جامعة آماری همة کارمندان زن و مرد (1044 نفر) دانشگاه شیراز و روش نمونه‌گیری، تصادفی ساده بود. به منظور انجام‌دادن پژوهش، از بین کارمندان دانشگاه یادشده، نمونه‌ای به حجم 122 نفر انتخاب شد. ابزار پژوهش مقیاس‌های توانمندسازی کارکنان، حمایت سازمانی ادراک‌شده و توسعة سازمانی بود، که پس از محاسبة روایی و پایایی آن، بین نمونه توزیع و گرد‌آوری شد. داده‌ها با نرم‌افزارهای SPSS و Lisrel، و با روش‌های آماری ضریب همبستگی پیرسون و تحلیل مسیر تحلیل شد. یافته‌ها نشان داد بین توانمندسازی کارکنان، حمایت سازمانی ادراک‌شده و توسعة سازمانی رابطة معناداری وجود دارد. توانمندسازی کارکنان به‌طور مستقیم بر توسعة سازمانی تأثیر معناداری دارد. توانمندسازی کارکنان به‌طور مستقیم بر حمایت سازمانی ادراک‌شده تأثیر معناداری دارد. حمایت سازمانی ادراک‌شده تأثیر مثبت و معناداری بر توسعة سازمانی دارد. همچنین، توانمندسازی کارکنان با میانجی حمایت سازمانی ادراک‌شده، بر توسعة سازمانی به‌طور غیرمستقیم تأثیری معنادار می‌گذارد. در نهایت، توانمندسازی کارکنان می‌تواند به‌طور مستقیم توسعة سازمانی را تحت تأثیر قرار دهد. همچنین، توانمندسازی کارکنان می‌تواند به‌طور مستقیم حمایت سازمانی ادراک‌شده را تحت تأثیر قرار دهد. با توجه به این دو نتیجه، توانمندسازی کارکنان به‌طور غیرمستقیم و با واسطة حمایت سازمانی ادراک‌شده می‌تواند توسعة سازمانی را تحت تأثیر قرار دهد.&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;  </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توسعة سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توانمندسازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حمایت سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_61278_b4f56b5b4c6b8830ee48154f2282b465.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
