<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>16</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identifying, Conceptualizing, and Explaining the Process of Whistleblowing in the Organization (Case Study: Gohar-Zamin Iron Ore Company)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی، مفهوم‏سازی، و تبیین فرایند سوت‏ زنی در سازمان (مطالعۀ موردی: شرکت سنگ ‏آهن گهرزمین)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>617</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>643</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68783</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2018.217672.1007011</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>صفری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری مدیریت سیاست‏ گذاری بازرگانی، دانشکدة مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3286-3957</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>فتاح زیارانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‏ارشد مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشکدة مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>26</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Immoral, illegal, and corruptive activities are observable in all governmental and non-governmental organizations all over the world. But they are different in their dimensions and aspects. So, it is important to have a regulatory system, which is aware of the organization’s details and structural defects. Henceforth, a controller person with accountability, who delivers so-called organization’s voice to officials, is required. A person with this character is called a whistleblower and her/his movements are called whistle-blowing in an organization. The purpose of this article is to study and discuss this kind of persons and their action and it’s a relation with accountability and job satisfaction in the intended organization. The results showed that the organization has skillful human capital, but the problem is the organization’s culture. Whistle-blowing and defending the whistle-blowers must be made a part of the organization’s culture, after that, constructive criticisms and good performances will become visible in the organization. The final outcome will be a healthy organization with accountable, clever, satisfied, and integrated staff. This construction with these staff will enable the organization to survive in the competitive environment. However, the survival of organizations in today&#039;s competitive world necessitates such competitive advantages.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">فعالیت‏های غیراخلاقی و غیرقانونی، صرف‏نظر از شدت و پیامدهای منفی ناشی از آن، در همة نقاط جهان و در سازمان‏های دولتی و غیردولتی دیده‏ شده است. از این نظر، وجود سیستمی نظارتی که از سازمان آگاه باشد و کاستی‏ها را مشاهده و گزارش کند قبل از بروز پیامدهای نامطلوب ضروری است. ازاین‏رو، وجود افرادی به‏عنوان ناظر با احساس مسئولیت در سازمان، که به‏عنوان صدای سازمان، فریاد سازمان را در صورت وجود انحراف به گوش مسئولان برسانند، اجتناب‏ناپذیر است. این افراد، که در این مطالعه اصطلاحاً سوت‏زن نامیده می‏شوند، باید در فرهنگ سازمانی تعریف‏ شوند و موردحمایت قانونی قرار گیرند. هدف از این مقاله بررسی و مفهوم‏سازی این مسئله و نیز تبیین آن در سازمان موردبررسی است تا میزان مسئولیت‏پذیری و رضایت شغلی کارکنان بر اساس متغیرهای متفاوت مؤثر بر آن‏ها ارزیابی شود. با به‏کارگیری روش توصیفی همبستگی و با استفاده از آزمون‏های تحلیل آماری تی‏تک نمونه‏ای و آزمون همبستگی پیرسون، متغیرها و عوامل شناسایی‏‏شده در تحقیق بررسی و تحلیل شد. پس از تحلیل‏های مربوطه و آزمون فرضیه‏های تحقیق، یافته‏های مبتنی بر آن‏ها ارائه شد. نتایج حاصل نشان می‏دهد سازمان موردبررسی در این مطالعه از سرمایة انسانی توانمند برخوردار است و با حمایت از آن‏ها راه برای انتقادهای سازندة آن‏ها و نتیجتاً سوت‏زنی در سازمان و کسب عملکرد بالاتر فراهم است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انتقاد سازنده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سوت‏زنی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فساد سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مسئولیت‏پذیری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_68783_b9a6a46117e58a6c34d59e748d6248c8.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
