<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>18</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Meta-analysis of the Relationship between the Use of Management Information Systems and the Improvement of Managerial Decision-Making</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>فرا تحلیلی بر رابطۀ بین به‌کارگیری سیستم‌های اطلاعاتی مدیریت و بهبود تصمیم‌گیری مدیران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>217</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>247</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">74768</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2019.271143.1007663</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اسد</FirstName>
					<LastName>حجازی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت آموزشی، دانشگاه فرهنگیان، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>یاسر</FirstName>
					<LastName>صیادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکترای مدیریت آموزشی، دانشکدة علوم تربیتی و روان‌شناسی، دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2876-7591</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study was to combine quantitative studies on the relationship between the use of management information systems and manager&#039;s decision-making from April 1991 to the end of March 2018 in Iran. To this end, the meta-analysis method was used. The statistical population consisted of all studies done on the relationship between information systems and manager&#039;s decision-making. To select a sample, a series of criteria for the inclusion or exclusion of the studies was considered. Finally, 23 studies were selected as final sample for the inclusion in the meta-analysis. Part of the process of the meta-analysis operations was done manually and other part was done using the effect size combination method in the second version of Comprehensive Meta-Analysis software (CMA-2). Duval and Tweedie’s Trim fit test was applied to both random and fixed effects model. The Average effect size was 0.524 for the fixed model and 0.373 for the random model. Thus, according to Cohen&#039;s criteria, the effect size of the relationship between management information systems and managers’ decision-making in the random and fixed effects model is medium to high. In the end, some strategic suggestions are provided for managers.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از پژوهش حاضر فراتحلیلی بر پژوهش‌های انجام‌شده در رابطة بین به‌کارگیری سیستم‌های اطلاعاتی و تصمیم‌گیری مدیران بود که در سال‌های 1370 تا پایان اسفندماه سال 1396 در کل کشور انجام شده است. در این پژوهش از روش فراتحلیل استفاده شد و جامعة آماری شامل همة پژوهش‌های انجام‌شده در زمینة ارتباط سیستم‌های اطلاعاتی با تصمیم‌گیری مدیران بود. جهت انتخاب نمونة پژوهش معیارهایی برای ورود و خروج از پژوهش در نظر گرفته شد. در نهایت، بیست و سه پژوهش به منزلة نمونة نهایی برای ورود به فراتحلیل انتخاب شدند. برای محاسبة ضرایب و شاخص‌ها، قسمتی از مراحل عملیات فراتحلیل حاضر به صورت دستی و قسمت‌هایی با استفاده از نرم‌افزار جامع فراتحلیل (CMA-2) و به روش ترکیب اندازة اثر صورت گرفت. آزمون اصلاح برازش دووال و توئیدی برای هر دو مدل ثابت و تصادفی انجام شد. میانگین اندازة اثر در مدل ثابت 524/0 و در مدل تصادفی 373/0 به دست آمد. بنابراین، طبق معیار کوهن، اندازة اثر رابطة سیستم‌های اطلاعاتی و تصمیم‌گیری مدیران در مدل آثار تصادفی و ثابت متوسط رو به بالاست. همچنین در پایان پژوهش برخی پیشنهاد‌های راهبردی برای مدیران ارائه شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تصمیم‌گیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیستم‌های اطلاعاتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فراتحلیل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیران</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_74768_095f327059def9db347d6e9561903350.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
