<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>14</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Desired Pattern of Organizational Culture, the Jihadi Approach 
Case: Holy Defense</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>الگوی فرهنگ سازمانی مطلوب با رویکرد جهادی (مورد مطالعه: دفاع مقدس)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>27</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>46</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">56505</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2016.56505</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>خصاف مفرد</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، دانشکدة مدیریت، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ‌ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>باقری نصرآبادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، دانشکدة مدیریت، دانشگاه امام صادق (علیه‌السلام)، تهران، ‌ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>08</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The phenomenon of war has always caused redefining new scientific horizons and areas in societies, which next generations can use them too. Because of threatening the entity of a nation, it causes implementing all mental, intellectual and practical strengths of a community, to be used. One of the most used knowledge&#039;s in the war, has been management. On the other hand, the dominant organizational culture is the key criteria for success or failure of an organization. In this paper, by studding and analyzing the dominant culture of Iranian forces during the 8 year of imposed war, we try to reach to a desired organizational culture for Iranian institutions. The conceptual framework for this analysis is the three level model of Edgar Shein. The methodology of this research is a thematic analysis of numerous documents and different interviews. Results show that Jihadi organizational culture, in the most basic levels (beliefs, assumptions and intrinsic values) in different times is a driving force toward change and excellence although in the level of artifacts and instrumental values can vary according to the goal and mission of the organization.
&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;
 </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به‌دلیل آنکه جنگ هستی یک ملت را تهدید می‌کند، در جوامع مختلف همواره باعث بازتولید افق­های دانشی جدید در آن جامعه شده است، از جمله می­توان به دانش مدیریت اشاره کرد. از دیگر سو، فرهنگ سازمانی حاکم بر سازمان را می‌توان از عوامل اصلی موفقیت یا شکست آن برشمرد. در این نوشتار با مطالعه و بررسی فرهنگ تشکیلاتی حاکم بر رزمندگان کشور در دوران دفاع مقدس و تجزیه‌وتحلیل آن، به الگویی از فرهنگ سازمانی مطلوب برای سازمان­های ایرانی با الگوگیری از مدل سه‌سطحی ادگار شاین دست می­یابیم. روش تحقیق در این پژوهش، تحلیل مقوله­های حاصل از مطالعة کتابخانه­ای و اسناد و نیز مصاحبه­های عمیق انجام‌گرفته بوده است. نتایج نشان داد الگوی فرهنگ سازمانی جهادی در مبنایی­ترین سطح خود، یعنی سطح باورها، مفروضات و ارزش­های غایی، می­تواند در همة دوره­ها منشأ تحول و پیشرفت سازمان‌های کشور باشد، هر چند در سطح نمودها، مصنوعات و ارزش­های ابزاری به اقتضای هدف و نوع سازمان متفاوت است.
&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;
 </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزش­ها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">باورها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرهنگ جهادی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل سه‌سطحی شاین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نمودهای سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_56505_e49960636bde55956b24b8ea517eb7dd.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
