<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Sociological Foundations and Cultural Requirements of the State Development
in the Iranian Society</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مبانی جامعه‌شناختی و اقتضائات فرهنگی تکوین دولت در جامعة ‌ایرانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>289</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>315</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">53304</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2015.53304</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>بالوی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، پردیس فارابی، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهناز</FirstName>
					<LastName>بیات کمیتکی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The modern state is a renewable and evolutionary phenomenon and it cannot be evaluated so that it has Single Cause. Therefore none of the fields of the Human Sciences alone cannot fully explain the emergence of the modern state without interaction with other disciplines. Political superstructure in various countries, primarily influenced by the social and cultural systems of communities as the cornerstone of the governance structure and then it is based on political, legal, economic, and military approach. Sociological and cultural characteristics of each society in conjunction with the economic, political, legal, executive structures play a significant role in the development of the modern state. In other words, the form and content of the governance system has a meaningful relationship with sociological and cultural characteristics of its people and their historical attitude towards concepts such as the power, the government, and the legitimacy.In this article we will present a conceptual analysis of the state and explain development of state in the Iranian society and then we will analyze the evolution and transformation of the state from the perspective of most distinctive social features and cultural characteristics and mental components of Iranian people.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">دولت مدرن پدیده‌ای تکاملی و تجدیدشونده است و نمی‌توان آن را به‌طور تک‌عاملی و تک‌ساحتی ارزیابی کرد، لذا هیچ‌یک از حوزه‌های متکثر علوم انسانی به‌تنهایی و بی‌کنشگری متقابل با حوزه‌های دیگر، نمی‌تواند پیدایش دولت مدرن را به‌طور کامل توضیح دهد. &lt;br /&gt;روبنای سیاسی دولت در کشورهای مختلف، در وهلة نخست تابعی از ساختار اجتماعی و فرهنگی آن جوامع به مثابة سنگ‌بنای ساختار حکمرانی است، و در مرحلة بعد، بر ‌اندیشة خاص سیاسی، حقوقی، اقتصادی، نظامی‌ و جز آن بنا نهاده شده است. بر‌ این اساس، فقدان آمادگی لازم بافت اجتماعی و فرهنگی برای ‌ایجاد نهاد دولت- ملت، استقرار معیوب ‌اندام‌واره‌های اقتدار نظام سیاسی را به دنبال خواهد داشت. خصیصه‌های جامعه‌شناختی و فرهنگی مردم هر جامعه در تلفیق با ساختارهای اقتصادی، سیاسی، حقوقی و اجرایی، نقشی مهم در روند تکوین دولت ملی ‌ایفا می‌کند و تأثیری بسزا دارد. به بیان دیگر، شکل و محتوای نظام حکمرانی در هر کشور با خصلت‌های جامعه‌شناختی و فرهنگی مردم آن کشور و نحوة نگرش تاریخی آنان به مفاهیمی‌ مانند قدرت، حکومت، مبنای مشروعیت و جز آن ارتباط معنادار دارد. &lt;br /&gt;در ‌این نوشتار پس از تحلیل مفهومی ‌پدیدة دولت و تشریح روند تکوین و تکامل آن در جامعة ‌ایرانی، تطور و تحول دولت مدرن از منظر بارز‌ترین خصیصه‌های اجتماعی، مقوله‌های فرهنگی و مؤلفه‌های فکری و نظری مردم ‌ایران‌زمین بررسی و تجزیه‌وتحلیل شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دولت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دولت مدرن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جامعة ‌ایرانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عوامل فرهنگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مبانی جامعه‌شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_53304_999c930c53348eccf023c09f78961f70.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
