<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>24</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Designing of Effective Human Resources Management Model based on Organizational Culture in the Public Section in Iran.</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی مدل مدیریت منابع انسانی اثربخش مبتنی بر فرهنگ سازمانی در بخش دولتی ایران.</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">73761</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2019.268827.1007635</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدمحمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>سبحانی پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترا، دانشکده مدیریت وحسابداری ، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد قزوین ، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>زارعی متین</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد دانشکده مدیریت -پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدمهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>الوانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>. استاد،ﮔﺮوه ﻣﺪﻳﺮﻳﺖ دوﻟﺘﻲ، واﺣﺪ ﻗﺰوﻳﻦ، داﻧﺸﮕﺎه آزاد اﺳﻼﻣﻲ، ﻗﺰوﻳﻦ، اﻳﺮان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>غلامرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>جندقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران پردیس فارابی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Understanding theories of management science, especially in the field of human resource management, is not possible without regard to the cultural context that contributed to their formation. Since each organization has different units, one can not define a specific culture for all of them, so each organizational unit must be defined in its own specific contexts in an appropriate organizational culture to increase its effectiveness. Accordingly, in this research, the systems for entering, maintaining and withdrawing human resources adapted to the specific organizational culture, according to the policies and laws in the state administrative system, are matched, and the collected data and experts&#039; opinions through the combination tool of the questionnaire and interview Analyzed using fuzzy logic, and after identifying the existing legal framework, the barriers to implementation of that review are presented and necessary reforms have been presented to increase the organizational effectiveness in the field of different cultures of the organization in the field of human resource management.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">درک نظریه های علم مدیریت به  ویژه در حوزه مدیریت منابع انسانی بدون توجه به بسترهای فرهنگی که در شکل گیری آنها نقش داشته اند میسر نمی باشد. از آنجا که هر سازمان دارای واحدهای مختلفی می باشد، نمی توان برای تمام آنها یک فرهنگ خاص تعریف نمود، بنابراین می بایست هر واحد سازمانی با شرایط خاص خود ،در فرهنگ سازمانی متناسب تعریف شده تا اثربخشی آن افزایش یابد. بر همین اساس در این پژوهش نظام های ورود ،نگهداری و خروج منابع انسانی متناسب با فرهنگ سازمانی خاص با در نظر گرفتن سیاستها و قوانین موجود در نظام اداری کشور منطبق گردیده و داده های جمع آوری شده و نظرات خبرگان از طریق ابزار ترکیبی پرسشنامه و مصاحبه با استفاده از منطق فازی مورد تحلیل قرار گرفته و و پس از شناسایی بسترهای قانونی موجود ، موانع اجرایی آن احصاء و اصلاحات لازم نیز برای افزایش اثربخشی سازمانی در حیطه فرهنگ های مختلف سازمانی در حوزه استراتژیها و کارکردهای مدیریت منابع انسانی ارائه گردیده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرهنگ سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اثربخشی سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استراتژی های مدیریت منابع انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظام های مدیریت منابع انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
