<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>18</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identifying the Organizational Factors Affecting the Entrepreneurial University: A Meta-analysis</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی عوامل سازمانی مؤثر بر دانشگاه کارآفرین (با رویکرد فراترکیب)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>425</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>456</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">73769</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2019.277833.1007749</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیده جمیله</FirstName>
					<LastName>مدرسی سریزدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانش‌آموختة دکترا، دانشکدة روانشناسی و علوم تربیتی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>عباس پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، دانشکدة روانشناسی و علوم تربیتی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کمال</FirstName>
					<LastName>سخدری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکدة کارآفرینی، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعید</FirstName>
					<LastName>غیاثی ندوشن</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکدة روانشناسی و علوم تربیتی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>15</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study was to provide a comprehensive picture of the organizational factors affecting the entrepreneurial university through the synthesis of literature. The research method was qualitative with a meta-synthesis approach. To this end, after the exploration of the databases in the period 1998-2017, 325 articles were collected in the field of entrepreneurial university, and finally 65 articles that directly examined the subject of entrepreneurial university were selected through a purposive sampling method and were included in the analysis phase. To analyze the data, coding method was used. Analyzing the findings of previous researchers and synthesizing the results, 21 codes, 10 concepts, and 5 factors were identified and validated through Kappa coefficient and the importance and priority of the identified codes were determined by Shannon&#039;s entropy method. According to the research findings, strong, comprehensive, and supportive leadership, flexible and distinctive structure, entrepreneurial spirit and attitude of members, and entrepreneurial organizational culture had the strongest coefficients of importance in the development of entrepreneurial university. Finally, after the research process was completed, the model of effective organizational components for the entrepreneurial university was generated. The results confirm the important role of leadership and culture in the transformation of universities toward entrepreneurship. By adopting a comprehensive approach, this research provides valuable insights into entrepreneurial universities.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این تحقیق با هدف ارائة تصویری جامع از عوامل سازمانی مؤثر بر دانشگاه کارآفرین از طریق ترکیب تحقیقات پیشین انجام شد. روش پژوهشْ کیفی با رویکرد فراترکیب بود. بدین منظور پس از جست‌وجو در پایگاه‌های اطلاعاتی، در فاصلة زمانی 1998 تا 2017، تعداد 325 مقاله در حوزة دانشگاه کارآفرین ارزیابی و در نهایت 65 مقاله، که به صورت مستقیم موضوع دانشگاه کارآفرین را بررسی کرده بودند، به روش هدفمند، انتخاب و وارد مرحلة تحلیل شدند. برای تجزیه‌وتحلیل داده‌ها از روش کدگذاری استفاده شد. پس از تحلیل یافته‌های محققان قبلی و ترکیب نتایج حاصله، تعداد 21 کد و 10 مفهوم و 5 مؤلفه شناسایی و اعتبار آن‌ها از طریق آزمون کاپای کافمن تأیید شد. سپس، میزان اهمیت و اولویت کدهای شناسایی‌شده با روش آنتروپی شانون تعیین شد. بر اساس یافته‌های تحقیق، کدهای رهبری قوی و همه‌جانبه و پشتیبان‌ـ ساختار منعطف و متمایزـ و روحیه و نگرش کارآفرینانة اعضا و فرهنگ سازمانی کارآفرینانه بیشترین ضریب اهمیت را در توسعة دانشگاه کارآفرین داشتند. در نهایت، پس از طی مراحل پژوهش، الگوی مؤلفه‌های سازمانی مؤثر بر دانشگاه کارآفرین ترسیم شد. نتایج‌ْ مؤید نقش رهبری و فرهنگ در تحول دانشگاه‌ها در جهت کارآفرینی بود. این پژوهش، با اتخاذ رویکردی جامع، بینش‌هایی ارزشمند در زمینة دانشگاه‌های کارآفرین ارائه می‌دهد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آنتروپی شانون</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دانشگاه کارآفرین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رهبری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فراترکیب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرهنگ</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_73769_2c5d41f87bf674016b82fd6b8cbd234a.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
