<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>17</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Relationship between Ethical Intelligence and Organizational Citizen Behavior (Case Study: Aboureihan Campus of Tehran University)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رابطۀ هوش اخلاقی و رفتار شهروندی سازمانی (مطالعۀ موردی: کارکنان و اعضای هیئت‌علمی پردیس ابوریحان ـ دانشگاه تهران)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>45</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>64</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">71184</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2019.130238.1006514</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نسرین</FirstName>
					<LastName>اردستانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‌ارشد مدیریت آموزشی دانشکدة علوم تربیتی و روان‌شناسی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد گرمسار، سمنان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>هادی</FirstName>
					<LastName>رزقی شیرسوار</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت دانشکدة علوم تربیتی و روان‌شناسی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد گرمسار، سمنان، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2780-3332</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>04</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study was to investigate the relationship between ethical intelligence and organizational citizenship behavior among staff and faculty members of ABIURIHAN campus of Tehran University using a correlation-descriptive research method. The statistical population in this study is all staff and faculty members of ABIURIHAN campus of Tehran University, which according to the latest statistics and information, are 230 members (163 staff and 67 professors). We used stratified sampling method. 144 people were selected as samples. In order to measure the variables used in the research, two questionnaires of ethical intelligence Lennick and Kiel(2005) and organizational citizenship behavior questionnaire of Podsakov et al. (1990) were used. The content validity of the questionnaires has been approved by the experts. The reliability of the questionnaires based on Cronbach&#039;s alpha coefficient was 0&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;86 for moral intelligence and 0&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;89 for organizational citizenship behavior, respectively. For analyzing, descriptive statistics and inferential statistics (Pearson correlation) were used. Findings of the research showed that moral intelligence and all its components (integrity, compassion, responsibility and passage) have a positive and significant relationship with organizational citizenship behavior.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی رابطة بین هوش اخلاقی و رفتار شهروندی سازمانی در میان کارکنان و اعضای هیئت‌علمی پردیس ابوریحان دانشگاه تهران، با استفاده از روش تحقیق توصیفی، از نوع همبستگی، انجام شد. جامعة آماری مورد نظر در این تحقیق را کلیة کارکنان و اعضای هیئت‌علمی پردیس ابوریحان دانشگاه تهران تشکیل دادند که بر اساس آخرین آمار و اطلاعات 230 نفر (163 نفر کارکنان و 67 نفر استادان) بودند و 144 نفر به عنوان نمونه به روش نمونه‌گیری طبقه‌ای انتخاب شدند. به منظور سنجش متغیرهای مورد استفاده در پژوهش از دو پرسش‏نامة «هوش اخلاقی» لنیک و کیل و «رفتار شهروندی سازمانی» پودساکف و همکارانش استفاده شد. روایی محتوایی پرسش‏نامه‌ها به تأیید متخصصان و استاد راهنما رسید. پایایی پرسش‏نامه‌ها، بر اساس ضریب آلفای کرونباخ، برای هوش اخلاقی 86&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0 و برای رفتار شهروندی سازمانی 89&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0 برآورد شد. برای تجزیه‌وتحلیل، روش‌های آماری توصیفی و آمار استنباطی (همبستگی پیرسون) به کار رفت. یافته‌های پژوهش نشان داد هوش اخلاقی و همة مؤلفه‌های آن (درست‌کاری، دلسوزی، مسئولیت‌پذیری، گذشت) با رفتار شهروندی سازمانی رابطة مثبت و معنادار دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اخلاق</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اخلاق حرفه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفتار شهروندی سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هوش اخلاقی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_71184_56081d0b542f0fab03a97c1d1f8d675d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
