<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Relationship between Spiritual Intelligence and Communication Skills of Lorestan University Staffs</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رابطة هوش معنوی با مهارت‌های ارتباطی کارکنان دانشگاه لرستان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>667</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>689</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">54734</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2015.54734</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فخرالسادات</FirstName>
					<LastName>نصیری و لیک بنی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیارگروه علوم تربیتی، دانشکدة ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه بوعلی‌سینا، همدان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>-	محمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>اردلان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیارگروه علوم تربیتی، دانشکدة ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه بوعلی‌سینا، همدان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احترام</FirstName>
					<LastName>میزاخانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‌ارشد مدیریت آموزشی، دانشکدة ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه بوعلی‌سینا، همدان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Companies are always looking to use all possible means to achieve success and effectiveness. Today, is notable the use of people with more subjective and skills specific characteristics. The importance of the issue of spirituality and religion, especially spiritual intelligence, felt the various aspects of new era. One of the necessities in the field of anthropology, is according to scientists from the perspective of the human Spiritual dimension that defines the human being has biological, psychological, social and spiritual. This study was conducted to examine the relationship between spiritual intelligence and communication skills. Methods of descriptive/co relational. The population of the study justice minister, staff, Lorestan University in the academic year 91-92, Which include 520 of which 220 patients a class based on table krejcie and Morgan as were selected. The instruments used were: 1. Spiritual intelligence scale Hild Brant reliability 0.88, 2. Communication skills inventory Barton, with a reliability of 0.80.The date collected through the questionnaire white the appropriate statistical methods such as tables, graphs, mean, frequency, frequencies, standard deviation, one-group t- test, t-independent, a multivariate analysis of variance, person correlation and multipath anova and regression the same method of analysis was. The results that were obtained from the review questions and research hypotheses are: communications skills, spiritual intelligence is much lorestan university staff. Component of spiritual intelligence the only predicator variable personal means of communication. skill and other variables, these variables were not significant predictors , between spiritual intelligence lorestan university staff in term of age, years of service and education, there is no difference and communication between staff skills lorestan university of demographic characteristics (gender, age, work experience, and education), there is no difference.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA"> سازمان‌ها همواره به دنبال استفاده از همة امکانات برای رسیدن به موفقیت و اثربخشی‌اند و برای تحقق این هدف علاوه بر دستیابی به عوامل مختلف، بحث به‌کارگیری افرادی با ویژگی‌های خاص ذهنی و مهارت بیشتر، مورد توجه قرار گرفته  است. یکى از این ضرورت‌ها در عرصة انسان‌شناسى، توجه به بعد معنوى انسان از دیدگاه دانشمندان، به‌ویژه کارشناسان سازمان بهداشت جهانى است. با این وصف، هدف از این پژوهش بررسی رابطة هوش معنوی با مهارت‌های ارتباطی کارکنان در دانشگاه لرستان بود. این تحقیق از نوع مطالعات توصیفی پیمایشی- همبستگی است و جامعة آماری آن را همة کارکنان دانشگاه لرستان تشکیل دادند که با روش نمونه­گیری تصادفی طبقه‌ای220 نفر انتخاب شدند. برای بررسی روایی پرسشنامه­ها روش محتوایی و صوری به‌کار گرفته شد و برای بررسی پایایی آلفای کرونباخ محاسبه شد. نتایج نشان داد وضعیت هر دو متغیر در جامعة مورد مطالعه بالاتر از میانگین آماری است. همچنین، بین هر یک از مؤلفه‌های هوش معنوی با مهارت‌های اجتماعی  ارتباط مثبت و معنادار وجود دارد. کارکنان مرد هوش معنوی بالاتری نسبت به کارکنان زن دارند ولی مهارت‌های ارتباطی و هوش معنویکارکنان در گروه‌های مختلف سنی، تحصیلی و سابقة خدمت یکسان است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دانشگاه لرستان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مؤلفه‌های هوش معنوی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مهارت ارتباطی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هوش</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_54734_5d586bc04b037b7d984ad92fea8b7db3.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
