<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Promoting Organizational Citizenship 
Behavior through Organizational Spirituality
(Case: Mayoralty of Zahedan)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>معنویت سازمانی گامی مؤثر در جهت بهبود رفتارهای شهروندی سازمانی (OCB)(مورد: شهرداری زاهدان)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>163</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>188</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">35492</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2013.35492</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>غلامرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>طالقانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>رستمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد روانشناسی بالینی، گروه آموزشی روانشناسی، دانشگاه آزاد اردبیل</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Organizational Spirituality is a new paradigm that has emerged in organizational behavior district and finds very advocates. Spirituality in workplace is referred to an individual attempts for seeking purpose in working life, sense of solidarity with coworkers and alignment with organization&#039;s mission and values. Spirituality could involve religion viewpoint or not, however, historically intentions to spirituality have been rooted in traditional religions. Organizational Citizenship Behaviors (OCB) includes a set of discretionary and voluntary behavior which contributes to organizational productivity. In this study we spot organizational spirituality as a factor enhancing organizational citizenship behavior. This faith is found that spirituality in the workplace improves employees OCBs in an indirectly way through affecting on their job attitudes. The aim of this study is to survey significantly of relationship between workplace spirituality and organizational citizenship behavior in target society. Findings suggest that there is significant relationship between organizational spirituality and organizational citizenship behaviors by 99% level of significance.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">معنویت سازمانی از جمله دریچه­های نوینی است که در حوزه رفتار سازمانی گشوده شده و می­تواند مشتمل بر دیدگاه دینی باشد. معنویت می­تواند مشتمل بر دیدگاه دینی باشد. در هر صورت از لحاظ تاریخی علاقه به معنویت ریشه در مذاهب و ادیان سنتی داشته است. از طرفی، رفتار شهروندی سازمانی شامل مجموعه­ای از رفتارهای بصیرتی و اختیاری می­باشد که موجب بهبود بهره­وری سازمان می­شود. هدف از پژوهش حاضر بررسی معناداری رابطه معنویت سازمانی و رفتار شهروندی سازمانی می­باشد. روش تحقیق در این پژوهش، کاربردی و توصیفی/ پیمایشی می­باشد. جامعه آماری تحقیق کلیه کارکنان شهرداری زاهدان می­باشند که از بین آن­ها 127 نفر به روش تصادفی ساده انتخاب شد. ابزار گردآوری داده­ها پرسشنامه است، که داده­های آن از طریق مدلسازی معادلات ساختاری تجزیه و تحلیل گردید. یافته­های این پژوهش حاکی از آن است که رابطه معناداری بین معنویت سازمانی و رفتار شهروندی سازمانی کارکنان وجود داشته و تمام مؤلفه­های معنویت سازمانی در بروز رفتارهای شهروندی مؤثر هستند. از این میان، دینداری و معنویت فردی بیشترین همبستگی را با رفتار شهروندی سازمانی داشته است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معنویت سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دین¬داری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفتار شهروندی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_35492_ac0e75b43dc9e87cb3815777b0575c85.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
