<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>16</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Visual Research; Photo-voice, Photo Elicitation; A New Methodology in Organizational Culture Management</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحقیقات دیداری: آوای عکس و تفسیر عکس روش‌شناسی نوین در مطالعات فرهنگ سازمانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>973</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>1000</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">70046</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2019.203802.1007304</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ناهید</FirstName>
					<LastName>نادری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>26</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Photo-voice and photo-elicitation represent a major field of visual research methodology which has been little employed in the organization and management. So the purpose of this paper is to present photo-voice and photo-elicitation methodologies and their use in the organizational culture research. The results showed that photos can provide tangible stimuli for more effectively tapping into tacit and often unconscious information, images, and metaphors that results in producing different and richer information than other techniques; and may also help to reduce differences in power, class, and knowledge between researcher and researched because these methods have unique potential to empower participants’ involvement in activities related to organizational culture management. Also, this paper will explore its theoretical foundation and then critically review the impact of photo-voice on a variety of changes in societies or organizations. Lastly, this paper will review the planning and implementation process of photo-voice by qualitative researchers.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">آوای عکس و تفسیر عکس یکی از حوزه‌های اصلی روش‌شناسی تحقیقات دیداری است که به‌ندرت در حوزه‌های مدیریتی و سازمانی به‌کار گرفته می‌شود. هدف این مقاله معرفی روش‌شناسی آوای عکس و تفسیر عکس و کاربرد آن‌ها در تحقیقات مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی است. روش تحقیق از نظر هدف کاربردی و از نظر جمع‌آوری اطلاعات توصیفی ـ تحلیلی است. به‌منظور جمع‌آوری داده‌ها از اسناد و مدارک و مجلات معتبر علمی استفاده شد. یافته‌های بررسی حاکی از آن است که عکس‌ها می‌توانند محرکی ملموس برای تلنگر زدن به اطلاعات ضمنی و ناخودآگاه، تصاویر، و استعاره‌ها باشند که موجب تولید اطلاعات مختلف و غنی‌تر نسبت به سایر فنون در حوزة فرهنگ سازمانی می‌شود. این مقاله با بررسی مبانی و چارچوب نظری آوای عکس نشان می‌دهد این روش‌شناسی به تغییر فرهنگ جامعه یا سازمان‌ها منجر می‌شود. همچنین، آوای عکس از هم‌پوشانی سه چارچوب نظری آموزش‌وپرورش توانمندساز، نظریة فمینیست، و عکس‌برداری مستند شکل گرفت. از نظر محققان کیفی طراحی و اجرای آوای عکس فرایندی ده‌مرحله‌ای است که از تعیین مخاطبان بعد از مفهوم‌سازی موضوع شروع و به بررسی نهایی ختم می‌شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آوای عکس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحقیقات دیداری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تصاویر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تفسیر عکس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرهنگ سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_70046_f5630091382f7da4634b12e24c6606b4.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
