<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Development of Social Entrepreneurship; Problems, Effective Factors, and Solutions</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>توسعه کارآفرینی اجتماعی؛ آسیب‌ها، عوامل مؤثر و راهکارها</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>277</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>297</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">51184</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2014.51184</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>تیمور</FirstName>
					<LastName>مرجانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت، دانشکدة علوم انسانی، دانشگاه علم و فرهنگ، تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید صدرالدین</FirstName>
					<LastName>صدری</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‌ارشد برنامه‌ریزی آموزشی، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>15</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Today, development of social entrepreneurship has been regarded as a social and altruistic mission and as a solution to some social problems and damages. Entrepreneurship has exerted positive and direct impact on the activities of many different countries. On one hand, it leads to economic development and creation of vocational opportunities; and on the other hand, it causes to improve social and cultural situation of the society. The present paper is resulted from a research conducted in one of the urban areas of Tehran with the goal of investigating social entrepreneurship situation based on a mixed methodology research approach. Questionnaire and interview with a group of experts and specialists have been utilized in order to access data and information. With regard to the fact that many social problems and damages root in unemployment of the individuals in the society, paying attention to social entrepreneurship can influence social damages to a large extent and can reduce them. Thus, this paper aims to review the issue of social damages and social entrepreneurship as well and then to present solutions for facilitating social entrepreneurship.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه به توسعة کارآفرینی اجتماعی به عنوان مأموریتی اجتماعی و انسان‌دوستانه، و یکی از راهکارهای حل برخی مسائل و آسیب‌های اجتماعی توجه می‌شود. کارآفرینی تأثیری مثبت و مستقیم در بسیاری از فعالیت‌های مختلف کشورها داشته است؛ از یک سو، سبب توسعة اقتصادی و ایجاد فرصت‌های شغلی می‌شود و از سوی دیگر، می‌تواند سبب بهبود وضعیت اجتماعی و فرهنگی جامعه شود. مقالة حاضر برگرفته از نتایج پژوهشی است که با هدف بررسی وضعیت کارآفرینی اجتماعی در یکی از مناطق شهری شهر تهران بر اساس طرح پژوهش آمیخته (کمی وکیفی) انجام گرفته است. برای دستیابی به اطلاعات و داده‌ها، ابزارهای پرسشنامه، مصاحبه با گروهی از کارشناسان و متخصصان، به‌کار گرفته شده است. با توجه به اینکه بسیاری از مسائل و آسیب‌های اجتماعی ریشه در بیکاری و عدم‌اشتغال افراد جامعه دارد، توجه به مقولة کارآفرینی اجتماعی می‌تواند تا حد زیادی آسیب‌های اجتماعی را تحت‌الشعاع قرار داده و آن‌ها را کاهش دهد، لذا این مقاله قصد دارد با مروری بر مسئلة آسیب‌های اجتماعی و همچنین، کارآفرینی اجتماعی با نتیجه‌گیری در این زمینه پیشنهادها و راهکارهایی برای تسهیل توسعة کارآفرینی اجتماعی مطرح کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آسیب‌های اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارآفرینی اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مأموریت اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مسائل شهری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_51184_63db4bb88a11c0911735a164c99ba088.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
