<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>15</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A System Dynamic Model for Effectiveness on the Broadcasting Viewers and Their Satisfaction and Loyalty (The Case: IRIB Education Channel)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی مدلی برای اثربخشی بر بینندگان صداوسیما و جلب رضایت و وفاداری آنان با رویکرد پویایی سیستم (مورد مطالعه: شبکة آموزش سیما)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>709</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>733</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">64078</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2017.121646.1006367</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>خجسته</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، دانشکدة مهندسی صنایع، دانشگاه یزد، یزد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>یحیی</FirstName>
					<LastName>زارع مهرجردی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، دانشکدة مهندسی صنایع، دانشگاه یزد، یزد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Today television is one of the most important tools for leisure humans and this has increased the Influence of this media in determining the attitude and lifestyle of people. Entry and expanding the use of satellite receivers in Iran have been caused a serious competitive atmosphere between broadcasting and cross-border networks and the necessity and importance of planning to increase the quality of programs for broadcasting executives have confirmed. The purpose of this study is providing a model for increase efficiency on television viewers and gain their satisfaction and loyalty. For this purpose, the system dynamics approach for analyzing dynamic and complex feedback systems has been used to achieve a comprehensive model for television broadcasting. By running the model obtained under different scenarios on one of these channels (IRIB Education Channel) we have analyzed the impact of different policies for the future success of the channel. The results show that policies to increase the competitiveness and integration of ancillary programs alongside the original network approach can increase network efficiency and attractiveness and the level of satisfaction and loyalty of its viewers. Also it prevents loss of audience and gradually caused growing number of them.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه تلویزیون یکی از مهم­ترین ابزارها برای گذران اوقات فراغت انسان­ها شده، و این امر تأثیرپذیری از این رسانه را در تعیین نگرش و سبک زندگی افراد افزایش داده است. ورود و گسترش ماهواره­ها در ایران، سبب ایجاد یک فضای رقابتی جدی میان صداوسیما و شبکه­های برون­مرزی شده است و ضرورت و اهمیت برنامه­ریزی برای افزایش کیفیت برنامه­ها را برای مدیران صداوسیما مشخص کرده است. هدف تحقیق حاضر طراحی مدلی برای افزایش اثربخشی و جلب رضایت­ و وفاداری بینندگان صداوسیما است. برای این هدف رویکرد پویایی سیستم که نگاهی پویا و بازخوردی به سیستم­های پیچیده دارد، به‌کار گرفته شده است. تا از این رهگذر مدلی جامع برای شبکه­های تلویزیونی صداوسیما به‌دست آید. با اجرای مدل ترسیم‌شده تحت سناریوهای مختلف بر روی یکی از این شبکه­ها­ (شبکة آموزش سیما) تأثیر اجرای سیاست­های گوناگون را برای موفقیت این شبکه در آینده تحلیل و بررسی شد. نتایج تحقیق حاکی از آن است که دو سیاست افزایش توان رقابت­پذیری و تلفیق برنامه­های جانبی در کنار رویکرد اصلی شبکه، می­تواند سبب افزایش اثربخشی و جذابیت شبکة آموزش و میزان رضایت­مندی و وفاداری بینندگان آن شده و با جلوگیری از ریزش مخاطبان به‌تدریج سبب رشد تعداد آنان شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پویایی‌‌‌شناسی سیستم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رضایتمندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">وفاداری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_64078_87b46111b19cac9682c408ba99bd2c59.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
