<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>16</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Designing an Interpretive Structural Model of Toxic Organization’s Antecedents</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی مدل ساختاری تفسیری پیشران‌های سازمان شرنگ‌آلود</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>347</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>367</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">66858</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2018.210980.1006895</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سلطنه</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسدزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد، دانشکدة علوم اداری و اقتصاد، دانشگاه ولی‏عصر (عج)، رفسنجان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName>
					<LastName>هادو‏ی‌نژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، دانشکدة علوم اداری و اقتصاد، دانشگاه ولی‏عصر (عج)، رفسنجان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study was designing the interpretive structural model of toxic organization’s antecedents. In this regard, having studied literature and identified antecedents of a toxic organization, a half-closed questionnaire embodied antecedents based on the Likert scale was developed and distributed among 26 experts from administrative organizations in Rafsanjan, using concept and snowball sampling. Based on the fuzzy analysis, the questionnaires statements were screened. Then, the other identified antecedents of toxic organization were screened and after categorizing, the measure for ISM was developed and distributed among mentioned experts. Finally, data were analyzed, and interpretative structural model of the studied phenomenon was drawn. The model possessed 12 variables in six different levels: firstly, toxic external environment; secondly, toxic leadership; thirdly, toxic human resource management and toxic processes; fourthly, toxic physical, job, and organizational structures, fifthly, toxic organizational climate and toxic personal perception; and finally, toxic public ethics, toxic interpersonal communication, and toxic organizational behaviors.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از این پژوهش طراحی مدل ساختاری تفسیری پیشران‏های سازمان شرنگ‏آلود برآمده از تجارب خبرگان سازمان‏های اجرایی رفسنجان است. برای این کار، پس از شناسایی پیشران‏های سازمان شرنگ‏آلود از دل ادبیات پژوهش و گنجاندن آن‏ها در پرسش‏نامة نیمه‏بسته‏ای مبتنی بر طیف لیکرت، با استفاده از روش نمونه‏گیری مفهوم و گلوله‏برفی، 26 خبره شناسایی و پرسش‏نامه میان آن‏ها توزیع شد. با استفاده از تحلیل فازی، گویه‏های پرسش‏نامه غربال‏ شد و پس از مقوله‏بندی در پرسش‏نامة متناسب با مدل‏یابی ساختاری تفسیری گنجانده شد و در اختیار خبرگان قرار گرفت. پس از تحلیل داده‏ها و ترسیم مدل، برای پیشران‏های سازمان شرنگ‏آلود در مجموع 12 متغیر در شش سطح شناسایی شد: سطح اول، محیط شرنگ‏آلود برون‏سازمانی؛ سطح دوم، رهبری شرنگ‏آلود؛ سطح سوم، مدیریت منابع انسانی و فرایندهای شرنگ‏آلود سازمانی؛ سطح چهارم، ساختارهای شرنگ‏آلود فیزیکی، شغلی، و سازمانی؛ سطح ششم، جو شرنگ‏آلود سازمانی و ادراک شرنگ‏آلود فردی؛ سطح ششم، اخلاق شرنگ‏آلود عمومی، ارتباطات شرنگ‏آلود بین‏گروهی، و رفتارهای شرنگ‏آلود سازمانی.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیشران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازمان شرنگ‏آلود</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شرنگ‏آلودگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">لبة تاریک رفتار سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل‏یابی ساختاری تفسیری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_66858_3030dd579fd6b39c5f1c762faa6f1b9d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
