<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Moderating Effect of Cynicism on Middle Managers&#039; Strategic Commitment</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اثر تعدیل‌کنندة بدبینی بر تعهد راهبردی مدیران میانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>23</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">52932</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2015.52932</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ناصر</FirstName>
					<LastName>صنوبر</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه تبریز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اژدر</FirstName>
					<LastName>کرمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه تبریز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>فرقانی بجستانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، گرایش MBA، دانشگاه تبریز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>25</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Organizational culture and managers&#039; personal attitudes play a crucial role in conducting change initiatives, especially strategic change. In this regard, middle managers&#039; commitment to change is of great importance and cynicism is the biggest obstacle in forming this commitment. In the present study, it is investigated whether organizational justice dimensions, senior management support for change and participation in decision-making bear any relationship to middle managers&#039; strategic commitment, and then the moderating effect of change cynicism on these relationships is explored. To this end, data were collected from 334 middle managers of ICT companies across Iran, and analyzed using structural equation modeling. According to the results, change cynicism fully moderated the relationships distributive and interactional justice bore to strategic commitment and partially reduced the positive effects of senior management support. Results also indicated cynicism had no effect on relationships procedural justice and participation bore to strategic commitment</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">فرهنگ سازمانی و نگرش‌های فردی مدیران نقش بسزایی در پیشبرد برنامه‌های تغییر، به‌ویژه تغییرات راهبردی ایفا می‌کند. در این میان، تعهد مدیران میانی به تغییرات راهبردی بسیار اهمیت دارد و بدبینی مهم‌ترین مانع در شکل‌گیری این تعهد است. در تحقیق حاضر رابطة ابعاد عدالت سازمانی، حمایت مدیریت ارشد از تغییر، و مشارکت در تصمیم‌گیری با تعهد راهبردی مدیران میانی بررسی و سپس، اثر تعدیل‌کنندة بدبینی به تغییر بر روابط یادشده ارزیابی شده است. بدین منظور، داده‌های مورد نیاز از 334 نفر از مدیران میانی شرکت‌های فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات سراسر کشور گردآوری شد و با روش مدل‌یابی معادلات ساختاری تجزیه‌وتحلیل شد. با توجه به نتایج، بدبینی به تغییر رابطة عدالت توزیعی و عدالت تعاملی با تعهد راهبردی را تعدیل می‌کند و آثار مثبت حمایت مدیریت ارشد را نیز به‌طور نسبی کاهش می‌دهد. نتایج تحقیق همچنین حاکی از آن است که بدبینی تأثیری بر رابطة عدالت رویه‌ای و مشارکت با تعهد راهبردی ندارد[1]. &lt;br /&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot; /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بدبینی به تغییر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تعهد راهبردی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عدالت سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیران میانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشارکت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_52932_2d5726aab1802ce3ffc3cd24c17b7e9b.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
