<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>20</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Organizational Justice on Employee’s Performance</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر عدالت سازمانی بر عملکرد کارکنان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>79</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>101</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">22981</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>حقیقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دولتی دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ایمان</FirstName>
					<LastName>احمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت دولتی دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمید</FirstName>
					<LastName>رامین مهر</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present study has been examined the effect of organizational justice on employee’s performance. after examinating revealed that organizational justice have three dimentions(Distributional Justice, Procedural Justice, Transactional Justice).then with providing a questionnaire concerning the three dimentions of organizational justice and the gathering the performance scores of the Employee&#039;s of Tehran state agricultural organization , the impact of the three dimentions on employee’s performance in Tehran state agricultural organization was examined.
The research findings indicate that Employee perceptions of the scale of respecting to Distributional and Procedural Justice in this organization will have a longer impact on employee’s performance, but was not found significant relationship between employee perceptions from Transactional Justice in this organization.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مقاله حاضر تأثیر عدالت سازمانی بر عملکرد کارکنان را مورد بررسی قرار داده است. پس از بررسی مشخص شد که عدالت سازمانی دارای سه بعد (عدالت توزیعی، عدالت رویه‌ای و عدالت مراوده‌ای) است. سپس با طرح پرسش‌نامه‌ای در زمینه سه بعد عدالت سازمانی و جمع‌آوری نمرات ارزش‌یابی عملکرد کارکنان، تأثیر این سه بعد بر عملکرد کارکنان در سازمان جهاد و کشاورزی استان تهران مورد بررسی قرارگرفت. نتایج تحقیق نشان داد که ادراکات کارکنان نسبت به میزان رعایت عدالت توزیعی و رویه‌ای در این سازمان بر عملکرد آنان تأثیر داشته، اما ارتباط چندان قوی بین ادراکات کارکنان از میزان رعایت عدالت مراوده‌ای و عملکرد کارکنان در این سازمان پیدا نشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عدالت توزیعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عدالت رویه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عدالت مراوده‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد.</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_22981_52836b82fbf918e9d4b5b8bff98966b6.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
