<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>15</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Study of the Effect of Emotional Intelligence Dimension on the Employee Performance (Case: Sport Channel of Islamic Republic of Iran)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مطالعة تأثیر ابعاد هوش هیجانی بر عملکرد کارکنان (مورد مطالعه: شبکۀ ورزش سیمای جمهوری اسلامی ایران)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>373</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>392</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">62701</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2017.62701</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>شریفی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکدة مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>ظریفیان یگانه</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری مدیریت رسانه، دانشکدة مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>صابری</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‌ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدة مدیریت، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The ability to comprehend and analyze one’s emotional experiences leads to the ability of knowing one’s self in communicating better with the environment and that controlling the emotions and developing the amplification of being good would be its outcome. Professional functionality is influenced by the ability of the staffs in utilization of emotions for facilitating the functionality and Staffs may take benefit of negative and positive emotions as an advantage in improvement of their own functionality. Objective of this research is studying the effects of emotional intelligence of the staffs of the Sports Channel on their functionality and its dimensions. Therefore, such differences apparently have meaningful influence on our life style, such as physical and mental health, functionality, occupation and social behavior. This research is accomplished using both questionnaire and quantitative methods and examined on 140 staffs of Sports Channel. Emotional intelligence and its four dimensions have a direct connection to the functionality of staffs and any increase in self-awareness, management of relations, social awareness and self-control will increase the functionality of the staffs. Concluding, emotional intelligence as an intermediate and organizer factor can improve the functionality of a group.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">توانایی برای فهم و تحلیل تجربه‌های هیجانی به توانایی فهم خویشتن در ارتباط بهتر خود با محیط منجر می‌شود که تنظیم کارآمد هیجان و تقویت خوب‌‌بودن را پرورش می‌دهد. عملکرد شغلی تحت تأثیر تو نایی کارمند در به‌کارگیری هیجان‌ها در تسهیل عملکرد است و کارمندان می‌توانند هیجان‌های مثبت و منفی را به‌عنوان مزیتی برای بهبود عملکرد خود به‌کار گیرند. هدف پژوهش حاضر بررسی تأثیر ابعاد هوش هیجانی کارکنان شبکة ورزش بر عملکرد آن‌ها و ابعاد آن است. از این رو، به نظر می‌رسد این تفاوت‌ها تأثیر معناداری بر سبک زندگی مانند سلامت جسم و روان، عملکرد، شغلی و روابط اجتماعی داشته باشد. تحقیق حاضر کاربردی و به روش توصیفی – همبستگی انجام گرفته است. ابزار پژوهش پرسشنامه است. نمونة 140 نفری از کارکنان شبکة ورزش سیما به روش تصادفی ساده انتخاب شد. نتایج حاکی از آن است که هوش هیجانی و ابعاد چهارگانة آن بر عملکرد کارکنان تأثیر مثبت و معنادار می‌گذاردو هرگونه افزایشی در خودآگاهی، مدیریت روابط، آگاهی اجتماعی و خودکنترلی افراد عملکرد کارکنان را افزایش می‌دهد. در نتیجه، هوش هیجانی عاملی سازمان‌دهنده است که موجب بهبود عملکرد گروه می‌شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آگاهی اجتماعی و خودکنترلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خودآگاهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت روابط</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هوش هیجانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_62701_911409341770c0fe4bcd5da0e26996e1.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
