<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Evaluating the Influence of Employee Voice on Employees&#039; Performance and Creativity through the Mediating Role of Job Engagement</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر صدای کارمند بر خلاقیت و عملکرد کارکنان با میانجیگری درگیری شغلی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>833</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>856</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">54741</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2015.54741</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>رنگریز</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایرا</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعید</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>26</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Employee voice, due to its role in improving the employees&#039; and organizations&#039; performance, has attracted the attention of researchers and managers in recent years. This study aims at developing an employee voice scale customized to Iran&#039;s context and also evaluating the influence of employee voice on employees&#039; performance and creativity through the mediating role of job engagement. This study is considered as applied considering its aim and as descriptive- correlative study considering the way data is gathered. Knowledge employees of Kaleh Company were selected as the population of this research. Census sampling was used and 234 questionnaires were distributed among the respondents for gathering data. Explorative factor analysis, confirmatory factor analysis and structural modeling tests were used for data analysis. The results of testing the hypotheses indicate that employee voice has significantly positive effect on job engagement. Results also prove that job engagement has positively significant effect on employees&#039; performance both directly and indirectly through the mediating role of creativity.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در چند سال اخیر، محققان و مدیران به صدای کارمند به دلیل نقشی که در کسب مزیت رقابتی ایفا می‌کند، توجه فراوان کرده‌اند. این پژوهش با هدف طراحی شاخصی بومی برای صدای کارمند و بررسی تأثیر صدای کارمند بر خلاقیت و عملکرد فردی کارکنان از طریق نقش میانجی درگیری شغلی انجام گرفت. پژوهش حاضر از نظر هدف کاربردی و از نظر نحوة گردآوری داده‌ها توصیفی- همبستگی است. کارکنان شرکت کاله جامعة آماری این تحقیق را تشکیل داده‌اند. نمونه‌گیری به روش سرشماری انجام گرفت و 234 پرسشنامه برای جمع‌آوری داده‌ها توزیع شد. برای تحلیل داده‌ها تحلیل عاملی اکتشافی، تحلیل عاملی تأییدی و مدل ساختاری به‌کار گرفته شد. طبق نتایج این پژوهش، صدای کارمند بر درگیری شغلی تأثیر مثبت و معنادار دارد. همچنین، نتایج، نشان داد درگیری شغلی هم به‌طور مستقیم و هم غیرمستقیم، از طریق خلاقیت بر عملکرد کارکنان تأثیر مثبت و معنادار دارد.



 </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">درگیری شغلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خلاقیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صدای کارمند</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_54741_5b1f2ada4c4bb14a4a239333b07d4637.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
