<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2003</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>-</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>حکمرانی خوب و نقش دولت</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14192</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>دکتر فتاح شریف</FirstName>
					<LastName>زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رحمت اله قلی</FirstName>
					<LastName>پور</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Good governance that is described with characteristics such as participation, transparency, accountability, effectiveness, efficiency, and rulership of law is
a model. with an interaction mechanism between the governmental sector, private sector and civil society for sustainable human development.
This model follows minimal role of state and enhancement of civil institutions
and private sector. For. this end in view, emphasis is put on interaction between governmental sector, private sector, and civil society. This theory believes that instead of incumbency, government must enhance its facilitating
and regulating role.
In Good Government Model, representative and participatory government is discussed and in this manner, the way is paved for activity of other sectors. In order to put the above role into practice, the model of
facilitating government in good governance with some variables such as democracy, participation, accountability, justice-orientation and effectiveness is proposed. If the above-mentioned variables are realized in government, interaction between it and other sector will increase. Theoretically analyzing
this model is ultimate purpose of this paper.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">نظریه حکمرانی خوب که با ویژگی هایی مانند مشارکت،شفافیت،پاسخگویی اثربخشی و کارآیی و حاکمیت قانون تعریف می شود،الگویی برای توسعه پایدار انسانی با ساز و کار تعامل عملی سه بخش دولت ، بخش خصوصی و جامعه مدنی است .
این الگو به دنبال نقش حداقل دولت و توانمند سازی نهادهای مدنی و بخش خصوصی می باشد. در این راستا بر رفتار تعاملی سه بخش دولت ، نهادهای مدنی و بخش خصوصی تأکید می شود و معتقد است دولت باید نقش هماهنگ کننده و تنظیم گر خود را تقویت نموده و به جای تصدیگری به تنظیم و تسهیل روابط بپردازد.
در الگوی حکمرانی خوب بحث از دولت نماینده و دولت مشارکتی است که از این طریق راه را برای فعالیت سایر بخش ها هموار می سازد.
به منظور اعمال نقش فوق، الگوی دولت تسهیل گر در حکمرانی خوب با متغیرهایی مانند دموکراسی،مشارکت،پاسخگویی،عدالت محوری و اثر بخشی پیشنهاد شده که در صورت تحقق متغیرهای فوق در دولت ، تعامل بین آن و دو بخش دیگر بیشترخواهد شد . بررسی نظری این الگو،هدف نهایی این مقاله خواهد بود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حکمرانی خوب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دولت پاسخگو و دولت عدالت محور</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دولت تسهیل گر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دولت دموکراتیک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دولت مشارکتی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_14192_c9df4cb49c7407a048bf8331d65863b5.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
