<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>21</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Using the Analytic Network Process (ANP) in SWOT for Determining and Evaluating the Organizational Strategies</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تدوین و ارزیابی استراتژی‌های سازمانی با به کارگیری مدل‌های SWOT و فرآیند تحلیل شبکه‌ای ANP</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>175</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>159</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">24015</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>ملکی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری تحقیق در عملیات دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>محقر</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد مهندسی صنایع دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>داوود</FirstName>
					<LastName>کریمی دستجردی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد یار دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Strengths, weaknesses, opportunities and threats (SWOT) analysis do not provide an analytical means to determine the importance of the identified factors or the ability to assess decision alternatives according to these factors. Although the analysis successfully pinpoints the factors, individual factors are usually described briefly and very generally. For this reason, SWOT analysis possesses deficiencies in the measurement and evaluation steps. Although the analytic hierarchy process (AHP) technique removes these deficiencies, it does not allow for the measurement of the possible dependencies among the factors. Therefore, it is better to employ a form of SWOT analysis that measures and takes into account the possible dependencies among the factors. This paper uses the analytic network process (ANP), which allows the quantitative analysis of SWOT and measurement of the dependencies among the factors. Dependencies among the SWOT factors affect the strategic and sub-factor weights and change the strategy priorities. Aim of this research, to determine priority of organizational strategies for using. SWOT is used for determining of strategies and ANP is used for evaluating strategies. Finally, strategy of SO is selected as best strategy for using because it had most weight in final matrix.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">تجزیه و تحلیل نقاط قوت، ضعف، فرصت و تهدید ( SWOT) قادر به تعیین اهمیت هر یک از عوامل شناخته شده نیست و راهکاری را برای ارزیابی گزینه‌های تصمیم با توجه به این عوامل ارایه نمی‌دهد. اگر چه تجزیه و تحلیل SWOT عوامل مورد نظر را مشخص می‌کند، اما هر یک از عوامل معمولا به صورت خلاصه و خیلی کلی توصیف می‌شوند. به همین خاطر، تجزیه و تحلیل SWOT در مراحل ارزیابی و اندازه‌گیری دارای برخی از نقص‌ها می‌باشد. روش فرآیند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی ( AHP) بعضی از نقاط ضعف تجزیه و تحلیل SWOT را مرتفع می‌کند، اما وابستگی‌های ممکن میان عوامل را در نظر نمی‌گیرد. به همین دلیل به کارگیری شکل خاصی از تجزیه و تحلیل SWOT که وابستگی‌های ممکن میان عوامل را در نظر می‌گیرد، مناسب‌تر است. در پژوهش حاضر برای تجزیه و تحلیل کمی SWOT و در نظر گرفتن وابستگی‌های ممکن میان عوامل از روش فرآیند تحلیل شبکه‌ای ( ( ANP استفاده نموده است. وابستگی‌های ممکن میان عوامل SWOT، وزن‌های عوامل استراتژیک، وزن‌های عوامل فرعی و اولویت‌های استراتژی‌های جایگزین را تحت تأثیر قرار می‌دهند. هدف این تحقیق، اولویت بندی استراتژی های سازمانی برای اجراست. برای تدوین استراتژی ها از تکنیک SWOT و برای اولویت بندی ... .</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">برنامه‌ریزی استراتژیک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تجزیه و تحلیل swot</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_24015_d9ec39edbae4ee7bc5e2bd15fb2784ab.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
