<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>16</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Citizen Perception of Political Stability and Political Displacement Indicators in Good Governance based on Native Components of Iranian Urban Utilities Organizations (Case Study: Governmental Organizations of Khuzestan Province)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ادراک شهروندان از شاخص‌های ثبات سیاسی و جابه‌جایی سیاسی در حکمرانی خوب، براساس مؤلفه‌های بومی سازمان‌های خدمات شهری ایران (مطالعۀ موردی: سازمان‌های دولتی استان خوزستان)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>927</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>950</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">70044</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2019.244049.1007358</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فؤاد</FirstName>
					<LastName>مکوندی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، واحد شوشتر، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، شوشتر، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمید</FirstName>
					<LastName>زارع</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امید</FirstName>
					<LastName>جلیلی قاسم‌آقا</LastName>
<Affiliation>مربی دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The aim of the present study was to understand the citizen perception of political stability and political displacement indicators in good governance based on native components of Iranian  urban utility organizations. The research was conducted at governmental service organizations in Masjedsoleyman, Ramhormoz, and Behbahan cities. The statistical population of this research was all of the clients of the government organization of Khuzestan province in Masjedsoleiman,  Ramhormoz, and Behbahan cities. The method of research was qualitative and the data  collection tool was an in-depth interview. The sampling method was convenience (62 customers of 4 governmental organizations). Data analysis based on thematic analysis showed that lawfulness, quality of service, monitoring and evaluation, responsiveness, commitment and responsibility,  and finally interaction were the most important political stability indicators on the organizations. Also, diversity and displacement selection, meritocracy, effectiveness monitoring, making agility of bureaucratic structured, transparency at the manager’s selection were the most important  political displacement indicators on the organizations.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">تحقیق حاضر با هدف شناسایی ادراک شهروندان از شاخص‌های ثبات سیاسی و جابه‌جایی سیاسی در حکمرانی خوب، براساس مؤلفه‌های بومی سازمان‌های خدمات شهری ایران، صورت گرفت. جامعة‌ آماری همة مراجعه‌کنندگان سازمان‌های دولتی استان خوزستان بودند. روش استفاده‌شده کیفی و ابزار گردآوری داده‌ها مصاحبة عمیق بود. با استفاده از نمونه‌گیری در دسترس، شصت‌ودو مراجعه‌کننده به چهار سازمان دولتی شهرستان‌های مسجدسلیمان، رامهرمز، و بهبهان انتخاب شدند. تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها، براساس تحلیل مضمون/ تم، نشان داد قانونمندی، کیفیت خدمات، نظارت و ارزیابی، پاسخگویی، تعهد و مسئولیت‌پذیری، و در نهایت تعامل مهم‌ترین شاخص‌های ثبات سیاسی در سازمان‌های مذکورند. همچنین، جابه‌جایی و تنوع انتخاب، شایسته‌سالاری، نظارت مؤثر، چابک‌سازی ساختار اداری، و شفافیت در انتخاب مدیران به ترتیب مهم‌ترین شاخص‌های جابه‌جایی سیاسی از دیدگاه مصاحبه‌شوندگان بودند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ثبات سیاسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جابه‌جایی سیاسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حکمرانی خوب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خدمات</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_70044_2ef894657e61002852442202486a8c57.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
