<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Meta- Analysis of the Antecedents and Consequences of Psychological Empowerment of Employees</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>فراتحلیل پیشایندها و پیامدهای توانمندسازی روان‌شناختی کارکنان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">76019</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2020.299080.1008002</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حامد</FirstName>
					<LastName>خامه چی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترا/ دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>رنگریز</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار/دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه خوارزمی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study was to identify the antecedents and consequences of psychological empowerment of employees using a meta- analysis approach. The present study is descriptive in terms of purpose, practical in terms of usage and quantitative in terms of type of data. The study population consists of articles published in scientific journals in the field of psychological empowerment of employees from 2011 to 2019 that 53 cases were entered through meta-analysis process with a non- random purposive sampling method. Selected studies were analyzed using CMA2 software (Comprehensive Meta-Analysis Software). The reliability of the research includes the reliability of identification was obtained through the agreement of the referees in selecting and categorizing the researches, the reliability of coding was obtained through the agreement of the referees on the use of specific concepts for coding variables, and the reliability of significant level and effect size was obtained through an agreement in measuring the effect size between the two meta- analyst. Findings showed that among the antecedents of psychological empowerment of employees, respectively, the variables of benevolent leadership (0.877), knowledge management (0.772), social capital (0.616), genuine leadership (0.609), organizational memory (0.603) and spiritual leadership (0.601) had the greatest effect size. Also, among the consequences of psychological empowerment of employees, respectively, the variables of Staff voices (0.853), competitive advantage (0.734), job performance (0.724), spirituality at work (0.655), staff creativity (0.630) and innovative atmosphere (0.626) had the greatest effect size.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف این تحقیق شناسایی پیشایندها و پیامدهای توانمندسازی روان‌شناختی کارکنان با استفاده از رویکرد فراتحلیل است. تحقیق حاضر از نظر هدف، توصیفی و از نظر نوع استفاده کاربردی و از نظر نوع داده‌ها، کمی است. جامعه مورد بررسی پژوهش، شامل مقالات چاپ شده در مجلات علمی- پژوهشی در زمینه توانمندسازی روان‌شناختی کارکنان از سال 1390 تا تابستان سال 1398 بود که 53 مورد با استفاده از روش نمونه‌گیری غیرتصادفی هدفمند به عنوان نمونه وارد فرایند فراتحلیل شدند. پژوهش‌های منتخب با استفاده از نرم افزار CMA2 (نرم افزار جامع فراتحلیل) مورد تحلیل قرار گرفتند. پایایی تحقیق شامل پایایی شناسایی از طریق توافق داوران در انتخاب پژوهش‌ها و طبقه‌بندی آن‌ها، پایایی کدگذاری از طریق توافق داوران درباره استفاده از مفاهیم خاص برای کدگذاری متغیرها و پایایی سطح معنی‌داری و اندازه اثر از طریق توافق در محاسبات اندازه اثر بین دو فراتحلیل‌گر به دست آمد. یافته‌ها نشان دادند که از بین پیشایندهای توانمندسازی روان‌شناختی کارکنان، به ترتیب متغیرهای رهبری خیرخواه (877/0)، مدیریت دانش (772/0)، سرمایه اجتماعی (616/0)، رهبری اصیل (609/0)، حافظه سازمانی (603/0) و رهبری معنوی (601/0) دارای بیشترین اندازه اثر هستند. همچنین از بین پیامدهای توانمندسازی روان‌شناختی کارکنان، به ترتیب متغیرهای آوای کارکنان (853/0)، مزیت رقابتی (734/0)، عملکرد شغلی (724/0)، معنویت در کار (655/0)، خلاقیت کارکنان (630/0) و جو نوآورانه (626/0) دارای بیشترین اندازه اثر هستند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توانمندسازی روان‌شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فراتحلیل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیشایندها و پیامدها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارکنان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
