<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Organizational Culture Ambidexterity and Performance: The Critical Role of Organizational Ambidexterity</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>فرهنگ‌سازمانی دوسوتوان و عملکرد: نقش حیاتی دوسوتوانی سازمانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1245</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>1266</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">55436</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2016.55436</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمود</FirstName>
					<LastName>مرادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار،گروه مدیریت، دانشکدة علوم انسانی، دانشگاه گیلان، رشت، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کیخسرو</FirstName>
					<LastName>یاکیده</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار،گروه مدیریت، دانشکدة علوم انسانی، دانشگاه گیلان، رشت، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>مدنی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکدة علوم انسانی، دانشگاه گیلان، رشت، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Ambidexterity concept refers to the ability of organizations to address two incompatible objectives. In environmental uncertainty, organizational ambidexterity typically has a positive effect on performance and leads to sustainable competitive advantage, long-term success and survival. Nevertheless, it is possible only when the culture enables organizational members to exploit current competence (exploitation) and explore new opportunities and abilities (exploration).The purpose of this study is to assess the effects of organizational culture ambidexterity and organizational ambidexterity on performance. In order to evaluate the research hypotheses, companies operating in the food industry were selected as population and questionnaires from managers of 62 companies is collected and analyzed. The proposed model is analyzed using Structural Equation Modeling techniques with the help of Warp PLS program. Results support the relationship between organizational culture ambidexterity and organizational ambidexterity, as well as their relationship with performance. Also according to the results, organizational ambidexterity has a mediator role in the relationship between organizational culture ambidexterity and performance.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مفهوم دوسوتوانی سازمانی، به توانایی سازمان برای توجه به دو هدف ناسازگار سازمانی به‌طور برابر اشاره می‌کند که در شرایط عدم اطمینان به‌طور معمول اثری مثبت بر عملکرد دارد و به عملکرد پایدار، بقا و موفقیت طولانی‌مدت منجر می‌شود. اما این فقط در صورتی امکان­پذیر است که فرهنگی ایجاد شود تا اعضای سازمانی را قادر کند از شایستگی‌های موجود بهره‌برداری کنند (بهره‌برداری) و از طرف دیگر فرصت‌ها و توانایی‌های جدید را کشف کنند (کتشاف). هدف از پژوهش حاضر نیز بررسی نقش فرهنگ سازمانی دوسوتوان و دوسوتوانی سازمانی بر عملکرد است. بدین منظور و برای آزمون فرضیه‌های پژوهش، شرکت‌های فعال در صنایع غذایی به‌عنوان جامعة آماری پژوهش انتخاب شدند و پرسشنامه بین  مدیران 62 شرکت توزیع، جمع‌آوری و تحلیل شده است. مدل پیشنهادی بر مبنای مدل­سازی معادلات ساختاری به روش حداقل مربعات جزئی با کمک نرم­افزار Warp PLS تجزیه‌وتحلیل شد. نتایج تحلیل از رابطة بین فرهنگ‌ سازمانی دوسوتوان و دوسوتوانی، همچنین رابطة این دو  با عملکرد حمایت می‌کند. همچنین، با توجه به نتایج، نقش میانجی دوسوتوانی در رابطة فرهنگ‌ سازمانی دوسوتوان و عملکرد تأیید شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دوسوتوانی سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرهنگ سازمانی دوسوتوان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_55436_4f48af76d62d7ec79338ae92d6e24aea.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
