<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>18</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Designing and Testing a Model Comprised of Some Antecedents and Consequences of Perceived Organizational Politics in the Employees of Abadan Oil Refinery Company</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی و آزمون الگویی از برخی پیشایندها و پیامدهای سیاسی‏ کاری ادراک‏ شده در کارکنان شرکت پالایش نفت آبادان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>69</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>90</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">73754</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2019.273535.1007698</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>الهام</FirstName>
					<LastName>ساعی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری روانشناسی، دانشکدة علوم تربیتی و روانشناسی، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، اهواز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کیومرث</FirstName>
					<LastName>بشلیده</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، دانشکدة علوم تربیتی و روانشناسی، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، اهواز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>مرعشی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکدة علوم تربیتی و روانشناسی، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، اهواز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نسرین</FirstName>
					<LastName>ارشدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، دانشکدة علوم تربیتی و روانشناسی، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، اهواز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study was designing and testing a model of antecedents (including ethical leadership, transformational leadership, transactional leadership, and organizational centralization) and consequences (including job frustration, job anxiety, workplace deviance, and employee silence) of perceived organizational politics in the employees of Abadan oil Refinery Company. The research design of this study was correlational, done through structural equation modeling (SEM). The statistical population included all employees in Abadan oil Refinery Company in the year 2018, out of which a sample of 459 employees was selected using multistage random sampling method. The data collection instruments included perceived organizational politics (Zho &amp; Ferris, 1996), ethical leadership (Brown et al., 2005), leadership styles (Ismail et al., 2010), organizational structure preference (McShane &amp; Von Gilnow, 2013), job frustration (Peters et al., 1980), job anxiety (Parker, &amp; De Cotiis, 1983), workplace deviance (Aquino et al., 1999) and employee silence (Brinsfield, 2013) scales. The structural equation modeling was used to test the proposed model. Also, bootstrapping method was used to evaluate indirect effects in the model. Results showed that the fitness indices for the proposed model were in the acceptable range; however, by imposing some modifications, the model achieved a better fitness. The results also showed that all direct paths (except for the paths of transactional leadership and centralization to perceived organizational politics, and the paths of job frustration to workplace deviance and employee silence) were significant. Based on the findings of the present research, political perceptions can bring about employee silence and workplace deviance. Therefore, it is essential to pay attention in this regards.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از پژوهش حاضر طراحی و آزمون الگویی از برخی پیشایندها (رهبری اخلاقی، سبک رهبری تبدیلی، سبک رهبری تبادلی، تمرکزگرایی سازمانی) و پیامدهای سیاسی‏کاری (ناکامی سازمانی، اضطراب شغلی، رفتار انحرافی کار، سکوت کارکن) در کارکنان شرکت پالایش نفت آبادان بود. طرح پژوهش حاضر از نوع همبستگی از طریق الگویابی معادلات ساختاری (SEM) بود. جامعة آماری همة کارکنان شرکت پالایشگاه نفت آبادان در سال 1397 بودند. از این جامعه تعداد 459 نفر با استفاده از روش نمونه‌گیری چندمرحله‏ای تصادفی انتخاب شدند. ابزار پژوهش شامل مقیاس‏های سیاسی‏کاری ادراک‏شده، رهبری اخلاقی، سبک رهبری، ترجیح ساختار سازمانی، ناکامی شغلی، اضطراب شغلی، رفتار انحرافی محیط کاری و سکوت کارکن بود. برای بررسی آثار غیرمستقیم در الگوی پژوهش، روش بوت استروپ به کار گرفته شد. نتایج نشان داد، با انجام دادن اصلاحات، شاخص‏های برازش الگوی پیشنهادی پژوهش در دامنة قابل قبولی قرار می‌گیرد. با اصلاحات بیشتر الگو برازش مطلوب‏تری حاصل می‌شود. نیز همة مسیرهای مستقیم در الگوی پیشنهادی (به جز مسیر رهبری تبادلی و تمرکزگرایی سازمانی به سیاسی‏کاری ادراک‏شده و مسیر ناکامی شغلی به انحراف کاری و سکوت کارکن) معنادار است. بر اساس یافته‏های پژوهش حاضر ادراکات سیاسی‏کاری می‏تواند موجب رفتارهای سکوت و انحراف کاری کارکنان شود. ازین‏رو، توجه به این موضوع در سازمان‏ها ضروری است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اضطراب شغلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفتار ‏انحرافی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سکوت کارکن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیاسی‏کاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ناکامی‏شغلی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_73754_4b6fb0aa1e779a57f10adccea1c1af44.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
