<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2004</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>-</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی رابطه تناظر یک به یک بین درجات مشارکت با درجات نیازهای غالب و ارائه مدلی کامپیوتری مربوطه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">11401</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>دکتر على اکبر</FirstName>
					<LastName>فرهنگى</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهندس میکائیل</FirstName>
					<LastName>برقى</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>What we are following in this research is whether there is basically a one-to-one correspondence between Ministry Of Roads and Transportation executive employees’ prevailing needs levels and their common levels or not. Employees’ prevailing needs levels are, according to Mazelo’s hierarchy needs theory, divided into five levels: 
physiology, security, social, respect, self-analysis. Their common levels start from full non-participation to full participation and are respectively divided into non-participation, participation according to suggestion. mutual decision-making, and independent teams. 
To carry out this research we devised some theories and by doing field4orks thai arc in line with theories and research aims we gathered data about theories and then by using Spearman hierarchical correlation test (on the whole 25 secondary tests) we analyzed and summarized data and existing information. And we concluded that there is not enough reasons for proving the theory that there is a one-to-one correspondence between employees’ prevailing needs levels and their common levels. 
By using chi - spuare (X2) test (on the whole 6 secondary tests), we are after this matter that employees with prevailing need (or needs) can prefer various levels of participation, therefore, with regards to the above tests, the deduction that there are multiple relations between employees’ prevailing needs and their common levels is valid. 
Moreover by using Freedman Variance Analysis Test we ranked research variables and prioritized common levels by planning and programming a computer model (that was done by researcher) of multiple-criterion decision-making with the approach MADM and with regards to models SAW and TOPSIS. Finally, emphasizing each theories of the research, we presented the achieved results, as the results of research and offered some suggestions about the carried out research, other studies and similar researches.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">آنچه در این تحقبق به دنبال آن هستیم عبارت از این است که اصولا آیا این درجات نیازهای غالب کارکنان حوزه ستادی وزارت راه و.ترابری و درجات مشارکت آنها تناظر یک به یک برقرار است یا خیر؟ درجات نیازهای غالب کارکنان بر اساس نظریه سلسله مراتب نیازهای مازلو به پنج درجه نیازهای فیزیولوژیکی, ایمنی، اجتماعی، احترام و خود یابی تقسیم گردیده و درجات مشارکت آنها بر اساس طیفی که از عدم مشارکت کامل آغاز و به مشارکت کامل منتهی میگردد به ترتیب به درجات عدم مشارکت، مشارکت لر مبنای پیشنهاد، مشارکت بر مبنای مشورت، تصمیم گیری دو جانبه و بالاخره تیم های خود گردان تقسیم شده است.
مشارکت بر مبنای پیشنهاد مشارکت بر کبنای مشورت تصمیم گیری دو جانبه و با لاخره تیم های خود گردلن تقسیم شده است .
در راستلی انجام تحقیق حاضر ابتدا فرضیاتی تدوین گردیده و سپس با انجام مطالعاتی میدانی همسو با فرضیات و اهداف تحقیق به جمع آوری اطلاعات در مورد فرضیات پرداخته و پس از پردازش و تلخیص داده ها و اطلاعات موجود با استفاده از روش آزمون همبستگی رتبه ای اسپیرمن ( جمعا بیست و پنج آزمون فرعی ) به این نتیجه می رسیم ه دلایلی کافی برای اثبات برقراری رابطه تناظر یک به یک بین درجات نیازهای کارکنان با درجات مشارکت آنها برقرار است وجود ندارد.
با استفاده از آزمون کای دو ( جمعا شش آزمون فرعی ) هب دنبال این هستیم که کارکنان با نیاز غالب میتوانند درجات مختلفی از مشارکت را ترجیح دهند لذا با عنایت به آزمونهای فوق استنتاج اینکه بین نیازهای غالب کارکنان و درجات مشارکت آنها روابط چند گانه حاکم است معتبر میباشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الویت بندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تصمیم گیری چند معیاره</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تناظر یک به یک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">درجات مشارکت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">درجات نیازهای غالب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سلسله مراتب نیازها</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_11401_a0c0a1bf8e42fc3f217365e1204658f0.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
