<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identifying and Ranking of Individual and Organizational Factors Affecting Transfer of High Technologies at Different Technology Readiness Levels (TRLs)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی و رتبه بندی عوامل فردی و سازمانی تأثیرگذار بر انتقال فناوری های پیشرفته در سطوح گوناگون آمادگی فناوری (TRLs)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>691</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>712</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">54735</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2015.54735</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جهانشاه</FirstName>
					<LastName>چرختاب مقدم</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت راهبردی، دانشگاه عالی دفاع ملی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اسماعیل</FirstName>
					<LastName>کلانتری</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‌ ارشد، دانشکدة کارآفرینی، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>One of the strategies for achieving the knowledge-based economy and wealth creation is High Technologies Transfer. Depending on their needs, all governments and knowledge-based corporations are transferring High Technologies at different technology readiness levels. In this study, the researcher seeks to identify and rank the individual and organizational factors affecting High Technologies transfer at different levels of readiness. For this purpose, the research method which has been used is qualitative -quantitative. Ten theoretical experts have been interviewed in the qualitative section and 100 practical experts have been interviewed using questionnaires in the quantitative section, also the results were analyzed. In qualitative section, analysis method is coding and in quantitative section, analysis methods are ANOVA and Friedman test. The findings revealed that the influence of individual factors on technology transfer is more than of organizational factors and also suggest this fact that by increasing the level of technology readiness the influence of individual and organizational factors on the success of technology transfer increases. Government and knowledge-based corporations will increase the possibility of success in transfer of High Technologies and will reduce its risks by considering individual and organizational factors that influence the transfer of High Technologies at various technology readiness levels.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">یکی از راهبردهای دستیابی به اقتصاد دانش­بنیان و خلق ثروت، انتقال فناوری­های پیشرفته است. اکنون دولت­ها و شرکت­های دانش­بنیان، بسته به قابلیت و نیاز خود، فناوری­های پیشرفته را در سطوح گوناگون آمادگی فناوری انتقال می­دهند. در این پژوهش، پژوهشگر در جست‌وجوی شناسایی و رتبه‌بندی عوامل فردی و سازمانی تأثیرگذار بر انتقال فناوری­های پیشرفته در سطوح گوناگون آمادگی فناوری است. بدین منظور روش پژوهش کیفی- کمی به‌کار گرفته شده است. در بخش کیفی، با 10 نفر از خبرگان نظری مصاحبه شد و در بخش کمی، نظرهای 100 نفر از خبرگان عملی از طریق پرسشنامه گردآوری و تحلیل شده است. روش تحلیل در بخش کیفی، کدگذاری، و در بخش کمی تحلیل عاملی، تحلیل واریانس یک‌راهه و آزمون فریدمن است. یافته­های پژوهش نشان می­دهد تأثیر عوامل فردی بر انتقال فناوری بیشتر از عوامل سازمانی است و نیز با افزایش سطوح آمادگی فناوری (از نظر اولیه تا تجاری­سازی) تأثیر عوامل فردی و سازمانی بر موفقیت انتقال فناوری افزایش می­یابد. درنظرگرفتن عوامل فردی و سازمانی تأثیرگذار بر انتقال فناوری­های پیشرفته در سطوح گوناگون آمادگی فناوری توسط دولت­ها و شرکت­های دانش­بنیان، احتمال موفقیت ایشان را در انتقال فناوری­های پیشرفته افزایش و مخاطرات آن را کاهش می­دهد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انتقال فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سطوح آمادگی فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عوامل سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عوامل فردی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فناوری های پیشرفته</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_54735_a356732ddd7a3e0f6ea267a5d8ec8d8c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
