<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>16</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Explaining the Concept of Strategic Thinking from an Islamic Perspective</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تبیین مفهوم تفکر راهبردی از منظر اسلام</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>751</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>777</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68790</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2018.230443.1007187</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>کبیری پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‌‌ارشد، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرتضی</FirstName>
					<LastName>سلطانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>عبدالهی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، پژوهشگاه حوزه و دانشگاه، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>04</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>With the advent of the concept of &quot;strategic thinking&quot;, visionaries and many researchers have tried to look at a definition for offering a logical model to measure the ability to provide strategic thinking. However, despite highly enriched Islamic religious sources and Sciences, little effort has been made to extract the components of strategic thinking with an Islamic approach, and deficiency of local and Islamic research in this area is quite evident. In this study, to collect data and information required, the direct reference to the Quran, the hadith, and Islamic Science Citation text presentations and resources have been employed and, according to research, open coding practices are used. In this manner, the text of the units studied in an evolutionary process scripts, concepts, and components were converted; then, after obtaining the opinion of the experts by questionnaire, to determine the preference of the components, the Analytical Hierarchy Process (AHP) and Expert Choice software were used. In this study, the final extracted components in order of preference were: considering the divine traditions, vision, idealism, foresight, wisdom, and prudence connection.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">با ظهور مفهوم «تفکر راهبردی»، متفکران و محققان بسیاری تلاش کرده‏اند تا از نگاه خود تعریف مشخصی برای آن ارائه کنند و یک مدل منطقی برای سنجش قابلیت تفکر راهبردی ارائه نمایند. باوجوداین و به‏رغم غنای بسیار زیاد منابع دینی و علوم اسلامی، تلاش‏های ناچیزی برای استخراج مؤلفه‏های تفکر راهبردی با رویکرد اسلامی ‏انجام شده و خلأ تحقیقات بومی ‏و اسلامی ‏در این زمینه کاملاً مشهود است. هدف از تحقیق حاضر شناسایی مؤلفه‏های اساسی تفکر راهبردی با بررسی منابع اسلامی‏ است. در این تحقیق، برای گردآوری داده‏ها و اطلاعات مورد نیاز، از تفاسیر قرآن کریم، احادیث و روایات، آثار و سخنرانی اندیشمندان دینی معاصر، و منابع استنادی علوم اسلامی ‏استفاده شده است. همچنین، با توجه به هدف تحقیق، از شیوة تحلیل مضمون (تم) بهره‏گیری شده و واحدهای منتخب متن مورد مطالعه در فرایندی تکاملی به کدها، تم‏ها، و محورها (مؤلفه‏های نهایی) تبدیل شده است. سپس، برای تعیین اولویت محورهای تفکر راهبردی، پس از اخذ نظر خبرگان، به‏وسیلة پرسش‏نامه، از تکنیک فرایند تحلیل سلسله‏مراتبی (AHP) استفاده شده است. بر اساس نتایج تحقیق، به‏ترتیب اولویت، محورهایِ توجه به سنت‏های الهی، بصیرت، آرمان‏خواهی، دوراندیشی، حکمت، و اتصالِ تدبیر تبیین‏کنندة مفهوم تفکر راهبردی از منظر اسلام است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل مضمون</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تفکر راهبردی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رویکرد اسلامی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرایند تحلیل سلسله‏ مراتبی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_68790_5dc019f395c683e3eba0dc6f5ee02586.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
