<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigation on the Effect of Error Management
Culture on Organizational Innovation</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر فرهنگ مدیریت خطا بر نوآوری سازمانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>87</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>114</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">35488</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2013.35488</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمود</FirstName>
					<LastName>مرادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه گیلان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کیخسرو</FirstName>
					<LastName>یاکیده</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه گیلان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرزانه</FirstName>
					<LastName>عبداللهیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه گیلان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عاطیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>صفردوست</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه گیلان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Nearly two decades, organizational failures are considered as an effective source of promoting organizational learning. Error management culture in the organization is established as a mechanism to facilitate organizational learning from errors that improves long-term and sustainable innovation and organizational performance. The main objective of this study is to investigate the relation between error management culture and organizational innovation, and to explain the role of organizational learning in this regard. Pharmaceutical and insurance companies in Tehran Stock Exchange were selected to data collection. More than 200 questionnaires distributed in 16 pharmaceutical companies and 3 insurance companies, 151 questionnaires were returned. Using a one-sample T-test and correlation analysis proved that error management culture has good position in these companies. Furthermore, its relationship with organizational learning and innovation was confirmed. Hierarchical regression results suggest that organizational learning plays as mediator in the relationship between organizational innovation and error management culture.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">خطا و شکست‌های سازمانی نزدیک به دو دهه است که به عنوان منبعی مؤثر در ارتقا یادگیری سازمانی مورد توجه واقع شده است. استقرار فرهنگ مدیریت خطا در سازمان به عنوان راهکاری است که یادگیری از خطاهای سازمانی را تسهیل کرده و موجب بهبود بلندمدت و پایدار در نوآوری و عملکرد سازمانی می‌شود. هدف اصلی این تحقیق، بررسی رابطه‌ی بین فرهنگ مدیریت خطا و نوآوری سازمانی و تبیین نقش یادگیری سازمانی در این رابطه می‌باشد و به آزمون پنج فرضیه می‌پردازد. جامعه آماری تحقیق شرکت‌های داروسازی و بیمه پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران می‌باشد. از 200 پرسشنامه توزیع شده در 16 شرکت داروسازی و سه شرکت بیمه، تعداد 151 پرسشنامه بازگشت داده شد. با استفاده از آزمون‌های T تک نمونه­ای و همبستگی، ثابت شد که جایگاه فرهنگ مدیریت خطا در جامعه آماری از موقعیت مطلوبی برخوردار است. همچنین، رابطه‌ی آن با هریک از متغیرهای یادگیری سازمانی و نوآوری مورد تأیید واقع شد. نتایج حاصل از رگرسیون سلسله مراتبی حاکی از آن است که یادگیری سازمانی در رابطه بین فرهنگ مدیریت خطا و نوآوری سازمانی نقش متغیر میانجی را دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرهنگ مدیریت خطا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">یادگیری از خطا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">یادگیری سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوآوری سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_35488_ef740cfe2d7c70d32d1501915e8d202b.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
