<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6942</Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Effect of Spiritual Intelligence on Individual Performance (Case: Department of Education and Training of the Region 6)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تاثیر هوش معنوی بر عملکرد شغلی (مورد مطالعه: ادارۀ آموزش پرورش منطقه 6 تهران)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1267</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>1287</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">55437</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jomc.2016.55437</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>یکتایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه فلسفه و حکمت، دانشگاه شاهد، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>علی پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‌‌ارشد، دانشکدة مدیریت، دانشگاه شاهد، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>خسروی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‌‌ارشد، دانشکدة مدیریت، دانشگاه شاهد، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حانیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>بذرافشان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>As the spiritual intelligence structure is more complete than other ones such as emotional intelligence and intellectual intelligence and it influences other intelligences, the present research assesses the impact of this intelligence on performance. In order to measure the related parameters, most of the items of Naseri tool have been used, but according to its generality and non-nativeness, we achieved seven main indicators to measure the variable of the spiritual intelligence by taking advantage of the opinions of the experts. A questionnaire was prepared and distributed with the Kazemi tool in the department of Education and Training of the region 6 of Tehran, with a population of 120 and 85 samples were analyzed. The factor analysis was performed and the reliability and validity of the prepared tool and the Kazemi tool was approved. According to the results of this research, the impact of the indicators of self-awareness, flexibility, patience, spiritual experiences and problem-solving ability on performance was confirmed; but the same was rejected for the impact of indicators of targeting and Excellency.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">با توجه به اینکه سازة هوش معنوی از هوش­های هیجانی، عاطفی و عقلایی کامل­تر است و سایر هوش­ها را تحت تأثیر قرار می­دهد، پژوهش حاضر تأثیر این هوش را بر عملکرد ارزیابی می­کند. این پژوهش از نظر هدف کاربردی و از نظر نحوة گرآوری داده‌ها توصیفی از نوع همبستگی است. جامعة آماری پژوهش ادارة آموزش‌وپرورش منطقة شش تهران است که به روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی 85 نفر به عنوان نمونه از میان آن‌ها انتخاب شد. در راستای سنجش شاخص‌های مربوطه با بهره­گیری از نظرهای خبرگان، به هفت شاخص اصلی برای سنجش متغیر هوش معنوی دست یافتیم. ابزار تحقیق پرسشنامه است که پایایی و روایی آن، به ترتیب، از طریق محاسبة آلفای کرونباخ، و روایی محتوا و روایی سازه تأیید شد. داده‌ها به روش مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری با کمک نرم‌افزار PLS تجزیه‌وتحلیل شد. بر اساس نتایج این پژوهش، تأثیر شاخص­های خودآگاهی، انعطاف‌پذیری، شکیبایی، تجربه‎های معنوی و توانایی حل مسئله بر عملکرد تأیید، و تأثیر دو شاخص هدفمندی و تعالی‌جویی بر عملکرد رد شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد فردی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هوش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هوش معنوی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jomc.ut.ac.ir/article_55437_189824c64998b405ce5d4fd5fa3e0db3.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
