<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1382</year>
	<month>8</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2003</year>
	<month>11</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>1</volume>
<number>2</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>پهنه‌بندی خطر رانش زمین در منطقه طالش با استفاده از سیستم‌های هوشمند (شبکه‌های عصبی مصنوعی پرسپترون)</title_fa>
	<title>Landslide Hazard Zonation Using Artificial Neural Network in the Talesh Area</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>با توجه به توانایی‌های شبکه‌های عصبی مصنوعی، کاربرد آن‌ها در رشته‌های مختلف مهندسی و علوم زمین گسترش قابل ملاحظه‌ای داشته است. در این مقاله کاربرد شبکه‌های عصبی مصنوعی در زمین شناسی مهندسی و در پیش بینی خطر زمین لغرش‌های منطقه طالش مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. نتایج بررسی‌ها نشان می‌دهد که مدل تهیه شده براساس پارامترهای ورودی مؤثر در وقوع زمین لغزش قادر خواهد بود اطلاعات ورودی را پردازش و خطر زمین لغزش را به عنوان خروجی شبکه عصبی اعلام کند. با توجه به نقشه پهنه‌بندی خطر زمین‌‌لغزش منطقه که با استفاده از این سیستم تهیه گردیده است, منطقه طالش جزء مناطق پر خطر از نظر رانش زمین محسوب می‌شود. و مهم‌ترین عوامل موثر در ناپایداری شیب‌های منطقه تغییرات کاربری اراضی، از بین رفتن پوشش گیاهی، زیر شویی دامنه‌ای، فرسایش حاشیه رودخانه‌ها و فعالیت‌های تکتونیکی هستند</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>(Paper pages 179-192) Artificial Neural Network (ANN), has many abilities which have increade its application in different fields of engineering and geosciences. In this paper, the application of ANN in geological engineering(prediction of landslide hazard) in Talesh area, north of Iran, is evaluated. The results are shown that, the system is able to process input data by selecting effective parameters of landslide and give the landslide hazard potential as a ANN output. By considering the landslide hazard zonation map of the area and by using the ANN system, it becomes clear that, the Talesh area is a landslide hazard prone area. The most effective factors of slope instability of the area, are land use and land cover conditions, ground water and surface water effects, river erosion and tectonics activities.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>شبکه‌های عصبی مصنوعی , آموزش پس انتشار خطا , زمین لغزش ,</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Artificial neural network , Back Propagation Learning , landslide hazard , </keyword>
	<start_page>179</start_page>
	<end_page>193</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-3-48&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
