<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1399</year>
	<month>10</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2021</year>
	<month>1</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>14</volume>
<number>5</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>en</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>پایداری سقف تونل توسط آنالیز گوه ای</title_fa>
	<title>Roof Tunnel Stability by Wedge Analysis</title>
	<subject_fa>ژئوتکنیک (مکانیک خاک و سنگ)</subject_fa>
	<subject>Geotecnic</subject>
	<content_type_fa>علمی پژوهشی</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>s</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:12.0pt;&quot;&gt;توده سنگ درزه&amp;shy;دار دارای مسائل طراحی پیچیده&amp;shy;تری نسبت به سایر توده&amp;shy;های سنگی است. این پیچیدگی ناشی از تعداد ( بزرگتر از 2) دسته درزه است که سبب به وجود آمدن یک محیط ناپیوسته می&amp;shy;شود. در این حالت بلوک&amp;shy;های سنگی مجزا با هندسه متفاوت ایجاد می&amp;shy;شوند که به وسیله سطوح گسیختگی طبیعی و سطوح حفاری شکل می&amp;shy;گیرند. مسائل پایداری در سنگ&amp;shy;های درزه&amp;shy;دار بلوکی شده عموماٌ مربوط به سقوط بلوک&amp;shy;ها از سقف و دیواره&amp;shy;ها است. از آنجایی که برای بلوک&amp;shy;های مشخص شده در تاج تونل، ضروری است که پتانسیل جابه&amp;shy;جایی هر بلوک تحت تاثیر نیروهای سطحی ناشی از میدان تنش محلی و بار گرانشی بررسی شود، در این مقاله حالتهای مختلف تشکیل گوه در تاج تونل ناشی از تقاطع دسته درزه&amp;shy;های با شیب مختلف بررسی شده است و سپس حالت پایداری گوه از طریق ضریب اطمینان در برابر گسیختگی سقف ارزیابی گردید. در ادامه گوه&amp;shy;های تشکیل شده در تاج تونل&amp;shy;های شهرهای نیویورک و واشنگتن با روش تحلیلی تعادل حدی و استفاده از معیار گسیختگی هوک و براون بررسی گردیدند. نتایج به دست آمده از روش تحلیلی با مشاهدات میدانی مطابقت داشت.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:12.0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>A jointed rock mass presents a more complex design problem than the other rock masses. The complexity arises from the number (greater than two) of joint sets which define the degree of discontinuity of medium. &amp;nbsp;The condition that arises in these types of rock masses is the generation of discrete rock blocks, of various geometries. They defined by the natural fracture surfaces and the excavation surface. Stability problems in blocky jointed rock are generally associated with gravity falls of blocks from the roof and sidewalls. Whereas for block defined in the crown of tunnel,the requirement is to examine the potential for displacement of each block under the influence of the surface tractions arising from the local stress field and the gravitational load, in this paper various types of wedge formation in the crown of tunnel due to intersection of joint sets with various dip were examined. The state of stability of the wedge was then assessed through the factor of safety against roof failure. Following that the formed wedges in New York city and Washington D.C tunnels crown were investigated with limiting equilibrium analytical method and by use of Hoek and Brown failure criterion. The obtained results from analytical method corresponded with field observation.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>تعادل حدی, آنالیز پایداری, دسته درزه, توده سنگ, گوه</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Limiting equilibrium, Stability analysis, Joint set, Rock mass, Wedge</keyword>
	<start_page>0</start_page>
	<end_page>0</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1585-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>mehdi</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>zamani</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مهدی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>زمانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846004301</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004301</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>ali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>nikjoo</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نیکجو</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846004302</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004302</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
