<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1399</YEAR>
<VOL>14</VOL>
<NO>5</NO>
<MOSALSAL>47</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>0</PAGE_NO>


<ARTICLES>

	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>Ecological Risk Assessment and Source identification of PAHs by PMF model in petroleum contaminated soils; West of Kermanshah province</TitleF>
		<TitleE></TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>We collected soil samples at 23 sites from the petroleum contaminated soils (PC) in the west of Kermanshah province to investigate the sources and ecological risk of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs). In this study, source apportionment has been carried out using Positive Matrix Factorization (PMF).The total PAHs concentration, have a mean value of 92.79 mg/kg, ranging from 7.37 to 609.67 mg/kg in PC soil samples. The average abundance order of different PAH ring compounds are 3 rings &#62; 5+6 rings &#62; 4 rings&#62; 2 rings. The ecological risk assessment of PAHs revealed that all of the PAHs levels were higher contents than the effects range low (ERL) value and show higher concentrations than the ERM values, except for Pyr, Chr, BaA, BbF, BkF and BaP in the soil samples. The result of benzo (a) pyrene equation (BaPeq) values indicates that the carcinogenic potency of PAHs should be given more attention due to the impending environmental risk in the study areas. Based on the PMF analysis four sources of PAHs are identified including coal combustion (21.48%), vehicular source (13.74%), unburned petroleum (20.84%) and creosotes (43.92%).Therefore, it was concluded that petroleum activities were major sources of PAHs in west of Kermanshah province.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>0</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>0</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>Ata</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>Shakeri</Family>
				<NameE>Ata</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Shakeri</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>shakeri1353@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>Maryam</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>Madadi</Family>
				<NameE>Maryam</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Madadi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>mary.madadi22@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>Behzad</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>Mehrabi</Family>
				<NameE>Behzad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Mehrabi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>mehrabi44@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>PAHs</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>PMF model</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Ecological risk</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Soil</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Kermanshah</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Iran</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1. Li, J., Liu, G., Yin, L., Xue, J., Qi, H., Li, Y. (2012). Distribution characteristics of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons in sediments and biota from the Zha Long Wetland, China. Environ Monit Assess. DOI 10.1007/s10661-012-2780-0 ##2. Bojes, HK., Pope, PG. (2007). Characterization of EPA's 16 priority pollutant polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) in tank bottom solids and associated contaminated soils at oil exploration and production sites in Texas. Regul Toxicol Pharm, 47:288 -95.##3. Net, S., Dumoulin, D., El-Osmani, R., Rabodonirina, S. and Ouddane, B. (2014). Case study of PAHs, Me-PAHs, PCBs,Phthalates and Pesticides Contamination in the Somme River water, France. Int. J. Environ. Res, 8(4):1159-1170. ##4. Ahmed, E. N., Tarek, O. S., Azza, K., Amany, E. S., &amp; Aly, M. A. (2007). The distribution and sources of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons in surface sediments along the Egyptian Mediterranean coast. Environmental Monitoring and Assessment, 124, 343–359.##5. Wang,W., Massey Simonich, S.L., Xue, M., Zhao, J., Zhang, N.,Wang, R., Cao, J., Tao, S. (2010). Concentrations, sources and spatial distribution of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons in soils from Beijing, Tianjin and surrounding areas, North China. Environmental Pollution, 158, 1245-1251.##6. Peng, C., Chen, W., Liao, X., Wang, M., Ouyang, Z., Jiao, W. (2011). Polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons in urban soils of Beijing: status, sources, distribution and potential risk. Environ Pollut, 159:802–8.##7. Motelay-Massei, A., Ollivon, D., Garban, B., Chevreuil, M. (2003).  Polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbonsin bulk deposition at a suburban site: assessment by principal component analysis of the influence of meteorological parameters. Atmos Environ, 37:3135–46.##8. Stanimirova, I., Tauler, R., Walczak, B. (2011). A comparison of positive matrix factorization and the weighted multivariate curve resolution method. Application to environmental data. Environ Sci Technol, 45:10102–10.##9. Sun, J.H.,Wang, G.L., Chai, Y., Zhang, G., Li, J., &amp; Feng, J. L. (2009). Distribution of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) in Henan Reach of the Yellow River, Middle China. Ecotoxicology Environment Safe, 72, 1614–1624.##10. Nam, JJ., Song, BH., Eoma, KC., Lee, SH., Smith, A. (2003). Distribution of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons in agricultural soils in South Korea. Chemosphere, 50:1281–9.##11. Ping, L. F., Luo, Y. M., Zhang, H. B., Li, Q. B., &amp; Wu, L. H. (2007). Distribution of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons in thirty typical soil profiles in the Yangtze River Delta region, east China. Environmental Pollution, 147(2), 358–365.##12. Wang, X-T., Miao, Y., Zhang, Y., Li, Y-C., Wu, M-H., Yu, G. (2013). Polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) in urban soils of the megacity Shanghai: occurrence, source apportionment and potential human health risk. Sci Total Environ, 447:80–9.##13. Agarwal, T. (2009). Concentration level, pattern and toxic potential of PAHs in traffic soil of Delhi, India. Journal of Hazardous Materials, 171, 894-900.##14. Morillo, E., Romero, A. S., Maqueda, C., Madrid, L., Ajmone Marsan, F., Grcman, H., et al. (2007). Soil pollution by PAHs in urban soils: a comparison of three European cities. Environmental Monitoiring, 9, 1001–1008.##15. Ma, Ch., Ye, S., Lin, T., Ding, X., Yuan, H., Guo. Zh. (2014). Source apportionment of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons in soils of wetlands in the Liao River Delta, Northeast China. Marine Pollution Bulletin, 80,160-167.##16. Zheng,T., Ran, Y., Chen , L. (2014).  Polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) in rural soils of Dong jiang River Basin: occurrence, source apportionment, and potential human health risk.  J Soils Sediments, 14, 110– 120.##17. USEPA (1998) Method 8270D: semi-volatile organic compounds by gas chromatography/mass spectrometry (GC/MS). Washington, DC: US Environmental Protection Agency.##18. Li, K., Christensen, ER. Van Camp, RP., Imamoglu, I. (2001).  PAHs in dated sediments of Ashtabula River, Ohio, USA. Environ Sci Technol, 35:2896–2902.##19. Boonyatumanond R., Murakami M., Wattayakorn G., Togo A., Takada H. (2007). Sources of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (pahs) in street dust in a tropical Asian mega-city, Bangkok. Thailand Sci. Total Environ, 384:420–432.##20. Liu, Y., Chen, L., Huang, Q-H., Li, W-Y., Tang, Y-J., Zhao, J-F. (2009). Source apportionment of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) in surface sediments of the Huangpu River, Shanghai, China. Sci Total Environ, 407:2931–2938.##21. Paatero, P., Tapper, U. (1994). Positive matrix factorization: a non-negative factor model with optimal utilization of error estimates of data values. Environmetrics, 5:111–26.##22. US EPA. EPA positive matrix factorization (PMF) 2.5 fundamentals &amp; user guide; (2008) [Online available at http://www.epa.gov/heasd/products/pmf/pmf.htm].##23. US EPA. EPA positive matrix factorization (PMF) 5.0 fundamentals &amp; user guide; (2014) [Online available at http://www.epa.gov/heasd/products/pmf/pmf.htm].##24. Paatero, P. (1997). Least square formulation of robust non-negative factor analysis. Chemom Intell Lab Syst, 37:23–35.##25. Paatero, P. (1999). The multilinear engine: a table-driven least squares program for solving multilinear problems, including the n-way parallel factor analysis model. J Comput Graph Stat, 8:1-35.##26. Long, E. R., MacDonald, D. D., Smith, S. L., &amp; Calder, F. D. (1995). Incidence of adverse biological effects within ranges of chemical concentrations in marine and eatuarine sediments. Environmental Management, 19, 81–97.##27. Jon, M. H., Joy, M. B., Michael, B., &amp; Robert, J. (2005). Sediment quality survey of the Choctawhatchee Bay system in the Florida panhandle. Marine Pollution Bulletin, 50, 889–903.##28. Li, J., Liu, G.,Yin, L., Xue, J., Qi, H.,  Li, Y. (2013). Distribution characteristics of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons in sediments and biota from the Zha Long Wetland, China. Environ Monit Assess, 185, 3163-3171.##29. Peters, CA., Knightes, CD., Brown, DG. (1999). Long-term composition dynamics of PAH-containing NAPLs and implications for risk assessment. Environ Sci Technol, 33:4499–4507.##30. Lang, Y., Wang,N., Gao, H., Bai, J. (2012). Distribution and risk assessment of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) from Liaohe estuarine wetland soils. Environ Monit Assess, 184,5545–5552.##31. Amit, M., &amp; Ajay, T. (2006). Polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) concentrations and related carcinogenic potencies in soil at a semi-arid region of India. Chemosphere, 65, 449–456.##32. Ray, S., Khillare, P. S., Agarwal, T., &amp; Shridhar, V. (2008). Assessment of PAHs in soil around the international airport in Delhi, India. Journal of Hazardous Materials, 156, 9–16.##33. Nadal, M., Schuhmacher, M., &amp; Domingo, J. L. (2004). Levels of PAHs in soil and vegetation samples from Tarragona County, Spain. Environmental Pollution, 132, 1–11.##34. Jiang, YF., Wang, X., Wang, F., Jia, Y., Wu, MH., Sheng, GY., et al. (2009).  Levels, composition profiles and sources of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons in urban soil of Shanghai, China. Chemosphere, 75:1112-8.##35. Zhang, Y., Guo, C-S., Xu, J., Tian, Y-Z., Shi, G-L., Fen, Y-C. (2013). Potential source contributions and risk assessment of PAHs in sediments fromTaihu Lake, China: comparison of three receptor models. Water Res, 46:3065–73.##36. Harrison, R. M., Smith, D. J. T., &amp; Luhana, L. (1996). Source apportionment of atmospheric polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons collected from an urban location in Birmingham, UK. Environmental Science and Technology, 30(3), 825–832.##37. Li, A., Jang, J. K., &amp; Scheff, P. A. (2003). Application of EPA CMB8.2 model for source apportionment of sediment PAHs in Lake Calumet, Chicago. Environental Science &amp; Technology, 37(13), 2958–2965.##38. Simcik, MF., Eisenreich, SJ., Lioy, PJ. (1999). Source apportionment and source/sink relationships of PAHs in the coastal atmosphere of Chicago and Lake Michigan. Atmos Environ, 33:5071–9.##39. Miguel, A., &amp; Pereira, P. (1989). Benzo(k)fluoranthene, benzo (ghi) perylene, and indeno(1,2,3-cd)pyrene: new tracers of automotive emissions in receptor modeling. Aerosol Science and Technology, 10(2), 292–295.##40. Khalili, NR., Scheff, PA., Holsen, TM. (1995). PAH source fingerprints for coke ovens, diesel and, gasoline engines, highway tunnels, and wood combustion emissions. Atmos Environ, 29:533–42.##41. Ravindra, K., Sokhi, R., Van Grieken, R. (2008). Atmospheric polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons: source attribution, emission factors and regulation. Atmos Environ, 42:2895–921. ##42. Kohler, M., Künniger, T., Schmid, P., Gujeer, E., Crockett, R., Wolfensberger, M. (2000).  Inventory and emission factors of creosote, polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAH), and phenols from railroad ties treated with creosote. Environ Sci Technol, 34:4766–72.##رفرنس فارسی ندارد ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>پایداری سقف تونل توسط آنالیز گوه ای</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Roof Tunnel Stability by Wedge Analysis</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>توده سنگ درزه&#173;دار دارای مسائل طراحی پیچیده&#173;تری نسبت به سایر توده&#173;های سنگی است. این پیچیدگی ناشی از تعداد ( بزرگتر از 2) دسته درزه است که سبب به وجود آمدن یک محیط ناپیوسته می&#173;شود. در این حالت بلوک&#173;های سنگی مجزا با هندسه متفاوت ایجاد می&#173;شوند که به وسیله سطوح گسیختگی طبیعی و سطوح حفاری شکل می&#173;گیرند. مسائل پایداری در سنگ&#173;های درزه&#173;دار بلوکی شده عموماٌ مربوط به سقوط بلوک&#173;ها از سقف و دیواره&#173;ها است. از آنجایی که برای بلوک&#173;های مشخص شده در تاج تونل، ضروری است که پتانسیل جابه&#173;جایی هر بلوک تحت تاثیر نیروهای سطحی ناشی از میدان تنش محلی و بار گرانشی بررسی شود، در این مقاله حالتهای مختلف تشکیل گوه در تاج تونل ناشی از تقاطع دسته درزه&#173;های با شیب مختلف بررسی شده است و سپس حالت پایداری گوه از طریق ضریب اطمینان در برابر گسیختگی سقف ارزیابی گردید. در ادامه گوه&#173;های تشکیل شده در تاج تونل&#173;های شهرهای نیویورک و واشنگتن با روش تحلیلی تعادل حدی و استفاده از معیار گسیختگی هوک و براون بررسی گردیدند. نتایج به دست آمده از روش تحلیلی با مشاهدات میدانی مطابقت داشت.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>A jointed rock mass presents a more complex design problem than the other rock masses. The complexity arises from the number (greater than two) of joint sets which define the degree of discontinuity of medium. &#160;The condition that arises in these types of rock masses is the generation of discrete rock blocks, of various geometries. They defined by the natural fracture surfaces and the excavation surface. Stability problems in blocky jointed rock are generally associated with gravity falls of blocks from the roof and sidewalls. Whereas for block defined in the crown of tunnel,the requirement is to examine the potential for displacement of each block under the influence of the surface tractions arising from the local stress field and the gravitational load, in this paper various types of wedge formation in the crown of tunnel due to intersection of joint sets with various dip were examined. The state of stability of the wedge was then assessed through the factor of safety against roof failure. Following that the formed wedges in New York city and Washington D.C tunnels crown were investigated with limiting equilibrium analytical method and by use of Hoek and Brown failure criterion. The obtained results from analytical method corresponded with field observation.
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>0</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>0</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهدی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>زمانی</Family>
				<NameE>mehdi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>zamani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه یاسوج،</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>نیکجو</Family>
				<NameE>ali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>nikjoo</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه یاسوج</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Limiting equilibrium</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Stability analysis</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Joint set</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Rock mass</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Wedge</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تعادل حدی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>آنالیز پایداری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دسته درزه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>توده سنگ</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>گوه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] J. W. Bray, Personal communication (1979).##[2] K. W. John, &amp;quot;Graphical stability analysis of slopes in jointed rock&amp;quot;, J. Soil Mech.               ##     Found Div. (ASCE).  94(2), PP. 497–526 (1968).            ##[3] P. Londe, G. Vigier and R. Vormeringer, &amp;quot;Stability of rock slopes, a three-##     dimensional study&amp;quot;, J. Soil Mech. Found. Div. (ASCE). 95(1), PP. 235–262 (1969).##[4] A. J. Hendron, E. J. Cording and A. K. Aiyer, &amp;quot;Analytical and graphical methods ##     for the analysis of slopes in rock masses&amp;quot;, Technical Report GL-80-2, US Army ##     Engineers Nuclear Cratering Group, Livermore, CA, PP. 1-55 (1980).##[5] E.T. Hoek and J. W. Bray, &amp;quot;Rock slope engineering&amp;quot;, 3rd ed. London, England: ##     Institute of Min. and Metallurgy, PP. 275-342 (1981).##[6] P. M. Warburton, &amp;quot;Vector stability analysis of an arbitrary polyhedral rock block ##      with any number of free faces&amp;quot;, Int.  J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci. Geomech. ##      Abstr; 18(5), PP. 415–427 (1981).##[7] S. D. Priest, &amp;quot;Hemispherical projection methods in rock mechanics&amp;quot;, London: ##     George Allan &amp; Unwin, PP. 75-84 (1985).##[8] R. E. Goodman and G. H. Shi, &amp;quot;Block theory and its application to rock ##     Engineering&amp;quot;, London: Prentice-Hall, PP. 147-162 (1985).##[9] H. C. Chan and H. H. Einstein, &amp;quot;Approach to complete limit equilibrium analysis ##     for rock wedges—the method of artificial supports&amp;quot;, Rock Mech; 14(2), PP. 59–86 (1981).##[10] M. Mauldon and R. E. Goodman, &amp;quot;Vector analysis of keyblock rotation&amp;quot;, J.  ##       Geotech. Geoenv. Eng. (ASCE); 122(12) PP. 976–987 (1996).##[11] F. Tonon, &amp;quot;Generalization of Mauldon’s and Goodman’s analysis of keyblock ##       Rotations&amp;quot;, J. Geotech. Geoenviron. Eng. (ASCE); 124 (10), PP. 913–922 (1998).##[12] Y. Mirzaeian, K. Shahriar and M. Sharifzadeh, &amp;quot;Tunnel Probabilistic Structure Analysis Using##       the FORM&amp;quot;, Journal of Geological Research, Hindawi Publishing Corporation, Article ID##       3947, PP. 1-10 (2015).##[13] J. H. Curran, B. Corkum and R. E. Hammah, &amp;quot;Three-dimensional Analysis of Underground##       Wedges under the Influence of Stresses&amp;quot;, http:/www.rocscience.com/documents/pdfs/uploads/##       7776.pdf, PP. 1-7 (2015). ##[14] R. C. Budiman, R. Pratama, D. Muslim and I. Sophian, &amp;quot; Design Analysis of Tunnel Portal in##       Pasi Jawa L250 Pongkor's GMBU Underground Mine PT. Aneka Tambang Tbk., 10th Asian##      Regional Conference of IAEG, PP. 1-6 (2015).##[15] B.H.G. Brady and E. T. Brown, &amp;quot;Rock Mechanics for Underground mining&amp;quot;, ##       George Allen &amp; Unwin.  (publishers) Ltd, PP. 352-364 (1992).##[16] E. Hoek and E. T.  Brown, &amp;quot;Underground excavations in rock&amp;quot;, The Institution of    ##       Mining and Metallurgy, PP. 115-127 (1980).##[17] E. J. Cording, J. W.  Mahar and G. S. Brierley, &amp;quot;Observation for Shallow Chambers in  ##        Rock&amp;quot;, Proceedings of the International Symposium, Zurich, April 4-6, PP.  485-508 (1977).##[1] J. W. Bray, Personal communication (1979).##[2] K. W. John, &amp;quot;Graphical stability analysis of slopes in jointed rock&amp;quot;, J. Soil Mech.               ##     Found Div. (ASCE).  94(2), PP. 497–526 (1968).            ##[3] P. Londe, G. Vigier and R. Vormeringer, &amp;quot;Stability of rock slopes, a three-##     dimensional study&amp;quot;, J. Soil Mech. Found. Div. (ASCE). 95(1), PP. 235–262 (1969).##[4] A. J. Hendron, E. J. Cording and A. K. Aiyer, &amp;quot;Analytical and graphical methods ##     for the analysis of slopes in rock masses&amp;quot;, Technical Report GL-80-2, US Army ##     Engineers Nuclear Cratering Group, Livermore, CA, PP. 1-55 (1980). ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>Estimation of Internal Friction angle for Carbonate Soils of the Southern Iranian Coasts</TitleF>
		<TitleE></TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Abstract:

The present work is conducted to investigate the effect of texture and carbonate content on internal friction angle of carbonate soils. Carbonate soils are majorly found in the bed of shallow waters and also offshores in tropical regions. Recently there is a huge construction projects including oil and gas extraction platform and facilities, harbors, refineries, huge bridges and other big construction projects in many offshore and onshore areas around the world. One of these area is located on southern part of Iran. Using soil samples from these areas. The results show that the average internal friction angle of carbonate soil is higher respect to known silicate sands. This angle is affected by effective grain size, grain angularity, and calcium carbonate content. Based on experimental results of this study using a statistical method an equation was proposed for estimation of internal friction angle of carbonate soils of this geographical area.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>0</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>0</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>Habib</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>Shahnazari</Family>
				<NameE>Habib</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Shahnazari</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>hshahnazari@iust.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>Mahmoud</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>Fatemiaghda</Family>
				<NameE>Mahmoud</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Fatemiaghda</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>fatemi@khu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>Hamid Reza</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>Karami</Family>
				<NameE>Hamid Reza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Karami</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>hkarami@iust.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>Mehdi</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>Talkhablou</Family>
				<NameE>Mehdi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Talkhablou</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>talkhablou@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Internal friction angle</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>shear strength</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Carbonate soils</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Soil texture</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Calcium carbonate content</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Mohr, O. Welche Umstande Bedinge die Elastizitatsgrenze und den Bruch eines Materiales? Zeitschrift des Vereines Deutscher Ingeniure, 1900, Vol. 44, 1524-1530, 1572-1577.##[2] Coulomb, C. A. Essai sur une application des regles des maximis et minimis a quelquels problemesde statique relatifs, a la architecture. Mem. Acad. Roy. Div. Sav., 1776, vol. 7, pp. 343–387.##[3] Vafaeian M. Properties of coastal calcareous sand, Journal of Geotechnic &amp; Strength of Construction materials, 2002, Vol. 88, pp. 9-21 (in Persian).##[4] Poulos H.G. &amp; Chua E.W. Bearing capacity of foundation on calcareous sand, Proceeding of 11th International Conference on Soil Mechanics &amp; Foundation Engineering, 1985,Vol. 3, pp. 1619-1622.##[5] Poulos H.G. &amp; Chan K.F. Model pile skin friction in calcareous soil, Geotechnical Engineering, 1986, Vol. 17, pp. 235 – 257.##[6] Douri R.H. &amp; Poulos H.G. Behaviour of pile groups in calcareous sand,Geotechnical Engin., 1994, Vol. 25, No. 2, pp. 3-21 El-Sohby.##[7] Hasanlourad, M., Salehzadeh, H. and Shahnazari, H., Dilation and particle breakage effects on the shear strength of calcareous sands based on energy aspects&amp;quot;. International Journal of Civil Engineering, 2008, 6(2): pp. 108-119.##[8] Braja M. Das, Principle of geotechnical engineering, Stamford, Conn.: Cengage Learning, ISBN: 0495411329 (pbk) 1941.##[9] Baziar,M. H., Salehzadeh H., Soil Mechanic Laberatory Handbook, 1996, P. 81 (in Persian)## [10] Shahnazari, H. and Rezvani, R., Effective parameters for the particle breakage of calcareous sands: An experimental study, Engineering Geology, 2013, Vol. 159, pp. 98-105.##[11] API, Recommended Practice for Planning, Designing and Constructing Fixed Offshore Platforms, American Petroleum Institute API RP-2A, 2000.##[12] Semple, R. M., Mechanical Properties of Calcareous Soils: State of the Art Report, 1st International Conference on Calcareous Sediments, Australia, Perth, 1988.##[13] McClelland, B., Calcareous Sediments: An Engineering Enigma, 1 st International Conference on Calcareous Sediments. Perth, Australia, Vol. 1988, 2: 777-784.##[14] Golightly, C.R. and Hyde, A.F.L., Some Fundamental Properties of CarbonateSands, Preceding 1st International Conference on Calcareous Sediments, Perth, Australia, 1988, Vol. 1, pp. 69-78.##[15] Hull, T.S., Poulos, H.G., and Alehossein, H., The Static Behavior of Various Calcareous Sediments, Proceeding 1st International Conference on Calcareous Sediments&amp;quot;, Perth, Australia, 1988, Vol. 1, pp. 87-96.##[16] Shambhu, S., Sharma and Mostafa A., Ismail, Monotonic and Cyclic Behavior of two Calcareous Soils of Different Origins, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering Div., Am. Soc. Civ. Eng., 2006,Vol. 128, No. 6, pp. 520529.##[17] Vesic, A.S. and Clough, G.W., Behavior of Granular Material under High Stresses, Proceeding ASCE, Journal of Soil Mechanics and Foundation Engineering, 1968, Vol. 94(SM3). pp. 661-688.##[18] Bolton, M.D., (1986). The Strength and Dilatancy of Sands.  Geotechnique, Vol. 36 No. 1, pp. 65-78.##[19] Airey, D.W., Randolph, M.F., and Hyden, A.M., The Strength and Stiffness of Two Calcareous Sands, Proceeding, International  Conference Calcareous Sediments, Perth, Western Australia, ISSMFE, 1988, Vol. 1, pp. 43-50.## [20] Poulos, H., M. Uesugi, and G. Young, Strength and deformation properties of Bass Strait carbonate sands. Geotechnical Engineering, 1980,13(2): pp. 189-211.##[21] Datta, M., Gulhati, S.K., and Rao, G.V., Crushing of Calcareous Sands During Shear, Proceeding 11th Offshore Technology Conference, Houston, Texas, 1979, Vol. 3, pp. 1459-1467.##[22] Salehzadeh, H., Ghazanfari, E., Parametric Study of Kish Carbonate Sand under Triaxial Shearing, International Journal of Civil Engineering, 2004, Vol. 2, No. 4, pp. 223-231.##[23] Pansu M., Gautheyrou J., Handbook of Soil Analysis, Mineralogical, Organic and Inorganic Methods, ISBN: 978-3-540-31210-9 (Print) 978-3-540-31211-6, Springer Berlin Heidelberg, 2006, pp. 593-604, ##[24] Tucker M.E., Sedimentary petrology. An introduction, Blackwell, Oxford, 1981.##[25] Hashemnejad, A., Ghafoori, M., Tarigh_ Azali, S., Utilizing water, mineralogy and sedimentary properties to predict LCPC abrasivity coefficient, Bull Eng Geol Environ DOI 10.1007/s10064-015-0779-9, 2015. ##[26] Friedman, G. M. &amp; Sanders, J.E., Principle of sedimentology. New York, John Wiley &amp; Sons, 1978.##[27] Vangla P. &amp; Latha G.M., Inﬂuence of Particle Size on the Friction and Interfacial Shear Strength of Sands of Similar Morphology, Int. J. of Geosynth and Ground Eng. 1:6, 2015.##- ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>Bearing Capacity of Triangular Shell Foundations Adjacent to the Reinforced Sandy Slopes</TitleF>
		<TitleE></TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>This paper investigates response of triangular shell strip footings situated on the sandy slope. A series of reduced-scale plate load tests were conducted to cover different parameters including three shell footing types with different apex angles in addition to a flat footing, four different distances for strip footings from the crest of the slope namely &#8220;edge distance&#8221; and reinforcement status (unreinforced and geotextile-reinforced statuses). Bearing capacity of shell footings adjacent to crest of the slope, bearing capacity ratio, shell efficiency factor, influence of apex angle on settlement of footings and the mechanism of slope failure are discussed and evaluated. Also, empirical equations for determination of the maximum bearing capacity of triangular shell strip footings are suggested. As a whole, it has been observed that decrease of shell&#8217;s apex angle as good as increase of edge distance could significantly improve the bearing capacity. However, as the edge distance increases, the effect of apex angle on the bearing capacity got decreased. Also, it was found out that the beneficial effect of reinforcement on the bearing capacity decreased with increase of the edge distance. Furthermore, the efficiency of shell footings on bearing capacity was attenuated in reinforced slopes compared to the unreinforced status.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>0</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>0</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>Seyed Ali</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>Ghaffari</Family>
				<NameE>Seyed Ali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ghaffari</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Kharazmi University</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>std_ghafari@khu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>Amir</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>Hamidi</Family>
				<NameE>Amir</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Hamidi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Kharazmi University</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>hamidi@khu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>Gholamhossein</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>Tavakoli Mehrjardi</Family>
				<NameE>Gholamhossein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Tavakoli Mehrjardi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Kharazmi University</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>ghtavakoli@khu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Soil-geosynthetic interaction</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Geotextiles</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Shells</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Foundations</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Slope stabilization.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Kurian NP, Shah SH (1985) Parametric studies on the ultimate strength of conical and spherical shell foundations. J Structural Engrg 12: 49-57. ##[2] Kurian NP (2006) Shell foundations (Geometry, Analysis, Design and Construction). Alpha Science International, Harrow, UK.##[3] Yamamoto K, Lyamin AV, Abbo AJ et al (2009) Bearing capacity and failure mechanism of different types of foundations on sand. Soils and Foundations 42: 305-314.##[4] Fernando N, Sendanayake E, Sendanayake D et al (2011) The experimental investigation of failure mechanism and bearing capacity of different types of shallow foundations. Research Report, Department of Civil Engineering, University of Moratuwa, Sri Lanka. ##[5] Kurian NP, Mohan CS (1981) Contact pressures under shell foundations. In: Proceedings of 10th international conference on soil mechanics and foundation engineering, Stockholm, Sweden.##[6] Esmaili D, Hataf N (2008) Experimental and numerical investigation of ultimate load capacity of shell foundation on reinforced and unreinforced sand. Iranian J Sci Tech 32: 491-500.##[7] Thilakan S, Naik N (2015) Geotechnical behaviour of shell foundations. In: Proceedings of 50th Indian geotechnical conference, Pune, India.##[8] Hanna A, Abdel-Rahman M (1990) Maximum bearing capacity of triangular shell strip footings on sand. J Geotech Engrg 116: 1851-1863. ##[9] Hanna A, Abdel-Rahman M (1998) Experimental investigation of shell foundations on dry sand. Can Geotech J 35: 847-857.##[10] Shaligram PS (2011) Behavior of triangular shell strip footing on georeinforced layered sand. Int J Advanced Engrg Tech 2: 192-196.  ##[11] Azzam WR, Nasr AM (2015) Bearing capacity of shell strip footing##on reinforced sand. J Advanced Res 6: 727-737.##[12] Lee KM, Manjunath VR (2000) Experimental and numerical studies of##geosynthetic-reinforced sand slopes loaded with a footing. Can Geotech J 37: 828-842.##[13] Viswanadham BVS, Konig, D (2004) Studies on scaling and instrumentation of a geogrid. Geotex Geomem 22: 307-328.##[14] El Sawwaf M (2007) Behavior of strip footing on geogrid-reinforced sand over a soft clay slope. Geotex Geomem 25: 50-60.##[15] Alamshahi S, Hataf N (2009) Bearing capacity of strip footings on sand slopes reinforced with geogrid and grid-anchor. Geotex Geomem 27: 217-226.##[16] Duangkhae S, Bergado DT, Baral P et al (2014) Analyses of reinforced embankment on soft and hard foundations. Ground Improvement 167: 3-23.##[17] Artidteang S, Bergado DT, Chaiyaput S et al (2015) Embankment reinforced with limited life geotextiles on soft clay. Ground Improvement, 168: 130-143.##[18] Rajabian AB, Viswanadham BVS (2016) Behaviour of anchored geosynthetic- reinforced slopes subjected to seepage in a geotechnical centrifuge. Geosyn Int 23: 36-47.##[19] Tavakoli Mehrjardi Gh, Ghanbari A and Mehdizadeh, H (2016) Experimental study on the behaviour of geogrid-reinforced slopes with respect to aggregate size. Geotex Geomem 44: 862-871. ##[20] Vahidipour A, Ghanbari A and Hamidi A (2016) Experimental study of dynamic compaction adjacent to a slope. Ground Improvement, 169: 79-89.##[21] Kazi M, Shukla SK, Habibi D (2016) Behaviour of an embedded footing on geotextile-reinforced sand. Ground Improvement, 169: 120-133.##[22] ASTM D 2487 (2011) Standard practice for classification of soils for engineering purposes (Unified Soil Classification System). ASTM Int, West Conshohocken, USA.##[23] Selig ET, Mc Kee KE (1961) Static and dynamic behaviour of small footings. J Soil Mech Div 87: 29-47.##[24] Chummer AV (1972) Bearing capacity theory from experimental results. J Soil Mech Found Div 98: 1311-1324.##[25] Dash SK and Bora MC (2013) Improved performance of soft clay foundations using stone columns and geocell-sand mattress. Geotex Geomem 41: 26-35.##[26] ASTM D 4253 (2011) Standard test methods for maximum index density and unit weight of soils using a vibratory table. ASTM Int, West Conshohocken, USA.##[27] ASTM D 4254 (2011) Standard test methods for minimum index density and unit weight of soils and calculation of relative density. ASTM Int, West Conshohocken, USA.##[28] Sakti JP, Das BM (1987) Model tests for strip foundation on clay reinforced with geotextile layers. Transport Res Rec 1153: 40-45.##[29] Chen Q, Abu-Farsakh MY, Sharma R et al (2007) Laboratory investigation of behavior of foundations on geosynthetic-reinforced clayey soil. Transport Res Rec 2004: 28-38.##[30] Abu-Farsakh MY, Chen Q and Yoon S (2008) Use of reinforced soil foundation (RSF) to support shallow foundation. Research Report, Louisiana Transportation Research Center, Louisiana, USA.##[31] Altalhea EB, Tahaa MR and Abdrabbo FM (2013) Bearing capacity of strip footing on sand slopes reinforced with geotextiles and soil nails. J Teknologi 65: 1-11.##[32] Colmenares JE, Kang SR, Shin YJ et al (2013) Ultimate bearing capacity of conical shell foundation. Structural Engrg Mech 52: 507-523.##[33 Badakhshan, E., Noorzad, A (2017) Load eccentricity effect on behavior of circular footing reinforced with geogrid sheets. J Rock Mech Geotech Engrg 7: 691-699.##[34] Badakhshan, E., Noorzad, A (2017) Effect of footing shape and load eccentricity on behavior of geosynthetic reinforced sand bed. Geotex Geomem 45: 58-67.##[35] Abdel-Rahman, M (1996) Geotechnical behavior of shell foundations. Dissertation, Concordia University.##[36] Hanna A, Abd El‐Rahman M (1990) Ultimate bearing capacity of triangular shell strip footings on sand. J Geotech Engrg 116: 1851-1863.##[37] Attarzadeh A, Ghanbari A and Hamidi A (2015) A study of bearing capacity of shallow foundations next to sand slope with experimental model. J Engrg Geol, Kharazmi University 9: 2695-2710.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>Salinity, Chemistry and Quality of Groundwater in Robat – Khorramabad Plain, West of Iran</TitleF>
		<TitleE></TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Salinization of groundwater in semiarid regions, as a limiting factor of use, has a strategic importance. In this study, the sources of salinity, chemistry and Quality of groundwater in Robat &#8211; Khorramabad plain have been identified using geochemical methods. Using data analysis, the concentration of cations and anions are recognized as Ca2+&#62;Na+ &#62;Mg2+&#62;K+ and HCO3-&#62; Cl-&#62; SO42+&#62; NO3-&#62; F-. High concentration of Na+, Cl-, and EC in some places are related to the gypsum and salty Formations. In the study area, the salinization processes have been determined by natural and artificial activities. The mechanisms of salinization are defined by natural dissolution of gypsum and salt from Ghachsaran formation and man-made source (boreholes drilled through Ghachsaran Formation, salt mining, agricultural activity). In addition, high concentration of nitrate is related to agricultural fertilizers and effects of karstification with some possible influence of atmospheric NO3-. HCO3-, Ca2+ and Mg2+ concentration exceeded the standard limit in a few samples; elevated concentration appears to be related to the calcareous formation. Besides, Ca- HCO3 facies is a mainly hydro chemical facies of the groundwater followed by Na-K-HCO3 facies. Finally, according to the hydrogeological properties, chemical analysis, Schoeller, US Salinity Laboratory, piper diagrams and statistical analysis, it is revealed that dissolution of evaporate minerals such as halite and gypsum, increased concentration of total dissolved solids and amount of anoins and cations of groundwater of Robat &#8211; Khorramabad plain that caused increase of salinity in the study area.
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>0</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>0</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>Ramin</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>Sarikhani</Family>
				<NameE>Ramin</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Sarikhani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Lorestan University</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>sarikhanin765@lu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>Amin</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>Jamshidi</Family>
				<NameE>Amin</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Jamshidi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Lorestan University</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>jamshidi.am@lu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>Aritimes</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>Gahasemi Dehnavi</Family>
				<NameE>Aritimes</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Gahasemi Dehnavi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Lorestan University</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>dehnavi.artimes90@lu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Robat – Khorramabad plain</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Groundwater quality</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Salinity</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Chemistry</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Aghanabati S, Hamedi A (2004) Geological survey of Iran Geology of Iran, Tehran, Iran##APHA (1998) Standard methods for the examination of water and waste water##Arthur JM, Turner J, Lyons W, Thirlwall M (1989) Salt sources and water-rock interaction on the Yilgarn Block, Australia: isotopic and major element tracers. Applied Geochemistry 4:79-92##Ayenew T, Demlie M, Wohnlich S (2008) Hydrogeological framework and occurrence of groundwater in the Ethiopian aquifers. Journal of African Earth Sciences 52:97-113##Davis JC, Sampson RJ (1986) Statistics and data analysis in geology vol 646. Wiley New York ##Domenico PA, Schwartz FW (1990) Physical and chemical hydrogeology##Ender P (1998) Multivariate Analysis. Hierarchical Cluster Analysis UCLA. Department of Education##ESRI R (2011) ArcGIS desktop: release 10 Environmental Systems Research Institute, CA##Fetter CW (1988) Applied Hydrogeology##Freeze RA, Cherry JA (1977) Groundwater. Prentice-Hall##Guler C, Thyne GD (2004) Hydrologic and geologic factors controlling surface and groundwater chemistry in Indian Wells –Owens Valley area, southeastern California, USA. Journal of Hydrology 285:177-198##Helsel DR, Hirsch RM (2002) Statistical methods in water resources vol 323. US Geological survey Reston, VA, ##Hem JD (1985) Study and interpretation of the chemical characteristics of natural water vol 2254. Dept. of the Interior, US Geological Survey, ##Hosseinifard SJ, Aminiyan MM (2015) Hydrochemical Characterization of Groundwater Quality for Drinking and Agricultural Purposes: A Case Study in Rafsanjan Plain Iran. Water Quality, Exposure and Health 7:531-544##Howarth RW, Marino R (2006) Nitrogen as the limiting nutrient for eutrophication in coastal marine ecosystems: Evolving views over three decades. Limnology and Oceanography 51:364-376##Kapil N, Bhattacharyya KG Bimonthly variation of wetland water quality: A case study with Deepor Beel, Assam, India. In: sixteenth national symposium on environment, Haryana, India, 2008. pp 166-170##Keshavarzi B, Moore F, Mosaferi M, Rahmani F (2011) The source of natural arsenic contamination in groundwater, west of Iran. Water Quality, Exposure and Health 3:135-147##Kumar A, Singh CK (2015) Characterization of Hydrogeochemical Processes and Fluoride Enrichment in Groundwater of South-Western Punjab. Water Quality, Exposure and Health:1-15##Lgourna Z et al. (2015) Elucidating the sources and mechanisms of groundwater salinization in the Ziz Basin of southeastern Morocco. Environmental Earth Sciences 73:77-93##Li C, Ji H (2016) Chemical weathering and the role of sulfuric and nitric acids in carbonate weathering: Isotopes (13C, 15N, 34S, and 18O) and chemical constraints. Journal of Geophysical Research: Biogeosciences 121:1288-1305##McArthur J, Turner J, Lyons W, Thirlwall M (1989) Salt sources and water-rock interaction on the Yilgarn Block, Australia: isotopic and major element tracers. Applied Geochemistry 4:79-92##Mohammadzadeh H, Ebrahimpoor S (2012) Application of Stable Isotope and Hydrogeochemistry to Investigat the Origin and Water Resources Quality Variations in Zarivar Lake Cathment Area. Journal of Water and Soil 26:1018-1031##Oberlander T (1965) The Zagros streams, a new interpretation of transverse drainage in an orogenic zone. Syracuse Geographical series, University of California##Omo-Irabor OO, Olobaniyi SB, Oduyemi K, Akunna J (2008) Surface and groundwater water quality assessment using multivariate analytical methods: A case study of the Western Niger Delta, Nigeria Physics and Chemistry of the Earth, Parts A/B/C 33:666-673##Pacheco F, Oliveira AS, Van der Weijden A, Van der Weijden C (1999) Weathering, biomass production and groundwater chemistry in an area of dominant anthropogenic influence, the Chaves-Vila Pouca de Aguiar region, north of Portugal. Water, Air, and Soil Pollution 115:481-512##Pacheco FA, Landim PM, Szocs T (2013) Anthropogenic impacts on mineral weathering: a statistical perspective. Applied geochemistry 36:34-48##Pacheco FA, Szocs T (2006) “Dedolomitization reactions” driven by anthropogenic activity on loessy sediments, SW Hungary. Applied Geochemistry 21:614-631##Pacheco FA, Van der Weijden CH (2002) Mineral weathering rates calculated from spring water data: a case study in an area with intensive agriculture, the Morais Massif, northeast Portugal. Applied geochemistry 17:583-603##Piper AM (1953) A graphic procedure the geo-chemical interpretation of water analysis USGS Groundwater Note No, 12:21-46##Rockware (2011) AqQA Software (2011) Version AQC10664. http://www.rockware.com. ##Sarikhani R, Dehnavi AG, Ahmadnejad Z, Kalantari N (2015) Hydrochemical characteristics and groundwater quality assessment in Bushehr Province, SW Iran. Environmental Earth Sciences 74:6265-6281##Sheykhi V, Moore F (2012) Geochemical characterization of Kor river water quality, Fars Province, Southwest Iran. Water Quality, Exposure and Health 4:25-38##Spalding RF, Exner ME (1993) Occurrence of nitrate in groundwater– a review. Journal of Environmental Quality 22:392-402##Staff USSL (1954) Diagnosis and Improvement of Saline and Alkali  Soils Handbook 60##Tanji KK, Wallender WW Nature and extent of agricultural salinity and sodicity. In: Agricultural salinity assessment and management, 1990. ASCE, pp 1-25##Todd DK (1985) Groundwater Hydrology##UNESCO-FAO (1973) Irrigation, Drainage and Salinity##Van der Weijden CH, Pacheco FA (2006) Hydrogeochemistry in the Vouga River basin (central Portugal): pollution and chemical weathering. Applied Geochemistry 21:580-613##WHO G (2006) Guidelines for drinking-water quality WHO: World Health Organization##Wilcox L (1955) Classification and use of irrigation water. Department of Agri., Circ. , Washington, DC##Wilcox LV (1948) The quality of water for irrigation use. United States Department of Agriculture##Williams MW, Bales RC, Brown AD, Melack JM (1995) Fluxes and transformations of nitrogen in a high-elevation catchment, Sierra Nevada. Biogeochemistry 28:1-31##Zarei M, Raeisi E, Merkel BJ, Kummer N-A (2013) Identifying sources of salinization using hydrochemical and isotopic techniques, Konarsiah, Iran Environmental Earth Sciences 70:587-604## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>

</ARTICLES>

</JOURNAL>
</XML>
