<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<language>fa</language>
<journal_id_issn></journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi></journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_isnet></journal_id_isnet>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1399</year>
	<month>10</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2021</year>
	<month>1</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>14</volume>
<number>5</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>en</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa></title_fa>
	<title>Ecological Risk Assessment and Source identification of PAHs by PMF model in petroleum contaminated soils; West of Kermanshah province</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa></abstract_fa>
	<abstract>We collected soil samples at 23 sites from the petroleum contaminated soils (PC) in the west of Kermanshah province to investigate the sources and ecological risk of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs). In this study, source apportionment has been carried out using Positive Matrix Factorization (PMF).The total PAHs concentration, have a mean value of 92.79 mg/kg, ranging from 7.37 to 609.67 mg/kg in PC soil samples. The average abundance order of different PAH ring compounds are 3 rings &#62; 5+6 rings &#62; 4 rings&#62; 2 rings. The ecological risk assessment of PAHs revealed that all of the PAHs levels were higher contents than the effects range low (ERL) value and show higher concentrations than the ERM values, except for Pyr, Chr, BaA, BbF, BkF and BaP in the soil samples. The result of benzo (a) pyrene equation (BaPeq) values indicates that the carcinogenic potency of PAHs should be given more attention due to the impending environmental risk in the study areas. Based on the PMF analysis four sources of PAHs are identified including coal combustion (21.48%), vehicular source (13.74%), unburned petroleum (20.84%) and creosotes (43.92%).Therefore, it was concluded that petroleum activities were major sources of PAHs in west of Kermanshah province.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>PAHs, PMF model, Ecological risk, Soil, Kermanshah, Iran</keyword_fa>
	<keyword></keyword>
	<start_page>0</start_page>
	<end_page>0</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1544-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Ata</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Shakeri</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<first_name_fa></first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa></last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>shakeri1353@gmail.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846004294</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004294</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Maryam</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Madadi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<first_name_fa></first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa></last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>mary.madadi22@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846004295</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004295</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Behzad</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mehrabi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<first_name_fa></first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa></last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>mehrabi44@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846004296</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004296</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>en</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>پایداری سقف تونل توسط آنالیز گوه ای</title_fa>
	<title>Roof Tunnel Stability by Wedge Analysis</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>توده سنگ درزه&#173;دار دارای مسائل طراحی پیچیده&#173;تری نسبت به سایر توده&#173;های سنگی است. این پیچیدگی ناشی از تعداد ( بزرگتر از 2) دسته درزه است که سبب به وجود آمدن یک محیط ناپیوسته می&#173;شود. در این حالت بلوک&#173;های سنگی مجزا با هندسه متفاوت ایجاد می&#173;شوند که به وسیله سطوح گسیختگی طبیعی و سطوح حفاری شکل می&#173;گیرند. مسائل پایداری در سنگ&#173;های درزه&#173;دار بلوکی شده عموماٌ مربوط به سقوط بلوک&#173;ها از سقف و دیواره&#173;ها است. از آنجایی که برای بلوک&#173;های مشخص شده در تاج تونل، ضروری است که پتانسیل جابه&#173;جایی هر بلوک تحت تاثیر نیروهای سطحی ناشی از میدان تنش محلی و بار گرانشی بررسی شود، در این مقاله حالتهای مختلف تشکیل گوه در تاج تونل ناشی از تقاطع دسته درزه&#173;های با شیب مختلف بررسی شده است و سپس حالت پایداری گوه از طریق ضریب اطمینان در برابر گسیختگی سقف ارزیابی گردید. در ادامه گوه&#173;های تشکیل شده در تاج تونل&#173;های شهرهای نیویورک و واشنگتن با روش تحلیلی تعادل حدی و استفاده از معیار گسیختگی هوک و براون بررسی گردیدند. نتایج به دست آمده از روش تحلیلی با مشاهدات میدانی مطابقت داشت.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>A jointed rock mass presents a more complex design problem than the other rock masses. The complexity arises from the number (greater than two) of joint sets which define the degree of discontinuity of medium. &#160;The condition that arises in these types of rock masses is the generation of discrete rock blocks, of various geometries. They defined by the natural fracture surfaces and the excavation surface. Stability problems in blocky jointed rock are generally associated with gravity falls of blocks from the roof and sidewalls. Whereas for block defined in the crown of tunnel,the requirement is to examine the potential for displacement of each block under the influence of the surface tractions arising from the local stress field and the gravitational load, in this paper various types of wedge formation in the crown of tunnel due to intersection of joint sets with various dip were examined. The state of stability of the wedge was then assessed through the factor of safety against roof failure. Following that the formed wedges in New York city and Washington D.C tunnels crown were investigated with limiting equilibrium analytical method and by use of Hoek and Brown failure criterion. The obtained results from analytical method corresponded with field observation.
&#160;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>Limiting equilibrium, Stability analysis, Joint set, Rock mass, Wedge</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>تعادل حدی, آنالیز پایداری, دسته درزه, توده سنگ, گوه</keyword>
	<start_page>0</start_page>
	<end_page>0</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1585-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>mehdi</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>zamani</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>مهدی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>زمانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>0031947532846004301</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004301</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>ali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>nikjoo</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نیکجو</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>0031947532846004302</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004302</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>en</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa></title_fa>
	<title>Estimation of Internal Friction angle for Carbonate Soils of the Southern Iranian Coasts</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa></abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Abstract:

The present work is conducted to investigate the effect of texture and carbonate content on internal friction angle of carbonate soils. Carbonate soils are majorly found in the bed of shallow waters and also offshores in tropical regions. Recently there is a huge construction projects including oil and gas extraction platform and facilities, harbors, refineries, huge bridges and other big construction projects in many offshore and onshore areas around the world. One of these area is located on southern part of Iran. Using soil samples from these areas. The results show that the average internal friction angle of carbonate soil is higher respect to known silicate sands. This angle is affected by effective grain size, grain angularity, and calcium carbonate content. Based on experimental results of this study using a statistical method an equation was proposed for estimation of internal friction angle of carbonate soils of this geographical area.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>Internal friction angle, shear strength, Carbonate soils, Soil texture, Calcium carbonate content</keyword_fa>
	<keyword></keyword>
	<start_page>0</start_page>
	<end_page>0</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1413-2&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Habib</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Shahnazari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<first_name_fa></first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa></last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>hshahnazari@iust.ac.ir</email>
	<code>0031947532846004297</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004297</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mahmoud</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Fatemiaghda</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<first_name_fa></first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa></last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>fatemi@khu.ac.ir</email>
	<code>0031947532846004298</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004298</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Hamid Reza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Karami</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<first_name_fa></first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa></last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>hkarami@iust.ac.ir</email>
	<code>0031947532846004299</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004299</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mehdi</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Talkhablou</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<first_name_fa></first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa></last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>talkhablou@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846004300</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004300</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>en</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa></title_fa>
	<title>Bearing Capacity of Triangular Shell Foundations Adjacent to the Reinforced Sandy Slopes</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa></abstract_fa>
	<abstract>This paper investigates response of triangular shell strip footings situated on the sandy slope. A series of reduced-scale plate load tests were conducted to cover different parameters including three shell footing types with different apex angles in addition to a flat footing, four different distances for strip footings from the crest of the slope namely &#8220;edge distance&#8221; and reinforcement status (unreinforced and geotextile-reinforced statuses). Bearing capacity of shell footings adjacent to crest of the slope, bearing capacity ratio, shell efficiency factor, influence of apex angle on settlement of footings and the mechanism of slope failure are discussed and evaluated. Also, empirical equations for determination of the maximum bearing capacity of triangular shell strip footings are suggested. As a whole, it has been observed that decrease of shell&#8217;s apex angle as good as increase of edge distance could significantly improve the bearing capacity. However, as the edge distance increases, the effect of apex angle on the bearing capacity got decreased. Also, it was found out that the beneficial effect of reinforcement on the bearing capacity decreased with increase of the edge distance. Furthermore, the efficiency of shell footings on bearing capacity was attenuated in reinforced slopes compared to the unreinforced status.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>Soil-geosynthetic interaction, Geotextiles, Shells, Foundations, Slope stabilization.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword></keyword>
	<start_page>0</start_page>
	<end_page>0</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-41-4&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Seyed Ali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ghaffari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Kharazmi University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa></first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa></last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>std_ghafari@khu.ac.ir</email>
	<code>0031947532846004303</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004303</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Amir</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Hamidi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Kharazmi University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa></first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa></last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>hamidi@khu.ac.ir</email>
	<code>0031947532846004304</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004304</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Gholamhossein</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Tavakoli Mehrjardi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Kharazmi University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa></first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa></last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>ghtavakoli@khu.ac.ir</email>
	<code>0031947532846004305</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004305</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>en</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa></title_fa>
	<title>Salinity, Chemistry and Quality of Groundwater in Robat – Khorramabad Plain, West of Iran</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa></abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Salinization of groundwater in semiarid regions, as a limiting factor of use, has a strategic importance. In this study, the sources of salinity, chemistry and Quality of groundwater in Robat &#8211; Khorramabad plain have been identified using geochemical methods. Using data analysis, the concentration of cations and anions are recognized as Ca2+&#62;Na+ &#62;Mg2+&#62;K+ and HCO3-&#62; Cl-&#62; SO42+&#62; NO3-&#62; F-. High concentration of Na+, Cl-, and EC in some places are related to the gypsum and salty Formations. In the study area, the salinization processes have been determined by natural and artificial activities. The mechanisms of salinization are defined by natural dissolution of gypsum and salt from Ghachsaran formation and man-made source (boreholes drilled through Ghachsaran Formation, salt mining, agricultural activity). In addition, high concentration of nitrate is related to agricultural fertilizers and effects of karstification with some possible influence of atmospheric NO3-. HCO3-, Ca2+ and Mg2+ concentration exceeded the standard limit in a few samples; elevated concentration appears to be related to the calcareous formation. Besides, Ca- HCO3 facies is a mainly hydro chemical facies of the groundwater followed by Na-K-HCO3 facies. Finally, according to the hydrogeological properties, chemical analysis, Schoeller, US Salinity Laboratory, piper diagrams and statistical analysis, it is revealed that dissolution of evaporate minerals such as halite and gypsum, increased concentration of total dissolved solids and amount of anoins and cations of groundwater of Robat &#8211; Khorramabad plain that caused increase of salinity in the study area.
&#160;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>Robat – Khorramabad plain, Groundwater quality, Salinity, Chemistry</keyword_fa>
	<keyword></keyword>
	<start_page>0</start_page>
	<end_page>0</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1640-6&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Ramin</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Sarikhani</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Lorestan University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa></first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa></last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>sarikhanin765@lu.ac.ir</email>
	<code>0031947532846004306</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004306</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Amin</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Jamshidi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Lorestan University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa></first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa></last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>jamshidi.am@lu.ac.ir</email>
	<code>0031947532846004307</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004307</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Aritimes</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Gahasemi Dehnavi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Lorestan University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa></first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa></last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>dehnavi.artimes90@lu.ac.ir</email>
	<code>0031947532846004308</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004308</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
