<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1394</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2015</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>9</volume>
<number>3</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تخمین مقاومت فشاری تک‌محوری سنگ آهک میکرایتی با استفاده از آزمایش نفوذ</title_fa>
	<title>Estimation the Uniaxial Compressive Strength of Microcrystalline Limestones Using Indentation Test</title>
	<subject_fa>زمین شناسی مهندسی</subject_fa>
	<subject>En. Geology</subject>
	<content_type_fa>مقاله استخراج شده از پایان نامه</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research Paper</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>تعیین مقاومت فشاری تک­محوری (UCS) سنگ در بیش‌تر پروژه­های مهندسی ضروری است. در حفاری‌های عمیق برای دست‌یابی به منابع هیدروکربوری و یا حفاری­های اکتشافی برای تونل­های عمیق تهیۀ نمونۀ مناسب برای اندازه­گیری مستقیم UCS مشکل، هزینه­بر و گاهی غیرممکن است. بنا بر این استفاده از روش­های غیرمستقیم (نظیر استفاده از خرده­های حفاری) برای تخمین UCS متداول شده است. استفاده از نفوذ کننده‌ای سخت که به داخل خرده سنگ تثبیت شده در یک چسب نگه‌دارنده نفوذ می‌کند و به‌عنوان آزمایش نفوذ&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; شناخته می­شود، یکی از این روش­ها است. در این مقاله تعداد 8 نمونه سنگ آهک میکرایتی تهیه و پس از تعیین UCS آن‌ها در آزمایشگاه، نمونه­ها خرد و آزمایش نفوذ با نفوذ کننده­هایی به قطرهای 6/0، 8/0 و 1 میلی‌متر روی 720 خرده ذره با اندازه­های 2، 3 و 4 میلی‌متر انجام شده و نیروی انتقال بحرانی (CTF) که معرف مقاومت نهایی خرده ذره در مقابل ورود نفوذکننده به داخل آن است، تعیین شده است. روابط تجربی بین UCS و CTF برای نمونه­ها و نفوذکننده‌های با قطرهای مختلف با R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; &amp;ge 0.78 پیشنهاد شده است. با استفاده از رگرسیون چند متغیره، رابطه­ای کلی بین UCS، CTF، اندازۀ ذرات (D) و قطر نفوذکننده (I) با R = 0.85 ارائه شده است. صحت روابط تجربی پیشنهادی با انجام 135 آزمایش نفوذ روی 3 نمونه سنگ آهک میکرایتی و مقایسه UCS اندازه­گیری شده در آزمایشگاه با UCS تخمین زده شده ارزیابی شده که شباهت 88% آن‌ها نشان دهندۀ رواداری روابط تجربی پیشنهادی در تحقیق حاضر است.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Measuring of uniaxial compressive strength (UCS) of intact rocks is required in many engineering projects. In deep well drilling for petroleum production or exploration drilling in deep tunnels, because of depth of wells, obtaining suitable core samples for UCS test is too expensive and sometimes impossible. Therefore, indirect methods for determine UCS (for example using rock particles) are common. One of these methods is known as indentation test. In this test an indenter that is hard penetrates into rock particle which is surrounded by resin used. In this paper, 11 microcrystalline limestone block samples from carbonate Zagros formation outcrops were prepared and UCS test in laboratory was performed. Then cores are crushed and 720 rock particle samples with 2, 3 and 4 millimeter size was prepared. Indentation test with indenter 0.6, 0.8 and 1 millimeter diameter was done and critical transitional force (CTF) for each particles was determined. Empirical equation between UCS and CTF for different samples and has been provided. Based on the obtained results it is suggestedto utilize indenter with a R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;ge0.78. Using multiple regression general equation between UCS, CFT, particle size (D) indenter diameter (I), R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;=0.85 is proposed. 135 indentation tests were performed on 3 microcrystalline limestone samples with the aim of verification of obtained empirical equations. Comparing measured UCS in laboratory and estimated UCS values showed 88% similarity</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>آزمایش نفوذ , مقاومت فشاری تک محوری , نیروی انتقال بحرانی , خرده حفاری , </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>indentation test , uniaxial compressive strength , critical transitional force , drilling cutting , </keyword>
	<start_page>2891</start_page>
	<end_page>2916</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-269-2&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>E</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ahmadi sheshdeh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ابراهیم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>احمدی ششده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>ahmadi_sheshde@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>100319475328460080</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460080</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>مسئول آزمایشگاه زمین شناسی مهندسی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Akbar</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Cheshomi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>اکبر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>چشمی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>a.cheshomi@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>100319475328460081</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460081</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>استادیار بخش زمین شناسی مهندسی دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
