<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1390</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2011</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>5</volume>
<number>1</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تخمین ویژگی های مکانیکی سنگ آهک با استفاده از داده‌های پتروفیزیکی</title_fa>
	<title>Estimating mechanical properties of limestone from petrophysical data</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa>علمی پژوهشی</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>s</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>پارامترهای الاستیک سنگ به دو روش دینامیکی و استاتیکی قابل اندازه­گیری هستند. در روش دینامیکی، با اندازه­گیری سرعت عبور امواج تراکمی (Vp) و برشی (Vs) در شرایط برجا و یا آزمایشگاه، ویژگی­های الاستیک دینامیکی سنگ به‌دست می­آیند. در روش استاتیکی نیز با انجام آزمایش­های تخریبی مانند مقاومت فشاری تک محوری و یا سـه محوری بر روی مغزه سنگ، پارامترهای مقاومتی و الاستیک استاتیکی اندازه­گیری می­شوند. روش­های استاتیکی نتایج واقع­بینانه­تری نسبت به روش­های دینامیکـی مـی­دهند، اما هزینه انجام آن بیش‌تر بوده و اندازه­گیری آن به نقـاط دارای مغزه سنگی محدود می­شود. متأسفانه پارامترهای دینامیکی و استاتیکی با یک‌دیگر برابر نیستند و معمولاً پارامترهای دینامیکی از پارامترهای استاتیکی متناظر خود بزرگ‌تر هستند. به‌منظور اندازه­گیری پیوسته ویژگی­های مکانیک سنگ در طول چاه، ایجاد روابط تجربی بین پارامترهای دینامیکی و استاتیکی ضروری به‌نظر می­رسد. در این پژوهش با انجام آزمایش­های مقاومت فشاری تک‌محوری و التراسونیک بر روی مغزه­های نفتی مربوط به سازندهای کربناته سروک و آسماری یکی از چاه­های نفتی جنوب غرب ایران، روابطی تجربی برای تخمین مقاومت فشاری تک‌محوره (c&amp;sigma) و مدول یانگ استاتیکی (Es) بر اساس سرعت موج تراکمی (Vp) و مدول یانگ دینامیکی (Ed) پیشنهاد شده است که یکی از پیش­نیازهای اساسی برای تحلیل پیوسته پایداری در طول مسیر حفاری چاه­های نفت و گاز را تأمین می­کند.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Abstract &lt;br&gt;(Paper pages 1159-1178) &lt;br&gt;Young’s modulus measured as the slope of the stress-strain curve under static loading conditions (Es) in the lab is one of the most essential parameters for reservoir geomechanical modeling. However, information on the value of Es along the well length is often discontinuous and limited to cross well with the core. On the other hand, well log data for wave velocities Vp and Vs are often available for most hydrocarbon reservoirs. Hence, well-known equations are needed to calculate static Young’s modulus based on the compressional and shear wave velocities (Vp and Vs) that is dynamic Young’s modulus (Ed). Unfortunately, because of porosity and micro cracks in rock texture, Es and Ed are not equal. Therefore, correlation between static and dynamic parameters could result in a continuous and more reliable knowledge on the elastic parameters along the well length. In this research, laboratory experiments were carried out on limestone rock core specimens of Sarvak formation obtained from an oil well in the South West of Iran. Empirical relations were suggested to estimate UCS and static Young’s modulus from compressional wave velocity (Vp) and dynamic Young’s modulus. These empirical relations are prerequisite for continuous wellbore stability analysis in oil and gas well drilling</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>سنگ آهک , مقاومت فشاری تک محوره , مدول یانگ دینامیکی و استاتیکی , التراسونیک , </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Limestone , uniaxial compressive strength , Dynamic and Static Young’s modulus , Ultrasonic , </keyword>
	<start_page>1159</start_page>
	<end_page>1175</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-3-56&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
