<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1390</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2011</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>5</volume>
<number>1</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی مکانیسم سقوط سنگ و تهیۀ نقشۀ محدودۀ خطر و ارائه راه‌کارهای لازم در روستای یدک (شمال استان خراسان رضوی)</title_fa>
	<title>Investigation of rock fall mechanism and risk mapping of Yadak village area in north of Khorasan Razavi</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa>علمی پژوهشی</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>s</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>اساسی­ترین روش برای کاربری زمین در مناطق کوهستانی ارزیابی خطر سقوط سنگ است که به‌علت گسترش ساخت­وساز در آن مناطق و خطر سقوط سنگ، مسائل جانی و مالی فراوانی ایجاد می­کند. هدف این مقاله ارزیابی خطر سقوط سنگ در شمال روستای یدک است. روستای یدک از توابع شهرستان قوچان در استان خراسان رضوی در شمال­شرق­­­­ ایران قرار دارد. وجود آهک­های تیرگان با درز و شکاف فراوان در شمال‌شرق این روستا سبب ناپایداری شیب و احتمال سقوط سنگ شده و برای مناطق مسکونی روستایی نزدیک شیب خطر آفرین است. نوع سنگ، ژئومورفولوژی، شبکه زه‌کش و فعالیت­های لرزه­ای از عوامل مؤثر در لغزش هستد. برای بررسی سیستم درز و شکاف­ها در منطقه، 180 ناپیوستگی برداشت و از نرم‌افزار Dips استفاده شده است. از آن‌جا که سقوط سنگ از جمله ناپایداری­های اصلی در شیب قسمت شمالی روستای یدک است، از برنامه Rocfall برای تعیین محدودۀ خطر و بررسی نحوۀ سقوط سنگ استفاده شده است. سرانجام نقشه پهنۀ خطر سقوط سنگ در این روستا با استفاده از نرم افزار GIS تهیه شده است.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Rock fall hazard assessment is a fundamental land-use planning tool in high mountain area, where human settlements progressively develop across side valley areas, using the worth of potential losses and the restoration costs. The aim of this paper is to evaluate the potential of rock falls along the north east of the Yadak village. This village is located in the Khorasan-Razavi province near the Ghochan city in the northeast of Iran. The existence of the Tirgan limestones with abundant joints and fractures in the north part of the Yadak village causes instability such as rock falls that provide many problems for the residents. Many factors such as rock type, slope morphology, drainage pattern and the seismic activity are considered in this research as affecting factors. For joints investigation in the study area, the dip and dip direction of more than 180 discontinuities measured and analyzed using dips. Since most of the slope instability along the north part of the Yadak village are the rock falls type. Rocfall software was used to investigate the rock fall mechanism. Finally, the rock fall hazard zonation map is prepared using GIS program.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>سقوط سنگ , آهک تیرگان , ناپیوستگی , نرم‌افزار Rocfall ,</keyword_fa>
	<keyword></keyword>
	<start_page>1089</start_page>
	<end_page>1110</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-3-37&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
