<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1393</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>8</volume>
<number>3</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی و انتخاب غار طبیعی مناسب برای ذخیره‌سازی زیرزمینی نفت‌خام با استفاده از ترکیب دو روش FAHP و TOPSIS</title_fa>
	<title>Determining Appropriate Natural Caves for Underground Crude Oil Storage by Admixture FAHP and TOPSIS Methods</title>
	<subject_fa>زمین شناسی مهندسی</subject_fa>
	<subject>En. Geology</subject>
	<content_type_fa>علمی پژوهشی</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>s</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>بحران مالی دنیا در طی سال‌های اخیر باعث افزایش قیمت بسیاری از کالاها از جمله مواد هیدروکربوری شده است. این اتفاق بار دیگر اهمیت استراتژیک ذخیره‌سازی نفت‌خام را نشان می‌دهد. با عنایت به جایگاه ویژه نفت در اقتصاد ملی کشور، توسعه صنعت ذخیره‌سازی می‌تواند یکی از راهکارهای کنترل این گونه بحران‌ها باشد. ذخیره‌سازی زیرزمینی نفت‌خام در سازه‌های مصنوعی (شامل مغارهای سنگی، مغارهای نمکی و معادن متروکه) و ساختارهای طبیعی (شامل میادین تهی شده نفت و گاز، سفره‌های آب‌های زیرزمینی و غارهای طبیعی) امکان پذیر است. از بین این روش‌ها، طبیعا روشی مناسب‌تر است که سازگاری بیشتری با شرایط منطقه ذخیره‌سازی داشته باشد. در ایران به دلیل وجود غارهای طبیعی بسیار، ذخیره‌سازی نفت‌خام در درون غارهای طبیعی جزء گزینه‌های مناسب به نظر می‌رسد. بدیهی است اگر به جای حفر مغارها، از غارهای طبیعی برای ذخیره‌سازی استفاده شود، هزینه‌ی حفر مغار از هزینه‌های احداث مغار حذف می‌شود. در مقاله حاضر به منظور انتخاب غار مناسب برای ذخیره‌سازی نفت‌خام، غارهای طبیعی بر اساس معیارهای مختلف و با استفاده از ترکیبی از دو روش‌ تحلیل سلسله‌مراتبی فازی (FAHP) و شباهت به گزینه ایده‌آل (TOPSIS) مورد بررسی قرار گرفته‌ و گزینه مستعد انتخاب شده است. لازم به ذکر است وزن معیارها بر اساس نظرسنجی از افراد باتجربه در زمینه ذخیره‌سازی تعیین شده است. بر این اساس غار رودافشان به عنوان غاری مناسب برای ذخیره‌سازی زیرزمینی نفت‌خام انتخاب شد. این غار در شمال شرق استان تهران و در شهرستان فیروزکوه قرار گرفته و دارای 3 تالار بوده که جزء بزرگترین تالارها در میان غارهای ایران می‌باشد. به طور کلی می‌توان گفت حجم نفت‌خام قابل انباشت در غار مذکور در حدود 000،250 متر مکعب تخمین زده می‌شود.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>The world financial crisis has drastically raised the costs of hydrocarbon materials. This simply manifests the strategic significance of crude oil storage. Regarding the special rank of the oil in Iran’s economy, storage industry development can be one of the solutions to control such a crisis. Underground storage of crude oil in synthetic structures (rock caverns, salt caverns, and obsolete mines) and natural structures (depleted fields of oil and gas, underground water resources, and natural caves) is possible. Among these possibilities more adaptable to the environment is the most appropriate. Due to the existence of many caves in Iran, crude oils storage in natural caves is a proper option. It is clear that if natural caves are used instead of caverns, much can be saved. The present article intends to choose a proper cave for crude oil storage through studying the natural caves based on a combination of fuzzy analytical hierarchy process (FAHP) and technique for order performance by similarity to idea solution (TOPSIS). The likely option is chosen. Roudafshan Cave is considered appropriate for crude oil underground storage based on several qualitative and quantitative criteria including tourism and environment protection regulations, capacity, distance from both main pipes of crude oil transfer and country's major petroleum factories. It should be noted that these criteria are ranked by an experienced team. This cave is located in the north east of Tehran in Firoozkooh and has three passageways which are among the largest ones in the country. Generally, its capacity is estimated to be about 250,000 square meters</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>ذخیره‌سازی نفت‌خام , غارهای طبیعی , FAHP , TOPSIS ,</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Crude Oil Storage , Natural Caves , FAHP , TOPSIS ,</keyword>
	<start_page>2239</start_page>
	<end_page>2260</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-106-3&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>A</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Soltanalizadeh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>امیر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سلطان علیزاده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>aminsoltanalizadeh@gmail.com</email>
	<code>100319475328460069</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460069</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شاهرود</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>A</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ramezanzadeh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>احمد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رمضان زاده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>aramezanzadeh@shahroodut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>100319475328460070</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460070</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شاهرود</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>ME</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Jalali</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمد اسماعیل</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>جلالی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>smejalali@shahroodut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>100319475328460071</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460071</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
