<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1398</year>
	<month>10</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2020</year>
	<month>1</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>13</volume>
<number>4</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی ضرایب سایندگی و شکنندگی سنگدانه‌های مسیر مترو تبریز</title_fa>
	<title>The Abrasion and Brittleness Coefficients of Tabriz’s Metro Aggregates</title>
	<subject_fa>ژئوتکنیک (مکانیک خاک و سنگ)</subject_fa>
	<subject>Geotecnic</subject>
	<content_type_fa>علمی پژوهشی</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>s</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;حفر&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;تونل&#8204;های طویل&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;غالباً به&#8204;صورت مکانیزه&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;و با ماشین حفاری تونل &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman,serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;TBM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt; انجام می&#8204;شود. یکی از عوامل مهم در حفاری این تونل&amp;shy;ها اثر سایندگی خاک و سنگدانه&#8204;ها بر ابزارهای برشی و سایر بخش&amp;shy;های دستگاه حفار تونل است که باعث کاهش چشم&#8204;گیری در راندمان حفاری پروژه می&#8204;شود. محققان عوامل مختلفی که باعث ایجاد سایش در ابزار حفاری می&#8204;شوند را بررسی کرده&#8204;اند. در تحقیق حاضر 32 نمونه از سنگ&#8204;دانه&#8204;های مسیر تونل خط دو&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;مترو تبریز انتخاب شده و میزان سایندگی و شکنندگی این سنگ&#8204;دانه&#8204;ها برای بخش&#8204;های مختلف مسیر تعیین شده است. هم&#8204;چنین از بین مهم&#8204;ترین عوامل مؤثر، تأثیر پارامترهای وجود و میزان آب، جنس،&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;اندازه و شکل سنگ&#8204;دانه&#8204;ها، نوع و میزان فوم حفاری بر میزان ضریب سایندگی و شکنندگی سنگ&#8204;دانه&#8204;های مسیر بررسی شده، قرار گرفته است. بدین&#8204;منظور نیز حدود 130 نمونه از سنگ&#8204;دانه&#8204;ها شامل 20 نمونه برای بررسی تأثیر وجود و میزان آب، 15 نمونه برای جنس، 20 نمونه برای اندازۀ دانه&amp;shy;ها، 30 نمونه برای شکل و 42 نمونه برای تأثیر نوع و میزان فوم مصرفی تهیه شده است. روش&amp;shy;های زیادی برای آزمایش سایندگی خاک و خرده سنگ&amp;shy;ها در بخش&amp;shy;های حفاری به&#8204;وسیلۀ محققان ارایه شده است که یکی از معتبرترین و متداول&#8204;ترین این آزمایش&#8204;ها آزمون &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman,serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;LCPC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt; است.&amp;nbsp; بر اساس نتایج حاصل برای بررسی تأثیر میزان آب بر سایندگی، روی سه جنس آندزیت، ماسه سنگ و کنگلومرای مسیر از حالت خشک تا وجود آب به میزان 30% وزنی نمونه&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;آزمایش انجام شده است که در دو جنس ماسه سنگ و کنگلومرا با افزایش میزان آب سایندگی بیش&#8204;تر شده ولی در آندزیت از 20% به بعد کاهش سایندگی مشاهده می&amp;shy;شود، میزان ضریب شکنندگی نیز در کل با افزایش میزان آب کاهش می&amp;shy;یابد. از لحاظ سنگ&#8204;شناسی بیش&#8204;ترین تأثیر بر سایندگی را کنگلومرا داشته و از نظر شکنندگی هم آندزیت شکننده&amp;shy;ترین است. در تأثیر اندازۀ دانه&amp;shy;ها، با افزایش اندازۀ دانه&amp;shy;ها سایش زیادتر و شکنندگی کم&#8204;تر می&amp;shy;شود. تأثیر فوم بر سایندگی به این صورت است که تا حد خیس&#8204;&amp;shy;شدگی سایندگی کاهش یافته و بیش&#8204;تر از آن باعث افزایش سایندگی می&amp;shy;شود. از بین فوم&#8204;های مختلف آزمایش&#8204;شده نیز فوم شیمی بتن دارای حداقل سایندگی است.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Urban development and rapid extension of cities have been accompanied by a considerable growth in mechanized tunneling. The abrasivity of rock and even soil is a factor with considerable influence on the wear of tools. Soil abrasion and the resulting tool wear has a major impact on machine operation, utilization, and tunneling costs and time. One of the problematic aspects of working in abrasive grounds is the frequent need for the replacement of cutting tools, especially in pressurized face tunnel boring machines (TBMs). The effect of worn and damaged TBM cutter heads has been documented for numerous tunnel projects around the world. However, the lack of a standard or universally accepted test for soil abrasivity in geotechnical investigations has made the prediction of tool wear a difficult task.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Material and methods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A reliable prognosis of the abrasiveness of soils on a project would be of great benefit for designers, clients, and contractors. Many abrasion tests exist for rocks, and some have been proposed for soils; however, there is no universally accepted or international standard test for soil abrasivity testing. One of the most important and available tests in this field is LCPC abrasivity test which was developed by the Laboratoire Central des Ponts et Chauss&amp;eacute;es in the 1980&amp;rsquo;s. The LCPC Abrasivity Coefficient (ABR or LAC) can be used as a measure for both the abrasivity of the soil material and the influence of the grain size. The&amp;nbsp; abrasivity&amp;nbsp; testing&amp;nbsp; of&amp;nbsp; rock&amp;nbsp; is&amp;nbsp; controlled&amp;nbsp; by well-known parameters, whereas in soils many factors are influencing the abrasivity such as in-situ soil conditions, sedimentary petrology and technical&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; properties.&lt;br&gt;
Tabriz metro line 2 Project about 22 km in length that will connect eastern part of the Tabriz city to its western part, considered as a case study. The project comprises a single tunnel which has been constructed using two earth pressure balance EPB-TBM with a cutting-wheel diameter of 9.49 m. In this study, based on geological and geotechnical properties, the tunnel route was divided into four parts and the abrasion and brittleness coefficients of alluviums determined by LCPC test. Besides that, the influences of some factors such as moisture content, mineralogy, grain size and shape, type and amount of foam have been studied.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Results and discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Based on more than 130 LCPC test results, in general, the Tabriz Metro&amp;rsquo;s line-2 route alluviums have the abrasion in the range of low to very high and the brittleness in the range of high to very high. In order to measure the effect of moisture content on abrasion and brittleness coefficient, the LCPC test was done on some samples related to the tunnel route in dried and moistened modes (5%, 0%, 15%, 20%, 25%, and 30%). Three types of sandstone, andesite, and conglomerate of the route were used to test the effect of moisture and petrology on abrasion. In a moisture range of 0 to 5%, in all types of materials, abrasion was increased. In a moisture range of 5 to 10%, abrasion was decreased in all three types, and this shows that a moisture level of 10% is a normal moisture content to create minimum abrasion. The behavior of sandstone and conglomerate is similar at higher moisture contents, and an increase in moisture content to 30% can increase abrasion of materials in both types. In conglomerate, abrasion at higher moisture levels is significantly more than in other modes. In andesite, an increase in moisture content to 20% can increase abrasion, although the abrasion is decreased with a moisture content of over 20%. In most samples, increase in moisture content led to decrease in brittleness of materials. In general, the highest abrasion level was related to conglomerate and the lowest level was related to sandstone. Moreover, andesite was at a lower level than conglomerate and a higher level than sandstone in terms of abrasion. Also, the results show that increased grain size led to increased abrasion, and the changes in andesite were greater than in sandstone.&lt;br&gt;
In order to test the effectiveness of foam on abrasion, the foam used in workshops (A 168) made by Komeil Company Kashan was used for four types of petrography: conglomerate, andesite, sandstone, and silica. This test was conducted in the range of dried to 100 ml foam. In all types, decreased abrasion is observed from 0 to 20 ml and increased abrasion is observed from 20 to 100 ml.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The following conclusions are drawn from this research.&lt;br&gt;
- With regard to the effect of grain size, increased size of grains could lead to more abrasion and less brittleness&lt;br&gt;
- In terms of the effect of mineralogy, the conglomerate had the most effect on abrasion. In terms of brittleness, andesite was the most brittle.&lt;br&gt;
- When the foam is moisturized in the sample, minimum abrasion is observed and above this level, the abrasion is increased.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;./files/site1/files/134/4.pdf&quot;&gt;./files/site1/files/134/4.pdf&lt;/a&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa> ضریب سایندگی, شکنندگی, آزمون LCPC, فوم حفاری, آبرفت‌های مسیر خط 2 مترو تبریز.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword> LCPC test, soil abrasion, Tabriz metro aggregates, foam.</keyword>
	<start_page>617</start_page>
	<end_page>644</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1629-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Amirhasan</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Rezaei Farei</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>امیر حسن</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رضایی فرعی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>rezaei.ah@azaruniv.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846004015</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004015</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید مدنی آذربایجان، دانشکدۀ فنی و مهندسی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name> Masoud</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Mostafaei</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مسعود</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مصطفایی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846004016</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004016</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تبریز</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Kazem</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Razavi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سید کاظم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رضوی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846004017</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004017</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تبریز، دانشکدۀ مهندسی عمران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
