<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1398</year>
	<month>11</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2020</year>
	<month>2</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>13</volume>
<number>5</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>en</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی مقایسه ای پاسخ لرزه ای دیوار میخ کوبی شده تحت اثر زلزله های نزدیک و دور از گسل</title_fa>
	<title>A Comparative Study of the Seismic Response of Soil-Nailed Walls under the Effect of Near-fault and Far-fault Ground Motions</title>
	<subject_fa>ژئوتکنیک (مکانیک خاک و سنگ)</subject_fa>
	<subject>Geotecnic</subject>
	<content_type_fa>مقاله مستقل</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Original Manuscript</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;در سال&amp;shy;های اخیر با گسترش استفاده از روش میخ&amp;shy;کوبی برای تثبیت دیوارۀ گودبرداری&amp;shy;ها، نیاز به بررسی جامع رفتار این روش احساس می&amp;shy;شود. در پژوهش&#8204;های پیشین، رفتار دیوار میخ&amp;shy;کوبی&amp;shy;شده در &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;حالت&amp;shy;های&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt; استاتیکی و دینامیکی تحت شرایط مختلف بررسی شده&amp;shy;اند اما با توجه به ماهیت متفاوت زلزله&amp;shy;های حوزۀ نزدیک گسل، بررسی اثر این حرکات روی رفتار دیوار میخ&amp;shy;کوبی&amp;shy;شده ضروری است. از این&#8204;رو &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;در این پژوهش با در نظر گرفتن یک مدل دوبعدی گودبرداری، اثر زلزله&amp;shy;های حوزه نزدیک و حوزه دور از گسل روی پاسخ مدل بررسی شده است. برای تشریح رفتار خاک از مدل موهر کولمب و برای میخ&amp;shy;ها پارامترهای الاستیک و پلاستیک در نظر گرفته شده است. هم&#8204;چنین با توجه به قابلیت&amp;shy;های نرم&amp;shy;افزار&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman,serif;&quot;&gt;PLAXIS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman,serif;&quot;&gt;2D&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;، برای مدل&amp;shy;سازی روند گودبرداری، از روش ساخت مرحله&amp;shy;ای استفاده شده است. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;در این بررسی، 10 شتاب&#8204;نگاشت زلزله (5 شتاب&#8204;نگاشت زلزله حوزۀ نزدیک و 5 شتاب&#8204;نگاشت زلزله حوزۀ دور)، که روی سنگ سخت ثبت شده&amp;shy;اند، به کف مدل اعمال شد. مقادیر لنگرخمشی، نیروی برشی و نیروی محوری ایجاد شده در میخ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&amp;shy;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;ها، در حالت زلزله حوزۀ نزدیک بزرگ&#8204;تر از مقادیر ایجاد شده تحت زلزله&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&amp;shy;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;های حوزه دور هستند. این مقادیر تقریباً برای بیشینۀ لنگرخمشی برابر 23 درصد، نیروی برشی 30 درصد و نیروی محوری 22 درصد هستند. به&#8204;دلیل این که در زلزله&amp;shy;های حوزۀ نزدیک انرژی بیش&#8204;تری در مدت زمان کم&#8204;تری به مدل اعمال می&amp;shy;شود (به&#8204;دلیل وجود پالس) تغییرمکان ایجاد شده نیز بیش&#8204;تر است. افزایش طول میخ و سختی موجب کاهش تغییر مکان دیوار میخ کوبی شده تحت زلزله حوزۀ نزدیک می شود، مع&#8204;ذلک رفتار کلی خاک&amp;nbsp; تحت این زلزله عوض نمی&#8204;شود. بر مبنای نتایج به&#8204;دست آمده در یک حداکثرشتاب ثابت رابطۀ مستقیمی بین حداکثر پیک سرعت و جابه&#8204;جایی بالای دیوار وجود دراد. لیکن رابطۀ ذکر شده در زلزله&#8204;های حوزۀ دور مشاهده نمی&#8204;شود.&lt;/span&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>In recent years, with the growing use of the nailing method for stabilizing excavation walls, there has been a need for a comprehensive investigation of the behavior of this method. In the&amp;nbsp; previous studies, the behavior of nailed walls has been investigated in static and dynamic states and under different conditions. However, due to the different feature of near-field ground motions, it is&amp;nbsp; necessary to study the effect of these motions on the behavior of the nailed walls. Near-fault ground motion is significantly affected by the earthquake record direction and the rupture mechanism. So, in this study, to compare the effects of near-field and far-field ground motions, a two-dimensional (2D) soil- nailed wall was considered. PLAXIS 2D was used for the modeling of the soil-nailed wall system. An excavation with a dimension of 10 meters in height was taken into the account. In this study, 10 records (Five fault-normal near-field ground motion records and five far-field ground motion records), were recorded&amp;nbsp; on the rock and&amp;nbsp; applied to the model. These ground motion records were derived from the near-fault ground motion record set used by Baker. These records were scaled to the Peak Ground Acceleration (PGA) of 0.35g and then applied to the bottom of the finite element models. Mohr-Coulomb model was then used to describe the soil behavior, and Elasto-plastic model was employed for the nails. A damping ratio of 0.05 was considered at the fundamental periods of the soil layer. The results showed that the&amp;nbsp; generated values of bending moment, shear force and axial force in nails under the effect of the near-fault ground motions were&amp;nbsp; more than those in the far-ault ground motions. These values were&amp;nbsp; almost equal to 23% for the maximum bending moment, 30% for the&amp;nbsp; shear force,&amp;nbsp; and 22% for the axial force. The created displacement under the effect of near-fault ground motions was&amp;nbsp; more than that in the far-fault since a higher energy was&amp;nbsp; applied to the model in the near-field ground motions during a short time (pulse-like ground motions). In contrast, in the far-fault ground motions, due to the more uniform distribution of energy during the record, such pulse-like displacements were not observed in the system response. Increasing in nail length and soil densification, decreases the displacement of the soil-nailed wall but does not change the general behavior of the soil under the effect of near-field ground motions. Based on the obtained results, for a constant PGA, there were&amp;nbsp; positive correlations between the values of the&amp;nbsp; maximum displacement on the top of the wall and&amp;nbsp; the PGV values of near-fault ground motion records. However, the mentioned correlations were&amp;nbsp; not observed in the case of far-fault ground motions.&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>دیوار میخ کوبی شده, زلزله حوزه نزدیک, روش اجزا محدود,2D PLAXIS, مدل سازی عددی</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Soil-nailed walls, Near-fault Ground Motions, Finite element method, PLAXIS2D, Numerical modeling</keyword>
	<start_page>121</start_page>
	<end_page>146</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1658-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Maryam</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mokhtari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مریم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مختاری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>mokhtari@yazd.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846004168</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004168</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Civil Engineering Department, Faculty of Engineering, Yazd University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه یزد، پردیس فنی و مهندسی، دانشکدۀ مهندسی عمران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Kazem</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Barkhordari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>کاظم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>برخورداری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>kbarkhordari@yazd.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846004169</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004169</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Civil Engineering Department, Faculty of Engineering, Yazd University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه یزد، پردیس فنی و مهندسی، دانشکدۀ مهندسی عمران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Saeid</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Abbasi Karafshani</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سعید</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عباسی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>abbasi.civil@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846004170</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004170</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه یزد، پردیس فنی و مهندسی، دانشکدۀ مهندسی عمران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
