<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <records>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Kharazmi University</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</journalTitle>
	<issn>2228-6837</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>9</volume>
	<issue>3</issue>
	<startPage>2891</startPage>
	<endPage>2916</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Estimation the Uniaxial Compressive Strength of Microcrystalline Limestones Using Indentation Test</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>E Ahmadi sheshdeh</name>
	<email>ahmadi_sheshde@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Akbar Cheshomi</name>
	<email>a.cheshomi@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Measuring of uniaxial compressive strength (UCS) of intact rocks is required in many engineering projects. In deep well drilling for petroleum production or exploration drilling in deep tunnels, because of depth of wells, obtaining suitable core samples for UCS test is too expensive and sometimes impossible. Therefore, indirect methods for determine UCS (for example using rock particles) are common. One of these methods is known as indentation test. In this test an indenter that is hard penetrates into rock particle which is surrounded by resin used. In this paper, 11 microcrystalline limestone block samples from carbonate Zagros formation outcrops were prepared and UCS test in laboratory was performed. Then cores are crushed and 720 rock particle samples with 2, 3 and 4 millimeter size was prepared. Indentation test with indenter 0.6, 0.8 and 1 millimeter diameter was done and critical transitional force (CTF) for each particles was determined. Empirical equation between UCS and CTF for different samples and has been provided. Based on the obtained results it is suggestedto utilize indenter with a R2&#59;ge0.78. Using multiple regression general equation between UCS, CFT, particle size (D) indenter diameter (I), R2=0.85 is proposed. 135 indentation tests were performed on 3 microcrystalline limestone samples with the aim of verification of obtained empirical equations. Comparing measured UCS in laboratory and estimated UCS values showed 88% similarity</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1713-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>indentation test</keyword>
	<keyword>uniaxial compressive strength</keyword>
	<keyword>critical transitional force</keyword>
	<keyword>drilling cutting</keyword>
	<keyword></keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Kharazmi University</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</journalTitle>
	<issn>2228-6837</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>9</volume>
	<issue>3</issue>
	<startPage>2917</startPage>
	<endPage>2940</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Estimation of Surface Settlement in Niayesh Subway Tunnel Using Empirical, Nnumerical Methods and Actual Settlements</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Gholam Reza Khanlari</name>
	<email>khanlari_reza@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Maleki</name>
	<email>maleki_m@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Reza Hydari-Torkemani</name>
	<email>hydari-torkemani@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Somaye Alipour</name>
	<email>engineergeo2013@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Fateme Naseri</name>
	<email>f.naseri91@basu.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>5</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
             Bu-Ali Sina university-Hamedan    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
             Bu-Ali Sina university-Hamedan    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
             pajohesh omran Rahvar company    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
             Bu-Ali Sina Hamedan    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="5">
             Bu-Ali Sina university    
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">One of the best approaches to reduce transportation problem is to use the underground tunnels. Therefore, Niayesh highway tunnel was performed by the New Austrian Tunnelling Method (NATM) in the northern part of Tehran and it includes north and south tunnels. The excavation of tunnels and other underground structures cause considerable changes in local stress conditions around structures that lead to surface settlement. In this research, surface settlement has been studied for five sections (CS-1 to CS-5) by empirical methods, numerical analysis and actual settlements. For the empirical and numerical methods, O’Reilly and New (1982) method and also finite element method (PLAXIS2D software) have been used, respectively. On the basis of the obtained results, the numerical method in all sections (except section 3) is in agreement with the actual settlements. While, empirical methods have estimated the settlements more than actual values in those sections.  Also, the achieved results from the aforementioned methods show that the maximum settlement due to tunnel excavation is more than allowable settlement and it is in risk condition</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1891-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Niayesh tunnel</keyword>
	<keyword>ground settlement</keyword>
	<keyword>empirical method</keyword>
	<keyword>numerical method</keyword>
	<keyword>PLAXIS2D</keyword>
	<keyword></keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Kharazmi University</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</journalTitle>
	<issn>2228-6837</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>9</volume>
	<issue>3</issue>
	<startPage>2941</startPage>
	<endPage>2960</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Estimating the Variable Horizontal Acceleration Coefficient in Height of Embankment Dams Considering Dam Flexibility and Reservoir Elevations</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>M Davoodi</name>
	<email>m-davood@iiees.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Ali Ghanbari</name>
	<email>ghanbari@tmu.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>S. Abedini</name>
	<email>saeed abediny2002@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The pseudo-static analysis is one of the conventional methods in embankment dams design and International Commission on Large Dams (ICOLD) suggests using this method before ultimate dynamic analyses. In this research, the static, pseudo-static and dynamic analysis of Masjed Soleyman embankment dam was performed. Using dynamic and pseudo-static analyses results, the safety factor of critical sliding surface was calculated. Permanent displacements of critical sliding surface were evaluated by New mark method and the calculated safety factor was compared. Based on the comparison results in different water levels of the reservoir and by introducing a new equation, the variable horizontal acceleration coefficients in height of the dam body were calculated. Finally, the obtained horizontal acceleration coefficients were compared with the other criteria introduced in different embankment dam's design codes. Totally, the results indicate that the proposed method leads to a larger horizontal acceleration coefficient in higher parts of the dam body.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1710-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>embankment dams</keyword>
	<keyword>horizontal acceleration coefficients</keyword>
	<keyword>pseudo-static analysis</keyword>
	<keyword>dynamic analysis</keyword>
	<keyword></keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Kharazmi University</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</journalTitle>
	<issn>2228-6837</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>9</volume>
	<issue>3</issue>
	<startPage>2961</startPage>
	<endPage>2982</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Investigation of Changes in Groundwater Affected by the Electromagnetic Fields of the Earth to Predict Earthquake</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Maryam Rezaei</name>
	<email>maryam.rezaie65@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>N. Hasani</name>
	<email>hassaniamoozeshi@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>A. Khorsandi</name>
	<email>a_khorsandi@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>A. Rezaei</name>
	<email>a_rezaei2000@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Several studies show that during and before the earthquake, ground water existing in layers of the earth crust undergoes physical and chemical changes. These changes are recorded by measurement devices and known as "Geohydrological Precursors". Based on the studies conducted in this field, earth electromagnetic field waves experience fluctuations during and even before happening of the earthquake, which are called "magnetic anomalies". This type of anomaly is known as "geomagnetic precursor" within the scope of earthquake knowledge. S, the aim of this study is to assess the feasibility of making a connection between two groups of earthquake precursors (hydrological and geomagnetic precursors). In the present research, a series of tests has been done in order to investigate the effect of magnetic fields on physical and chemical properties of water, including Electrical Conductivity (EC), Total dissolved solids (TDS), Height of Water (HW). The tests were designed and conducted to be used in short-term and middle-term earthquake prediction. Analysis of the experimental results using statistical tests indicates that there is a partial meaningful relationship between magnetic fields (geomagnetic precursor) and physical and chemical properties of water (hydrological precursors), with the confidence coefficient equal to 95 percent</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2042-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Earthquake</keyword>
	<keyword>ground water</keyword>
	<keyword>magnetic and electromagnetic field</keyword>
	<keyword>anomalous</keyword>
	<keyword>earthquake precursors</keyword>
	<keyword></keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Kharazmi University</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</journalTitle>
	<issn>2228-6837</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>9</volume>
	<issue>3</issue>
	<startPage>2983</startPage>
	<endPage>3002</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Prediction of Concrete Strength Containing Different Aggregates through Artificial Neural Networks</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>J. Sharifi</name>
	<email>javad2114@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>M. R. Nikodel</name>
	<email>nikudelm@modares.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng"> In this research, prediction of concrete strength containing different aggregates using Non-destructive (Ultrasonic) testing through Artificial Neural Networks was carried out. For this purpose, aggregates with different properties were selected from the quarries, and then their destructive and nondestructive properties were obtained in laboratory. The significance of this research, using different aggregates with physical, mechanical and chemical properties also used two different test methods, such as Non-destructive static and dynamic testing, which are respectively uniaxial compressive strength and compressive wave velocity. Thus, this model includes various types of samples and the prediction model includes static and dynamic tests. The results showed that the use of artificial neural networks not only increases the accuracy, but also it reduces costs and time.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1819-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Concrete</keyword>
	<keyword>Aggregate</keyword>
	<keyword>Compressive Wave Velocity</keyword>
	<keyword>Artificial neural network</keyword>
	<keyword></keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Kharazmi University</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</journalTitle>
	<issn>2228-6837</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>9</volume>
	<issue>3</issue>
	<startPage>3003</startPage>
	<endPage>3032</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Landslide Hazard Zonation in Latian Dam Using Analytic Hierarchy Process, Valuing Area Accumulation, Factor Overlay and Information Value</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>h atapour</name>
	<email>atapour@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>r ahmadi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">In present research, landslide hazard zonation of Latian dam watershed area has been carried out using Analytic Hierarchy Process (AHP), Valuing area accumulation, Factor overlay and Information value methods. At first, different maps comprising slope, aspect, altitude, faults, drainage network, access roads, lithology, land use and friction angle maps were prepared digitally using GIS. Afterward affecting factors were evaluated using old landslides. The results of evaluation show that seven parameters are important effective factors on sliding in this area. These parameters were leaded to landslide zonation maps. These maps show that potentially high risk zones point of view landslides are located near the central and western boundaries of the reservoir. Performance of four used classification methods were evaluated and compared. The evaluation results show that Valuing area accumulation and Factor overlay are precise methods for evaluating landslide potential in the study area respectively</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2667-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>landslide hazard zonation</keyword>
	<keyword>Latian dam</keyword>
	<keyword>Analytic Hierarchy Process (AHP)</keyword>
	<keyword>Valuing area accumulation</keyword>
	<keyword>Factor overlay</keyword>
	<keyword>Information value</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Kharazmi University</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</journalTitle>
	<issn>2228-6837</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>9</volume>
	<issue>3</issue>
	<startPage>3033</startPage>
	<endPage>3050</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Assessment of Impact of Performance Parameters on TBM Tool Wear by Use of Silica Samples</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>hossein mirmehrabi</name>
	<email>hosseinmirmehrabi@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Ghafoori</name>
	<email>ghafoori@ferdowsi.um.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>G.R. Lashkaripur</name>
	<email>lashkaripour@um.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Unpredicted and excessive tool wear is a major challenge in some tunnel projects. Due to more need for maintenance, abrasivity problems increese time and cost of excavation activity. A new laboratory test machine has been built in Engineering Geological Laboratory of Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, to obtain a proper view about relation between performance parameters of a TBM and the soil abrasion. In this paper the results of abrasion tests carried out on silica samples, as an abundant hard mineral, by the machin, are presented. Hence 36 tests have been performed on coarse silica sand samples, with various amount of deadweight and rotation speed at different times. The results prove direct relation between time, surcharge and rotation speed versus tool wear. For example a linear relation between tool wear and surcharge or rotation speed was observed. Besides a logarithmic relation was achieved for time effect</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1887-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Mechanized excavation</keyword>
	<keyword>Tool wear</keyword>
	<keyword>Soil abrasivity</keyword>
	<keyword>Soil abrasion test</keyword>
	<keyword></keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Kharazmi University</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</journalTitle>
	<issn>2228-6837</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>9</volume>
	<issue>3</issue>
	<startPage>3051</startPage>
	<endPage>3068</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Effects of soil Properties and Fault Crossing Angle on the Behavior of Buried Pipeline</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>G.R. Noori</name>
	<email>r.nouri@khu.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>M. Balo</name>
	<email>mehdy_baloo@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Buried pipeline system form a key part of global lifeline infrastructure and any significant disruption to the performance of these systems often lead to undesirable impact on regional business, economies or the living condition of citizens. In this paper the response of buried pipelines at fault crossings are studied. A fault movement can be resolved into an axial component, a lateral component in the horizontal plane, and a vertical component. Applying finite element method, the effect of various parameters such as anchored length, internal friction angle of surrounding soil, fault movement and fault crossing angle on the behavior of buried pipeline were studied. Nonlinear behavior for pipe and surrounding soil are assumed using beam-spring model. Results showed an increase in internal friction angle of surrounding soil increases strain and also normalized bending moment and axial force. Comparing bending moment at friction angle of 20° and 40° shows about 30% differences with certain crossing angle we can prevent producing large strain and bending moment on pipeline</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1889-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Buried pipeline</keyword>
	<keyword>soil friction angel</keyword>
	<keyword>fault movement</keyword>
	<keyword>fault crossing angle</keyword>
	<keyword>nonlinear analysis</keyword>
	<keyword></keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
 </records>
 
  
  
  
  
 