<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.0//EN" "http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov:80/entrez/query/static/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</JournalTitle>
<Issn>2228-6837</Issn>
<Volume>13</Volume>
<Issue>1</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2019</Year>
<Month>8</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Investigating the Engineering Properties of Kerman Soils and Factors Controlling their Collapsibility</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>28</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Iman</FirstName>
	<LastName>Aghamolaie</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Gholamreza</FirstName>
	<LastName> Lashkaripour</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>mohammads</FirstName>
	<LastName>ghfoori</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>naser</FirstName>
	<LastName>hafezimoghadas</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Introduction
The problematic collapsible soils are deposits with wind origin that constitute about 10% of the total area of ​​the earth. Several countries, including China, Russia, the United States, France, Germany, New Zealand, and Argentina have vast areas of collapsible soils. These deposits usually form a semi-stable honeycomb structure and are highly susceptible to sudden changes in the volume reduction due to becoming humid. Collapsibility and other related issues such as different subsidences, land cracks and landfalls seriously damage the infrastructures constructed on these soils.
&#160;By the growing rate of urbanization in different parts of the world, the probability of construction on these soils and consequently water availability for these soils will increase; as a result, humidity increases and the collapse of these soils may occur. Therefore, studying the behavior of these types of soils is very important. Over the past six decades, many researchers have studied the collapse mechanism of collapsible soils due to becoming humid. Discussions on this subject are summarized in three categories: traditional methods, soil structure studies, and soil mechanics-based methods. In the present work, collapsibility and its controlling factors in the soils of Kerman city are investigated.
&#160;
Material and methods
To determine engineering properties of Kerman deposits in this research, the geotechnical information was gathered and 50 core samples were extracted from different parts of the city. The sampling points were selected such that they could have a high overlap. X-ray diffraction (XRD) was applied to determine the mineral type and soil structures while scanning electron microscopy (SEM) was used to study grain arrangement.
Results and discussion
Geotechnical characteristics of the samples collected from Kerman plain deposits include their physical and mechanical properties. Based on the obtained results, this fine-grained sediment generally includes two CL and CL-ML groups. The mineralogy studies of Kerman city soils show that the minerals in these deposits are mainly illite, chlorite, illite-smectite, calcite, quartz, and gypsum. In order to study the collapsibility level of the soils in Kerman through the field studies, samples were taken from different parts of the city and the tests were carried out to determine the physical properties, collapsibility index, and structural studies. Through the SEM analyses, samples related to Haft Bagh area, Motahhari Town, and Pedar Town revealed an open structure and intergranular pores and thus a high level of collapsibility. On the other hand, in the majority of samples taken from the central part of the city, such as Esteghlal Street, Azadi Square, Bahmaniyar Street, and Hafez Street, the soil aggregates generally have corner-to-corner connectivity, with no specific order in their structure, and the arrangement of the particles is random and irregular. The orientation of the particles mostly shows no sharp pattern. In addition to soil particles, they have shown random and disorientated cavities with small sizes, suggesting the density and compactness of the soil indicating a low to moderate collapsibility. In some areas (e.g., Pedar Township and Motahhari Township), crystalline salt and gypsum crystals are clearly seen. It is expected that by increasing the amount of water, these salts dissolve and their effects can be observed as dissolution cavities.
&#160;The dissolution of soluble crystals can also reduce the strength of the soil structure and ultimately lead to soil degradation. Calcite crystals are also found in some places in the form of calcite cement among the grains, sometimes as single crystals, and sometimes as lime nodules within the soils of Kerman city. Among the stated criteria in this research, Denisov, Holtz, and Hill criteria, the Russian regulations and ASTM standards were employed to assess the potential of the studied soil collapsing. Based on the criterion of the construction regulations of Russia, it was found that the deposits of the city of Kerman are mainly collapsible (L&#62;-0.1).&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;
Moreover, based on the Denisov criterion (if e/eL&#62;1.5 the soil is non-collapsible, if it is between 0.75 and 1.5, the soil is prone to collapsing, and if it is between 0.5 and 0.75, the soil is severely collapsible), soils of Kerman are within the range of collapse-prone soils. Finally, based on the ASTM criterion, in some areas of the city like Motahhari Town, Pedar Town, and Haft bagh, soils show a high collapsibility. In comparison, in the central parts of the city, the values of this criterion vary between 0.15 and 11, suggesting the presence of soils with a moderate collapsibility. Comparing the results obtained using these criteria it is seen that areas with a collapsible behavior are relatively similar collapsibility results are obtained.
Conclusion
Based on the achieved results, fine-grained sediments of Kerman city are mainly composed of CL and CL-ML groups. Mineralogy results indicate that the minerals in these deposits are mainly illite, chlorite, illite-smectite, calcite, quartz, and gypsum. SEM results for the central part of Kerman city confirm the compressed and densely compact form of soil particles. The results obtained, using the construction regulations of Russia show that the soils in the study area are collapsible. According to the Denisov criterion, they were found to be prone to collapse. Finally, based on the ASTM results for the central parts of the city, soils exhibit a low to moderate collapsibility. However, in some areas of the city, such as Motahhari and Haft bagh, soils show a complete collapsibility behavior../files/site1/files/131/1Extended_Abstract.pdf
&#160;</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</JournalTitle>
<Issn>2228-6837</Issn>
<Volume>13</Volume>
<Issue>1</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2019</Year>
<Month>8</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Evaluation of a New Injection Method for Biologically Improvement of Sandy Soils</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>29</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>44</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mehrdad</FirstName>
	<LastName> Emami Tabrizi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Bahareh</FirstName>
	<LastName> Mohammad Seyyedi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Introduction
Microbial induced calcite precipitation (MICP) is one of the environment-friendly soil improvement methods that uses urease activity of the microorganisms to bound soil grains.
This method is based on three following steps:
1. Urea hydrolysis by urease activity of microorganisms and formation of ammonium and carbonate ions:
(2)
2. The reaction between carbonate and calcium ions and formation of calcium carbonate:
(2)
3. Bonding the soil particles by calcium carbonate.
One of the main challenges in use of MICP for soil improvement is the selection of proper injection method. An efficient injection method should lead to the construction of a homogeneous specimen beside of less used materials. In this study, a new method based on the theory of convection of liquids, for injection of bacteria and cementation solution is introduced.
Specimens are made according to the new injection method and their strength and homogeneities are tested. The obtained results are compared with the specimens which are made based on common injection method. Eventually, the success of the proposed injection method is investigated.
&#160;
Material and methods
Gram-positive microorganism Sporosarcina Pasteurii No. 1645 (DSM 33) is provided from Persian type culture collection (PTCC). To make sand columns, Poly Vinyl Chloride (PVC) tubes were used with an internal diameter of 5cm and length of 12cm. Molds were placed vertically and a scouring pad and approximately 1 cm gravel as a filter are placed at the bottom of the column. Then the column packed with pure silica (Table 1). Finally, a scouring pad and approximately 1 cm gravel as a filter are placed at top of the column and mold were closed with a threaded Polypropylene layer on top and bottom with a hole for injection of bacteria and cementation solutions.
Table 1. Sand properties used in this study


	
		
			Soil Type
			Gs
			&#947;d
			e
			D10
			D30
			D60
		
		
			Sw
			2.6
			1.84
			41%
			0.11 mm
			0.43mm
			0.85mm
		
	

In this study, a new multi-step method of injecting bacterial and cementation solutions is introduced. Injection of solutions is done after washing the sand column with distilled water. At the first step, 0.25 times of the void volume of soil, the bacterial solution is injected into the sand column. The bacteria allowed resting in the sand for 2 hours before the cementation solution was injected. After 2 hours, cementation solution is injected into the sand column by the amount of 0.25 times of pore volume of soil. The cementation solution consisted of 1.5 M urea and 3 M Calcium chloride. Again after 2 hours delay, bacterial solution and cementation solution are injected into sand column both by the amount of 0.25 times of pore volume of soil, same as aforementioned steps. In order to provide a comparison between the proposed injection methods of this study with conventional injection method, specimens are also made by the conventional method. In these specimens, bacterial solution and cementation solution are injected into the soil both by the amount of 1.5 times of pore volume of soil.
Results and discussion
To evaluate the homogeneity of the biologically improved sand specimens, the specimen is divided into 6 equal parts and the amount of calcium carbonate in each part is measured. It is found that calcium carbonate crystals are formed more homogenous in parts of specimens which are improved by new injection method (Figure 1). While specimens improved with conventional injection method are not homogeneous. The new injection method used in this study is based on the theory of convection in cementation and bacterial solution. Since the specific gravity of used cementation solution (3M urea and 1.5M calcium chloride solution) is 1.120 gr/cm3 and the specific gravity of ammonium chloride (which is the result of reaction between ammonium and chloride ions) is 1.031 gr/cm3, therefore a convection flow occurs in cementation solution after urease reaction (reaction 1) because of difference in specific gravity of two mentioned solutions. This convection flow causes a sustainable contact between cementation and bacterial solution in entire height of specimen.

Figure 1. Amount of calcium carbonate deposition along improved specimens by new and conventional injection method
To examine the efficiency of newly suggested injection method in this study, uniaxial compressive strength test (UCS) is performed on biologically improved sand specimens. Figure 2 shows stress-strain curves of specimens. The peak strength of specimens with conventional injection method is about 0.6 MPa. While the peak strength of biologically improved specimens prepared by new injection method is about 1.6 MPa. The reason for this difference in the obtained results is that when the volume of bacterial solution is more than the pore volume of soil, a part of bacteria solution in the first step of injection is removed. Then with an injection of cementation solution, more amounts of bacteria removes from the specimen before efficient placement of bacteria between soil particles. However, in new injection method the total volume of injection solutions (bacterial and cementation solutions) are equal to the pore volume of soil and this prevents the removal of bacteria from a porous medium.

Figure 2. Uniaxial stress-uniaxial strain curves of biologically improved specimens
Conclusion
In this study, the feasibility of using a new injection method for biological soil improvement is investigated based on the theory of convection with the aim to decrease the volume of bacteria and cementation solution. In this method, the final volume of bacterial and cementation solutions are reached the soil void volume in 4 consecutive injection steps. Specimens are made to investigate the efficiency of the proposed injection method. Also, specimens are made base on conventional injection method to provide the comparing possibility. Studying the precipitated calcium carbonate along the specimens show more homogeneity in ones prepared by proposed injection method in comparison to the specimens made by the conventional method. The obtained results of UCS tests are also showed that specimens made by new injection method have the more uniaxial strength (1.6 MPa) while the conventional method specimens are presented the strength of 0.6 MPa. Eventually, the proposed injection method of this paper implies less amount of bacterial and cementation solutions in a proper and efficient manner to bond the soil particles which leads to specimens with more strength, stiffness and homogeneity../files/site1/files/131/2Extended_Abstract.pdf
&#160;</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</JournalTitle>
<Issn>2228-6837</Issn>
<Volume>13</Volume>
<Issue>1</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2019</Year>
<Month>8</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Effect of Nano Calcium Carbonate on Mechanical Strength and Permeability of Roller-Compacted Concrete</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>45</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>68</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Vahid</FirstName>
	<LastName> Daneshjoo</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Reza</FirstName>
	<LastName> Farokhzad</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Introduction
Nanostructured materials have gained increasing attention of industry and the academia in recent decades, due to their prominent behaviors. In this regard, the building industry is considered to be the major consumer of nanostructured materials in terms of its needs, including strength, resistance, durability and high performance. Studies on nanoscale behavior of cement and concrete to develop new building materials and their applications are of high importance. A typical method for the development of high performance concrete (HPC) often contains various parameters, including the mix of conventional concrete with different types of additives. Nano-Calcium carbonate (Nano-Precipitated&#160;Calcium Carbonate) is a nano-sized filler which is used in this research. The results indicate that the higher the optimal content of nano-precipitated&#160;calcium carbonate powder, the higher the initial heat of the roller-compacted concrete; also, the resistance of the samples significantly increases over time. However, the level of permeability of roller-compacted concrete decreases by optimal increase of nano-calcium carbonate powder due to its fine grains, filling properties, and high specific level. The results of this study show that the adequate use of this material improves some properties of roller-compacted concrete.
Material and methods
In this study, the content of Nano-calcium carbonate used was selected at 0, 1, 2, 3 and 4 percent replacing a volume of cement consumed in concrete. Type II Portland cement, crushed fluvial sand, and crushed coarse aggregates with a maximum size of 19 mm were used. The aggregates&#8217; grading range in the mix has been selected according to the ACI325-10R. The chemical formula of Nano-calcium carbonate powder is CaCo3 and the average particle size is between 15-40 nm
According to the roller-compacted concrete specifications, 5 mix designs have been used with different proportions of stone materials in preparing of concrete. The samples were made on a vibrating table and in the cylindrical molds of 15 &#215; 30 cm according to ASTM C1176 standard.
By increasing the cement grade, the slope of the Vebe curve increases, which means an increase in speed and reduction in efficiency over time in higher grades. Increasing the cement grade from 275 to 300 kg/m3 leads to increased Vebe time. In other words, it can be said that the efficiency is reduced at a lower rate in lower grades of new roller-compacted concrete mix. The Vebe time of the roller-compacted concrete pavement should be between 30-40 s to achieve optimal efficiency. According to the results of Vebe time, the efficiency of the roller-compacted concrete with the grade of 300 kg/m3 has a better functionality than other mixtures and lasted more than others in the 30 to 40 second range. Accordingly, concrete with a grade of 300 kg/m3, is the compressive strength according to this design.
Determining the compressive strength of cylindrical concrete samples of different ages is done according to the ASTM C39/C39M standard. For permeability test, the BS EN 12390-8: 2009 was used in which the sample should be put under pressure of&#160; (0.5&#177;)5 for 72 hours immediately after molding. Determining the tensile strength of concrete cylindrical samples at different ages is done according to the ASTM C496 standard. The peak is obtained using the XRD analysis of the crystallite size by determining the width of the peaks. In interpreting the XRD data, a list of peak resolution and their intensities is observed. To determine the elemental composition of materials, a non-destructive analytical technique is used by X-ray which is so-called XRF (X-ray fluorescence). A scanning electron microscope is a powerful magnification tool and is used to distinguish elements.
Results and discussion
The results indicate that the increased Vebe time occurs by an increase in the percentage of nano-calcium carbonate. In terms of the compressive strength of cylindrical roller-compacted concrete samples, 2% of nano-calcium carbonate at the ages of 7, 28, and 90 days has been effective in increasing compressive strength in higher ages. Such that, at the ages of 28 and 90 days, it is increased by 12% and 15 % compared to the control sample, respectively. The nano content increases over 15% causes decreased compressive strength and thus had negative effects on the rheological properties of the roller-compacted concrete. In terms of tensile strength of the cylindrical roller-compacted concrete samples, 2% of nano-calcium carbonate at the ages of 7, 28 and 90 days has been effective in increasing compressive strength in higher ages, such that at the ages of 7, 28 and 90 days, it has been increased by 25%, 30% and 30 % compared to the control sample, respectively. However, it can also be concluded that the excessive increase has partly reduced the tensile strength.
The variation of the permeability coefficient is a function of concrete porosity and water penetration in the roller-compacted concrete. Also, there are significant changes in the concrete permeability coefficient by adding different percentages of nano-calcium carbonate to concrete.
Adding nano-calcium carbonate up to 2% of cement weight to the roller-compacted concrete reduces the permeability coefficient of the roller-compacted concrete. One of the reasons for this phenomenon is capillary interstice filling in the roller-compacted concrete. Moreover, the nano-calcium carbonate increase of over 2% of cement weight raises the permeability of the roller-compacted concrete.
Adding 4% of nano-calcium carbonate to the roller-compacted concrete pattern increases the intensity of the peaks in the XRD test. Given that the average crystallite size is obtained from full&#160;width&#160;at&#160;half height of the&#160;peaks, by increasing the peaks&#8217; intensity and their width at&#160;half height of the&#160;peaks, we get smaller crystallite size. Also, by adding 4% of nano-calcium carbonate, the widths of the peaks are increased, which means smaller crystals and increased crystallite inner tension.
Conclusion
Nano-calcium carbonate, due to its special features, including a high specific surface area, has a good performance in improving the mechanical properties and durability of the roller-compacted concrete, if it is used at a certain and optimal amount. The roller-compacted concrete with the grade of 300 kg / m3 has better functionality than other mixtures, and lasted more in the 30 to 40 second range.
The mix design containing 2% of nano-calcium carbonate replacing cement, has the highest compressive strength at the age of 7 days and shows 4% increase in resistance compared to a control sample at the age of 7 days. The mix design containing 2% nano-calcium carbonate has the highest compressive strength at the age of 28 days and shows 12% increase in resistance compared to a control sample at this age and improved the compressive strength. The mix design containing 2% nano-calcium carbonate has the highest compressive strength at the age of 90 days and shows 15% increase in resistance compared to a control sample at this age. The mix design including 3% of nano-calcium carbonate replacing cement, has the highest tensile strength at the age of 7 days, and shows 25% increase in resistance compared to a control sample at the same age. The mix design containing 2% of nano-calcium carbonate replacing cement, has the highest tensile strength at the age of 28 days and shows 30% increase in resistance compared to a control sample at the same age. The mix design containing 2% of nano-calcium carbonate replacing cement, has the highest tensile strength at the age of 90 days and shows 30% increase in resistance compared to a control sample at the same age. ./files/site1/files/131/3Extended_Abstract.pdf
&#160;</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</JournalTitle>
<Issn>2228-6837</Issn>
<Volume>13</Volume>
<Issue>1</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2019</Year>
<Month>8</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Gully Erosion Hazard Zoning in the Gharnaveh Watershed, Golestan Province</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>69</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>94</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Kazem</FirstName>
	<LastName> Saber Chenari</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Abolareza</FirstName>
	<LastName> Bahremand1</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName> Vahed</FirstName>
	<LastName> Berdi Sheikh</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Chooghi</FirstName>
	<LastName> Bairam Komaki</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Introduction
One of the main problems in the Golestan province watersheds is the high degree of erosion and soil degradation, so that the equilibrium between the soil process and the soil erosion is unbalanced, and the erosion rate increases from west to east. Among these, the gully erosion and piping have the highest role. Gully is a canal or stream with the headcut with active erosion, sharpened slope and steep walls that results from the destruction of surface flow (usually during or after the occurrence of precipitation), dissolution movements, and small mass movements. The extent of gully in the eastern parts of Golestan province has caused the land degradation of arable land and landscape and has increased the conservation cost and etc. Because of connecting upstream areas of the basin to the downstream areas, gully has particular importance, which provides the possibility of sediment and pollutant transport, road destruction and financial losses to agricultural lands. In order to prevent and control the development of gully processes from a small scale to large one, it is a versatile utility to identify and extract the areas prone to gully erosion.
Due to the high intensity of gully erosion and its increasing growth in the Gharnaveh watershed, the Garnaveh River has an unstable status and severe eroded gully, and in some areas it has a great depth and vertical lateral walls, as well. Therefore, in this research, the watershed of Garnaveh was selected to prepare the risk areas of gully erosion.
The aim of this research is to determine Gully Erosion Hazard zoning using Frequency Ratio and Gupta &#38; Joshi methods (Gully Nominal Risk Factor-GNRF) in the Garnaveh watershed (Golestan province). Ultimately, the accuracy of the model has been evaluated using quality sum method and Kappa coefficient.
Material and methods
The study area is located in the northern part of Iran, Golestan province. The Garnaveh watershed with an area of about 78430 hectares lies between longitudes 370360 E and 414472 E, and latitudes of 4183819 N and 4155267 N (UTM Zone 40).
At first, gully erosion inventory map with the scale of 1:75,000 (dependent variable) for the Gharnaveh watershed has been prepared using multiple field surveys and satellite images. From total gullies, 70% have been selected randomly for building gully erosion hazard zoning model and the remaining ones (30%) have been used to validate the provided model.
In this research, seven data layers including slope percent, slope aspect, plan curvature, lithology formation, land use types, distance from rivers and distance from roads have been selected as gully erosion controlling factors (covariates/ independent variables) and then they have been digitized in ArcGIS software. The amount of Gully density of each factor class has been calculated from a combination of independent and dependent variables, and the rating of classes have done based on Frequency Ratio and Gully Nominal Risk Factor equations. Finally, the Gully erosion hazard zoning map has been drawn from the summation of weighting maps in ArcGIS. In this map, the value of each pixel is calculated by summing the weights of all the factors in that pixel. The pixel values are categorized based on the natural breaks classifier into very low, low, medium, high and very high hazard zones. Then, an accuracy of zoning map has been evaluated by quality sum method and Kappa coefficient.
Results and discussion
The result of affecting factors classification of the gullies shows that loess deposits formation, rangeland, areas with low distance from road and rivers, northwest aspect, low slope amplitude and concave slopes contain the most susceptibility to gullying. The results of frequency percent comparison of gullies in hazard classes show that from all gully zones in the validation step of the GNRF and frequency ratio models %74.52 and %78.11 of zones are located in the high and very high risk classes, respectively. The result of model validation using the quality sum method and a Kappa coefficient show that the frequency ratio model is a more appropriate model for gully erosion hazard zoning (with the quality sum and a Kappa coefficient of 3 and 0.89, respectively) than the GNRF model (having the quality sum and Kappa coefficient of 1.27 and 0.74, respectively).
Conclusion
In this research, the areas susceptible to gully erosion in the Gharnaveh watershed have been mapped with the frequency ratio and GNRF (for the first time) models. For this purpose, 7 affecting factors (independent variable) and 805 gully zones (dependent variable) were provided to measure the hazard maps of gully erosion. The following results are obtained from this study.
- The geology factors were identified as the most effective factors in the occurrence of gully erosion in the Gharnaveh watershed.
- Based on the gully erosion zoning hazard map of the Gharnaveh watershed, more than 70 percent of gullies are situated in the very high and high hazard classes.
- The produced gully erosion hazard map is useful for planners and engineers to reorganize the areas susceptible to gully erosion hazard, and offers appropriate methods for hazard reduction and management, as well../files/site1/files/131/4Extended_Abstract.pdf
&#160;</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</JournalTitle>
<Issn>2228-6837</Issn>
<Volume>13</Volume>
<Issue>1</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2019</Year>
<Month>8</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Geotechnical and Geological Information on the City of Sanandaj</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>95</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>122</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Behrooz</FirstName>
	<LastName> Samadian</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
	<LastName> Fakher</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Introduction
Geotechnical investigations merely through boring and engineering experiments are considered a difficult task as they are highly costly and time-consuming. The identification of large areas initially requires geological studies followed by the inclusion of geotechnical information. Finally, a geological and geotechnical classification is prepared for the entire area. This type of classifications is employed in strategic urban planning and quick selection of geotechnical variables in small-scale projects. The present research performed the steps involved in these investigations and classifications for the city of Sanandaj, Iran. Hence, the geological-geotechnical classification of the city of Sanandaj was presented by integrating the geological information of this city with the geotechnical data obtained from drilled boreholes as well as multiple wells at different locations in this city.
Materials and Methods
This study was conducted on the city of Sanandaj in six steps. The steps involved and their respective objectives are given in summary in Table 1.
Discussion
This study is applicable to those regions with insufficient information on their boreholes. The present study used only 211 boreholes, the distance
Table1. Steps involved in this study


	
		
			Objective or result
			Title
			Step
		
		
			Identifying the general geological characteristics
			General geological investigation of the considered region
			1
		
		
			Determining the rock units and soil layers as well as their outcrops and investigating their appearance
			Determining the appearance of the layers through field investigations
			2
		
		
			Determining the layer types and drawing the longitudinal and lateral profiles 
			Identifying subsurface layers
			3
		
		
			Determining the characteristics of geological units and their origin of emergence
			Geological classification based on the steps involved in formation of units
			4
		
		
			a)Collecting the available information, b) controlling the available information, c) completing the information
			Determining the geotechnical attributes of geological units
			5
		
		
			a) Presenting geological-geotechnical classification, b) presenting geological identification criteria to determine the type of a given unit at the site of the project
			Presenting a geological-geotechnical classification for the considered region
			6
		
	

between which was greater than 5 km in some areas of the Sanandaj city. Hence, although no sufficient information was available on many areas of Sanandaj, the proposed method in this study was able to identify the geotechnical attributes of all soil layers and rock units. This study emphasizes on geological and geotechnical classification and presents a step-by-step method to systematically relate geological and geotechnical studies. By integrating these classifications, geotechnical identification of extensive regions such as urban areas can be facilitated even if the number of boreholes is insufficient. Moreover, simple identification criteria can be extracted from this method, through which the engineering attributes of the layers at each point can be determined. This method can be used as an optimal and economical method for geotechnical identification of extensive areas.
Conclusion
The following summaries can be concluded from this study:
-The step-by-step procedure of integrating geological and geotechnical information was described, through which the geological-geotechnical classification for this city was obtained.
-The geological units identified for Sanandaj were shale, limestone, andesite, and Quaternary, which includes layers of alluvial clay, residual clay, and sand and gravel. The extent and distribution of each of the aforementioned units in Sanandaj were identified and plotted. Moreover, the physical and mechanical characteristics of each of the units as well as their geotechnical hazards were determined and presented.
-In this study, simple geotechnical criteria such as faults, altitude level, and distance from river were identified. These parameters were effective in identification of geological units in Sanandaj../files/site1/files/131/5Extended_Abstract.pdf
&#160;</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</JournalTitle>
<Issn>2228-6837</Issn>
<Volume>13</Volume>
<Issue>1</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2019</Year>
<Month>8</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Investigating the Effect of Survey Parameters on the Results of GPR Method Through forward Modeling and Field Studies</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>123</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>154</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hosein</FirstName>
	<LastName> Fereydooni</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Reza </FirstName>
	<LastName>Ahmadi2</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Introduction
Ground-penetrating radar (GPR) is a high-resolution geophysical method which uses electromagnetic waves with high-frequency in order to map structures and objects buried in subsurface without any destruction of the medium. In present research, choice of optimum parameters of real data acquisition for this method has been studied. The governed behavior on the GPR fields can be simulated by solving the Maxwell&#8217;s equations and the appropriate boundary conditions that form the basis of electromagnetic theory. Among the variety of available numerical methods, the finite-difference time-domain (FDTD) method has paid more attention due to having the simple understanding of the concepts, flexibility, simulation and modeling of complex environments and the acceptability of its responses in the applied cases. The purpose of this study is to identify what reasonable information can be obtained from field data under different environmental conditions and different survey parameters.
&#160;
Materials and methods
To achieve the goal, first forward modeling of GPR data has been carried out for several synthetic models corresponding to common targets in subsurface installations, using 2-D finite-difference time-domain method by means of GPRMAX, ReflexW and Radexplorer softwares. The main purpose of the simulations is investigation of the effect of survey parameters such as spatial sampling intervals (trace interspacing) and temporal sampling frequency on the GPR response of targets with various physical and geometrical parameters. Also to select and design the most appropriate conditions and survey parameters for real GPR data, numerous field traverses were performed in Isfahan University of Technology campus over the pre-known buried cylindrical targets containing power cable, petro-gas pipe, water pipeline and waste water pipeline with diverse host media. In this operation due to having one monostatic GPR system equipped by shielded antenna with central frequency of 250 MHz, some of the survey parameters containing central frequency, antenna separation and antenna directivity are invariant. The most important investigated survey parameters are temporal sampling frequency, spatial sampling distance (trace intervals), time window and number of stacked traces.
&#160;
Results and discussion
Regarding carried out investigations through field data acquisition, in only one case the GPR system failed to detect any understated targets which this mode is related to choice a sampling distance of 1 cm and a sampling frequency of 504 MHz. The sampling frequency of 504 MHz is just capable to detect the surface water pipeline (due to its low burial depth). Also only in three cases the GPR system is capable to detect all subsurface targets so that the first mode of the trace interval is 2 cm and the sampling frequency is 1954 MHz, whereas in the latter two, the trace interval is 1 cm and the sampling frequencies have been selected 1563 and 1954 MHz. At the end success or failure of the targets detection was investigated on the basis of selected survey parameters and the probability of successful target detection was determined depending on the temporal and spatial sampling frequency so that the maximum probability of target detection is regarding to temporal sampling frequency of 1954 MHz and trace interval of 1 cm. Regarding GPR field data acquisition, considering the relations between the central frequency of GPR measurement systems, the depth of penetration and resolution, the diversity of materials and various components of the host media of targets and their surface overburdens a range of dierse equipments with a variety of frequencies is needed, which all of them are not generally available.
&#160;
Conclusion
As a general conclusion of this study, in order to reduce the risk in GPR data acquisition operation, optimal survey parameters are suggested as follows:
The sampling frequency should be about 7 to 8 times the central frequency of the employed system (should not be less than this value in order to avoid aliasing and on the other hand, due to reduction in the amount of data and thus the memory needed for storage and processing), trace interspacing equal to 1 cm (in order to detect all buried targets especially targets with small size), the number of stacked traces equal to 16 (to reduce the amount of computer memory required for processing and storing data) and time window according to the computational-empirical relation (1).
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; (1)
Where W is time window, D is the maximum depth and V is the minimum velocity.
The results of this research are not restricted to the investigated case, but in practice are applicable for cases with similar host environments, especially in urban areas (which application of non-destructive methods such as GPR is necessary)../files/site1/files/131/6Extended_Abstract(1).pdf</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</JournalTitle>
<Issn>2228-6837</Issn>
<Volume>13</Volume>
<Issue>1</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2019</Year>
<Month>8</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Proposed Theoretical Equations for Estimating the Compressive and Tensile Strength of Unreinforced and Reinforced Soil and Soil-Cement</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>155</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>184</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammad</FirstName>
	<LastName> Moghadas</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName> Ali</FirstName>
	<LastName> Raeesi Estabragh</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Amin</FirstName>
	<LastName> Soltani</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Introduction
Improving the mechanical behavior of clay soil by stabilization agents is a mean of fulfilling geotechnical design criteria. The method of stabilization can be divided into chemical, mechanical, or a combination of both methods. Chemical stabilization is performed by adding chemical agents such as cement, lime or fly ash to the soil (Bahar et al., 2004). Soil reinforcement is one of the mechanical methods that is used for improving the behavior of soils (Tang et al., 2007). Reinforcement of soil achieved by either inclusion of strips, bars, grids and etc. within a soil mass in a preferred direction or mixing discrete fibers randomly with a soil mass.
Mixing of cement with soil is made a production that is called soil-cement and results in chemical reaction between soil, cement, and water. The compressive strength of soil-cement is increased by increasing the cement content and this leads to brittle behavior or sudden failure. On the other hand, by increasing the cement to soil ratio for cohesive soils, shrinkage micro-cracks may develop in the soil as a result of the loss of water content during drying or hydration of cement. Therefore, if the tensile strength of these materials is not sufficient cracks will develop under loading and damage will be resulted (Khattak and Alrashidi, 2006). Consoli et al. (2003) and Tang et al. (2007) indicated that adding the fiber to soil can prevent from occurrence of these cracks and increases the tensile strength of the soil.
The focus of this paper is on the statistical analysis of the results and development of regression models. Regression relationships are developed based on the experimental results that were presented by Estabragh et al. (2017). These relationships relate the compressive and tensile strengths of the soil to percent of used fiber, cement and curing time.
Material and methods of testing
Unconfined compression and tensile strength tests were carried on unreinforced and reinforced soil, soil cement according to ASTM standards. Samples of soil-cement were made by mixing a clay soil and two different weight percent of cement (8 and 10%). Reinforced soil samples were also prepared by mixing 0.5 and 1 weight percent of Polypropylene fibers with 10, 15, 20 and 25 mm lengths. The dry unit weight and water content of prepared samples were the same as optimum water content and maximum dry unit weight that were resulted from standard compaction test. The compressive and tensile strength tests were conducted on the samples by considering the curing time according to ASTM standards until the failure of the sample is achieved.
Results and discussion
The experimental tests showed that reinforcement of the soil and soil cement increase the peak compressive and tensile strength. The peak compressive strength of reinforced soil is increased by increasing the fiber content at a constant length of the fiber. It can be said that by increasing the percent of fiber, the number of fibers in the sample is increased and contact between soil particle and fibers is increased which result in increase in the strength (Maher 1994). However, by increasing the length of the constant fiber inclusion there will be no significant increase in strength because the number of shorter fiber is more than longer fiber in a specific sample (Ahmad et al., 2010). Inclusion of fibers can greatly increase the tensile strength of clay soil. In addition to reinforcement of soil cement showed the same trend. When fiber is added to soil cement, the surface of fiber adheres to the hydration products of cement and some clay particle. Therefore, this combination increases the efficiency of load transfer from the composition to the fibers which increase the peak strength (Tang et al., 2007). In addition, the tensile strength shows the same trend.
Based on the experimental data on the behavior of a randomly reinforced clay soil and soil cement multiple regression models (linear and non-linear) were developed for calculating the peak compressive and tensile strength (dependent variables) based on the value of the coefficient of determination (R2). The proposed regression models were functions of independent variables including weight percent of fiber, length of fiber (length/diameter of fiber), weight percent of cement, and curing time. Finally, the comparison is made between the predicted results from proposed models and experimental results. In order to investigate the model accuracy, the Root Mean Square Error (RMSE) and Normalized Root Mean Square Error (NRMSE) are used.
&#160;The Multiple Linear Regression models (MLR) was very suitable for the study of the effect of independent variables on the quantitative analytic dependent variable. The NRSME for peak compressive and tensile strength is was 3.59% and 5.11% respectively for these models. Also, the Multiple Nonlinear Regression models (MNLR) had a much lower error than the linear model because of the quadratic equation, the equation will be able to predict the increase and decrease of the output variable in terms of the increase of the independent input variable. Therefore, The NRMSE for peak compressive and tensile strength was 1.02% and 4.04% for MNLR models respectively.
Conclusion
The following conclusions can be drawn from this study:
- The strength of reinforced soil and soil cement is increased by increasing the fiber content.
- Increasing the length of the fibers in the soil and soil cement has no significant effect on increasing the peak compressive strength, but it will be effective in increasing the tensile strength.
- The Multiple Nonlinear Regression models (MNLR) have more accuracy for prediction of output variable (peak strength) because of lower normalized root mean square error../files/site1/files/131/7Extended_Abstract.pdf


&#160;</Abstract>


</Article>
</ArticleSet>
