<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1391</year>
	<month>1</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2012</year>
	<month>4</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>5</volume>
<number>2</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ارائه روش جدیدی برای برآورد مقاومت سنگ درزه دار با استفاده از ضریب درزه داری</title_fa>
	<title>Development of a New Method to Estimate Rock Strength Using Joint Factor</title>
	<subject_fa>ژئوتکنیک (مکانیک خاک و سنگ)</subject_fa>
	<subject>Geotecnic</subject>
	<content_type_fa>علمی پژوهشی</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>s</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>ناپیوستگی ها دارای ویژگی¬هایی همچون جهت یابی، تعداد دسته و فراوانی هستند که می¬توانند در مقاومت سنگ مؤثر واقع شوند. نمونه های سنگ به ترتیب دارای یک، دو و سه دسته ناپیوستگی متقاطع، فراوانی های مختلف و زاویه شیب صفحه ناپیوستگی ها با جهت افقی برابر با 0، 30، 45، 60 و 90 درجه آماده سازی شدند. با افزایش تعداد دسته ناپیوستگی و فراوانی آنها تعداد قطعات به صورت تصاعدی افزایش یافت. طوری که بخشی از نمونه های دارای سه دسته ناپیوستگی که یکی از دسته های آنها دارای چهار ناپیوستگی موازی بود از 20 قطعه سنگ تشکیل می شدند و مصداق سنگ به شدت درزه دار بودند. ضریب درزه داری و مقاومت فشاری یک محوری نمونه ها و زاویه اصطکاک در امتداد سطح درزه در برش مستقیم تعیین شدند. مقاومت فشاری یک محوری نمونه های دارای یک، دو و سه دسته ناپیوستگی در جهت افقی یا قائم کمتر از مقاومت نمونه سنگ سالم نشان داد. مقاومت یک محوری سنگ دارای ناپیوستگی به ویژه وقتی که جهت یافتگی 60 درجه نسبت حالت افقی بود، حدوداً به مقدار صفر نزدیک می شد. این شدت کاهش مقاومت برای نمونه های دارای دو و سه دسته ناپیوستگی متقاطع و عمود برهم در زاویه جهت یافتگی ناپیوستگی ها با حالت افقی برابر 30 درجه نیز اتفاق افتاد. تحلیل نتایج نشان داد که رابطه بین نسبت مقاومت فشاری یک محوری نمونه های درزه دار به مقاومت فشاری یک محوری سنگ سالم (ضریب ناهمسانگردی) و ضریب درزه داری (Jf) حاصل از این تحقیق با رابطه ارائه شده توسط رامامورتی دارای تفاوت قابل توجهی است. ویژگی های ناپیوستگی ها توأماً نقش اساسی در مقاومت توده سنگ دارند.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Discontinuities have properties such as orientation, number of set and frequency that can affect the rock strength. Rock specimens having one, two and three cross- sets of discontinuities, various frequencies and orientations of 0, 30, 45, 60 and 90 degrees were prepared. The numbers of rock pieces increased progressively with an increase of frequency and set of discontinuities. As specimens having three sets of discontinuities that one of their sets had four number of parallel discontinuities were consisted 20 rock pieces and they represented jointed rock mass. Joint factor, uniaxial compressive strength and friction angle along the discontinuity surface in direct shear were determined. The uniaxial compressive strength of specimens having one, two and three sets of discontinuities in horizontal and vertical direction was less than the uniaxial compressive strength of intact rock. The uniaxial compressive strength of specimens approached approximately to zero value particularly when the orientation of discontinuities was 60 degrees. This considerable decrease of strength was occurred also for specimens having two and three sets of discontinuities at orientation of 30 degrees. The analysis of results showed that the relationship between ratio of uniaxial compressive strength of jointed specimens to the uniaxial compressive strength of intact rock specimens (anisotropy factor) and joint factor of this research is considerably different with the suggested relationship by Ramamurthy. Properties of discontinuities have altogether essential role on the strength of rock mass.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>تعداد دسته ناپیوستگی , مقاومت , ناهمسانگردی , ضریب درزه داری , </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>discontinuity set , strength , anisotropy , joint factor ,</keyword>
	<start_page>1313</start_page>
	<end_page>1326</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-162-2&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Hassan</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Moomivand</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حسن</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مومیوند</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>h.moomivand@urmia.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600289</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600289</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Urmia University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>استادیار دانشگاه ارومیه</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mir Ali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Moomivand</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>میرعلی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>محمدی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>m.ahmadi@urmia.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600290</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600290</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Urmia University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشیار دانشگاه ارومیه</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
