<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1389</year>
	<month>1</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2010</year>
	<month>4</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>3</volume>
<number>2</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>اثر محلول نمک بر مشخصات لایه پوششی مراکز دفن مواد زائد</title_fa>
	<title>Effect of Salt Solutions on Landfill Clay Liners</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>مراکز دفن مواد زائد به منظور جداسازی زباله دفن شده از محیط اطراف و آب‌های زیرزمینی طراحی می‌شوند. پوششی که در کف مراکز دفن قرار می‌گیرد، از اهمیت زیادی برخوردار است چرا که از انتقال آلودگی به آب‌های زیرزمینی جلوگیری می‌کند. پوشش کف می‌تواند مخلوطی از خاک محل و بنتونیت باشد. در این پژوهش به بررسی اثر دو نمک NaCl و MgCl2 در چندین غلظت بر روی مشخصات مخلوط خاک محل- بنتونیت در دو نسبت 100:10 و 100:20 (10 و 20 درصد وزنی بنتونیت و 100 درصد وزنی کل مخلوط خاک) پرداخته شده است. آزمایش‌های انجام گرفته شامل آزمایش تحکیم یک بعدی به منظور تعیین نفوذپذیری و فشردگی مخلوط‌های خاک، آزمایش تعیین حدود آتربرگ و آزمایش تورم آزاد است. نتایج نشان می‌دهد که نوع نمک و غلظت آن بر مشخصات مخلوط خاک مؤثر است. مقایسه محلول‌های نمک نشان می‌دهد که کاتیون‌های دوظرفیتی نسبت به کاتیون‌های تک ظرفیتی بر روی هدایت هیدرولیکی مخلوط اثر بیش‌تری دارند. مقایسه اثر غلظت‌های مختلف نمک در یک نوع نمک بر روی مخلوط خاک مشخص، بیان‌گر این است که با کاهش غلظت نمک، هدایت هیدرولیکی کاهش می‌یابد. این پدیده بر اساس تئوری لایه دوگانه پخشیده قابل توجیه است.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>(Paper pages 677-696) Engineered waste landfills separate the buried waste from the groundwater system and the above ground environment during and after the operational periods of the disposal facility. Liners of these landfills are of great import-anttce as they play a crucial role in minimizing pollutant migration and therefore preventing ground water contamination. Liners may consist of a locally available soil and bentonite mixtures. In this study effect of NaCl and MgCl2 solutions of various concentrations has been investigated.The mixtures were prepared with a local clay specimen from Varamin and a proportion of bentonite content of 10 % and 20 % of total dry weight. Laboratory tests including 1D consolidation for determining permeability and compressibility of the soil mixtures, liquid limit and free swell tests were carried out. Results indicated that both solution type and its concentration affect the properties of the mixtures. Comparison of hydraulic conductivity of different salt solutions shows that the divalent cations have more effect than monovalent cations. Comparison of different salt concentrations for a particular salt on a particular soil mixture shows that the hydraulic conductivity decreases with decreasing salt concentration. This decrease can be attributed to an increase in diffuse double layer thickness.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>اثر غلظت‌های مختلف نمک در یک نوع نمک بر روی مخلوط ,</keyword_fa>
	<keyword></keyword>
	<start_page>677</start_page>
	<end_page>696</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-3-35&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
