<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <ArticleSet>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2228-6837</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>10</Volume>
			<Issue>1</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>8</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Assessment of the GAP-SENSOR Use for Measuring Maximum Shear Modulus in Layered sandy and Gravelly Dacite Materials</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>3227</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>3244</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>aghaeiaraei@bhrc.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.1.3227</DOI>
	<Abstract>Among dynamic parameters, the maximum shear modulus and damping ratio of the materials has the great importance in the dynamic analyses. In this paper, the high frequency GAP-SENSORs (20 kHz) is used to measure shear wave velocity of the sandy and gravelly Dacite materials in the cyclic triaxial equipment. The test procedure is as follows: firstly, a weak impact on the top cap triaxial specimen is induced. The induced low horizontal and vertical displacements time histories (strain in the range 10-6) are recorded using data logger with rate of 100,000 samples per secent for each channel. Then by traveling time and distance between two GAP-SENSORs, wave velocity is measured. Finally, by calculating the poison ratio via horizontal and vertical strains, the maximum shear modulus of the material is calculated. The results indicate that the value of wave velocity is increased by increasing confining pressure, and their values are dependent on particle size. Also, using the reduced vibration amplitude technique at different levels of specimen, damping ratio value is calculated by temping method. By comparing the results of shear modulus and damping ratio using local measurement of axial strain (with GAP-SENSORs in the cyclic triaxial) at small strain level with the results of the proposed method, cofirmed the high precision of the innovative used method.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>GAP-SENSOR , Maximum shear modulus , damping ratio , Dacite , </Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2163-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2163-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2228-6837</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>10</Volume>
			<Issue>1</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>8</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Investigation on the effect of sedimentary basin on engineering properties of soils of Kerman city based on resistance behavior</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>3245</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>3270</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>ab.aminizadeh@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>imaneng189@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Gholam</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Lashkaripour</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>lashkaripour@um.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>ghafoori@um.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.1.3245</DOI>
	<Abstract>Kerman city and its surrounding towns in terms of morphology, consist of a flat alluvial plain of fine silt and clay materials. These sediments have very gentle slope, and constitute the city's main infrastructure. Natural soils generally are structured by passing times due to the influence of environmental factors. Geological factors in Kerman alluviums have caused fine structure after deposition. This paper studies briefly sedimentary basin Kerman, mineralogical and geotechnical properties of the sediments of these areas.semi-qualitative analysis of samples has shown that the mineral deposits in Kerman are mainly illite, chlorite, smectite and calcite. then In order to evaluate the effect of depositional environments and geological history of the engineering properties of the sediments of the Kerman city, A large number of triaxial tests on reconstituted soil moisture greater than LL and different confining pressures, consolidated drained and consolidated undrained is done . In order to evaluate the applicability of soil behavior in normal conditions and the reconstructed curves and stress - strain sensitive soils and soil structure compared with standard sensitivity and then their resistance have been investigated. The results of triaxial tests can be used to interpret the depositional environments and geological history. Comparing the curves of stress - strain in natural and reconstituted samples indicates that in many cases the behavior of intact and reconstituted soils were similar and cementation and soil structure have not been much development. Also Comparison of electron microscopy images of reconstituted and intact samples, not random arrangement of particular structure and soil compaction within the city limits have confirmed. therefore, soils of Kerman are relatively similar by the influence of depositional environments and geological history. these soils have a lot of structure and cementation and are generally compact and strengthening.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Sedimentary basin , Fine-grained soils , Kerman ,</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2141-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2141-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2228-6837</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>10</Volume>
			<Issue>1</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>8</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Development of a new method for estimating strength of rock blocks using non-destructive ultrasonic wave</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>3271</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>3286</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>dariush.miner@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hassan</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Moomivand</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Assistant Professor of Urmia University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>h.moomivand@urmia.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>babaei@sut.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.1.3271</DOI>
	<Abstract>Non-destructive methods such as ultrasonic wave velocity are extensively used for estimating physical and mechanical properties of rock due to the simplicity, economical, fast and harmless nature. Rock constructions have been made worldwide from past to present. Determination of strength of rock constructions such as archeological evidence is not possible using conventional rock strength tests. Developing a cheap, simple, non-destructive, efficient and accurate method to estimate the strength of such constructions can be useful. Rock blocks and constructions have various shapes and sizes. Rock blocks having various shapes and sizes have been prepared from marble, travertine, granite, and limestone and ultrasonic wave velocity at various directions of the blocks dimensions and the uniaxial compressive strength of cylindrical core obtained from the blocks have been measured. The results show that shapes and sizes have no effect on the ultrasonic wave velocity. At the end relationships between uniaxial compressive strength and ultrasonic wave velocity have been determined. The uniaxial compressive strength of blocks and rock constructions can be estimated by the obtained relationships using non-destructive, simple and indeed low cost method of ultrasonic wave velocity.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>ultrasonic wave , shape and size , strength , rock blocks ,</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2143-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2143-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2228-6837</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>10</Volume>
			<Issue>1</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>8</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Application of probability analysis in assessing optimal depth of 2nd line of Mashhad city subway.</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>3287</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>3308</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>khanlari_reza@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohamad</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Ghafoori</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>ghafoori@um.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Javad</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Ahmadzadeh</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>ahmadzadeh.javad@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Salameh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Afshar</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>salameh_1984@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.1.3287</DOI>
	<Abstract>In tunnelling in soil mass, in groundwater existing mode, liquefaction, elastic displacements and settlement in soils upon the tunnel, are the risks may attack the excavated underground space stability. In this case study that were performed on second line of Mashhad city subway route, information catched from Standard Penetration Test, in situ and laboratorial tests, were used to optimum numerical values search for soil engineering parameters that could optimize the TBM stationing level. In order to this goal attaining, intelligent, numerical and probabilistic methods were used and the reliability of intelligent and numerical methods with the Safety Factors of tunnel stability, investigated simultaneously. The results were denoting the accordance of intelligent models such as Genetic Algorithm (GA) and Multi objective Genetic Algorithm with Finite Element model's output. So these models could be complement of each others in planning and designing of tunnels and using of them advised in tunneling and excavations.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Soil settlement , Liquefaction , Elastic displacement , Safety Factor (SF) , Probability analysis , </Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1888-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1888-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2228-6837</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>10</Volume>
			<Issue>1</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>8</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Effect of delay time on In Situ Stress Determination by Acoustic Emission</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>3309</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>3324</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>khosravi.em@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>moahmadi@modares.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.1.3309</DOI>
	<Abstract>The in-situ stress is one of the most important parameters in the design of underground structures. Conventional methods such as in-situ stress measurements using hydraulic fracturing method has two main disadvantages are time and cost of this methods. Acoustic emission is one of the indirect in-Situ stress measurement methods which is based on the theory of the Kaiser effect. When a rock is stressed, it release acoustic signals this phenomenon is called acoustic emission. Kaiser Effect is defined as lack of acoustic signals in the lower stress levels than the previous maximum stress level. In other words, as long as rock is not reached to the previous maximum stress level, do not show significant acoustic emission. Several factors affect on Kaiser Effect such as delay time, temperature, rock fabric, porosity, discontinuities, joints and geological structure. In this paper, effect of the delay time on Kaiser Effect has been presented. The time between coring operations and acoustic emission test is called delay time. The limestone rock is selected as main samples of test and after preloading, reloading and acoustic emission test were carried out with different delay times. The results showed that the felicity ratio is less than 1, when delay time is about 20 days and after three months has increased to be more than one.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>in-situ stress measurement , Acoustic Emission , Kaiser Effect , Delay Time , Powerhouse cavern , </Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2196-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2196-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2228-6837</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>10</Volume>
			<Issue>1</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>8</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Investigating the effect of the statistical distribution function of the GSI on the probabilistic analysis of rock mass geomechanical parameters</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>3325</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>3350</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>kariminasab@uk.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mojtaba</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Rabiei Vaziri</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>mojtabavaziri@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hamidreza</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Mohammadi Azizabadi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>hamid_azizabadi@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.1.3325</DOI>
	<Abstract>Hoek and Brown suggested a method to estimate the strength and deformation modulus parameters of rock masses. The method was then widely used in rock engineering designs. In such designs, the mean values of Hoek and Brown parameters are often used which are not proper values due to the variability of rock mass properties within a great range of values. In such cases, probability analysis of rock mass properties is highly important. The geological strength index is one of the most important parameters in Hoek and Brown equations. Determination of this parameter includes greater uncertainties than determining other parameters. In this paper, based on the results of rock mechanical tests carried out on rock samples of Gol-Gohar iron ore mine, and the required field surveys, the sensitivity of rock mass geomechanical properties on the type of the statistical distribution function of the geological strength index in statistical analysis of these parameters using Monte Carlo simulation method was investigated. The results showed that the sensitivity of Hoek and Brown equations to determine different rock mass geomechanical parameters varies as the type of the statistical distribution function of the geological strength index changes. The sensitivity of geomechanical parameters such as internal friction angle, cohesion, total strength and rock mass modulus on the type of the statistical distribution function of the geological strength index is much less than parameters such as uniaxial compressive strength and tension strength of rock mass. The greatest variations based on changes of the type of the statistical distribution function of the geological strength index are less than 5% for the internal friction angle, cohesion and total strength, less than 10% for the modulus, and less than 25% for the uniaxial compressive strength and tension strength.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>rock mass properties , GSI , Monte Carlo simulation , Gol-Gohar mine No. 1 , Hoek and Brown failure criteria , </Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2164-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2164-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Engineering Geology</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2228-6837</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>10</Volume>
			<Issue>1</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>8</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The Assessment of Salt Weathering and Freeze-thaw Effect on Strength and Durability of Upper Red Formation Sandstones</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>3351</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>3378</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>mh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>ghobadi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>amirghobadi@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>r</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Babazadeh</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.1.3351</DOI>
	<Abstract>Strength and durability of sandstones and their influences from natural conditions, are the most important factors which should be considered as engineering materials. In this study, the effect of freeze-thaw and salt crystallization phenomena on strength and durability of upper red formation sandstones collected from southern part of Qazvin province was investigated. Nine specimens of sandstones (specified by A, B, C, CG, S, S1, Tr, Min and Sh) were collected from different part of studied area, then their physical and mechanical characteristics were determined. In order to assessing the effect of freeze-thaw on physical and mechanical characteristics of sandstones, 60 cycles of freeze-thaw test was performed. Also in order to investigate the effect of salt crystallization on strength of studied sandstone, sodium sulphate crystallization test (100% weight solution of Na2SO4) was carried out in 20 cycles. Physical and mechanical characteristics of sandstones such as point load index, Brazilian tensile strength, wave velocity (Vp) and weight loss were computed after different cycles. To evaluate the effect of freeze-thaw and salt crystallization phenomena on durability of sandstones, slake durability test was conducted on specimens subjected to mentioned processes and changes occurred in slake durability index in 15 cycles were investigated. Based on results obtained from current study, it could be concluded that in comparison to freeze-thaw, salt crystallization can considerably reduce the strength and durability of sandstones and deteriorate them. Also it was found that index tests such as point load index, Brazilian tensile strength, wave velocity (Vp) and weight loss can predict the behavior of sandstones in different cycles of freeze-thaw and salt crystallization tests.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Sandstone, Upper Red Formation, Freeze-thaw, Salt weathering, Durability.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2663-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2663-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
 </ArticleSet>
 
  
  
  
  
 