<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1394</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2015</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>9</volume>
<number>2</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>en</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>شاخص آلودگی مخاطره آمیز، راه‌کاری یک‌پارچه به‌سوی تعیین مخاطره آلودگی فلزی در رسوبات</title_fa>
	<title>Risky Pollution Index: An Integrated Approach Towards Determination of Metallic Pollution Risk in Sediments</title>
	<subject_fa>مهندسی محیط زیست</subject_fa>
	<subject>En. Ecosystem</subject>
	<content_type_fa>مقاله استخراج شده از پایان نامه</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research Paper</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p&gt;بر خلاف شاخص&#8204;های فاکتور جابه&#8204;جایی MF و کد ارزیابی ریسک RAC که آن&#8204;ها نیز نقش پیوندهای فلزی را در تفسیر آلودگی لحاظ می&#8204;کنند، در شاخص جدید مستقیماً سهمی از مخاطره به فازهای احیا شونده و اکسید شونده داده شده است که این مسئله در هیچ یک از دو شاخص مذکور دیده نشده است. به&#8204;بیان دیگر در شاخص جدید پیوندهای فلزی که به&#8204;شکل بالقوه قابلیت رهاسازی فلز در محیط را دارند نیز با تخصیص وزن&#8204;های جداگانه در تفسیر مخاطره آلودگی موجود دخالت دارند. این مشخصه شاخص جدید امکان تفسیر واقعی آلودگی موجود فلزی به&#8204;ویژه هنگامی که بخش چشم&#8204;گیری از غلظت همۀ فلز در فازهای احیا شونده و اکسیدشونده جمع شده است را ممکن می&#8204;سازد. وابستگی نبودن سطح مخاطره به غلظت کل در شاخص جدید سبب می&#8204;شود تفسیری از مخاطره در سطوح مختلف غلظت کل ارائه شود. علاوه بر این توانایی شاخص در تفسیر مخاطره آلودگی فلزی فارغ از منبع تولید اعم از انسان&#8204;ساخت و طبیعی نداشتن قطعیت&#8204;های ناشی از تفکیک این دو نوع آلودگی را نیز کاهش می&#8204;دهد.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>In contrast with Mobility Factor (MF) and Risk Assessment Code (RAC) indices, I&lt;sub&gt;R&lt;/sub&gt; attributes a risk share to metal species bound to reducible and oxidizable phases which are totally neglected in both of the two above-mentioned indices. In other words, besides the absolutely mobile fractions, the potentially mobile ones are also regarded in risk evaluation process elaborated by I&lt;sub&gt;R&lt;/sub&gt;. The different structure of the newly-developed index may prevent risk level underestimation especially in case where a remarkable percent of bulk concentration is accumulated within reducible and oxidizable phases. The independency of the index value to the bulk concentration makes it possible to discuss the potential risk in different levels of bulk concentration. Furthermore, the index capability in indication of risky pollution, regardless of the pollution source type, may prevent the probable misleading caused by distinct separation of bulk concentration into geopogenic and anthropogenic portion</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>شاخص آلودگی مخاطره آمیز IR , رسوب , فلز , استخراج متوالی ,</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Bioavailability , Risky pollution index (IR) , sediment , metal , sequential extraction , </keyword>
	<start_page>2841</start_page>
	<end_page>2868</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-697-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>T</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Nasrabadi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>تورج</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نصرآبادی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>tnasrabadi@gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001140</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001140</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده محیط زیست دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
