<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1392</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>7</volume>
<number>2</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تخمین پارامترهای مقاومت برشی زه‌کشی شده خاک‌های ریزدانه جنوب تهران با استفاده از مدل رگرسیون غیرخطی</title_fa>
	<title>Estimation of the drained shear strength parameters of fine grained soil of southern Tehran using nonlinear regression model</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa>علمی پژوهشی</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>s</content_type>
	<abstract_fa> همواره تعیین دقیق پارامترهای مقاومت برشی خاک‌های ریزدانه با مشکلاتی همراه است. از مهم‌ترین این مشکلات، تهیۀ نمونه دست‌نخورده با کیفیت مناسب برای انجام آزمایش به‌منظور تعیین پارامترهای مکانیکی خاک است. به‌همین سبب، محققان مختلفی در طی چند دهه گذشته سعی کرده‌اند تا با ایجاد ارتباطی بین پارامترهای مقاومتی با خصوصیات فیزیکی خاک‌ها در یک منطقه مشخص، امکان تخمین پارامترهای مقاومتی را بر اساس خصوصیات فیزیکی خاک‌ها فراهم کنند. هدف از تحقیق حاضر تخمین پارامترهای مقاومتی منطقه‌ای وسیع با خاک‌های آبرفتی ریزدانه در جنوب شهر تهران است. این تخمین بر مبنای تحلیل آماری داده‌های گردآوری شده از این منطقه صورت پذیرفته است. بر این اساس، ابتدا اطلاعات ژئوتکنیکی شامل پارامترهای فیزیکی و مقاومتی 294  گمانه حفر شده در این منطقه گردآوری شده است. سپس این داده‌ها به‌طور مستقل از لحاظ آماری تجزیه و تحلیل شدند و بر اساس این تحلیل‌ها، برآوردی از پارامترهای ژئوتکنیکی خاک‌ها در اعماق مختلف و با سطح اطمینان قابل قبول ارائه گردیده است. علاوه بر تجزیه و تحلیل مستقل داده‌ها، بر پایۀ داده‌های گردآوری شده از این گمانه‌ها، مدل رگرسیونی غیرخطی برای تخمین پارامترهای مقاومت برشی برحسب خصوصیات فیزیکی شاخص خاک‌های ریزدانه (درصد رطوبت و شاخص خمیری) ارائه گردیده است. مدل ارائه شده با دقت قابل قبولی قادر به پیش‌بینی پارامترهای مقاومت برشی زهکشی شده خاک منطقۀ پژوهش و سایر مناطق  مشابه است</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Determining the precise shear strength parameters of the fine grained soils is always a difficult task. In order to conduct the shear strength tests and determine the mechanical parameters of the soil, achieving an untreated high quality sample is a problem with a high degree of importance. Therefore, during the recent decades many researchers have attempted to provide relations between strength parameters and soil physical characteristics in a specific structure and so to provide the possibility of estimating the strength parameters based on these characteristics. The aim of this research is to estimate the shear strength parameters of a wide region of fine grained alluvial soil located in southern Tehran, Iran. In this regard, the geotechnical data including physical and shear strength parameters of 294 boreholes were firstly collected from the site. Then, the obtained data were statistically and independently analyzed. Based on the results of analyzes, the soil geotechnical parameters were presented for various depths with an acceptable level of reliability. Moreover, they were considered as a basis for providing a nonlinear regression model to estimate the soil shear strength parameters and based on the index physical characteristics of the fine grained soil (water content and plasticity index). The developed model is capable to predict the soil drained shear strength parameters and also other similar soil properties with a very good accuracy</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>آبرفت ریزدانه , مقاومت برشی زهکشی شده , تحلیل آماری , مدل رگرسیون غیر خطی , </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Fine grained alluvium , Drained shear strength , Statistical analysis , Nonlinear regression model , </keyword>
	<start_page>1869</start_page>
	<end_page>1900</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-106-22&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>A</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ghorbani</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>قربانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>ghorbani@guilan.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600330</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600330</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه گیلان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>F</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Kalantari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>فرزین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کلانتری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>fz_kalantary@knt.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600331</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600331</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه صنعتی خواجه نصیرالدین طوسی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>M</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Zohori</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مازیار</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>ظهوری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>mz-geotechnical@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600332</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600332</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه گیلان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
