<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1393</year>
	<month>8</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>11</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>8</volume>
<number>2</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>معرفی دستگاه دوام بزرگ مقیاس و کارایی آن برای ارزیابی دوام سنگ های سخت</title_fa>
	<title>Introduction of large-scale durability device and its applicability for evaluating hard rocks durability</title>
	<subject_fa>زمین شناسی مهندسی</subject_fa>
	<subject>En. Geology</subject>
	<content_type_fa>علمی پژوهشی</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>s</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>یکی از مهمترین مسائل مرتبط در طراحی و اجرای سازه¬های مهندسی، ارزیابی و بررسی دوام آن¬ها در مقابل فرآیند سایش و تر و خشک شدن¬های متوالی است. با توجه به این که دوام عبارت است از مقاومت سنگ در برابر هوازدگی فیزیکی و شیمیایی، حفظ شکل، اندازه و وضیعت ظاهری اولیه در یک مدت زمان طولانی و در شرایط محیطی حاکم بر سنگ، ارزیابی و بررسی آن دارای اهمیت زیادی می باشد. از آنجایی که دستگاه آزمایش دوام استاندارد برای ارزیابی و بررسی دوام سنگ¬های آرژیلیتی و نرم طراحی شده است در نتیجه، ضروری به نظر می¬رسد دستگاه دوامی طراحی شود که بتواند برای ارزیابی دوام سنگ¬های سخت کارایی لازم را داشته باشد. بدین منظور، با تلاش محققین گروه زمین¬شناسی مهندسی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس تهران، دستگاه دوامی تحت عنوان &quot;دستگاه دوام بزرگ مقیاس&quot; طراحی و ساخته شد. طول و قطر این دستگاه به ترتیب 6 و 3/4 برابر دستگاه دوام استاندارد طراحی شده توسط [1] است و در هرآزمایش به ده نمونه با وزن 400 تا 600 گرم نیاز دارد. برای بررسی کارایی این دستگاه در ارزیابی دوام سنگ¬های سخت، 17 نمونه سنگ با منشا آذرین، رسوبی، دگرگونی و آذر آواری تهیه و ویژگی¬های کانی¬شناسی، فیزیکی و مکانیکی آن¬ها بررسی شد. در ادامه آزمایش¬های دوام استاندارد و بزرگ مقیاس تا 15 چرخه انجام شد و داده¬های بدست آمده مورد تجزیه و تحلیل قرار گرفت. نتایج نشان می¬دهد دستگاه دوام بزرگ مقیاس کارایی بیشتر و مناسبتری نسبت به دستگاه دوام استاندارد در ارزیابی دوام سنگ¬های سخت دارد.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>One of the most important issues in the design and implementation of engineering structures is to evaluate and investigate their durability against processes of consecutive wear, wet and dry. The durability of rock is resistance against chemical and physical weathering, the shape, size and status of the initial appearance in a long time and environmental conditions prevailing in the rock, hence it is important to evaluate the durability of rock. Since the device of standard durability (Franklin &amp; Chandra, 1972) designed to evaluate and investigate durability of soft and argillites rocks. So, appears to be essential to design a durability device, which can evaluate hard rocks. For this purpose, Researchers of the Department of Geological Engineering, Tarbiat Modares University, durability device as &quot;large-scale durability device &quot; was designed and built which the length and diameter of the device, is 6 and 4.3 times standard durability device, respectively, and needs 10 samples with weight of 400 to 600 g. In order to investigation the applicability of this device for hard rocks durability, we selected 17 building rocks samples of the igneous, sedimentary, metamorphic and pyroclastic rocks. Then their mineralogical, physical and mechanical properties were investigated. More, experiments of standard and large-scale durability up to 15 cycles were performed and data obtained were analyzed. The results show that, the large-scale durability device than standard durability, have more applicability for evaluating the durability of hard rocks.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>   دوام , دوام بزرگ مقیاس , دوام استاندارد , سنگ‌های سخت ,</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Durability , Large-scale durability , Standard durability , Hard rock , </keyword>
	<start_page>2199</start_page>
	<end_page>2222</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-106-19&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>MR</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>nikudel</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمدرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نیکودل</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>nikudelm@modares.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600303</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600303</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>H</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Bahramkhani</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حبیب الله</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بهرامخانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>h.bahramkhani@gmail.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600304</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600304</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>M</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Khamech</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ماشالله</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>خامه چیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>khamechm@modares.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600305</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600305</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>A</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Jamshidi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>امین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>جمشیدی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>jamshidi.geo85@yahoo.coئ</email>
	<code>1003194753284600306</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600306</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
