<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1392</year>
	<month>1</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2013</year>
	<month>4</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>6</volume>
<number>2</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تأثیر تغییرات بازۀ تناوب مبنای تطبیق بر فرآیند مقیاس جنبش نیرومند زمین</title_fa>
	<title>Effect of Matching Period-Interval Variation on Strong Ground Motion Scaling</title>
	<subject_fa>ژئوفیزیک مهندسی</subject_fa>
	<subject>En. Geophisic</subject>
	<content_type_fa>علمی پژوهشی</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>s</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>تحلیل‌ تاریخچۀ زمانی به‌عنوان ابزاری مهم در کاربردهای متنوع مهندسی زلزله به‌شدت به مشخصات نگاشت زلزلۀ اعمالی وابسته‌اند چنان‌که نتایج آن‌ها مورد به مورد دست‌خوش تغییر می‌شود. مقیاس کردن جنبش نیرومند زمین به‌عنوان راه‌کاری آیین‌نامه‌ای برای کاهش چنین وابستگی و افزایش قابلیت اطمینان تحلیل‌های مذکور شناخته شده است. اما روش متداول با کاربرد ضرایب یک‌نواخت مقیاس می‌تواند به طرح‌های غیراقتصادی به‌دلیل خطای زیاد تطبیق منجرشود. در این پژوهش مسئلۀ اخیر در قالب بهینه‌یابی با ضرایب پیوسته مقیاس رابطه‌بندی شده و روش فراابتکاری جستجوی هماهنگی برای حل مثال‌های آن به‌کار رفته، سپس خطای تطبیق نسبت به طیف هدف استاندارد با تغییرات بازۀ تناوبی به‌طور منحصر به‌فرد توسط بهینه‌یابی ارزیابی گردیده است. علاوه بر مشاهدۀ کاهش چشم‌گیر خطا طی این بهینه‌یابی، اثر تناوب مبنا و بازه‌های تناوبی مختلف بررسی شد که نتایج حاکی از وابستگی خطا به کشیدگی و تغییرات بازۀ مذکور و یا تناوب مبنا است. هم‌چنین در مثال‌های بررسی شده با نگاشت‌های فیلتر شده در عبور از بستر نرم آبرفتی تغییرات چشم‌گیری در خطای تطبیق طیفی مشاهده شد.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;span&gt;Time history analyses as crucial means in many earthquake engineering applications are highly dependent to characteristics of the seismic excitation record so that the resulting responses may vary from case to case. Strong ground motion scaling is a known codified solution to reduce such a dependency and increase reliability of time history analyses. The well-known code practice may result in highly non-economic designs due to considerable error in the spectra scaled to match the target code spectrum. This problem is formulated here in an optimization framework with the scaling coefficients as the design variables. Harmony search as a recent meta-heuristic algorithm is utilized to solve the problem and is applied to the treated examples. Using a variety of target period ranges the scaling error is evaluated and studied after more unified via optimization. The effect of base structural period and interval variation on the scaling error is then studied in addition to considerable error decrease with respect to traditional code-based procedure. The results also show dependency of spectral matching error to the period-interval elongation/variation, the base-structural period and more error sensitivity for narrow-band resonance with the filtered records on softer soil types&lt;/span&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>جنبش نیرومند زمین , تطبیق طیفی بهینه , بازه تناوبی تطبیق , جستجوی هماهنگی , </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Strong Ground Motion , Optimal Spectral Scaling , Matching Period Interval , Harmony Search , </keyword>
	<start_page>1577</start_page>
	<end_page>1600</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-115-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Peyman</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Derakhshani</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>پیمان</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>درخشانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Peyman_shiny@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600324</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600324</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشجوی دانشکده فنی دانشگاه (خوارزمی)</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mohsen</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Shahrozi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محسن</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>شهروزی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>shahruzi@khu.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600325</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600325</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>عضو هیات علمی دانشکده فنی دانشگاه خوارزمی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
