<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" 

"journalpublishing3.dtd">

<article 
article-type="research-article"
dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en" 
xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
>

<front>

<journal-meta>

  <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher">1</journal-id>
  <issn>2228-6837</issn>

  <publisher>

	<publisher-name>Kharazmi University</publisher-name>
  </publisher>

</journal-meta>



<article-meta>

  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2045</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject></subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>E.C</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>3</month>

	<year>2015</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>8</volume>

  <issue>4</issue>

  <fpage>1</fpage>

  <lpage>4</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>


</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2044</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject></subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>P.C</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>3</month>

	<year>2015</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>8</volume>

  <issue>4</issue>

  <fpage>1</fpage>

  <lpage>8</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>


</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">427</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Geotecnic</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Evaluation of Earthquake Waves Amplification Due to Trapezoidal Hill by 1D and 2D Time Domain Analysis</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>shareghi</surname>
		<given-names>arash</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic>b</italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Amelmelsak</surname>
		<given-names>m</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Sohrabi Bidar</surname>
		<given-names>A</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic>b</italic>

	</sup>urmia university 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>3</month>

	<year>2015</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>8</volume>

  <issue>4</issue>

  <fpage>2389</fpage>

  <lpage>2412</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Evaluation of strong ground motion up beneath the construction is important in both geotechnical engineering (site effect) and earthquake engineering aspects (analysis of earth behavior). The common methods of microzonation in geotechnical engineering are based on one dimensional dynamic analysis, in which ground surface is assumed to be horizontal. However in many cases, because of variety of topography conditions, recorded responses are different on the top of hills and their corners. In this study, FLAC 2D software, as finite difference software, is used to analysis the trapezoidal hill with different shape ratios. These topography models are analyzed by far field earthquake records, and their dimensionless amplification ratios are compared with the obtained results of one dimensional analysis. Assessment of these two analyses methods in some points on the topography and around it, demonstrated considerable differences that show the necessity of two dimensional analysis in earthquake geotechnical engineering.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">425</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>En. Geology</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Geotechnical Properties Assessment of Subsurface Dams (Case Study)</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Ajalloeyan</surname>
		<given-names>Rasol</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>safary</surname>
		<given-names>azat</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>3</month>

	<year>2015</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>8</volume>

  <issue>4</issue>

  <fpage>2413</fpage>

  <lpage>2434</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Subsurface dams is accordant with nature structure which is useful for water resources management, especially for preventing unused underground water. Regarding to reservoir alluvium, geological and geotechnical characteristics of this type of dam is important. Therefore, in present study, characteristics of the underground reservoir alluvium in Mastbandy area (South of Ardestan-North East of Isfahan) has been investigated. In this regard physical and mechanical properties of reservoir alluvium has been determined, using in situ and laboratory tests. Test results show that the type of alluvium is mostly non uniform dense granular soils without plasticity. Also its permeability is medium to high. Due to the porosity obtained from tests and the depth of the reservoir sediments (5 to 12 meters), in the case of subsurface dam construction, its volume would be about 200000 cubic meters. In general, due to full and empty of reservoir, loading and unloading cause the settlement. Since almost reservoir sediment are gravel and sand, the settlement is mainly immediate settlement. Due to obtained mechanical parameters, the amout of immediate settlement is equal to 16 milimeter
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">1716</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Geotecnic</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Effect of soil nonlinearity on ground motion amplification in Urmia City</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>mahdavian</surname>
		<given-names>abbas</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>fathi azar kalkhoran</surname>
		<given-names>abbas</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>3</month>

	<year>2015</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>8</volume>

  <issue>4</issue>

  <fpage>2435</fpage>

  <lpage>2462</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Direct observation and experience of past earthquakes together with modeling carried out by researchers, has shown that ground motion acceleration and frequency is affected by the nonlinear behavior of site soil. In the process of assessing the seismic response of structures and lifelines, it is essential to understand the nonlinear behavior of the soil and how it can affect the results. In this paper, the nonlinear behavior of Urmia's subsurface soil is studied by performing one dimensional nonlinear site response analysis in time domain. Artificial acceleration time histories that were synthesized based on the result of seismic hazard analysis, conducted over three return periods, are used as input motion. Spectral acceleration at the ground surface is compared with those calculated for seismic bedrock, and spectral acceleration amplification curves are obtained. These curves show that, the amplification is greater in the central and eastern regions of the city than those for other regions of the city because of a deeper soil profile. The results show that the maximum amplification for higher return period is smaller because of greater soil nonlinear behavior
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">1551</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>En. Geology</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>study of engineering geological properties of the Ilam - Sarvak formations in Khorramabad city</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Ghobadi</surname>
		<given-names>M. H.</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Ghorbani</surname>
		<given-names>A</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Mohseni</surname>
		<given-names>H</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Uromeiea</surname>
		<given-names>Ali</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>3</month>

	<year>2015</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>8</volume>

  <issue>4</issue>

  <fpage>2463</fpage>

  <lpage>2486</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

 Knowing the engineering geological characteristics of carbonate formations is necessary for database. In this research, using petrological study and mechanical tests on 5 types of Ilam-Sarvak formations limestones in Khorramabad city, their engineering geological characteristics were determined and the relationship between physical and mechanical properties have been analyzed. IBM SPSS Statistics (version 19.0) software was used to determine the required relations. The relations have high correlations. Based on the studies on this of thin sections, rocks are characterszed as biomicrite. Limestones of Ilam-Sarvak formations have high hardening and low porosity. These rocks are in medium to high density, very resistant durability index, medium to high UCS and high point load strength category. The rocks are also impermeable. Based on the UCS, modulus ratio of the intact rock, the limestones are CM and CL. According to solubility test, the solution velocity constant was 1.39×10-6 m/s.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">1712</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>En. Geology</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Assessment water leakage zones of Minab Esteghlal dam</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Kordavani</surname>
		<given-names>M</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>hafezi moghadas</surname>
		<given-names>N</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Ramazani omali</surname>
		<given-names>Ramazan</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>3</month>

	<year>2015</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>8</volume>

  <issue>4</issue>

  <fpage>2487</fpage>

  <lpage>2512</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The Minab (Esteghlal) dam site is located in east of Minab city in Hormozgan province. The Minab active fault cross the reservoir of dam and have an important role in leakage from the reservoir. The joint study of area in ten stations around the reservoir of dam display the four main joint sets. For assessment of leakage of reservoir, the permeability of rock masses outcrops in the reservoir is estimated by hydraulic conductivity HC experimental model. For this, the RQD, GSI and other characteristics of rock mass around the reservoir were measured in field studies. The results show that the permeability of embankments changes from 9.14×10-6 up to 2.02×10-5 m/s. Also the water lost for three different condition of minimum, mean and maximum level of water table is about 0.14, 0.20 and 0.29 m3/s. The results indicate that the discontinuities with trend of east-west and northeast-southwest and also shear fault zone of Minab have main effects in leakage of reservoir.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">426</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Geotecnic</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Modification and improvement of collapsible soils</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>maroof</surname>
		<given-names>mohamad ali</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Bolouri Bazaz</surname>
		<given-names>Jafar</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Civil Engineering Dept. Ferdowsi University, P O Box 91775-1111 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>3</month>

	<year>2015</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>8</volume>

  <issue>4</issue>

  <fpage>2513</fpage>

  <lpage>2536</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The collapsible soils are usually known as soils with open structure and weak bonding between particles. The behavior of such soils is similar to very loose soils. These types of soils, when saturated without any changes in loading or subjecting vibratory loads, experiences huge settlements. The present research deals with investigation on collapsible soils located in the North East of Mashhad. The results of laboratory and in situ tests show that collapsible soil in this region was very sensitive to the increasing of moisture content. This means that an increase in soil moisture content, significant excess settlement occurs during a short time. This indicates that the soil in this region suffers from high potential collapsibility. The huge soil settlement will lead to the stability of existing structures to be at risk. It is, therefore, necessary for the collapsible soil in the region to be improved. For soil improvement, many techniques including moisture mitigation and soil replacement or compaction may be employed. Also stabilization of soil with lime, cement or coarse aggregates are practical methods. Which The results of the present research indicate that stabilization of soil lime is the most appropriate method for increasing bearing capacity of soil and reducing structural settlement.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">1640</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>En. Geology</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Estimation of Soil Hydraulic and Thermal Conductivity Parameters Using Geophysical and Thermal Methods</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>nakhaei</surname>
		<given-names>M</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>3</month>

	<year>2015</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>8</volume>

  <issue>4</issue>

  <fpage>2537</fpage>

  <lpage>2558</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

For prediction of exact effect of soil temperature, soil water retention, unsaturated hydraulic conductivity and water flow of soils on seep development, information about soil hydraulic, physical properties soil temperature is necessary. In this study, using geophysical and thermal methods the hydraulic properties and thermal conductivity of unsaturated porous media was estimated. Infiltrated water temperature was 50° C and the temperature data used in inverse solution technique was recorded by 2 thermal sensors during 3255 sec. One of thermal sensor was installed at a depth of 50 cm and the soil hydraulic and thermal parameters were estimated using 48 collected data of the injection water temperature variations. In this research 121 geoelectrical sounding with the Wener, Schlumberger and polar-polar arrays configuration were used. Evaluation and interpretation of the sounding curves show that the water table is located at depth of 75 meters. Top alluvium layer (unsaturated zone) is composed of three layers. In this study, to investigate the distribution and diffusion of pollutants in the unsaturated zone, the brine concentration of 20 g/L was used. Wener and polar-polar arrays were used to detect and image the contaminants plume. The polar-polar configuration shows less spreading of contaminated plume in both vertically and horizontally direction than the Wener array.  Particularly by the Wener configuration the plume depth is more underestimated than the real value. Based on water injection visibility in the vicinity of the trenches and observing the water seepage at the trench face, the real velocity of the water at direction of 35 degrees relative to the horizon was measured equal to 0.159 m/h. Horizontal and vertical contaminant plume expansion coefficient was determined equal to 1.4. Evaluation of thermal and hydraulic properties of unsaturated porous media was done by HYDRUS-2D software. In this study five hydraulic parameters &#59;thetar, &#59;thetas, &#59;alpha, n and Ks and five soil heat transfer parameters including the &#59;lambdaL, &#59;lambdaT, Cn, Co and Cw were included in the parameter estimation process. After implementation of the parameter estimation (adjusted for ​​observed and predicted temperature values) Coefficient of Determination  R2 was equal to 0.97 and the objective function value was equal to 11.5. Computational error in the mass balance was about 67 percent. 
</body>

</article>

