<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" 

"journalpublishing3.dtd">

<article 
article-type="research-article"
dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en" 
xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
>

<front>

<journal-meta>

  <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher">1</journal-id>
  <issn>2228-6837</issn>

  <publisher>

	<publisher-name>Kharazmi University</publisher-name>
  </publisher>

</journal-meta>



<article-meta>

  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2562</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>En. Geology</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Evaluation of Engineering Geological Properties of Chapar-abad Alluvial Dam Foundation: Revisiting Sealing Problems</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>9</month>

	<year>2007</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>2</volume>

  <issue>1</issue>

  <fpage>281</fpage>

  <lpage>302</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Considering the seepage and choosing an efficient sealing method is very important in dam projects. This issue has a close relationship with engineering geological properties of the dam site. Chapar-abad dam is an inhomogeneous earth-fill dam of 44.5 meters height, crest length about 427 meters and a reservoir capacity of 127 million cubic meters. The dam project is under construction and is located about 75 Km southeast of Uromieh city, in West Azerbaijan Province. The foundation materials include 60 meters of alluvium deposits overburden bedrock layers of carbonate units. The abutments consist of carbonate and schistose layers of Precambrian age. In order to control the seepage through the Alluvial foundation, several sealing methods were considered. The methods include grout curtain, cutoff-wall, impervious blanket, open compacted trenches, and the use of geosynthetics are evaluated. In this research using a finite element package named Plaxis was utilized. The results indicate that although the cutoff-wall is usually considered as the best method for this type of geological condition, but due to the instability of granular soils and the possibility of liquefaction capability, the grout curtain is proposed as to be an efficient method.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2563</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>En. Geology</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Inspection of encountered water in power tunnel of Saymareh dam site, Ilam</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>9</month>

	<year>2007</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>2</volume>

  <issue>1</issue>

  <fpage>301</fpage>

  <lpage>323</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Saymareh dam and hydro-power plant are under construction on Saymareh River in Ravandi anticline, Ilam province. During boring the power tunnel which crosses the anticline, a large volume of water was encountered. This volume of water was not observed in the past. Considering the water quality of springs, water level of dam site piezometers, geological and hydrogeological inspections, isotope analysis, tracing experiments and water balance, it was concluded that the main portion of water is not supplied by the Ravandi anticline. The neighboring Veizenhar, Gavar and Milleh anticlines contribute to providing the main body of water. The most probable paths of water are not cross the dam reservoir and a localized conduit flow is not established in this area. Therefore, water leakage from the reservoir is not expected.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2564</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>En. Geology</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>A Comparative Modeling Approach of Crustal Study in the Central Alborz</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>9</month>

	<year>2007</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>2</volume>

  <issue>1</issue>

  <fpage>323</fpage>

  <lpage>339</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Results of velocity structure modeling in the Earth's crust using a comparison approach of receiver function analysis and joint inversion of receiver functions with surface wave dispersion data are presented in this paper. Seismograms of the teleseismic events that have been recorded on a broadband seismic station in the central Alborz were used for data processing. Velocity models that were computed by using both modeling methods show analogy the depth&#160; discontinuities but differences in the absolute values of velocity. In addition, differences between computed models using different initial velocity models confirms that receiver function results are not a unique modeling method compared with the joint inversion results which show reasonable and stable values. Both methods show 56km depth for the Moho discontinuity.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2565</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>En. Geology</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Use of Composite Diagrams, Factor Analysis and Saturation Index for Quantification of Zeviercherry & Kheran Groundwater Plains</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>9</month>

	<year>2007</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>2</volume>

  <issue>1</issue>

  <fpage>339</fpage>

  <lpage>356</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Groundwater is the sole source of accessible resource for agriculture in Zeviercherry- Kherran plains and water quality often falls in brackish group. In order to determine the source of salinity and hydrochemical processess affecting groundwater environment of the area, 61 groundwater samples were taken for hydrochemical analysis and composite diagrams (two variant diagrams of total concentration verses concentration of major ions and two variant diagrams of chloride verses concentration of bicarbonate, sulfate and sodium), Factor analysis and saturation index of calcite, dolomite and gypsum were applied. The data indicated that groundwater is supersaturated with respect to calcite and dolomite and with respect to gypsum saturated to under saturation. Regional dissolution of gypsum, anhydride and local dissolution of sodium chloride are important controlling factors of groundwater salinity of the area.&#160;
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2566</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>En. Geology</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Influence of grain size distribution on engineering properties of soils treated with hydrated lime</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>9</month>

	<year>2007</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>2</volume>

  <issue>1</issue>

  <fpage>357</fpage>

  <lpage>376</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

This paper describes the results of a study which was primarily directed to the determination of geotechnical properties of fine and coarse grain soils stabilized by lime obtained from Taleghan, northwest of Tehran to assess its suitability as construction material. Soils were treated with lime mixtures in various portions between 3 to 9 percents by weight. The samples were cured for different periods of time up to 90 days under 30&#176;c and 60 percent relative humidity. The geotechnical properties were investigated by: (a) compaction characteristics, (b) compression tests and (c) direct shear tests. The results indicated soils maximum dry densities decreased while the optimum water contents increased. The compressive and shear strength of admixtures depicted an increasing trend. It was observed that addition of 6 percent of lime caused a significant increase in strength properties of CL and SC grain soils. However, the SC soil yielded the best results.
</body>

</article>

