<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1398</year>
	<month>8</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2019</year>
	<month>11</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>13</volume>
<number>3</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی واکنش کمی و کیفی چشمه‌علی شهرری و آبخوان اطراف آن، شمال ایران</title_fa>
	<title>Study of the Shahre Rye’s Karstic Spring and its Surrounding Alluvial Aquifers Relationship, Northern Iran</title>
	<subject_fa>زمین شناسی مهندسی</subject_fa>
	<subject>En. Geology</subject>
	<content_type_fa>مقاله مستقل</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Original Manuscript</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;در این تحقیق، ارتباط وواکنش کمی وکیفی آب چشمۀ کارستی شهر ری (چشمه علی) در جنوب شهر تهران با آب زیرزمینی آبرفت&#8204;های آبخوان&#8204;های محیط کارستی و محیط آبرفتی از یک&#8204;دیگر جدا است و دو محیط زمین&#8204;شناسی وآب زیرزمینی کاملاً متفاوت را نشان می&#8204;دهد. آبخوان آبرفتی، محیط متخلل پیوسته آب زیرزمینی است، در صورتیکه آبخوان کارستی&amp;nbsp; محیط درز وشکافدار آب زیرزمینی می باشد. در این تحقیق، ارتباط وواکنش کمی و کیفی آب چشمۀ کارستی شهر ری (چشمه علی) با آبخوان آبرفتی اطراف آن بررسی شده است. در این بررسی پژوهش&#8204;&#8204;های زمین&#8204;شناسی، کمیت و کیفیت آب زیرزمینی چشمه علی و آبرفت&#8204;های مجاور آن، خصوصیات هیدرودینامیکی چشمه و آبخوان آبرفتی مجاور چشمه مطالعه و بررسی شد. نتایج حاصل از بررسی&#8204;ها گویای شرایط زمین&#8204;شناسی، هیدروژئولوژی و شرائط هیدرولیکی متفاوت بین چشمۀ کارستی شهرری و آبخوان آبرفتی اطراف آن است و نبود ارتباط هیدرولیکی بین دو محیط آب زیرزمینی آبرفت و کارست در مجاور هم و متفاوت را نشان می&#8204;دهد، که در اثر عملکرد گسل شمال شهر ری شکل گرفته&#8204;اند.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>In this research, the relationship and reaction between quantitative and qualitative Shahre Rye spring&amp;rsquo;s karstic water (Cheshme Ali) and spring&amp;rsquo;s adjacent alluvium aquifer have been considered to determine the relationship between alluvial and karstic aquifers and to study the connections between the two different groundwater environments. The results of the present research suggest geological conditions, hydrogeology and different hydraulic condition between Cheshme Ali karstic water with its surrounding alluvium&amp;rsquo;s aquifer. However the study results show the lack of a hydraulic connection between the two different groundwater environments (karst and alluvium) that are formed by north Rye fault.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
There have been many studies in the field of the present research, some of which are mentioned below.&lt;br&gt;
(Tobarov, 1966). The N. Massei et al. (2002). (Robert E. 2005). (Ezatollah Raeisi 2008). (Cholami et al. 2008). (N. Goldscheider and C. Neukum 2010). (Dusan Polomcic et al. 2013).&lt;br&gt;
The aim of this research is to identify the hydraulic relation between the alluvial aquifer and the karstic aquifer of the Cheshme Ali, during which the geographic, topographic and geologic situations and the changes in water discharge of Cheshme Ali and the changes in water table of the observation wells of the aquifer to the north of the spring have been reviewed simultaneously.&lt;br&gt;
The results indicate a lack of relation between the alluvial aquifer and the karstic aquifer of the Cheshme Ali in Shahre Rye.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;The general specification of the study area&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The surface area of Shahre Rye equals to 2,293 km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; and the city is limited to the north by Tehran, to the south by Qom, to the east by Varamin and Pakdasht and to the west by Islamshahr, Robat Karim and Zarandieh (Fig. 1). The Cheshme Ali is located in the eastern parts of the city and southeast of Tehran. From a geographic point of view, the Cheshme Ali spring is situated in the southern part of the Cheshme Ali hill, and after leaving the ground, the spring's water flows to the south of Shahre Rye.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Methodology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;1. Topography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The topographic specifications of the Cheshme Ali and its surrounding are as follows:&lt;br&gt;
The highest points of the Cheshme Ali's surroundings are the Sepaye Hills with an altitude of 2,085 m above the sea, which are located to the east of Cheshme Ali. The height of Bibi Shahbanoo hill to the southeast of Cheshme Ali is about 1,498 m. The altitude of the northern hill of Cheshme Ali, where the spring is located is about 1,077 m and the lower sloped land surrounding it have an altitude of 1,072 m above the sea. This means that the opening of the Cheshme Ali spring is located at 1,072 m above the sea.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2. Geology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
From the geological point of view, the existing units around Cheshme Ali of Shahre Rye consist of Precambrian, Mesozoic and Cenozoic sediments and rocks as geological specifications of Cheshme Ali and its surroundings are shown in Fig. 2.&lt;br&gt;
From the structural geology, and geological specifications two geological sections AB, CD Were prepared and presented in Figure 3.&lt;br&gt;
The Figure 3 shows, Cheshme Ali spring appears from Cretaceous thick layered limestone (Tizkooh formation Kt1) and the shahre Rye fault mechanism on either side of layering. However the water flow of cheshme Ali is nearly east &amp;ndash; westerly after spring&amp;rsquo;s openings (A) and then spring water flow direction is to the south (Fig. 4).&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;The hydrogeology of the spring and the wells&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
1. The Cheshme Ali in Shahre Rye is a karstic spring, with few hydrogeological specifications that are concluded from the result of geological and hydrogeological review and analysis of the spring&amp;rsquo;s water quality.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
Therefore, the karstic Cheshme Ali spring has a varied range of discharge which is from medium (25 to 100%) to high (&gt;100%). Moreover in the curves of the spring&amp;rsquo;s discharge and simultaneous rainfall, shown in figure 5, the peak volume of water discharge of the spring corresponds fully with the peak rainfall, underlining the influence of simultaneous rainfall on the spring.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
The study of the hydrographic makeup of the spring (curve 2) shows the difference in the period between the upward curve (seven and a half months) and the downward curve (four and a half months) underlining the lower permeability of the spring&amp;rsquo;s intake area versus the grounds conducting spring water to the openings.&lt;br&gt;
2. The hydrogeology of the surrounding wells:&lt;br&gt;
For the purpose of studying the fluctuation of water tables of the observation wells around the spring and in its adjacent alluvial aquifer, the isobaths maps of groundwater level and groundwater table of the spring&amp;rsquo;s surrounding areas were drawn ( Fig.6). The level of groundwater table to the north of spring is 5.9 m and 6.6 m to the south of it, while the spring water is at ground level. In order to have a better understanding of the potentials of groundwater table in Shahre Rye&amp;rsquo;s Cheshme Ali and its surrounding environments from south to north, the potential profile is provided in figure 7 using the potential figures of witness wells and the Cheshme Ali spring. In the potential profile, the groundwater level of the Cheshme Ali is higher than the groundwater potential level of the witness wells, which seems to suggest the recharge of the plain by the spring.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;The review of the groundwater quality in wells and the Cheshme Ali spring&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The groundwater quality characters of the Cheshme Ali and the wells to the north and south of the spring are presented in table 2,that shows three differences and similarities in the results of the chemical analysis of water from Cheshme Ali and from wells located to the north and the south of the spring. The difference between the chemical composition of water from the spring and the chemical composition of the well located to the north is considerably more than the difference between the chemical compositions of the spring and the well located to the south.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Summary and conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Based on the geological studies of this research, the Cheshme Ali spring in Shahre Rye appears from the Karstic Tizkooh formation (Fig. 2) and the geological structure shows a northerly direction for the slopes of the layers in Tizkooh formation, and an east-westerly direction for the appearance of the spring water (Fig. 3 and Fig. 9). The spring&amp;rsquo;s flow is disseminated and the spring is of Karstic - fault type (table 1). The discharge of Cheshme Ali corresponds entirely to rainfall and is influenced a lot by it (Fig. 5). The condition of groundwater table of the well and the spring (Fig. 6, A) and the water level potential of the spring and its surrounding wells underlines the existence of two different hydraulic environments (Fig. 6, B). Moreover, from the aspect of potential groundwater column, there is a large difference between the groundwater table potential of the spring and the potentials of the two wells to the north and south of the spring (Fig. 7and8). From a qualitative aspect, the quality of spring water differs greatly from the quality of water from the wells located to the north and south (table 2).&lt;br&gt;
The results of this research are as follows:&lt;br&gt;
1. The study of geologic, structural geology and the geological section shows the water in the Cheshme Ali of Shahre Rye is originating from the Karstic formation of Tizkooh that layers sloping are to the north, the spring water appears from the site of the Rye fault and then flows to the west.&lt;br&gt;
2. The studies have proven that Cheshme Ali to be a Karstic &amp;ndash; fault spring with disseminated flow, whose discharge is influenced by rainfall and condition of groundwater level and the table which underlines the alluvial aquifer shows lack of relation between two alluvial and karstic aquifers.&lt;br&gt;
3. The water quality analyses show a great difference between the specifications of the spring water and its surrounding wells groundwater.&lt;br&gt;
4- The north Rye fault mechanism are formed two different groundwater environment ( Karstic and alluvium) and however different groundwater conditions between north and south of alluvium.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>کارست, آبرفت, چشمه علی شهر ری, ارتباط کارست وآبرفت</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Karst, alluvium, Cheshme Ali, Relation between Karst and alluvium</keyword>
	<start_page>395</start_page>
	<end_page>410</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-11-1184-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Ahmad </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Khorsandi Aghai</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>احمد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>خورسندی آقائی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>A_khorsandi@sbu.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846003900</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003900</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Civil, Water and Environment, Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، پردیس فنی شهید عباسپور</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
