<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>7</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>10</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>12</volume>
<number>2</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>پاک‌سازی خاک رسی چسبندۀ آلوده به گازوئیل با استفاده از روش‌های حرارتی و سورفکتنت</title_fa>
	<title> Remediation of Cohesive Clay Contaminated to Gasoline Using Thermal Method and Surfactants </title>
	<subject_fa>ژئوتکنیک (مکانیک خاک و سنگ)</subject_fa>
	<subject>Geotecnic</subject>
	<content_type_fa>مقاله استخراج شده از پایان نامه</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research Paper</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;در این پژوهش اثر گازوئیل بر خواص فیزیکی و مکانیکی خاک رسی چسبنده بررسی شد. سپس&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;تأثیر&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;روش&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;حرارتی و&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;استفاده از دو&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;نوع&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;سورفکتنت بر&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;مشخصات&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;فیزیکی&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;و مکانیکی&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;خاک آلوده بررسی شد. خاک&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;رسی&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;چسبنده&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;به&#8204;صورت مصنوعی با درصدهای گوناگون گازوئیل ( 10% و 5%) آلوده شد. به&#8204;منظور پاک&#8204;سازی خاک به&#8204;وسیلۀ اعمال حرارت نمونه&#8204;های خاک آلوده شده در معرض حرارت&#8204;های 50، 100 و 150 درجۀ سانتی&#8204;گراد قرار گرفت. علاوه بر آن پاک&#8204;سازی&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;با&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;شوینده&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman,serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;&#8204;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;های&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;سدیم دودسیل سولفات&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;و&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;تویین&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;80 نیز&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;انجام&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;شد.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;آزمایش&#8204;های&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:black;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;فیزیکی و مکانیکی شامل دانه&#8204;بندی، حدود اتربرگ، تراکم و مقاومت تک&#8204;محوری روی نمونه&#8204;هایی از خاک طبیعی آلوده شده و خاک پاک&#8204;سازی شده از دو روش گفته شده انجام شد. نتایج نشان داد افزودن گازوئیل موجب تغییراتی در مشخصات فیزیکی و مکانیکی خاک می&#8204;شود و این تغییرات تابعی از درصد گازوئیل است. علاوه بر آن نتایج پژوهش&#8204;ها نشان داد روش حرارتی و استفاده از شوینده در پاک&#8204;سازی خاک مؤثر است.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Contaminants can be categorized into organic and inorganic groups. Organic contaminants are carbon based, and their presence in waste forms may be as a single contaminant associated with inorganic contaminants, or a suite of complex mixtures which may be toxic at very low concentrations. Organics of greatest environmental concern are usually refined petroleum products, chlorinated and non-chlorinated solvents, manufactured biocides, organic sledges and substances from manufacturing processes. Most contamination due to organics are associated with accidental spills and leaks, originating from equipment cleaning, maintenance, storage tanks, residue from used containers and outdated material (Yong and Mulligan, 2004). Transport and fate of organic contaminants are important. Organic contamination migrations are due to advection (by fluid flow through soil) and diffusion, but other forms of transport e.g. infiltration may also contribute to migration (Environment Agency, 2002). The response of the soil to a contaminant depends upon the type of soil and the nature of the contaminant. The sensitivity of soil to contaminants depends upon the type of soil (such as particle size, mineral structure, bonding characteristics between particles and ion exchange capacity) and the nature of contaminants. Fang (1997) defined a sensitivity index (ranging from 0 to 1) to different types of soil. Sensitivity of sand and gravel (0.01 to 0.1) is much lower than clay particles (0.6-0.9). There are a number of techniques for remediation of contaminated land. These include physical (washing, flushing, thermal, vacuum extraction, solvent extraction), chemical (stabilization and solidification) and bioremediation techniques. However, the applicability and feasibility of different methods for remediation are dependent on many factors such as soil characteristics (soil type, degree of compaction and saturation), site geology, depth of contamination, extent of contaminant in lateral direction, topography, surface and ground water and the type and amount of contaminants. Thermal treatment and using surfactants are the most popular methods for remediating the soil contaminated with petroleum compounds. In this research remediation of a soil contaminated with different percentages of gasoline was studied through physical techniques in laboratory. The applied physical techniques were thermal technique and use of two different kinds of surfactants. The obtained results were compared with each other and discussion was performed.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Material and methods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Soil, gasoline and surfactant are the basic materials that were used in this work. The soil that was used in this testing program was &lt;s&gt;a &lt;/s&gt;clayey soil. Two different types of ionic and nonionic surfactant, namely Tween 80 and SDS, were used in this work for remediating soil, contaminated with gasoline. Contaminated soil was prepared by adding 5 and 10 % weight (to air dried soil) of gasoline. 6 kg air dried soil was selected and the desired amount of gasoline was weighted, then it was sprayed on the soil and thoroughly mixed by hand for about 2 hours. The prepared mixture was kept inside a covered container for a week in order to come to equilibrium with the soil. For thermal remediation the contaminated soil with a specific percent of gasoline was kept inside a constant convection oven at 50, 100, and 150&lt;sup&gt;o&lt;/sup&gt;C for about one week to desorb the contaminating compound. Tween 80 and SDS were used for remediation of the contaminated soil. The amount of used Tween 80 was 25% weight of contaminating compound and selection of SDS amount was based on 50% weight of contaminating matter. The samples for the main tests were prepared by static compaction according to the optimum water content and maximum dry unit weight that were obtained from standard compaction tests. Atterberg limits, grain size distribution, compaction and unconfined compression tests were performed on samples of natural, contaminated and remediated soil according to the ASTM standard.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Results and discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The results of Atterberg limits (LL, PL and PI) for the contaminated soil (with 5 and 10 % gasoline) indicated that the values of them are increased with increasing the percent of gasoline. These values are nearly the same as natural soil after remediation with thermal method and surfactants. The grain size distribution curves were determined for the natural soil, contaminated soil with 5% and10% gasoline and soil remediated by thermal and surfactant techniques. The results showed that by using thermal technique the percent of clay is decreased and the percent of sand and particularly silt is increased by increasing temperature. The results of grain size distribution for the soils remediated by SDS and Tween 80 showed that the percent of clay is reduced but the percent of silt and sand are increased. Comparing the results of the two surfactants shows that the effect of Tween 80 in reduction of the percent of clay is more than SDS. The results showed that after thermal treatment, the maximum dry unit weight decreases and the optimum water content increases. For the contaminated soil with gasoline a reduction in maximum dry unit weight is observed compared with natural soil. The effect of SDS and Tween 80 on soil remediation is reduction in maximum dry unit weight and optimum water content. The results of compression strength showed that adding gasoline to soil causes a reduction in final strength and this reduction is a function of gasoline percent. The results also indicated that the strength of remediated soil by thermal or surfactant techniques, is reached nearly to the strength of natural soil. Scanning electron microscopy (SEM) tests were performed on the samples in order to observe the microstructure of the samples in different conditions (natural and contaminated with different percent of gasoline). The results of SEM showed that the structure of soil is changed by contamination to gasoline. It can be said that the gasoline causes reduction in the thickness of DDL because of low dielectric constant and hence a flocculated structure is formed. In the flocculated structure due to attractive forces, the fine particles paste to each other and form coarse particles. Therefore, variations in the Atterberg limits and compaction parameters can be resulted from forming new structure by adding gasoline. These results of compression strength are not in agreement with the theory of diffuse double layer (DDL). The reduction in dielectric constant would cause a flocculated structure in soil and the strength of the contaminated soil should be increased in comparison with the natural soil. It can be said the viscosity of gasoline cause reduction in the strength of contaminated soil.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In this experimental work a cohesive soil was contaminated with 5% and 10% of gasoline. The experimental tests showed that the properties of contaminated soil are different from natural soil and the change in the properties is a function of gasoline percent. The contaminated soil, was remediated by thermal treatment and also using two surfactants. The results also showed that using surfactants is more effective than using thermal method in soil remediation, and can treat the soil nearly to its original condition.&lt;br&gt;
-Base on the SEM analysis results, adding gasoline to the soil, will change the soil micro structure to a flocculated one. &amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
-The gradation curves show that adding gasoline to the soil will change the gradation from finer to coarser.&lt;br&gt;
- Contamination to gasoline will change the compaction parameters of the soil, and will reduce the soil final strength significantly.&lt;br&gt;
- The results show that using thermal method and surfactants is effective in remediating the soil, but it is more effective to use surfactants.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Yong, R.N., Mulligan,. &amp;ldquo;Natural attenuation of the contaminants in soil&amp;rdquo;, CRC press, Boca Raton, FL (2004).&lt;br&gt;
Fang, M.Y. &amp;ldquo;Introduction to Environmental Geotechnology&amp;rdquo;, CRC Press,FL.USA, (1997).</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>گازوئیل, خاک چسبنده, پاک‌سازی, آلودگی, شوینده, روش حراراتی</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Gasoline, Cohesive clay, soil remediation, Contamination, Surfactants, Thermal method.</keyword>
	<start_page>213</start_page>
	<end_page>236</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1444-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mahmoud</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Babalar</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمود</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بابالار</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>babalar@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846002511</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002511</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>University of Tehran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران، پردیس کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی، گروه آبیاری و آبادانی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ali Raeesi</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Estabragh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رئیسی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>raeesi@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846002512</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002512</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران، پردیس کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی، گروه آبیاری و آبادانی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Jamal </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Abdolahi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>جمال</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عبداللهی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>jaabaik@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846002513</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002513</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران، پردیس کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی، گروه آبیاری و آبادانی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
