<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1398</year>
	<month>5</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2019</year>
	<month>8</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>13</volume>
<number>1</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ارائه اطلاعات زمین‌شناسی و ژئوتکنیکی برای ساختگاه شهر سنندج</title_fa>
	<title>Geotechnical and Geological Information on the City of Sanandaj</title>
	<subject_fa>زمین شناسی مهندسی</subject_fa>
	<subject>En. Geology</subject>
	<content_type_fa>مقاله استخراج شده از پایان نامه</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research Paper</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;با ترکیب مشخصات زمین&#8204;شناسی و ژئوتکنیکی می&#8204;توان اطلاعات زمین شناسی- ژئوتکنیکی ارائه کرد که در طراحی و برنامه&#8204;ریزی فعالیت&#8204;های عمرانی در منطقه&#8204;ای بزرگ مانند شهرها مفید باشد. در این تحقیق مراحل گام به&#8204;گام انجام این کار برای ساختگاه شهر سنندج ارائه شد که این مراحل در سایر مناطق نیز قابل انجام است. بدین&#8204;منظور، ابتدا انواع واحدهای زمین&#8204;شناسی سنندج شناسایی و خصوصیات آن&#8204;ها شامل نحوۀ تشکیل و منشأ پیدایش آن&#8204;ها تشریح و از نظر زمین&#8204;شناسی طبقه&#8204;بندی شدند. برای اضافه کردن متغیرهای مهندسی به این طبقه&#8204;بندی زمین&#8204;شناسی، از نتایج 211 گمانه ژئوتکنیکی در سطح شهر سنندج استفاده شد. برای تکمیل و کنترل متغیرهای ژئوتکنیکی به&#8204;دست آمده، 9 چاه در نقاط مختلف سنندج حفاری و یک سری آزمایش&#8204;های ژئوتکنیکی انجام شد. نهایتاً علاوه بر ارائۀ نقشۀ زمین&#8204;شناسی و طبقه&#8204;بندی زمین&#8204;شناسی- ژئوتکنیکی برای واحدهای سنندج، معیارهای زمین&#8204;شناسی برای تشخیص نوع واحد مورد برخورد در محل یک پروژه در سنندج ارائه شد. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Geotechnical investigations merely through boring and engineering experiments are considered a difficult task as they are highly costly and time-consuming. The identification of large areas initially requires geological studies followed by the inclusion of geotechnical information. Finally, a geological and geotechnical classification is prepared for the entire area. This type of classifications is employed in strategic urban planning and quick selection of geotechnical variables in small-scale projects. The present research performed the steps involved in these investigations and classifications for the city of Sanandaj, Iran. Hence, the geological-geotechnical classification of the city of Sanandaj was presented by integrating the geological information of this city with the geotechnical data obtained from drilled boreholes as well as multiple wells at different locations in this city.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Materials and Methods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This study was conducted on the city of Sanandaj in six steps. The steps involved and their respective objectives are given in summary in Table 1.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This study is applicable to those regions with insufficient information on their boreholes. The present study used only 211 boreholes, the distance&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table1. Steps involved in this study&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; border=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; dir=&quot;rtl&quot; style=&quot;width:100.0%;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
	&lt;tbody&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:46.94%;&quot;&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;_Hlk513585718&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;Objective or result&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:42.86%;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:10.2%;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;Step&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:46.94%;&quot;&gt;Identifying the general geological characteristics&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:42.86%;&quot;&gt;General geological investigation of the considered region&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:10.2%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:46.94%;height:57px;&quot;&gt;Determining the rock units and soil layers as well as their outcrops and investigating their appearance&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:42.86%;height:57px;&quot;&gt;Determining the appearance of the layers through field investigations&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:10.2%;height:57px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:46.94%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;Determining the layer types and drawing the longitudinal and lateral profiles&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:42.86%;&quot;&gt;Identifying subsurface layers&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:10.2%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:46.94%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;Determining the characteristics of geological units and their origin of emergence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:42.86%;&quot;&gt;Geological classification based on the steps involved in formation of units&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:10.2%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:46.94%;&quot;&gt;a)Collecting the available information, b) controlling the available information, c) completing the information&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:42.86%;&quot;&gt;Determining the geotechnical attributes of geological units&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:10.2%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:46.94%;&quot;&gt;a) Presenting geological-geotechnical classification, b) presenting geological identification criteria to determine the type of a given unit at the site of the project&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:42.86%;&quot;&gt;Presenting a geological-geotechnical classification for the considered region&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:10.2%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;clear:both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;bet&lt;a name=&quot;_GoBack&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;ween which was greater than 5 km in some areas of the Sanandaj city. Hence, although no sufficient information was available on many areas of Sanandaj, the proposed method in this study was able to identify the geotechnical attributes of all soil layers and rock units. This study emphasizes on geological and geotechnical classification and presents a step-by-step method to systematically relate geological and geotechnical studies. By integrating these classifications, geotechnical identification of extensive regions such as urban areas can be facilitated even if the number of boreholes is insufficient. Moreover, simple identification criteria can be extracted from this method, through which the engineering attributes of the layers at each point can be determined. This method can be used as an optimal and economical method for geotechnical identification of extensive areas.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The following summaries can be concluded from this study:&lt;br&gt;
-The step-by-step procedure of integrating geological and geotechnical information was described, through which the geological-geotechnical classification for this city was obtained.&lt;br&gt;
-The geological units identified for Sanandaj were shale, limestone, andesite, and Quaternary, which includes layers of alluvial clay, residual clay, and sand and gravel. The extent and distribution of each of the aforementioned units in Sanandaj were identified and plotted. Moreover, the physical and mechanical characteristics of each of the units as well as their geotechnical hazards were determined and presented.&lt;br&gt;
-In this study, simple geotechnical criteria such as faults, altitude level, and distance from river were identified. These parameters were effective in identification of geological units in Sanandaj.&lt;a href=&quot;./files/site1/files/131/5Extended_Abstract.pdf&quot;&gt;./files/site1/files/131/5Extended_Abstract.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>ساختگاه سنندج, زمین‌شناسی شهری, آزمایش‌های ژئوتکنیکی, طبقه‌بندی.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Sanandaj Site, Urban Geology, Geotechnical Tests, Classification</keyword>
	<start_page>95</start_page>
	<end_page>122</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1546-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Behrooz</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Samadian</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>بهروز</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>صمدیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>b_samadian@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846003888</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003888</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات، گروه عمران، تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Fakher</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>فاخر</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>afakher@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846003889</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003889</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران، دانشکدۀ عمران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
