<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1389</year>
	<month>8</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2010</year>
	<month>11</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>4</volume>
<number>1</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی پایداری دامنه های سازند گچساران واقع در مخزن سد گتوند تحت تاثیر آبگیری مخزن و انحلال مصالح نمکی</title_fa>
	<title>Stability study of Gachsaran formation slopes in reservoir of Gotvand dam with effect of reservoir recharge and dissolution of salty materials</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa>سایر</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Other</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>مخزن سد گتوند با طولی بیش از نود کیلومتر توسط سازند های گچساران، میشان، آغاجاری و بختیاری احاطه شده است. مسئله مهم در مخزن سد حضور سازند گچساران می باشد که حاوی حجم قابل ملاحظه ای از نمک است و به فاصله چهار کیلومتر، در بالادست سد قرار دارد. شور شدن آب سد در نتیجه انحلال نمک در آب مخزن می تواند عوارض جدی زیست محیطی به همراه داشته باشد. علاوه بر انحلال مستقیم نمک در تماس با آب مخزن، ناپایداری دامنه¬ای نیز می تواند بر این فرایند تاثیرگذار باشد. لغزش های احتمالی در دامنه های حاوی نمک، حجم قابل ملاحظه ای از نمک را در مدت زمان کوتاهی در تماس با آب مخزن قرار خواهد داد. در این تحقیق به منظور بررسی فرایند زمین لغزش در محدوده مخزن، و همچنین تاثیر انحلال لایه های نمکی بر لغزش، ویژگی¬های مهندسی مصالح غالب سازنده توده¬های سنگی با استفاده از آزمایش های مکانیک سنگ تعیین شد. سپس نتایج حاصل از آزمایش های انجام شده بر روی نمونه های سنگ بکر و روش GSI جهت برآورد پارامترهای مهندسی توده سنگ مورد استفاده قرار گرفت. از طرف دیگرجهت تعیین تاثیر انحلال لایه های نمکی بر لغزش، نمونه¬هایی از نمک به آزمایشگاه منتقل و با استفاده از روش سیرکولاسیون میزان انحلال پذیری آن در شرایط مختلف مورد بررسی قرار گرفت، و نتایج به شرایط مخزن تعمیم داده شد. در نهایت شرایط پایداری دامنه با توجه به ترازهای مختلف آبگیری مخزن، و همچنین تاثیر انحلال لایه های نمکی، با مدل سازی حالات مختلف در نرم¬افزار SLIDE مورد تجزیه و تحلیل قرار گرفت. نتایج حاصل از این تحلیل¬ها نشان می¬دهد که لغزش¬ها در محدوده مخزن بیشتر کم عمق هستند و تحت تاثیر انحلال لایه نمکی ایجاد می شوند.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Gotvand dam reservoir with over 90 km length is surrounded by Gachsaran, Mishan, Aghajari and Bakhtiari formations. The noticeable point in the dam reservoir is the presence of Gachsaran Formation that is composed of considerable volume of salt located  4 km upstream of dam. Salinity of dam water due to dissolution of salt in reservoir water can cause serious environmental problems. In addition to direct dissolution of salt in contact with reservoir water, slope instability can also influence on this process. Probable sliding in salty layers of slopes will insert a significant volume of salt in contact with reservoir water in a short time. In order to study the land-sliding process in reservoir area and also analysis of the effect of dissolution of salty layers on sliding, characteristics of dominant material engineering of mass constituent were defined by rock mechanics experiments. Then the results of performed tests on rock samples and GSI method were used to estimate the engineering parameters of rock mass. To investigate the land-sliding process in reservoir area and also the effect of dissolution of salty layers on sliding, some salt samples were transferred to the laboratory. Using circulation method, solubility of those samples were examined in different conditions. The results were generalized to the reservoir condition. Eventually, slope stability were analyzed by modeling with SLIDE software, considering different levels of reservoir water, influence of dissolution of salty layers. The obtained results indicate that slidings in reservoir area are mostly shallow and are caused by dissolution of salty layer.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>سد گتوند , زمین لغزش , انحلال پذیری , نرم افزار SLIDE , سیرکولاسیون , </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Gotvand dam , Landslide , solubility , SLIDE software , circulation , </keyword>
	<start_page>809</start_page>
	<end_page>826</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-11-4&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>B</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>B</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>بهمن</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بقاء دشتکی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>bahman.dashtaki@gmail.com</email>
	<code>100319475328460095</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460095</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>گروه زمین شناسی مهندسی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>m</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>kh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ماشاءا...</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>خامه چیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>khamechian@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>100319475328460096</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460096</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سید محمدحسن</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نظری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>nazari@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>100319475328460097</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460097</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>شرکت مهاب قدس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
