<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1398</YEAR>
<VOL>12</VOL>
<NO>4</NO>
<MOSALSAL>37</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>726</PAGE_NO>


<ARTICLES>

	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>مدل سازی پیش‌رو و وارون داده‌های GPR با هدف کاربرد در زمینۀ برف و یخ و یخ بندان شناسی، مطالعۀ موردی: یخچال علم کوه مازندران</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Forward and Inverse Modeling of GPR Data to use in Snow, Ice and Glaciological, A Case Study: Alam Kuh Glacier, Mazandaran Province</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>روش رادار نفوذی به زمین (GPR) روشی ژئوفیزیکی نسبتاً جدید، غیرمخرب و با قدرت تفکیک زیاد است که به&#173;دلیل شفاف بودن برف و یخ برای امواج الکترومغناطیسی به&#8204;طور گسترده برای شناسایی ضخامت لایه&#173;های برف و یخ و بستر یخچال&#173;ها استفاده می&#8204;شود. در پژوهش حاضر مدل&#173;سازی پیش&#8204;رو و وارون داده&#173;های GPR با هدف کاربرد در زمینۀ برف و یخ و یخ&#173;بندان&#173;شناسی در منطقۀ علم&#173;کوه مازندران، انجام شده است. برای این منظور ابتدا پاسخ GPR مدل مصنوعی متناظر با نگاشت راداری منطبق بر پروفیل واقعی GPR، به&#173;روش تفاضل محدود حوزۀ زمان (FDTD) دوبعدی، شبیه&#173;سازی شد. سپس برای اعتبارسنجی تعبیر و تفسیر برداشت&#173;های GPR واقعی، از روش مدل&#173;سازی وارون با حل یک مسئلۀ بهینه&#173;سازی، استفاده شد. نگاشت راداری نهایی مطلوب داده&#173;های واقعی GPR منطبق بر یکی از پروفیل&#173;های برداشت در این منطقه، با اعمال مراحل پردازشی مختلف مانند تصحیح اشباع سیگنال، تابع تقویت، اعمال فیلتر مهاجرت f-k و تصحیح توپوگرافی روی داده&#173;های خام، با استفاده از نرم&#8204;افزار Reflexw آماده&#173;سازی شده است. نتایج این پژوهش بر اساس بررسی میزان تطابق نگاشت راداری داده&#173;های واقعی GPR با پاسخ GPR مدل مصنوعی تولید شده متناظر با آن، درستی تفسیر زیرسطحی انجام شده در منطقۀ یخچال علم&#173;کوه را تأیید می&#173;کند.&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Introduction
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Ground-penetrating radar (GPR) method is a pretty new, non-destructive and high-resolution geophysical method that is widely used to identify the thickness of snow and ice layers and glaciers bed, because snow and ice are transparent for electromagnetic (EM) waves. Therefore, this method has been used to determine the thickness and basement topography of Alam-kooh glacier. In this research, only the GPR acquired data using unshielded antenna with central frequency of 25 MHz along one line in Alam-kuh glacier, Kelardasht- Mazandaran, have been processed and interpreted. The GPR data acquisition has been done by using common offset method, and transmitter-receiver separation of 6 meters. The final real radargram related to one of the surveyed GPR profiles in this region has been prepared after applying various processing operations containing signal saturation correction, amplitude gain, f-k migration filtering and static (topography) correction on the raw data. After applying processing sequences on the acquired data, the EM waves reflection off the interfaces of different layers including the reflections from the glacier basement have been detected, and by assigning a suitable EM wave velocity in the ice (0.16 m/ns), the thickness of 50 m for the ice layer laid under the survey line has been estimated. Also, in present research, forward and inverse modeling of GPR data have been performed to employ for snow, ice and glaciological investigations in the AlamKooh region of Mazandaran. To achieve this goal, GPR response of synthetic model corresponding to the real radargram was simulated first, by 2-D finite-difference time domain (FDTD) method. Afterward the inversion method by solving an optimization problem was employed to validate the interpretation of real GPR data.
Methodology and Approaches
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Based on the nature, physical and geometric properties of the subsurface target in the field data, their synthetic model have been built and their two-dimensional GPR responses forward modeling using ReflexW software and finite difference algorithms improved in the frequency domain, have been obtained. Also, it has been used an effective algorithm, coded in GUI environment of MATLAB programming software and as a result, a reliable and accurate inverse modeling has been carried out. In the present study, to simulate the behavior of the propagation of EM waves in GPR method, two-dimensional finite difference method has been used. The main advantage of this method is its comparative simplicity of the concept, high accuracy and simple implementation for complex and arbitrary models as well as easily adjusting the antenna when applied. In this study, acquisition of GPR field data and synthetic data modeling have been carried out in TM mode. The radargrams of the GPR data have been demonstrated using ReflexW software after performing necessary processing sequences.
Results and Conclusions
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; The obtained results reveal that moraine materials covering the surface of the area are mainly fine-grained granite. The bed-rock or basement in the area is also granite. The polarity representing ice-bed rock is clearly seen on the GPR profiles. The topography of the glacier basement has successfully been detectable using just by GPR method. The electrical resistive nature of the glacier has caused large penetration depth of GPR pulses in this research. Furthermore, the results of the research for presented profiles on the basis of forward and inverse modeling output of GPR data in comparison with real GPR radargrams in the region validated the accuracy of GPR investigations in the area. Although with a quick glance, the error obtained by the inverse modeling for real GPR data seems unexpected and unacceptable, absolutely the high rate of error depends on many factors influencing on the real earth models containing various limitations existing in all forward modeling algorithms and software packages, impossibility of making forward modeling exactly according to the real models (due to the complex nature of the ground), taking into account the homogeneity and uniform host environment and targets in the modeling process unlike the diversity, the presence of different types of noises and so on. Therefore, making a controlled geophysical test site and trying performance of inverse modeling algorithm for field GPR data in this site, as well as determining the important physical parameters such as dielectric permittivity and electrical conductivity by experimental method through sampling from different depths for complex geological environments are suggested../files/site1/files/124/1ahmadpur%DA%86%DA%A9%DB%8C%D8%AF%D9%87.pdf</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>543</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>570</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>افسانه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>احمدپور</Family>
				<NameE>Afsaneh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ahmadpour</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>aahmadpour_madan@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>ابوالقاسم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>کامکارروحانی</Family>
				<NameE>Abolghasem</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Kamkar Rouhani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>kamkarr@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>رضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>احمدی</Family>
				<NameE>Reza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ahmadi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی اراک</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه صنعتی اراک</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Rezahmadi@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Ground-penetrating radar (GPR)</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Snow</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ice and glaciology</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Alam-Kooh Glacier of Mazandaran</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Forward modeling</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Inverse modeling  </KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>رادار نفوذی به زمین (GPR)</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>برف و یخ و یخبندان‌شناسی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>یخچال علم‌کوه مازندران</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدل‌سازی پیش‌رو</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدل‌سازی وارون</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1. صداقت م.، معماریان ح.، &quot;زمین‌شناسی فیزیکی&quot;، جلد 1، چاپ 6، (1369) 413-435. 2. وزیری ف.، &quot;هیدرولوژی کاربردی در ایران (شناسایی یخچال های طبیعی در ایران)&quot;، جلد دوم، چاپ اول، سازمان مدیریت و برنامه‌ریزی کشور، معاونت امور پشتیبانی، مرکز مدارک علمی و انتشارات، تهران (1382) 104-108. 3. Eder K., Reidler C., Mayer C., Leopold M., &quot;Crevasse detection in Alpien areas using ground penetrating radar as a component for a mountain gulde system&quot;, The International Archives of the Photogrammetry, Remote Sensing and Spatial Inf. Sci., 37 (2008) 838-839. 4. Hagg w., Mayer c., Lambrecht A. Kriegel D., &quot;Glacier changes in the Big Naryn basin&quot;, Central Tian Shan, Global and Planetary Change. in press (2012). 5. Barnett T. P., Adam J. C., Lettenmaier D. P., &quot;Potential impacts of a warming climate on water availability in snow dominated regions&quot;, Nature, 438 (7066) (2005) 303-309. 6. ولدان زوج م. ج.، رضایی ی.، وزیری ف.، مباشری م. ر.، &quot;بررسی یخچال طبیعی علم‌چال با استفاده از تصاویر ماهواره‌ای KNTU&quot;، شمارۀ 70، دوره 18، (1386) 3-4. 7. Lrvine-Fynn T. D. L., Moorman B. J., Williams J. L. M., Walter F. S. A, &quot;Seasonal changes in Ground penetrating radar signature observed at a polythermal glacier&quot;, Bylot Island, Canada, Earth Surface processes and Landforms., 31, 7 (2006) 892-909. 8. Kennett, P., &quot;Reconnaissance gravity and magnetic surveys of part of the Larsen ice shelf and adjacent mainland&quot;, British Antarctic Survey Bulletin, 8 (1966) 49-62. 9. Crossley D. J., Clarke G. K. C., &quot;Gravity Measurements on “Fox Glacier”, Yukon Territory&quot;, Canada, Journal of Glaciology, 9 (1970) 363-374. 10. Bose R. N., Dutta N. P., Lahiri S. M., &quot;Refraction Seismic Investigation at Zemu Glacier&quot;, Sikkim, Journal of Glaciology, 10 (1971) 113-119. 11. Hubbard B., Glasser N., &quot;Field techniques in glaciology and glacial geomorphology&quot;, John Wiley and Sons Ltd, Chichester: UK, 400 (2005). 12. Gibas J., Rachlewicz G., Szczucinski W., &quot;Application of DC resistivity soundings and geomorphological surveys in studies of modern Arctic glacier marginal zones&quot;, Petuniabukta, Spitsbergen, Polish Polar Reserch., 26, 4 (2005) 239-258. 13. Reynolds J. M., &quot;The role of geophysics in glacial hazard assessment&quot;, First Break, 24 (9) (2006) 61-66. 14. David E., James W., David R., &quot;Shallow seismic surveys and ice thickness estimates of the Mullins Valley debris-covered glacier&quot;, McMurdo Dry Valleys, Antarctica, Antarctic Science., 19 (2007) 485-496. 15. Angelopoulos M. C., Pollard W. H., Couture N. J., &quot;The application of CCR and GPR to characterize ground ice conditions at Parsons Lake, Northwest Territories, Cold Regions Science and Technology, 85 (-2013) 22-33. 16. Apparao A., &quot;Development in geoelectrical methods&quot;, Balkema (-1997). 17. Stern W., &quot;Versucheiner elektrodynamischen dickenmessung von gletschereis&quot;, Gerl. Beitr. Zur Geophysik., 23 (1929) 292-333. 18. Watson M. I., Yelf R. J., Bertler N. A N., &quot;Bedrock topography and Isochrone mapping of five glaciers in Victoria Land&quot;, Antarctica, 12th International Conference on Ground Penetrating Radar (2008). 19. Binder D., Bruckl E., Roch K. H., Behm M., Schoner W., Hynek B., &quot;Determination of total ice volume and ice-thikness distribution of tow glaciers in the Hohe Tauern region&quot;, Eastern Alps, from GPR data, Annals of Glaciology., 50, 51, (2009) 71-79. 20. Previati M., Godio A., Ferraris, S., &quot;Validation of spatial variability of snowpack thickness and density obtained with GPR and TDR methods, J. of. Applied Geophysics., 75, (2011) 284-293. 21. Robin G. D. Q., Evans S., Bailey J. T., &quot;Interpretation of radio echo sounding in polar ice sheets&quot;, Philos. T. R. Soc. A, 265 (1969) 437-505. 22. Bauder A., Funk M., Gudmundsson G. H., &quot;The ice-thickness distribution of Unteraargletscher&quot;, Switzerland, Ann. Glaciol., 37 (2003) 331-336. 23. Brandt O., Langley K., Kohler J., Hamran S. E., &quot;Detection of buried ice and sediment layers in permafrost using multi-frequency Ground Penetrating Radar: A case examination on Svalbard&quot;, Remote Sensing of Environment., 111, 2 (2007) 213-226. 24. Singh S. K., Rathore B. P., Bahuguna I. M., Ramnathan A. L., &quot;Estimation of glacier ice thickness using Ground Penetrating Radar in the Himalayan Region&quot;, Current Science., 103, 1, ( 2012) 68-73. 25. Heilig A., Eisen O., Schneebeli M. &quot;Temporal observations of a seasonal snowpack using upward-looking GPR, Hydrol. Process., 24 (2010) 3133-3145. 26. Machguth H., Eisen O., Paul F., Hoelzle M., &quot;Strong spatial variability of snow accumulation observed with helicopter-borne GPR on two adjacent Alpine glaciers&quot;, Geophys. Res. Lett., 33 (2006) L13503. 27. Sold L., Huss M., Hoelzle M., Andereggen H., Joerg P. C., Zemp M., &quot;Methodological approaches to infer end-of-winter snow distribution on alpine glaciers&quot;, J. Glaciol., 59 (2013) 1047-1059. 28. Helfricht K., Kuhn M., Keuschnig M., Heilig A., &quot;Lidar snow cover studies on glaciers in the Ötztal Alps (Austria): comparison with snow depths calculated from GPR measurements&quot;, The Cryosphere, 8 (2014) 41-57. 29. Arcone S. A., Spikes V. B., Hamilton G. S., Mayewski P. A., &quot;Stratigraphic continuity in 400 MHz short-pulse radar profiles of firn in West Antarctica&quot;, Ann. Glaciol., 39 (2004)195-200. 30. Huybrechts P., Rybak O., Steinhage D., Pattyn F., &quot;Past and present accumulation rate reconstruction along the Dome Fuji-Kohnen radio-echo sounding profile&quot;, Dronning Maud Land, East Antarctica, Ann. Glaciol., 50 (2009) 112-120. 31. Azam M. F, Wagnon P., Ramanathan A., Vincent C., Sharma P., Arnaud Y., Linda A., Pottakkal J. G., Chevallier P., Singh V. B., Berthier E., &quot;Form balance to imbalance: A shift in the dynamic behaviour of Chhota Shigri glacier&quot;, western Himalaya, India, Journal of Glaciology,5:208 (2012) 315-324. 32. Miège C., Forster R. R., Box J. E., Burgess E. W., Mc-CONNELL J. R., Pasteris D. R., Spikes V. B., &quot;Southeast Greenland high accumulation rates derived from firn cores and ground-penetrating radar&quot;, Ann. Glaciol., 54 (2013) 322-332. 33. Hawley R. L., Courville Z. R., Kehrl L. M., Lutz E. R., Osterberg E. C., Overly T. B., Wong G. J., &quot;Recent accumulation variability in northwest Greenland from ground-penetrating radar and shallow cores along the Greenland Inland Traverse&quot;, J. Glaciol., 60 (2014) 375-382. 34. Fischer A., Span N., Kuhn M., Helfricht K., Stocker-Waldhuber M., Seiser B., Massimo M., Butschek M., &quot;Ground-penetrating radar (GPR) point measurements of ice thickness in Austria. Institute for Interdisciplinary Mountain Research of the Austrian Academy of Sciences (2015). 35. Li T., Zhao J., Jiao Y., Hou J., Mu L., &quot;Regional characteristics of sea ice thickness in Canadian shelf and Arctic Archipelago measured by Ground Penetrating Radar&quot;, Acta Oceanol Sin., 2015, Vol. 34, No. 5 (2015) 110-116. 36. Sinisalo A., Fujita K., Gustafsson J., Fukuda T., Joshi Sh., Stumm D., and Shea J., &quot;Ice thickness and thermal structure of a high altitude Himalayan glacier&quot;, Geophysical Research Abstracts, Vol. 18 (2016) EGU2016-11636. 37. Blindow N., Eisenburger D., Illich B., Petzold H., Richter T., &quot;Ground penetrating radar, In Environmental Geology (Eds K.Knödel, G.Lange and H.-J.Voigt) (2007) 283-335, Springer. 38. Parasnis D. S., &quot;Principles of applied geophysics&quot;, 5th edition, Chapman and Hall (1997). 39. Neal A., &quot;Ground-penetrating radar and its use in sedimentology: principles, problems and progress&quot;, Earth-science Reviews., 66 (2004) 261-330. 40. Van Overmeeren R. A., &quot;Georadar for hydrogeology&quot;, First break, 8 (1994) 401-4081. 41. Milsom J., Field Geophysics, John Wiley and Sons Ltd, (2003) 168-174. 42. Jol H. M., &quot;Ground Penitrating Radar: Theory and Applications&quot;, Oxford: Elsevier Science (2009) 508. 43. پرنو س.، پایان‌نامه ارشد:&quot;پردازش، مدل‌سازی و تفسیر داده‌های GPR به‌منظور تعیین عمق، ضخامت و محدودۀ جانبی یخچال‌ها در منطقه علم‌کوه مازندران&quot;، دانشکده مهندسی معدن، نفت و ژئوفیزیک، دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود (1393). 44. Tzanis A., &quot;MatGPR Release 2: A freeware MATLAB package for the analysis &amp; interpretation of common and single offset GPR data, FastTimes, 15(1) )2010( 17-43. 45. Karimi N., Farokhnia A., Shishangosht S., Elmi M., Eftekhari M., Ghalkhani H., &quot;Elevation changes of Alamkouh glacier in Iran since 1955, based on remote sensing data&quot;, International J. of Applied Earth Observation and Geoinformation., 19 (2012 a) 45-58. 46. Daniels D. J., &quot;Ground penetrating radar, The Institution of Electrical Engineers&quot;, The Institution of Electrical Engineers, Londo,United Kingdom (2004) 75-84 and 455-460. 47. Palli A., &quot;Polythrmal glacier studies in Svalbard determined by ground penetrating radar&quot;, Departmant of geosciences university of oulu, (2003) 15-17. 48. Annan ‌A. P., &quot;Ground penetrating radar workshop notes&quot;, Sensors and software Inc,Mississauga, ON, Canada (2001). ##1. صداقت م.، معماریان ح.، &quot;زمین‌شناسی فیزیکی&quot;، جلد 1، چاپ 6، (1369) 413-435. ##2. وزیری ف.، &quot;هیدرولوژی کاربردی در ایران (شناسایی یخچال های طبیعی در ایران)&quot;، جلد دوم، چاپ اول، سازمان مدیریت و برنامه‌ریزی کشور، معاونت امور پشتیبانی، مرکز مدارک علمی و انتشارات، تهران (1382) 104-108. ##3. Eder K., Reidler C., Mayer C., Leopold M., &quot;Crevasse detection in Alpien areas using ground penetrating radar as a component for a mountain gulde system&quot;, The International Archives of the Photogrammetry, Remote Sensing and Spatial Inf. Sci., 37 (2008) 838-839.## 4. Hagg w., Mayer c., Lambrecht A. Kriegel D., &quot;Glacier changes in the Big Naryn basin&quot;, Central Tian Shan, Global and Planetary Change. in press (2012).## 5. Barnett T. P., Adam J. C., Lettenmaier D. P., &quot;Potential impacts of a warming climate on water availability in snow dominated regions&quot;, Nature, 438 (7066) (2005) 303-309. ##6. ولدان زوج م. ج.، رضایی ی.، وزیری ف.، مباشری م. ر.، &quot;بررسی یخچال طبیعی علم‌چال با استفاده از تصاویر ماهواره‌ای KNTU&quot;، شمارۀ 70، دوره 18، (1386) 3-4.## 7. Lrvine-Fynn T. D. L., Moorman B. J., Williams J. L. M., Walter F. S. A, &quot;Seasonal changes in Ground penetrating radar signature observed at a polythermal glacier&quot;, Bylot Island, Canada, Earth Surface processes and Landforms., 31, 7 (2006) 892-909.## 8. Kennett, P., &quot;Reconnaissance gravity and magnetic surveys of part of the Larsen ice shelf and adjacent mainland&quot;, British Antarctic Survey Bulletin, 8 (1966) 49-62.## 9. Crossley D. J., Clarke G. K. C., &quot;Gravity Measurements on “Fox Glacier”, Yukon Territory&quot;, Canada, Journal of Glaciology, 9 (1970) 363-374. ##10. Bose R. N., Dutta N. P., Lahiri S. M., &quot;Refraction Seismic Investigation at Zemu Glacier&quot;, Sikkim, Journal of Glaciology, 10 (1971) 113-119.## 11. Hubbard B., Glasser N., &quot;Field techniques in glaciology and glacial geomorphology&quot;, John Wiley and Sons Ltd, Chichester: UK, 400 (2005).## 12. Gibas J., Rachlewicz G., Szczucinski W., &quot;Application of DC resistivity soundings and geomorphological surveys in studies of modern Arctic glacier marginal zones&quot;, Petuniabukta, Spitsbergen, Polish Polar Reserch., 26, 4 (2005) 239-258. ##13. Reynolds J. M., &quot;The role of geophysics in glacial hazard assessment&quot;, First Break, 24 (9) (2006) 61-66.## 14. David E., James W., David R., &quot;Shallow seismic surveys and ice thickness estimates of the Mullins Valley debris-covered glacier&quot;, McMurdo Dry Valleys, Antarctica, Antarctic Science., 19 (2007) 485-496. ##15. Angelopoulos M. C., Pollard W. H., Couture N. J., &quot;The application of CCR and GPR to characterize ground ice conditions at Parsons Lake, Northwest Territories, Cold Regions Science and Technology, 85 (-2013) 22-33.## 16. Apparao A., &quot;Development in geoelectrical methods&quot;, Balkema (-1997).## 17. Stern W., &quot;Versucheiner elektrodynamischen dickenmessung von gletschereis&quot;, Gerl. Beitr. Zur Geophysik., 23 (1929) 292-333.## 18. Watson M. I., Yelf R. J., Bertler N. A N., &quot;Bedrock topography and Isochrone mapping of five glaciers in Victoria Land&quot;, Antarctica, 12th International Conference on Ground Penetrating Radar (2008). ##19. Binder D., Bruckl E., Roch K. H., Behm M., Schoner W., Hynek B., &quot;Determination of total ice volume and ice-thikness distribution of tow glaciers in the Hohe Tauern region&quot;, Eastern Alps, from GPR data, Annals of Glaciology., 50, 51, (2009) 71-79. ##20. Previati M., Godio A., Ferraris, S., &quot;Validation of spatial variability of snowpack thickness and density obtained with GPR and TDR methods, J. of. Applied Geophysics., 75, (2011) 284-293.## 21. Robin G. D. Q., Evans S., Bailey J. T., &quot;Interpretation of radio echo sounding in polar ice sheets&quot;, Philos. T. R. Soc. A, 265 (1969) 437-505.## 22. Bauder A., Funk M., Gudmundsson G. H., &quot;The ice-thickness distribution of Unteraargletscher&quot;, Switzerland, Ann. Glaciol., 37 (2003) 331-336. ##23. Brandt O., Langley K., Kohler J., Hamran S. E., &quot;Detection of buried ice and sediment layers in permafrost using multi-frequency Ground Penetrating Radar: A case examination on Svalbard&quot;, Remote Sensing of Environment., 111, 2 (2007) 213-226.## 24. Singh S. K., Rathore B. P., Bahuguna I. M., Ramnathan A. L., &quot;Estimation of glacier ice thickness using Ground Penetrating Radar in the Himalayan Region&quot;, Current Science., 103, 1, ( 2012) 68-73. ##25. Heilig A., Eisen O., Schneebeli M. &quot;Temporal observations of a seasonal snowpack using upward-looking GPR, Hydrol. Process., 24 (2010) 3133-3145. ##26. Machguth H., Eisen O., Paul F., Hoelzle M., &quot;Strong spatial variability of snow accumulation observed with helicopter-borne GPR on two adjacent Alpine glaciers&quot;, Geophys. Res. Lett., 33 (2006) L13503.## 27. Sold L., Huss M., Hoelzle M., Andereggen H., Joerg P. C., Zemp M., &quot;Methodological approaches to infer end-of-winter snow distribution on alpine glaciers&quot;, J. Glaciol., 59 (2013) 1047-1059.## 28. Helfricht K., Kuhn M., Keuschnig M., Heilig A., &quot;Lidar snow cover studies on glaciers in the Ötztal Alps (Austria): comparison with snow depths calculated from GPR measurements&quot;, The Cryosphere, 8 (2014) 41-57.## 29. Arcone S. A., Spikes V. B., Hamilton G. S., Mayewski P. A., &quot;Stratigraphic continuity in 400 MHz short-pulse radar profiles of firn in West Antarctica&quot;, Ann. Glaciol., 39 (2004)195-200.##30. Huybrechts P., Rybak O., Steinhage D., Pattyn F., &quot;Past and present accumulation rate reconstruction along the Dome Fuji-Kohnen radio-echo sounding profile&quot;, Dronning Maud Land, East Antarctica, Ann. Glaciol., 50 (2009) 112-120. ##31. Azam M. F, Wagnon P., Ramanathan A., Vincent C., Sharma P., Arnaud Y., Linda A., Pottakkal J. G., Chevallier P., Singh V. B., Berthier E., &quot;Form balance to imbalance: A shift in the dynamic behaviour of Chhota Shigri glacier&quot;, western Himalaya, India, Journal of Glaciology,5:208 (2012) 315-324. ##32. Miège C., Forster R. R., Box J. E., Burgess E. W., Mc-CONNELL J. R., Pasteris D. R., Spikes V. B., &quot;Southeast Greenland high accumulation rates derived from firn cores and ground-penetrating radar&quot;, Ann. Glaciol., 54 (2013) 322-332. ##33. Hawley R. L., Courville Z. R., Kehrl L. M., Lutz E. R., Osterberg E. C., Overly T. B., Wong G. J., &quot;Recent accumulation variability in northwest Greenland from ground-penetrating radar and shallow cores along the Greenland Inland Traverse&quot;, J. Glaciol., 60 (2014) 375-382.##34. Fischer A., Span N., Kuhn M., Helfricht K., Stocker-Waldhuber M., Seiser B., Massimo M., Butschek M., &quot;Ground-penetrating radar (GPR) point measurements of ice thickness in Austria. Institute for Interdisciplinary Mountain Research of the Austrian Academy of Sciences (2015). ##35. Li T., Zhao J., Jiao Y., Hou J., Mu L., &quot;Regional characteristics of sea ice thickness in Canadian shelf and Arctic Archipelago measured by Ground Penetrating Radar&quot;, Acta Oceanol Sin., 2015, Vol. 34, No. 5 (2015) 110-116. ##36. Sinisalo A., Fujita K., Gustafsson J., Fukuda T., Joshi Sh., Stumm D., and Shea J., &quot;Ice thickness and thermal structure of a high altitude Himalayan glacier&quot;, Geophysical Research Abstracts, Vol. 18 (2016) EGU2016-11636.## 37. Blindow N., Eisenburger D., Illich B., Petzold H., Richter T., &quot;Ground penetrating radar, In Environmental Geology (Eds K.Knödel, G.Lange and H.-J.Voigt) (2007) 283-335, Springer. ##38. Parasnis D. S., &quot;Principles of applied geophysics&quot;, 5th edition, Chapman and Hall (1997).## 39. Neal A., &quot;Ground-penetrating radar and its use in sedimentology: principles, problems and progress&quot;, Earth-science Reviews., 66 (2004) 261-330. ##40. Van Overmeeren R. A., &quot;Georadar for hydrogeology&quot;, First break, 8 (1994) 401-4081. ##41. Milsom J., Field Geophysics, John Wiley and Sons Ltd, (2003) 168-174. ##42. Jol H. M., &quot;Ground Penitrating Radar: Theory and Applications&quot;, Oxford: Elsevier Science (2009) 508.## 43. پرنو س.، پایان‌نامه ارشد:&quot;پردازش، مدل‌سازی و تفسیر داده‌های GPR به‌منظور تعیین عمق، ضخامت و محدودۀ جانبی یخچال‌ها در منطقه علم‌کوه مازندران&quot;، دانشکده مهندسی معدن، نفت و ژئوفیزیک، دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود (1393).## 44. Tzanis A., &quot;MatGPR Release 2: A freeware MATLAB package for the analysis &amp; interpretation of common and single offset GPR data, FastTimes, 15(1) )2010( 17-43. ##45. Karimi N., Farokhnia A., Shishangosht S., Elmi M., Eftekhari M., Ghalkhani H., &quot;Elevation changes of Alamkouh glacier in Iran since 1955, based on remote sensing data&quot;, International J. of Applied Earth Observation and Geoinformation., 19 (2012 a) 45-58. ##46. Daniels D. J., &quot;Ground penetrating radar, The Institution of Electrical Engineers&quot;, The Institution of Electrical Engineers, Londo,United Kingdom (2004) 75-84 and 455-460.## 47. Palli A., &quot;Polythrmal glacier studies in Svalbard determined by ground penetrating radar&quot;, Departmant of geosciences university of oulu, (2003) 15-17. ##48. Annan ‌A. P., &quot;Ground penetrating radar workshop notes&quot;, Sensors and software Inc,Mississauga, ON, Canada (2001). ## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی عددی و پارامتریک زمین نرم به‌سازی شده با ستون سنگی مسلح به ژئوگرید</TitleF>
		<TitleE> Parametric and Numerical Study on Soft Ground Improvement using Stone Column Reinforced with Geogrid </TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>تکنیک&#8204;های مختلفی به&#8204;منظور به&#8204;سازی خاک&#8204;های نرم ارائه شده است. یکی از مناسب&#8204;ترین روش&#8204;ها استفاده از ستون&#8204;های سنگی است. ظرفیت باربری ستون&#8204;های سنگی وابسته به احاطه کردن خاک نرم در یک سلول محیطی است. از این&#8204;رو یکی از روش&#8204;های مورد نیاز برای افزایش تنش دورگیر در ستون&#8204;های سنگی استفاده از روکش&#173;&#8204;های ژئوگرید است. در این مقاله، تأثیر روکش&#8204;های ژئوگریدی در بازسازی ستون سنگی و تأثیر پارامترهای مختلف از قبیل درصد جای&#8204;گزینی، طول و سختی عناصر تسلیح در کاهش تغییرشکل زمین و افزایش ظرفیت باربری بررسی شد. هم&#8204;چنین نتایج برای ستون&#8204;های سنگی با و بدون عناصر تسلیح ارائه شده است. به&#8204;منظور تحلیل عددی خاک نرم به&#8204;سازی شده با ستون سنگی از نرم&#8204;افزارPLAXIS 2D استفاده شد. نتایج نشان داد که ظرفیت ستون سنگی با عناصر تسلیح افزایش یافته است. هم&#8204;چنین با افزایش طول و سختی عناصر تسلیح، ظرفیت باربری افزایش می&#8204;یابد. در نهایت یک ضریب نسبت نشست براساس نسبت نشست زمین به&#8204;سازی شده به زمین به&#8204;سازی نشده ارائه شده است. زمین به&#8204;سازی شده با استفاده از ستون سنگی با و بدون عناصر تسلیح باعث کاهش نسبت نشست می&#8204;شود. در نهایت مقدار نسبت نشست حاصل از این بررسی با رابطۀ ارائه شدۀ پورشاسب و مایرهوف در سال 1997 مقایسه شد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Introduction
The design engineers usually follow a specific decision-making process for optimal selection of the type of required foundation and its design. In this state, in case the surface foundation is not appropriate for the project conditions, before making any decisions about the use of deep foundations, the proper methods for optimization of the liquefied soil should be evaluated in order to compare the advantages and disadvantages of each of them with those of deep foundation, in terms of efficiency, implementation problems, costs, and finally to select the best choice. One of the best methods of soil improvement is the use of stone columns. The rationale behind the use of stone columns is the high shear strength of materials and the provision of lateral grip by surrounding soil. Therefore, the stone column can receive the load from the structure, and transfer it to the resistant layers. In the soils with low shear resistance, the lateral constraint crated by the surrounding soils is not enough for preventing the sideway buckling of the column under which is subjected to the loads. Thus, special measures should be considered for the use of stone columns in these soils. One of these methods is the use of reinforcement shelves such as geogrid and geotextile. Investigating the previous studies, the lack of evaluation of the design parameters such as the settlement ratio of the soil improved by the reinforced stone column to the geogrid, and provision of design graphs in this regard, has been revealed. Therefore, by extension of the studies conducted by Chub Basti et al. in 2011, the design graphs were provided in this regard.
Material and methods
The PLAXIS V8 Software was used for modelling the soft soil improved by the stone column. For increasing the precision of the results, the 15-knot element was used in the current study. The fine mesh was used in the models made for the analysis of the problem. For simulation of the improved soft soil with the stone column in a single cell, the modelling was implemented in a two-dimensional environment in axial symmetry conditions. In the current study, it was assumed the rigid foundation is on the improved bed. Thus, for analysis of the simulated model, a vertical strain up to 2% of the soft soil height has been applied on the ground. Also, for simulation of the soil behavior, an appropriate model of soil and parameters proportional to the materials should be allocated to the construct geometry. The non-linear stress-strain of the soil in different levels of the problem can be simulated. The number of model parameters increases with the level of problem rupture. For precise simulation, we need the proper parameters of the materials. For modeling of soft soils and stone columns, elastic-plastic model with Mohr-Coulomb rupture criterion was used. In the current study, it was assumed the soft bed is located on a very hard layer of soil. Therefore, the vertical deformation was prevented on this horizontal boundary. Also, the horizontal deformation in two vertical edges was prevented and only deformation in vertical direction was allowed. The soft bed close to saturation was considered without the determined free water level. For models with stone columns, the element of interface between the stone column and soft soil, has been used. The reason behind using this element is that the stone column rupture is of shear form and due to this, a significant shear stress is created on the common surface between the stone column and soft soil. The percentage of the replacement area is defined as the ratio of the total area of the stone columns to the total area of the non-improved area. In the current study, the percentage of the replacement area is utilized between 10 to 30%, which is used in implementation. Also, the diameter of the stone columns is from 0.6 to 1.2, in the analyses.
Results and discussion
The results of the numerical study were compared with the existing theoretical relationships provided by Poorooshasb and Meyerhof (1997), and Pulko et al. (2011). Figure 1 shows the comparison of the replacement percentage (RP) and settlement ratio (SR) in the non-reinforced state in the current study as well as theoretical relationships proposed by the previous researchers. Based on this figure, there is a difference between the results of the current study and those of Poorooshasb and Meyerhof (1997), and Pulko et al (2011). Poorooshasb and Meyerhof (1997) calculated the settlement ratio in their proposed material with the assumption of linear elasticity of the materials without consideration for plastic settlement. Therefore, the settlement of the improved soft soil with stone column, calculated by Poorooshasb and Meyerhof, would not show the real amount. However, Pulko et al. (2011), with consideration for the elastoplastic behavior of the materials, the lateral expansion of the stone column, and the primary stress of the soil around the column, provided more realistic results that correspond closely with the present study. Also, for designing the stone column, the results of its reinforcement have been also provided in the graph presented in Figure 2. Thus, by the use of these graphs, the ratio of settlement reduction can be obtained for each distance between columns and with different percentages of alternatives../files/site1/files/124/2jalili%DA%86%DA%A9%DB%8C%D8%AF%D9%87.pdf</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>571</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>598</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهدی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>جلیلی</Family>
				<NameE>Mehdi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Jalili</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد سمنان،  دانشکدۀ فنی و مهندسی، گروه مهندسی عمران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد سمنان،</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>m.jalili@semnaniau.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>امین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>زارع</Family>
				<NameE>Amin</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Zare</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد سمنان،  دانشکدۀ فنی و مهندسی، گروه مهندسی عمران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد سمنان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمدجواد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شعبانی</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad Javad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Shabani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه خوارزمی، دانشکدۀ فنی مهندسی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه خوارزمی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>soil improvement</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>stone column</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>geogrid coating</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>bearing capacity</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>settlement ratio.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>به‌سازی خاک</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ستون سنگی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>روکش ژئوگریدی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ظرفیت باربری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نسبت نشست</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1.	Barksdale R. D., Bachus R. C., &quot;Design and construction of stone column&quot;, FHWA/RD-December (1983). 2.	Lee J. S., Pande G. N. &quot;Analysis of stone column reinforced foundations&quot;, Int J Numer Anal Meth Geomech (1998) 22:1001–1020. 3.	Mokhtari M., Kalantari B., &quot;Soft soil stabilization using stone columns-A Review&quot;, Department of civil engineering, University of Hormozgan, Bandar Abbas, Iran (2012). 4.	Hughes J. M. O., Withers N. J., Greenwood D. A., &quot;A field trial of reinforcing effect of stone column in soil&quot;, Proc., Ground Treatment by Deep Compaction, Institution of Civil Engineers, London (1976) 32-44. 5.	Madhav M. R., Vitkar P. P., &quot;Strip footing on weak clay stabilized with a granular trench or pile&quot;, Can.Geotech. J (1978) 15(4) 605-609. 6.	Aboshi H., Ichimoto E., Harada K., Emoki M., &quot;The composer-A method to improve the characteristics of soft clays by inclusion of large diameter sand columns&quot;, Proc., Int. Conf. on Soil Reinforcement (1979) E.N.P.C., 1, Paris 211-216. 7.	Greenwood D. A., &quot;Mechanical improvement of soils below ground surfaces&quot;, Proc., Ground Engineering Conf., Institution of Civil Engineers, London (1970) 11-22. 8.	Jellali B., Bouassida M., De Buhan P., &quot;A homogenization method for estimating the bearing capacity of soils reinforced by stone columns&quot;, Int. J. Numer. Analyt. Meth. Geomech (2005) 29(10) 989-1004. 9.	Priebe H. J., &quot;The design of vibro replacement&quot;, Ground Eng (1995) 28(12) 31-37. 10.	Poorooshasb H. B., Meyerhof G. G., &quot;Analysis of behavior of stone columns and lime columns&quot;, comput geotech 20 (1) (1997) 47-70. 11.	McCabe B. A., McNeill J. A., Black J. A., &quot;Ground Improvement Using the Vibro-Stone Column Technique&quot;, The Institution of Engineers of Ireland (2007). 12.	Isaac D. S., &quot;Suitability of Different Materials for Stone Column Construction&quot;, M. Tech Thesis, College of engineering Trivandrum (2009). 13.	Gniel J., Bouazza A., &quot;Improvement of soft soils using geogrid encased stone columns&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes 27 (2009) 167-175. 14.	Halabian A. M., Naeemifar I., Hashemolhosseini S. H., &quot;Numerical analysis of vertically loaded rammed aggregate piers and pier groups&quot;, Ground Improvement (2012) 167-181. 15.	شعبانی م. ج.، روشن‌ضمیر م. ع.، &quot;بررسی عددی پایداری شیروانی ماسه‌ای روی رس نرم به‌سازی شده با ستون سنگی&quot;، مجله علمی و پژوهشی شریف، دورۀ 2.32، شمارۀ 2.3 (1395) 132-125. 16.	Murugesan s., Rajagopal k., &quot;Geosynthetic-encased stone columns: Numerical evaluation&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes 24 (2006) 349-358. 17.	Ambily A. P., Grandhi S. R., &quot;Behavior of stone columns based on experimental and FEM analysis&quot;, J Geotech Geoenviron Eng ASCE (2007) 133(4) 405-415. 18.	Zahmatkesh A., Choobbasti A. J., &quot;Settlement evaluation of soft clay reinforced with stone columns using the equivalent secant modulus&quot;, Arab J Geisci, 5 (2010) 103-109. 19.	Deb K., Chandra S., Basudhar P. K., &quot;Response of multilayer geosynthetic-reinforced bed resting on soft soil with stone columns&quot;, Computers and Geotechnics, 35 (2008) 323-330. 20.	Deb K., Samadhiya N. K., Namdeo J. B., &quot;Laboratory model studies on unreinforced and geofrid-reinforced sand bed over stone column-improved soft clay&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes, 29 (2011) 190-196. 21.	Mengfei Q., Xie Q., Cao X., Zhao W., He J., and Jin J., &quot;Model test of stone columns as liquefaction countermeasure in sandy soils&quot;, Frontiers of Structural and Civil Engineering 10, No. 4 (2016) 481-487. 22.	Gniel J., Abdelmalek Bouazza A., &quot;Improvement of soft soils using geogrid encased stone columns&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes 27.3 (2009) 167-175.  23.	Ghazavi M., Nazari Afshar J., &quot;Bearing capacity of geosynthetic encased stone columns&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes (2013) 1-11. 24.	Hosseinpour I., Riccio M., Almeida M. S. S., &quot;Numerical evaluation of a granular column reinforced by geosynthetics using encasement and laminated disks&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes 42 (2014) 363-373. 25.	Tang L., Cong S., Ling X., Lu, J., Elgamal A., &quot;Numerical study on ground improvement for liquefaction mitigation using stone columns encased with geosynthetics&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes (2015) 1-6. 26.	Hosseinpour I., Almeida M., and Riccio M., &quot;Ground improvement of soft soil by geotextile-encased columns&quot;, Proceedings of the Institution of Civil Engineers-Ground Improvement 169, no. 4 (2016) 297-305. 27.	Choobbasti A. J., Zahmatkesh A., Noorzad R., &quot;Performance of Stone Columns in Soft Clay: Numerical Evaluation&quot;, Geotech Geol Eng. 29 (2011) 675-684. 28.	Cooper M. R., Rose A. N., &quot;Stone column support for an embankment on deep alluvial soils&quot;, Proceedings of the institution of civil engineers-geotechnical engineering (1999) 137(1) 15-25. 29.	Brinkgreve R. B., Vermeer P. A., &quot;Plaxis-finite element code for soil and rocks analysis&quot;, Version 8. Rotterdam Brookfield: AA. Balkema (1998). 30.	Hu W., Wood D. M., Steward W., &quot;Ground improvement using stone column foundation: results of model tests&quot;, Proc. Int. Conf. on Ground Improvement techniques, Macau (1997) 247-256. 31.	Narasimha Rao S., Madhiyan M., Prasad Y. V. S. N., &quot;Influence of bearing area on the behavior of stone columns&quot;, Proc., Indian Geotech. Conf., Calcutta, India (1992) 235-237. 32.	Christian J. T, Carrier W. D., Janbu Bjerrum and Kjaernsli’s chart reinterpreted. Canadian Geotechnical Journal, 15 (1978) 123-128. 33.	Elshazly H., Elkasabgy M., Elleboudy A., &quot;Effect of Inter-Column Spacing on Soil Stresses due to Vibro-Installed Stone Columns: Interesting Findings&quot;, Geotech Geol Eng. 26 (2008) 225-236. 34.	Pulko B., Majes B., &amp; Logar J., &quot;Geosynthetic-encased stone columns: analytical calculation model&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes, 29 (1) (2011) 29-39. ##1.	Barksdale R. D., Bachus R. C., &quot;Design and construction of stone column&quot;, FHWA/RD-December (1983). ##2.	Lee J. S., Pande G. N. &quot;Analysis of stone column reinforced foundations&quot;, Int J Numer Anal Meth Geomech (1998) 22:1001–1020. ##3.	Mokhtari M., Kalantari B., &quot;Soft soil stabilization using stone columns-A Review&quot;, Department of civil engineering, University of Hormozgan, Bandar Abbas, Iran (2012).## 4.	Hughes J. M. O., Withers N. J., Greenwood D. A., &quot;A field trial of reinforcing effect of stone column in soil&quot;, Proc., Ground Treatment by Deep Compaction, Institution of Civil Engineers, London (1976) 32-44. ##5.	Madhav M. R., Vitkar P. P., &quot;Strip footing on weak clay stabilized with a granular trench or pile&quot;, Can.Geotech. J (1978) 15(4) 605-609.## 6.	Aboshi H., Ichimoto E., Harada K., Emoki M., &quot;The composer-A method to improve the characteristics of soft clays by inclusion of large diameter sand columns&quot;, Proc., Int. Conf. on Soil Reinforcement (1979) E.N.P.C., 1, Paris 211-216. ##7.	Greenwood D. A., &quot;Mechanical improvement of soils below ground surfaces&quot;, Proc., Ground Engineering Conf., Institution of Civil Engineers, London (1970) 11-22.## 8.	Jellali B., Bouassida M., De Buhan P., &quot;A homogenization method for estimating the bearing capacity of soils reinforced by stone columns&quot;, Int. J. Numer. Analyt. Meth. Geomech (2005) 29(10) 989-1004.## 9.	Priebe H. J., &quot;The design of vibro replacement&quot;, Ground Eng (1995) 28(12) 31-37.## 10.	##Poorooshasb H. B., Meyerhof G. G., &quot;Analysis of behavior of stone columns and lime columns&quot;, comput geotech 20 (1) (1997) 47-70. 11.	McCabe B. A., McNeill J. A., Black J. A., &quot;Ground Improvement Using the Vibro-Stone Column Technique&quot;, The Institution of Engineers of Ireland (2007).## 12.	Isaac D. S., &quot;Suitability of Different Materials for Stone Column Construction&quot;, M. Tech Thesis, College of engineering Trivandrum (2009). ##13.	Gniel J., Bouazza A., &quot;Improvement of soft soils using geogrid encased stone columns&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes 27 (2009) 167-175. ##14.	Halabian A. M., Naeemifar I., Hashemolhosseini S. H., &quot;Numerical analysis of vertically loaded rammed aggregate piers and pier groups&quot;, Ground Improvement (2012) 167-181.## 15.	شعبانی م. ج.، روشن‌ضمیر م. ع.، &quot;بررسی عددی پایداری شیروانی ماسه‌ای روی رس نرم به‌سازی شده با ستون سنگی&quot;، مجله علمی و پژوهشی شریف، دورۀ 2.32، شمارۀ 2.3 (1395) 132-125.## 16.	Murugesan s., Rajagopal k., &quot;Geosynthetic-encased stone columns: Numerical evaluation&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes 24 (2006) 349-358.## 17.	Ambily A. P., Grandhi S. R., &quot;Behavior of stone columns based on experimental and FEM analysis&quot;, J Geotech Geoenviron Eng ASCE (2007) 133(4) 405-415.## 18.	Zahmatkesh A., Choobbasti A. J., &quot;Settlement evaluation of soft clay reinforced with stone columns using the equivalent secant modulus&quot;, Arab J Geisci, 5 (2010) 103-109. ##19.	Deb K., Chandra S., Basudhar P. K., &quot;Response of multilayer geosynthetic-reinforced bed resting on soft soil with stone columns&quot;, Computers and Geotechnics, 35 (2008) 323-330.## 20.	Deb K., Samadhiya N. K., Namdeo J. B., &quot;Laboratory model studies on unreinforced and geofrid-reinforced sand bed over stone column-improved soft clay&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes, 29 (2011) 190-196. ##21.	Mengfei Q., Xie Q., Cao X., Zhao W., He J., and Jin J., &quot;Model test of stone columns as liquefaction countermeasure in sandy soils&quot;, Frontiers of Structural and Civil Engineering 10, No. 4 (2016) 481-487.## 22.	Gniel J., Abdelmalek Bouazza A., &quot;Improvement of soft soils using geogrid encased stone columns&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes 27.3 (2009) 167-175.##  23.	Ghazavi M., Nazari Afshar J., &quot;Bearing capacity of geosynthetic encased stone columns&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes (2013) 1-11.## 24.	Hosseinpour I., Riccio M., Almeida M. S. S., &quot;Numerical evaluation of a granular column reinforced by geosynthetics using encasement and laminated disks&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes 42 (2014) 363-373.## 25.	Tang L., Cong S., Ling X., Lu, J., Elgamal A., &quot;Numerical study on ground ##improvement for liquefaction mitigation using stone columns encased with geosynthetics&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes (2015) 1-6. 26.	Hosseinpour I., Almeida M., and Riccio M., &quot;Ground improvement of soft soil by geotextile-encased columns&quot;, Proceedings of the Institution of Civil Engineers-Ground Improvement 169, no. 4 (2016) 297-305.## 27.	Choobbasti A. J., Zahmatkesh A., Noorzad R., &quot;Performance of Stone Columns in Soft Clay: Numerical Evaluation&quot;, Geotech Geol Eng. 29 (2011) 675-684. ##28.	Cooper M. R., Rose A. N., &quot;Stone column support for an embankment on deep alluvial soils&quot;, Proceedings of the institution of civil engineers-geotechnical engineering (1999) 137(1) 15-25.## 29.	Brinkgreve R. B., Vermeer P. A., &quot;Plaxis-finite element code for soil and rocks analysis&quot;, Version 8. Rotterdam Brookfield: AA. Balkema (1998).## 30.	Hu W., Wood D. M., Steward W., &quot;Ground improvement using stone column foundation: results of model tests&quot;, Proc. Int. Conf. on Ground Improvement techniques, Macau (1997) 247-256.## 31.	Narasimha Rao S., Madhiyan M., Prasad Y. V. S. N., &quot;Influence of bearing area on the behavior of stone columns&quot;, Proc., Indian Geotech. Conf., Calcutta, India (1992) 235-237.## 32.	Christian J. T, Carrier W. D., Janbu Bjerrum and Kjaernsli’s chart reinterpreted. Canadian Geotechnical Journal, 15 (1978) 123-128.## 33.	Elshazly H., Elkasabgy M., Elleboudy A., &quot;Effect of Inter-Column Spacing on Soil Stresses due to Vibro-Installed Stone Columns: Interesting Findings&quot;, Geotech Geol Eng. 26 (2008) 225-236.## 34.	Pulko B., Majes B., &amp; Logar J., &quot;Geosynthetic-encased stone columns: analytical calculation model&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes, 29 (1) (2011) 29-39. ## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>پیشنهاد پوشش بتنی مسلح بر اساس کنترل نشت آب از تونل‎های تحت فشار با بهره‎گیری از مدل المان محدود</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Reinforced Concrete Lining Suggestion based on Seepage Control of Pressure Tunnels using the Finite Element Model</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>تونل&#8206;های تحت فشار با پوشش بتنی، منابعی از جریان نشت آب به توده&#8206;سنگ دربرگیرنده خود هستند، از این&#8204;رو، طی فرآیند آب&#8206;گیری مقاومت کمی در برابر فشار نشت آب خواهند داشت و با افزایش فشار آب داخلی تونل، فشار نشت آب به توده&#8206;سنگ منتقل خواهد شد. در این شرایط به&#8206;واسطۀ درزه، ترک، منافذ و همۀ المان&#8206;های توده&#8206;سنگ از تمام جهات تحت تأثیر فشار نشت آب قرار می&#8206;گیرند. این اندرکنش هیدرومکانیکی باعث تغییرات نفوذپذیری المان&#8206;های توده&#8206;سنگ طی فرآیند آب&#8206;گیری می&#8206;شود. بنابراین، تغییرات صورت گرفته در تنش منجر به تغییراتی در ضریب نفوذپذیری و توزیع مجدد میدان نشت می&#8204;شود. از این رو، در این تحقیق از روش المان محدود به&#8204;کمک نرم&#8206;افزارABAQUS &#160;برای مدل&#8206;سازی این اندرکنش استفاده شده است. در این راستا از داده&#8206;های تونل تحت فشار طرح سد و نیروگاه گتوند به&#8204;عنوان مطالعۀ موردی بهره گرفته شده است. به&#8204;منظور نزدیک&#8204;کردن مدل به شرایط واقعی، تأثیر تغییرات نفوذپذیری پوشش بتنی و توده&#8204;سنگ بر تغییر&#8204;شکل&#8204;ها و تنش&#8206;های ایجاد شده در محیط با استفاده از کد USDFLD به مدل&#8206; اعمال شده است. نتایج مدل عددی نشان می&#8206;دهد که به&#8204;منظور کنترل نشت از تونل&#8206;های تحت فشار با پوشش بتنی، ضخامت پوشش و آرایش مناسب میل&#8204;گردها در پوشش بتنی در ممانعت از نشت بیش از حد مجاز از تونل نقش به&#8204;سزایی را ایفا می&#8206;کنند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Introduction
Pressure tunnels in hydroelectric plants are used to convey water to powerhouses. These tunnels are the sources of seepage flow to the rock formation, thus, during the water filling, they will have a low resistance to seepage and, by increasing the internal water pressure of the tunnel, the inflow force will be transferred to the rock mass. In these conditions, the cracks, pores and all other elements of the rock mass are affected by the seepage forces in all directions. This hydro-mechanical interaction affects changing the stresses and displacements of the rock mass around the tunnel and causes modifications in the permeability of rock elements during the water filling. Therefore, changes in stress distribution lead to alterations in the permeability coefficient and redistribution of the seepage field. In these conditions, since the analytical solution of the problem is not possible, the numerical analysis based on the finite element method has been used in this study.
Material and methods
In this approach, the rock mass is considered as an equivalent continuum in which the effects of discontinuities are taken into account in its material behavior. High-pressure tunnels under internal water pressure requires reinforced concrete lining to prevent hydro-fracturing. The ABAQUS software is capable of analyzing such as seepage from the tunnel, modeling of the steel bars in concrete, and taking into account hydro-mechanical interaction. Thus, the software is used for numerical analysis.
The pressure tunnel of the Gotvand dam and hydroelectric power plant (HPP) scheme is taken as a case study for the numerical simulation. Pressure tunnel of the Gotvand dam located in the southwest of Iran is taken as a case study for the numerical simulation. Among behavioral models in the software, Mohr-Coulomb failure criterion is considered to describe the rock mass, but the principle of effective stress determines the rock mass behavior. Since the concrete lining of the pressure tunnel will undergo two mechanisms of the cracking due to tension and the crushing due to compression, concrete damaged plasticity model is used to predict the response of the concrete elements. The evolution of the yield surface of the concrete lining is also controlled with tensile and compressive equivalent plastic strains, correspondingly.
In this study, the hydro-mechanical interaction is implemented based on the analysis of the pore fluid/deformation analysis, and the direct-coupled method is used to solve the governing equations of the problem. To verify the proposed model, the elastic behavior of the media is simulated to compare the numerical and the analytical solutions and good agreement is obtained. The numerical analyses are carried out the hydro-mechanical interaction with constant permeability coefficient. When cracks develop in the concrete lining at high water pressure, the properties of the concrete lining change and as a result, the stress dependent permeability of the lining and surrounding rock mass in pressure tunnels should be considered. The coefficient of permeability controls the rate of seepage flow in porous and fractured media. Although permeability represents an original property of the porous media, it can be modified when subjected to the stress variations. Instead of changing aperture, the change in the void space or volume is the typical consequence that results to change the permeability coefficient. In order to bring the model closer to the real conditions and in the validation of the new model, the influence of the permeability coefficient variations of the concrete and rock mass on the deformations and stresses of the model has been added to nonlinear analysis by USDFLD code. Increasing the water head in the tunnel during water filling is also considered with the combination of DLOAD and DISP codes in the model.
Results and discussion
Since the lining and rock mass have nonlinear properties and complex behavior, for verification of the model in ABAQUS software, the model is simulated with homogeneous, isotropic and elastic behavior. The results of seepage flow on the interface of the concrete lining and rock mass obtained by analytical and numerical solutions indicate that there is a &#177;5 % difference between them. Then, the results of the elastic behavior of the model show a good agreement with the results of analytical solutions. Therefore, this numerical model has been employed for the nonlinear analyses.
Finally, the optimal thickness of the concrete lining with the appropriate arrangement of the reinforcement in the reinforced concrete linings is utilized to minimize water losses from the tunnel based on the new model. Thus, the results of the analysis with the aim of reducing the water losses from the tunnel indicate that the suitable arrangement of the steel bars in the concrete lining leads to the distribution of micro cracks in the lining, and the reinforcement stress stays at a lower value with high internal water pressure. Based on the new numerical model, it is suggested that the lining should be designed with the thickness of 40 cm and the reinforcement with the diameter of 16 mm and the spacing of 20 cm.
&#160;Conclusion
The results of the numerical model indicate that to control the seepage outflow from concrete-lined pressure tunnels, the thickness of the lining and the suitable arrangement of the steel bars in the concrete lining play a significant role in preventing excessive seepage from the tunnel./files/site1/files/124/3dadashi%DA%86%DA%A9%DB%8C%D8%AF%D9%87.pdf</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>599</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>616</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>احسان</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>داداشی</Family>
				<NameE>Ehsan</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Dadashi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم تحقیقات تهرانhttps://jeg.khu.ac.ir/admin_pg_old2.php?sid=1&#38;slc_lang=fa</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم تحقیقات</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>edadashi.22@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>نورزاد</Family>
				<NameE>Ali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Noorzad</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، دانشکدۀ مهندسی عمران، آب و محیط‌زیست</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>a_noorzad@sbu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>کورش</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شهریار</Family>
				<NameE>Koroush</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Shahriar</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر، دانشکده مهندسی معدن و متالورژی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>k.shahriar@aut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>کامران</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>گشتاسبی</Family>
				<NameE>Kamran</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Goshtasbi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، گروه مهندسی معدن مکانیک سنگ</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>goshtasbi.k@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Pressure Tunnel</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Reinforced Concrete Lining</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Hydro-Mechanical Interaction</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ABAQUS software</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Seepage Control.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تونل تحت فشار</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پوشش بتنی مسلح</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اندرکنش هیدرومکانیکی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نرم افزار ABAQUS</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نشت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سد و نیروگاه گتوند</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>کد USDFLD.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1. Ripley B. D., &quot;Design and Performance of Lined and Unlined Pressure Tunnels and Shafts&quot;, PhD Thesis, University of California, Berkeley, (1987) 40-150. 2. Olumide B. A, LI. C. W., &quot;Coupled Stress-Seepage Numerical Design of Pressure Tunnels&quot;, International Journal of Science and Technology, (2012) 216-223. 3. Schleiss A. J., ''Design of Pervious Pressure Tunnels&quot;, International Water Power and Dam Construction, Vol. 38 (1986) 21-28.  4. Schleiss A. J., &quot;Design of Reinforced Concrete Lining For Pressure Tunnels and Shafts&quot;, The International Journal of Hydropower &amp; Dams, Vol. 4 (1997) 88-94. 5. Schleiss A. J., &quot;Design of Concrete Linings of Pressure Tunnels and Shafts for External Water Pressure&quot;, Proceedings of Tunneling Asia, New Delhi, (1997) 291-300. 6. Fernandez G., &quot;Behavior of Pressure Tunnels and Guidelines for Liner Design&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical Engineering, Vol. 120 (1994) 1768-1791. 7. Chung S. K, Synn J. H., Park C., &quot;Design Criteria for the Reinforcement of a Water Pressure Tunnel Driven by TBM &quot;, Geosystem Engineering, Vol. 4 (2001) 43-49. 8. Simanjuntak T. D. Y. F., Marence M., Schleiss A. J., Mynett A. E., &quot;Design of Pressure Tunnels using a Finite Element Model&quot;, Hydropower &amp; Dams Construction, (2012) 98-105. 9. Zhou Y., Su, K., Wu, H., &quot;Hydro-Mechanical Interaction Analysis of High Pressure Hydraulic Tunnel&quot;, Tunneling and Underground Space Technology, Vol. 47 (2015) 28-34. 10. سروش ع.، محمدپورجیقه ج.، &quot;ارزیابی و تحلیل عددی اثر روباره کم بر پایداری ژئوتکنیکی تونل‌های تحت فشار&quot;، کنفرانس بین‌المللی سازه‌های هیدرولیکی، دانشکدۀ فنی و مهندسی عمران دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان، ایران (1380) 373-365. 11. قاسم‌زاده ح.، عبادی م. ح.، &quot;اندرکنش بین سنگ و پوشش در تونل‌ها و شفت‌های تحت فشار&quot;، هشتمین کنفرانس تونل، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس تهران، ایران (1388) 298-290. 12. زارعی‎فرد م.، فهیمی‎فر ا.، &quot;نشت و فشار آب منفذی در تونل‎ها و شفت‎های تحت فشار و وابستگی آن با تغییرشکل‎های پوشش و توده‎سنگ&quot;، اولین کنفرانس بین‎المللی و سومین کنفرانس سد و نیروگاه‎های برق‎آبی، تهران، ایران (1390) 15-1. 13. شرکت مهندسین مشاور مهاب قدس، &quot;مطالعات مرحلۀ دوم، گزارش سیمای طرح سد و نیروگاه گتوند&quot; (1388). 14. شرکت مهندسین مشاور مهاب قدس، &quot;مطالعات مرحله دوم، گزارش زمین‎شناسی و مکانیک‎سنگی طرح سد و نیروگاه گتوند&quot; (1388). 15. Dadashi E., Noorzad A., Shahriar K., Goshtasbi K., &quot;Hydro-mechanical interaction analysis of reinforced concrete lining in pressure tunnels&quot;, Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology, Vol. 69 (2017) 125-132. 16. Jun L. J., Bin Y. X., Zhou Z. J., &quot;Numerical Simulation of Geo-stress and Pore Pressure Evolution around Oil or Water Well under Different Injection-Production Ratio&quot;, Mathematical Problems in Engineering (2013) 1-10. 17. Cabot P. G., Dufour F., Choinska M., &quot;Permeability due to the Increase of Damage in Concrete: From Diffuse to Localized Damage Distributions&quot;, Journal of Engineering Mechanics, 135 (2009) 1022-1028. 18. Bai M., Meng F., Elsworth D., Zaman M., Roegiers J., &quot;Numerical Modeling of Stress-Dependent Permeability&quot;, International Journal Rock Mechanics and Mining Science, Vol. 34 (1997) 2-10. 19. Ying C., Youzhi W., Yu Z. Q., &quot;Coupled Seepage Elasto-Plastic Damage Analysis of Saturated Porous Media and its Application to Water Conveyance Tunnel&quot;, Tunneling and Underground Space Technology, Vol. 44 (2014) 80-87. 20. ITA Working Group, &quot;Guidelines for the Design of Tunnels&quot;. Tunneling and Underground Space Technology, Vol. 3 (1988) 237-249. 21. Marence M., &quot;Numerical Modeling and Design of Pressure Tunnels&quot;, Hydro, Ljubljana, Slovenia, (2008) 21-28. ##1. Ripley B. D., &quot;Design and Performance of Lined and Unlined Pressure Tunnels and Shafts&quot;, PhD Thesis, University of California, Berkeley, (1987) 40-150.## 2. Olumide B. A, LI. C. W., &quot;Coupled Stress-Seepage Numerical Design of Pressure Tunnels&quot;, International Journal of Science and Technology, (2012) 216-223. ##3. Schleiss A. J., ''Design of Pervious Pressure Tunnels&quot;, International Water Power and Dam Construction, Vol. 38 (1986) 21-28. ## 4. Schleiss A. J., &quot;Design of Reinforced Concrete Lining For Pressure Tunnels and Shafts&quot;, The International Journal of Hydropower &amp; Dams, Vol. 4 (1997) 88-94.## 5. Schleiss A. J., &quot;Design of Concrete Linings of Pressure Tunnels and Shafts for External Water Pressure&quot;, Proceedings of Tunneling Asia, New Delhi, (1997) 291-300. ##6. Fernandez G., &quot;Behavior of Pressure Tunnels and Guidelines for Liner Design&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical Engineering, Vol. 120 (1994) 1768-1791.## 7. Chung S. K, Synn J. H., Park C., &quot;Design Criteria for the Reinforcement of a Water Pressure Tunnel Driven by TBM &quot;, Geosystem Engineering, Vol. 4 (2001) 43-49.## 8. Simanjuntak T. D. Y. F., Marence M., Schleiss A. J., Mynett A. E., &quot;Design of Pressure Tunnels using a Finite Element Model&quot;, Hydropower &amp; Dams Construction, (2012) 98-105.## 9. Zhou Y., Su, K., Wu, H., &quot;Hydro-Mechanical Interaction Analysis of High Pressure Hydraulic Tunnel&quot;, Tunneling and Underground Space Technology, Vol. 47 (2015) 28-34.## 10. سروش ع.، محمدپورجیقه ج.، &quot;ارزیابی و تحلیل عددی اثر روباره کم بر پایداری ژئوتکنیکی تونل‌های تحت فشار&quot;، کنفرانس بین‌المللی سازه‌های هیدرولیکی، دانشکدۀ فنی و مهندسی عمران دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان، ایران (1380) 373-365.## 11. قاسم‌زاده ح.، عبادی م. ح.، &quot;اندرکنش بین سنگ و پوشش در تونل‌ها و شفت‌های تحت فشار&quot;، هشتمین کنفرانس تونل، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس تهران، ایران (1388) 298-290. ##12. زارعی‎فرد م.، فهیمی‎فر ا.، &quot;نشت و فشار آب منفذی در تونل‎ها و شفت‎های تحت فشار و وابستگی آن با تغییرشکل‎های پوشش و توده‎سنگ&quot;، اولین کنفرانس بین‎المللی و سومین کنفرانس سد و نیروگاه‎های برق‎آبی، تهران، ایران (1390) 15-1. ##13. شرکت مهندسین مشاور مهاب قدس، &quot;مطالعات مرحلۀ دوم، گزارش سیمای طرح سد و نیروگاه گتوند&quot; (1388).## 14. شرکت مهندسین مشاور مهاب قدس، &quot;مطالعات مرحله دوم، گزارش زمین‎شناسی و مکانیک‎سنگی طرح سد و نیروگاه گتوند&quot; (1388).## 15. Dadashi E., Noorzad A., Shahriar K., Goshtasbi K., &quot;Hydro-mechanical interaction analysis of reinforced concrete lining in pressure tunnels&quot;, Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology, Vol. 69 (2017) 125-132. ##16. Jun L. J., Bin Y. X., Zhou Z. J., &quot;Numerical Simulation of Geo-stress and Pore Pressure Evolution around Oil or Water Well under Different Injection-Production Ratio&quot;, Mathematical Problems in Engineering (2013) 1-10.## 17. Cabot P. G., Dufour F., Choinska M., &quot;Permeability due to the Increase of Damage in Concrete: From Diffuse to Localized Damage Distributions&quot;, Journal of Engineering Mechanics, 135 (2009) 1022-1028.## 18. Bai M., Meng F., Elsworth D., Zaman M., Roegiers J., &quot;Numerical Modeling of Stress-Dependent Permeability&quot;, International Journal Rock Mechanics and Mining Science, Vol. 34 (1997) 2-10.## 19. Ying C., Youzhi W., Yu Z. Q., &quot;Coupled Seepage Elasto-Plastic Damage Analysis of Saturated Porous Media and its Application to Water Conveyance Tunnel&quot;, Tunneling and Underground Space Technology, Vol. 44 (2014) 80-87.## 20. ITA Working Group, &quot;Guidelines for the Design of Tunnels&quot;. Tunneling and Underground Space Technology, Vol. 3 (1988) 237-249.## 21. Marence M., &quot;Numerical Modeling and Design of Pressure Tunnels&quot;, Hydro, Ljubljana, Slovenia, (2008) 21-28. ## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>ارائه مدلی بین مدول دینامیکی و استاتیکی سنگ آهک در سازند آسماری براساس آزمون‌های آزمایشگاهی و برجا</TitleF>
		<TitleE>A Model between Dynamic and Static Moduli of Limestone in Asmari Geological Formation ‎based on Laboratory and In-situ Tests ‎</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>آگاهی از مدول تغییرشکل سنگ برای طراحی سازه&#8204;های ژئوتکنیکی و مدل&#8204;سازی مخازن نفتی اهمیت زیادی دارد. در حالت کلی برای تعیین مدول تغییرشکل&#8204;پذیری سنگ دو روش مخرب یا استاتیکی و غیرمخرب یا دینامیکی وجود دارد، لیکن باتوجه به زمان&#8204;بر بودن و هزینۀ زیاد روش&#8204;های مخرب نسبت به افزایش عمق، استفاده از روش&#8204;های غیرمخرب متداول&#8204;تر است. از آن&#8204;جاکه سازند آسماری به&#8204;طور گسترده&#8204;ای در بخش چشم&#8204;گیری از غرب و جنوب&#8204;غرب کشور رخنمون داشته و پروژه&#8204;های مهندسی زیادی در این سازند اجرا و در دست بررسی است، بررسی خصوصیات ژئومکانیکی آن اهمیت خاصی دارد. ارائۀ عمده روابط تجربی در زمینۀ ارتباط مدول&#8204;های استاتیکی و دینامیکی با توجه به پژوهش&#8204;های انجام شده در مناطق دیگر جهان و پراکندگی و مستقل بودن پژوهش&#8204;های انجام شده بر سازند آسماری به&#8204;دلیل وسعت زیاد آن از یک طرف و اهمیت سازند مذکور از نظر پروژه&#8204;های نفتی و عمرانی از طرف دیگر، لزوم ارائه معیاری فراگیر حاصل از تمامی بررسی&#8204;های انجام شده روی سازند آسماری که بتواند بیان&#8204;کننده ارتباط بین مدول&#8204;های استاتیکی و دینامیکی در آن باشد را نمایان&#8204;تر کرده است. در این راستا در مقالۀ حاضر با استفاده از مدول&#8204;های به&#8204;دست آمده از روش ژئوفیزیکی درون گمانه&#8204;ای و مدول&#8204;های استاتیکی به&#8204;دست آمده از نتایج آزمایشگاهی سنگ سالم در تونل قلاجه واقع در سازند آسماری در استان ایلام، ارتباط بین مدول&#8204;های دینامیکی و استاتیکی ساختگاه تعیین و سپس با بررسی تحقیقات و معیارهای ارائۀ شده قبلی در این سازند، رابطه&#8204;ای فراگیر برای بیان ارتباط بین مدول&#8204;های استاتیکی و دینامیکی ارائه شد.&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Introduction
It is very important to have knowledge on the rock deformation modulus when designing geotechnical &#8206;structures and modeling oil reservoirs. In general, there are two destructive or static and non-&#8206;destructive or dynamic methods for determining the rock deformation modulus, but considering the &#8206;time and cost of destructive methods proportionate to the depth, it is more common to make use of &#8206;non-destructive approaches. The outcrops of Asmari Formation are widely spread in the west and &#8206;southwest of Iran, and many engineering projects have been constructed or are being studied &#8206;on this formation. Therefore, it is of great importance to study on the geomechanical characteristics of this &#8206;formation. Presentation of empirical relations regarding the relationship between static and dynamic &#8206;moduli, with respect to the studies carried out in other parts of the world and the dispersion and &#8206;independence of studies done on Asmari Formation due to its large extent on one hand and the &#8206;importance of this formation in terms of oil and development civil projects on the other hand, necessitate &#8206;presenting a comprehensive criterion resulted from all studies carried out on Asmari Formation which &#8206;can express the relationship between the static and dynamic moduli. This paper represents the &#8206;relationship between the dynamic and static moduli of the site using the moduli obtained by the &#8206;down-hole geophysical method and the static moduli obtained by the intact rock test results of &#8206;Ghalajeh tunnel located in Asmari Formation in Ilam province. Then, a comprehensive relation is &#8206;presented to express the relationship between static and dynamic modulus by studying the previous &#8206;researches and criteria on this formation.
Material and methods
Two sets of tests were conducted to determine the relationship between static and dynamic moduli in the Ghalajeh tunnel. First, a uniaxial compression strength test was performed on 13 cores taken from three boreholes to compute the elasticity modulus in accordance with ISRM standard. Then, down-hole test was conducted on two boreholes such that to determine the dynamic modulus using compressive and shear wave velocities. Seismographic apparatus of ABEM RAS 24 as well as three-component down-hole geophones were utilized in order to plot the seismic profile. After the performing the tests, the dynamic modulus of deformation was calculated using the velocity of P-waves and the density of the host rock.
Discussion and Conclusions
By conducting in-situ static and dynamic laboratory tests on Ghalajeh Tunnel project and determining the values ​​of the static and dynamic deformation moduli, a relation was presented between them. Then, taking into consideration the previous models studied in Asmari Formation, a comprehensive criterion was presented for wider use in the mentioned formation. Given the root mean square error (RMSE) and variance account for (VAF), the values predicted using the proposed comprehensive model have acceptable accuracy. In the interim, the correction factor between dynamic and static moduli in Asmari Formation was between 0.8 and 2.4. The results show that, in general, the relationship between static and dynamic moduli is linear up to a certain range (static modulus of 100 MPa) and then it has a power trend./files/site1/files/124/4darai%DA%86%DA%A9%DB%8C%D8%AF%D9%87.pdf</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>617</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>634</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>آکو</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>دارای</Family>
				<NameE>Ako</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Daraei</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه سوران، دانشکدۀ مهندسی عمران، کردستان، عراق</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه سوران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>عراق</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>daraii2004@yaoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>شکراله</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>زارع</Family>
				<NameE>Shokrollah</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Zare</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود، دانشکدۀ مهندسی معدن، نفت و ژئوفیزیک</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Zare@shahroodut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Static modulus</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Dynamic modulus</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Asmari formation</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Ghalajeh tunnel</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدول استاتیکی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدول دینامیکی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سازند آسماری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تونل قلاجه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1. Najibi Ali Reza., Ghafoori Mohammad, Lashkaripour Gholam Reza, Asef Mohammad Reza, &quot;Empirical relations between strength and static and dynamic elastic properties of Asmari and Sarvak limestones, two main oil reservoirs in Iran&quot;, Journal of Petroleum Science and Engineering, 126, (2015) 78-82. 2. Martı´nez-Martı´nez J., Benavente D., Garcı´a-del-Cura M. A., &quot;Comparison of the static and dynamic elastic modulus in carbonate rocks&quot;, Bull Eng Geol Environ, 71: (2012) 263-268. 3. Goodman R. E., &quot;Introduction to Rock Mechanics&quot;, Wiley (1989). 4. Chang C., Zoback M. D., Khaksar A., &quot;Empirical relations between rock strength and physical properties in sedimentary rocks&quot;, J.Pet.Sci.Eng. 51(3), (2006) 223-237. 5. Lama R. D., Vutukuri V. S., &quot;Handbook on Mechanical Properties of Rocks&quot;, Vol. II. Clausthal Germany Trans Tech Publications (1978). 6. Belikov B. P., Alexandrov K. S., Rysova T. W. &quot;Uprugie svoistva porodoobrasujscich mineralov I gomich porod&quot;, Izdat. Nauka, Moskva, (1970). 7. Van Heerden W. L., &quot;General relations between Static and dynamic moduli of rocks&quot;, Int. J. Rock. Mech. Min. Sci. Geomech. Abstr. 24 (6) (1987). 381-385. 8. King M. S., &quot;Static and dynamic elastic properties of rock from the Canadian Shield&quot;, Int.J.Rock Mech. Min. Sci. Geomech. Abstr. 20(5) (1983) 237-241. 9. Eissa A., Kazi A., &quot;Relation between static and dynamic Young’s moduli of rocks&quot;, Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci. Geomech. Abstr. 25 (6) (1988) 479-482. 10. McCann D. M., Entwisle D. C. &quot;Determination of Young's modulus of the rock mass from geophysical well logs&quot;, Geological Applications of Wireline Logs II, Eds: Hurst, A., Griffiths, C. M. &amp; Worthington, P. F., Geological Society Special Publication No. 65, (1992) 317-325. 11. Lacy L. L., &quot;Dynamic rock mechanics testing for optimized fracture designs&quot;, SPE Paper 38716 (1997). 12. Nur A.,Wang Z., &quot;Seismic and Acoustic Velocities in Reservoir Rocks: Recent Developments&quot;, Vol.10, Society of Exploration Geophysicists, (1999). 13. Mockoviakova A., Pandula B. &quot;Study of the relation between the static and dynamic moduli of rocks&quot;, Metalurgija 42, (2003) 37-39. 14. Ameen M. S., Smart B. G. D.,Somerville J. M. C.,Hammilton S., Naji N. A., &quot;Prediction rock mechanical properties of carbonated from wireline logs (A case study: Arab-D reservoir, Ghavar field, Saudi Arabia)&quot;, Int. J. Rock. Mech. Min Sci., 26 (2009) 430-444. 15. Fei W, Huiyuan B., Jun Y., Yonghao Z., &quot;Correlation of Dynamic and Static Elastic Parameters of Rock&quot;, EJGE, Vol. 21, Bund. 04, (2016) 1551-1560. 16. واحدی علی‌اکبر، &quot;ارتباط بین پارامترهای الاستیک استاتیکی و دینامیکی سنگ آهک در ساختگاه سد سیمره&quot;، اولین کنفرانس مکانیک سنگ ایران، تهران، (1380). 17. فولادچی سروش، حسینی محمد فاروق، گنجی مجتبی، &quot; بررسی آزمایشگاهی تأثیر اندازۀ نمونه بر ویژگی‌های الاستیک دینامیک و استاتیک سنگ آهک نکا&quot;، نشریه علمی- پژوهشی مهندسی معدن، دورۀ اول، شمارۀ 1 (1385). 18. زارعی وحید، داودی جاجرم امید، &quot;ارتباط بین پارامترهای استاتیکی و دینامیکی سنگ آهک دولومیتی تا دولومیت آهکی در ساختگاه سد رودبار لرستان&quot;، سومین کنفرانس مهندسی معدن ایران، یزد، (1388). 19. صالحی مسعود، اجل لوئیان رسول،‌ هاشمی محمود، &quot;مقایسۀ مدول الاستیسیته دینامیکی و استاتیکی سنگ‌های ساختگاه سد بازفت&quot;، چهارمین همایش ملی زمین‌شناسی، دانشگاه پیام نور مشهد (1389). 20 نجیبی علیرضا، آصف محمدرضا، اجل لوئیان رسول، صفیان غلام عباس، &quot;تخمین ویژگی‌های مکانیکی سنگ آهک با استفاده از داده‌های پتروفیزیکی، نشریۀ زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، ج پنجم، شمارۀ 1، (1390). 21. کریم نژاد مسعود، &quot;تعیین مدول یانگ استاتیک سنگ‌ها با استفاده از مدول یانگ دینامیک&quot; هشتمین همایش انجمن زمین‌شناسی مهندسی و محیط زیست ایران، (1392). 22. علی‌زاده مجتبی، خداپرست مهدی، رجبی علی‌محمد، &quot;بررسی ارتباط مدول الاستیسیته استاتیکی و دینامیکی مطالعه موردی آبرفت‌های شهر قم&quot;، دومین کنفرانس ملی مهندسی ژئوتکنیک ایران، کرمانشاه، (1393). 23. Koleini M., &quot;Engineering Geological Assessment and Rock Mass Characterization of the Asmari Formation&quot;, Ph.D. thesis, University of Pretoria (2012). 24. Rocsciences Inc., &quot;RocData Ver.3.013&quot;, user manual, (2004). 25. Ciccotti M., Mulargia F., &quot;Differences beween static and dynamic elastic moduli of a typical seismogenic rock&quot;, Geophys J Int 157: (2004) 474-477. 26. Al-Shayea N. A., &quot;Effects of testing methods and conditions on the elastic properties of limestone rock&quot;, Eng Geo 74: (2004) 139-156. 27. Yilmaz I.,&quot;Influence of water content on the strength and deformability of Gypsum&quot;, International journal of rock mechanics &amp; mining science, (2010). 28. آصف محمدرضا، &quot;سرعت موج در سنگ پارامتر کلیدی برای حل مسایل ژئومکانیک نفت&quot; اولین کنفرانس ملی ژئومکانیک نفت، مرکز همایش‌های بین‌المللی پژوهشگاه صنعت‌نفت، تهران، (1394). 29. Brotons V., Toma´s, R., Ivorra S., Grediaga A., &quot;Relationship between static and dynamic elastic modulus of calcarenite heated at different temperatures: the San Julia´n’s stone&quot;, Bull Eng Geol Environ, (2014). ##1. Najibi Ali Reza., Ghafoori Mohammad, Lashkaripour Gholam Reza, Asef Mohammad Reza, &quot;Empirical relations between strength and static and dynamic elastic properties of Asmari and Sarvak limestones, two main oil reservoirs in Iran&quot;, Journal of Petroleum Science and Engineering, 126, (2015) 78-82. ##2. Martı´nez-Martı´nez J., Benavente D., Garcı´a-del-Cura M. A., &quot;Comparison of the static and dynamic elastic modulus in carbonate rocks&quot;, Bull Eng Geol Environ, 71: (2012) 263-268.## 3. Goodman R. E., &quot;Introduction to Rock Mechanics&quot;, Wiley (1989).## 4. Chang C., Zoback M. D., Khaksar A., &quot;Empirical relations between rock strength and physical properties in sedimentary rocks&quot;, J.Pet.Sci.Eng. 51(3), (2006) 223-237. ##5. Lama R. D., Vutukuri V. S., &quot;Handbook on Mechanical Properties of Rocks&quot;, Vol. II. Clausthal Germany Trans Tech Publications (1978)##. 6. Belikov B. P., Alexandrov K. S., Rysova T. W. &quot;Uprugie svoistva porodoobrasujscich mineralov I gomich porod&quot;, Izdat. Nauka, Moskva, (1970)## 7. Van Heerden W. L., &quot;General relations between Static and dynamic moduli of rocks&quot;, Int. J. Rock. Mech. Min. Sci. Geomech. Abstr. 24 (6) (1987). 381-385.## 8. King M. S., &quot;Static and dynamic elastic properties of rock from the Canadian Shield&quot;, Int.J.Rock Mech. Min. Sci. Geomech. Abstr. 20(5) (1983) 237-241.## 9. Eissa A., Kazi A., &quot;Relation between static and dynamic Young’s moduli of rocks&quot;, Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci. Geomech. Abstr. 25 (6) (1988) 479-482.## 10. McCann D. M., Entwisle D. C. &quot;Determination of Young's modulus of the rock mass from geophysical well logs&quot;, Geological Applications of Wireline Logs II, Eds: Hurst, A., Griffiths, C. M. &amp; Worthington, P. F., Geological Society Special Publication No. 65, (1992) 317-325.## 11. Lacy L. L., &quot;Dynamic rock mechanics testing for optimized fracture designs&quot;, SPE Paper 38716 (1997).## 12. Nur A.,Wang Z., &quot;Seismic and Acoustic Velocities in Reservoir Rocks: Recent Developments&quot;, Vol.10, Society of Exploration Geophysicists, (1999).## 13. Mockoviakova A., Pandula B. &quot;Study of the relation between the static and dynamic moduli of rocks&quot;, Metalurgija 42, (2003) 37-39. ##14. Ameen M. S., Smart B. G. D.,Somerville J. M. C.,Hammilton S., Naji N. A., &quot;Prediction rock mechanical properties of carbonated from wireline logs (A case study: Arab-D reservoir, Ghavar field, Saudi Arabia)&quot;, Int. J. Rock. Mech. Min Sci., 26 (2009) 430-444. ##15. Fei W, Huiyuan B., Jun Y., Yonghao Z., &quot;Correlation of Dynamic and Static Elastic Parameters of Rock&quot;, EJGE, Vol. 21, Bund. 04, (2016) 1551-1560.## 16. واحدی علی‌اکبر، &quot;ارتباط بین پارامترهای الاستیک استاتیکی و دینامیکی سنگ آهک در ساختگاه سد سیمره&quot;، اولین کنفرانس مکانیک سنگ ایران، تهران، (1380).## 17. فولادچی سروش، حسینی محمد فاروق، گنجی مجتبی، &quot; بررسی آزمایشگاهی تأثیر اندازۀ نمونه بر ویژگی‌های الاستیک دینامیک و استاتیک سنگ آهک نکا&quot;، نشریه علمی- پژوهشی مهندسی معدن، دورۀ اول، شمارۀ 1 (1385).## 18. زارعی وحید، داودی جاجرم امید، &quot;ارتباط بین پارامترهای استاتیکی و دینامیکی سنگ آهک دولومیتی تا دولومیت آهکی در ساختگاه سد رودبار لرستان&quot;، سومین کنفرانس مهندسی معدن ایران، یزد، (1388).## 19. صالحی مسعود، اجل لوئیان رسول،‌ هاشمی محمود، &quot;مقایسۀ مدول الاستیسیته دینامیکی و استاتیکی سنگ‌های ساختگاه سد بازفت&quot;، چهارمین همایش ملی زمین‌شناسی، دانشگاه پیام نور مشهد (1389).## 20 نجیبی علیرضا، آصف محمدرضا، اجل لوئیان رسول، صفیان غلام عباس، &quot;تخمین ویژگی‌های مکانیکی سنگ آهک با استفاده از داده‌های پتروفیزیکی، نشریۀ زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، ج پنجم، شمارۀ 1، (1390).## 21. کریم نژاد مسعود، &quot;تعیین مدول یانگ استاتیک سنگ‌ها با استفاده از مدول یانگ دینامیک&quot; هشتمین همایش انجمن زمین‌شناسی مهندسی و محیط زیست ایران، (1392). ##22. علی‌زاده مجتبی، خداپرست مهدی، رجبی علی‌محمد، &quot;بررسی ارتباط مدول الاستیسیته استاتیکی و دینامیکی مطالعه موردی آبرفت‌های شهر قم&quot;، دومین کنفرانس ملی مهندسی ژئوتکنیک ایران، کرمانشاه، (1393). ##23. Koleini M., &quot;Engineering Geological Assessment and Rock Mass Characterization of the Asmari Formation&quot;, Ph.D. thesis, University of Pretoria (2012).## 24. Rocsciences Inc., &quot;RocData Ver.3.013&quot;, user manual, (2004). ##25. Ciccotti M., Mulargia F., &quot;Differences beween static and dynamic elastic moduli of a typical seismogenic rock&quot;, Geophys J Int 157: (2004) 474-477. ##26. Al-Shayea N. A., &quot;Effects of testing methods and conditions on the elastic properties of limestone rock&quot;, Eng Geo 74: (2004) 139-156. ##27. Yilmaz I.,&quot;Influence of water content on the strength and deformability of Gypsum&quot;, International journal of rock mechanics &amp; mining science, (2010).## 28. آصف محمدرضا، &quot;سرعت موج در سنگ پارامتر کلیدی برای حل مسایل ژئومکانیک نفت&quot; اولین کنفرانس ملی ژئومکانیک نفت، مرکز همایش‌های بین‌المللی پژوهشگاه صنعت‌نفت، تهران، (1394). ##29. Brotons V., Toma´s, R., Ivorra S., Grediaga A., &quot;Relationship between static and dynamic elastic modulus of calcarenite heated at different temperatures: the San Julia´n’s stone&quot;, Bull Eng Geol Environ, (2014). #### ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>	پهنه‌بندی خطر زمین‌لغزش‌های ناشی از زلزله با استفاده از مدل AHP  (مطالعۀ موردی: منطقه چلکاسر و چهارمحل)  </TitleF>
		<TitleE>The Zoning of Earthquake-Induced Earthquake Hazards using the AHP Model</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>از مهم&#8204;ترین اثرات ناشی از زلزله 31 خرداد 1369 منجیل (7/7M=) وقوع زمین&#8204;لغزش&#8204;های متعدد در مناطق تحت تأثیر این زلزله بوده است. بررسی و تحلیل مشخصات این زمین&#8204;لغزش&#8204;ها و نحوۀ توزیع آن&#8204;ها در شناخت مناطق مستعد زمین&#8204;لغزش در زلزله&#8204;های آینده اهمیت به&#8204;سزایی دارد. هدف از این پژوهش شناسایی عوامل مؤثر و پهنه&#8204;بندی زمین&#8204;لغزش&#8204;های ناشی از زلزله در چهارگوش&#8204;های چلکاسر و چهارمحل (منطقه&#8204;ای در نزدیکی رومرکز زلزله منجیل) به مساحت 30/309 کیلومترمربع، با استفاده از مدل AHP (دو روش استفاده از دانش کارشناسی و استفاده از دانش داده&#8204;ای و کارشناسی به&#8204;صورت توأم) است. به این منظور، ابتدا با توجه به موقعیت زمین&#8204;لغزش&#8204;های به&#8204;وقوع پیوسته، بررسی&#8204;های تطبیقی و نتایج سایر محققان، 7 عامل شامل؛ شدت آریاس، زاویۀ اصطکاک داخلی، چسبندگی، شیب، جهت شیب، ارتفاع و انحنای دامنه شناسایی شد. سپس با استفاده از مدل AHP معیارهای بررسی شده تعیین وزن شده و لایه&#8204;های رستری عوامل مذکور در محیط نرم&#8204;افزار Arc GIS تهیه شده، نهایتاً پهنه&#8204;بندی خطر زمین&#8204;لغزش با دو روش مذکور صورت گرفت. نتایج نشان می&#8204;دهد معیارهای شدت آریاس و انحنای دامنه با وزن&#8204;های 317/0و022/0 به&#8204;ترتیب بیش&#8204;ترین و کم&#8204;ترین تأثیر را بین معیارهای انتخابی دارند. هم&#8204;چنین برای ارزیابی و انتخاب مدل مناسب از دو شاخص مجموع کیفیت (QS) و دقت روش (P) استفاده شد. طبق نتایج به&#8204;دست آمده از این دو شاخص روشی که در آن، قضاوت&#8204;ها بر اساس استفاده از دانش داده&#8204;ای و کارشناسی به&#8204;صورت توأم صورت گرفته است، کارایی بهتری نسبت به مدل دیگر دارد.
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Introduction
In general, landslides, in particular, earthquake-induced landslides, are among the phenomena that have caused great damages in recent years in Iran and the world. Although many studies have been done on the identification and description of landslides in general, the study of landslides caused by the earthquake, especially in Iran, is at the beginning stages. In a few studies, some landslides and some of their characteristics have been introduced. A magnitude 7.7 earthquake occurred in the Guilan Province was occurred on May 31, 1990. This earthquake is one of the most important earthquakes in Iran history due to its magnitude and occurrence of landslides. In various studies, the most important landslides have been listed. The development of quantitative and qualitative studies on earthquakes that have caused many landslides (such as the Manjil, Avaj, Firoozabad, Kojur, Sarein and Ahar and Varzaghan earthquakes) increase our understanding of natural disasters and, consequently, the management of the dangers resulting from them. The purpose of this research is to identify the factors affecting the occurrence of landslides caused by earthquakes, to determine the impact of each on the occurrence of this phenomenon, and also to prepare a map of earthquake hazard zonation hazard by utilizing the methods used in this research. In this study, hierarchical analysis method has been used to prioritize the factors affecting the occurrence of landslide and also the zoning of earthquake landslide hazard in the study area.
Research Methodology
The study area is located between 49˚ 30ꞌ and 49 ꞌ45˚ and latitudes 36&#186; 00 ꞌ 45&#34; and 36&#186; 30ꞌ 52&#34; with a surface area of ​​309.30 km2. In this research, in order to zoning the earthquake-induced landslides hazard, in addition to providing a map of landslides, seven factors influencing the occurrence of this phenomenon were identified and examined. These factors included elevation, slope, arias intensity, friction angle, adhesion, curvature of the slope and aspect. In this research, Analytic Hierarchy Process (AHP) method, one of the multi-criteria decision making models, was used with two approaches to using expert knowledge and data and expert knowledge together to prioritize the factors influencing the occurrence of landslide. Finally, two landslide hazard zonation maps were prepared. In a hierarchical analysis method related to the expert judgment, it was used to determine the priority of different criteria and sub-criteria and convert them into small amounts of oral judgments (expert opinion) based on the pair comparison, in which the decision maker preferred the factor in relation to other factors using the relevant tables, these judgments are converted into small amounts. In the method of using data and expert judgment simultaneously, first, in order to determine the priority of criteria from oral judgments (collection of expert opinions), we used to determine the importance or weight (Wi) of each sub-criterion (R) is also used to link the landslide area to each class and landslide area in the region.
Results
The results obtained from the paired comparison of the effective factors in the occurrence of landslide show that the relative preference of the factors include the factor of arias intensity, friction angle, slope, adhesion, aspect, height and curvature of the amplitude. The greatest influence on the sub-criteria for the sub-criteria is 10-11.54, which is related to the arias factor and also the lowest effect for the sub-standard of the domain curvature factor. Also, according to the zoning maps, in the first model, 73% and in the second model, 57% of the surface area are very high and very high risk areas, which indicates the high sensitivity of the study area to the earthquake-induced earthquake phenomenon.
According to the results obtained from the verification and evaluation of the models and comparison of the mapped data with the hierarchical analysis method (using expert knowledge and data) and a method that uses only expert knowledge, the map is derived from a method where bundles of knowledge and data are used simultaneously, in order to weigh the parameters, it is more in line with the map of the landing list of the region.
Conclusion
According to the results obtained from the review and evaluation of the two models in a method in which knowledge and data were used together, the QS value was 0.40 and the accuracy of the method (P) was 0.016. However, in a method in which only the expert judgment used to weigh the criteria and sub-criteria, the sum of the quality and accuracy of the method were calculated to be 0.37 and 0.006, respectively. Hierarchical analysis method, in which the benchmarks and sub-criteria of benchmark knowledge and data are used together, have a better performance than the other model, and the results are closer to reality. In addition, it also works better in distinguishing between high and high risk areas../files/site1/files/124/5rajabi%DA%86%DA%A9%DB%8C%D8%AF%D9%87.pdf</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>635</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>658</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی محمد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رجبی</Family>
				<NameE>Ali M.</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rajabi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران، گروه زمین‌شناسی مهندسی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>amrajabi@ymail.com; amrajabi@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>خسروی</Family>
				<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Khosravi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه قم، گروه ژئوتکنیک</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه قم</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>H.khosravi23@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پهنه‌بندی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>زلزلۀ منجیل</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>زمین‌لغزش‌های ناشی از زلزله</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تحلیل سلسله مراتبی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>. مهدویفر م. ر.، &quot;ارزیابی تحلیلی و طراحی سامانه مدیریت ریسک زمین‌لغزش‌های ناشی از زلزله در کشور &quot;، پایان‌نامۀ دکتری پژوهشکدۀ زلزله‌شناسی و مهندسی زلزله (1385). 2. رجبی ع. م.، &quot;بررسی احتمالی خطر زمین‌لغزش‌های ناشی از زلزله در ایران.&quot;، پایان‌نامۀ دکتری زمین‌شناسی گرایش مهندسی، دانشکدۀ علوم پایه، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس (1389). 3. باقری و.، &quot;پهنه‌بندی زمین‌لغزش‌های ناشی از زلزله (مطالعۀ موردی زلزله اردبیل)&quot;، پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه خوارزمی تهران (1391). 4. کمک‌پناه ع.، حافظی مقدس ن.، &quot;پهنه‌بندی خطر زمین‌لغزش در ایران، جلد ششم: شناسایی و به نقشه درآوردن زمین‌لغزه‌های مهم تحریک‌شده در زلزله خردادماه 1369 منجیل&quot;، پژوهشکدۀ زلزله‌شناسی و مهندسی زلزله (1372). 5. نوگل سادات م.، &quot;طرح جامع خطر رانش استان گیلان&quot;، کارفرما: زیر کمیته زلزله و لغزش لایه‌های زمین معاونت شهرسازی و معماری وزارت مسکن و شهرسازی (1375). 6. مصفایی ج.، شریعت جعفری م.، &quot;مقایسه کارایی مدل‌های تجربی و آماری پهنه‌بندی خطر زمین‌لغزش (مطالعه موردی آبخیز الموت)&quot;، مجله پژوهش‌های حفاظت آب‌وخاک، جلد شانزدهم، شماره چهارم (1385). 7. علی مرادی م.، سیف ع.، شیرانی ک.، &quot;صحت‌سنجی روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی (AHP) و رگرسیون چند متغیره (MR) در پهنه‌بندی خطر زمین‌لغزش به‌کمک تکنیک GIS (مطالعه موردی حوزه رودخانه ماربر)&quot;، مهندسی فناوری اطلاعات مکانی، سال اول، شماره دوم (1391). 8. معماریان پ.، &quot;گزارش پژوهش 1 و 2 مقطع دکتری زمین‌لغزش‌های ناشی از زلزله&quot;، پژوهشکدۀ زلزله‌شناسی و مهندسی زلزله (1389). 9. قدسی‌پور ح.، &quot;فرآیند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی&quot;، چاپ هفتم، تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر(1388). 10. Ayalew L., Yamagishi H., &quot;The application of GIS-based logistic regression for landslide susceptibility mapping in the Kakuda-Yahiko Mountains&quot;, Central Japan. Geomorphology, 65,(2005) 15-31. 11. Jibson R.W., &quot;Regression models for estimating coseismic landslide displacement&quot;, Engineering Geology (2007). 12. Del Gaudio V., Wasowski J., &quot;Seismic rock fall hazard in the sele river valleyT southern Italy&quot;, Thomas Thelford (2000). 13. Keefer D. K., &quot;Landslides caused by earhquakes. Geological Society American Bulletin&quot;, 95 (1984) 406-421. 14. Mahdavifar M. R., Solaymani S., Jafari M. K., &quot;Landslides triggered by the Avaj&quot;, Iran earthquake of June 22. Engineering Geology, 86 (2002) 166-182. 15. Saaty T. L., &quot;Axiomatic foundation of analytical hierarchy process&quot;, Journal of Management science, Vol. 31, No. 7 ((1986)) 841-855.  16. Komac M., &quot;A landslide susceptibility model using the analytical hierarchy process method and multivariate statistics in Perialpine Slovenia&quot;, Geomorphology, 74 (2006) 17-28  17. Miles S. B., Keefer D. K., &quot;Toward a Comprehensive Areal Model of Earthquake- Induced Landslides , Natural Hazard Center (2009a). 18. Memarian P., Mahdavifar M., &quot;Distribution and Characteristics of Landslides Induced by the Varzeghan Ahar Earthquake Doublet (Mw=6.4 and Mw= 6.3) in 2012 in Azerbaijan E Sharghi, Northwest of Iran. IPL Symposium (2002) 35. 19. Gee, M. D.,&quot;Classification of River Basin&quot;, Central Italy, Environmental management, 25 (1992) 247-263.  20. Jade S., Sarkar S., &quot;Statistical Models for Slope Instability&quot;, Classifications Engineering Geology, 36 (1993) 91-98. ##. مهدویفر م. ر.، &quot;ارزیابی تحلیلی و طراحی سامانه مدیریت ریسک زمین‌لغزش‌های ناشی از زلزله در کشور &quot;، پایان‌نامۀ دکتری پژوهشکدۀ زلزله‌شناسی و مهندسی زلزله (1385). ##2. رجبی ع. م.، &quot;بررسی احتمالی خطر زمین‌لغزش‌های ناشی از زلزله در ایران.&quot;، پایان‌نامۀ دکتری زمین‌شناسی گرایش مهندسی، دانشکدۀ علوم پایه، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس (1389). ##3. باقری و.، &quot;پهنه‌بندی زمین‌لغزش‌های ناشی از زلزله (مطالعۀ موردی زلزله اردبیل)&quot;، پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه خوارزمی تهران (1391). ##4. کمک‌پناه ع.، حافظی مقدس ن.، &quot;پهنه‌بندی خطر زمین‌لغزش در ایران، جلد ششم: شناسایی و به نقشه درآوردن زمین‌لغزه‌های مهم تحریک‌شده در زلزله خردادماه 1369 منجیل&quot;، پژوهشکدۀ زلزله‌شناسی و مهندسی زلزله (1372). ##5. نوگل سادات م.، &quot;طرح جامع خطر رانش استان گیلان&quot;، کارفرما: زیر کمیته زلزله و لغزش لایه‌های زمین معاونت شهرسازی و معماری وزارت مسکن و شهرسازی (1375). ##6. مصفایی ج.، شریعت جعفری م.، &quot;مقایسه کارایی مدل‌های تجربی و آماری پهنه‌بندی خطر زمین‌لغزش (مطالعه موردی آبخیز الموت)&quot;، مجله پژوهش‌های حفاظت آب‌وخاک، جلد شانزدهم، شماره چهارم (1385). ##7. علی مرادی م.، سیف ع.، شیرانی ک.، &quot;صحت‌سنجی روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی (AHP) و رگرسیون چند متغیره (MR) در پهنه‌بندی خطر زمین‌لغزش به‌کمک تکنیک GIS (مطالعه موردی حوزه رودخانه ماربر)&quot;، مهندسی فناوری اطلاعات مکانی، سال اول، شماره دوم (1391). ##8. معماریان پ.، &quot;گزارش پژوهش 1 و 2 مقطع دکتری زمین‌لغزش‌های ناشی از زلزله&quot;، پژوهشکدۀ زلزله‌شناسی و مهندسی زلزله (1389).## 9. قدسی‌پور ح.، &quot;فرآیند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی&quot;، چاپ هفتم، تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر(1388).## 10. Ayalew L., Yamagishi H., &quot;The application of GIS-based logistic regression for landslide susceptibility mapping in the Kakuda-Yahiko Mountains&quot;, Central Japan. Geomorphology, 65,(2005) 15-31.## 11. Jibson R.W., &quot;Regression models for estimating coseismic landslide displacement&quot;, Engineering Geology (2007).## 12. Del Gaudio V., Wasowski J., &quot;Seismic rock fall hazard in the sele river valleyT southern Italy&quot;, Thomas Thelford (2000).## 13. Keefer D. K., &quot;Landslides caused by earhquakes. Geological Society American Bulletin&quot;, 95 (1984) 406-421.## 14. Mahdavifar M. R., Solaymani S., Jafari M. K., &quot;Landslides triggered by the Avaj&quot;, Iran earthquake of June 22. Engineering Geology, 86 (2002) 166-182.## 15. Saaty T. L., &quot;Axiomatic foundation of analytical hierarchy process&quot;, Journal of Management science, Vol. 31, No. 7 ((1986)) 841-855.##  16. Komac M., &quot;A landslide susceptibility model using the analytical hierarchy process method and multivariate statistics in Perialpine Slovenia&quot;, Geomorphology, 74 (2006) 17-28 ## 17. Miles S. B., Keefer D. K., &quot;Toward a Comprehensive Areal Model of Earthquake- Induced Landslides , Natural Hazard Center (2009a).## 18. Memarian P., Mahdavifar M., &quot;Distribution and Characteristics of Landslides Induced by the Varzeghan Ahar Earthquake Doublet (Mw=6.4 and Mw= 6.3) in 2012 in Azerbaijan E Sharghi, Northwest of Iran. IPL Symposium (2002) 35.## 19. Gee, M. D.,&quot;Classification of River Basin&quot;, Central Italy, Environmental management, 25 (1992) 247-263. ## 20. Jade S., Sarkar S., &quot;Statistical Models for Slope Instability&quot;, Classifications Engineering Geology, 36 (1993) 91-98. ## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>ارزیابی اثر ساختگاه با استفاده از تفسیر داده‌های میکروترمور (مطالعۀ موردی: شهر بابل)</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Evaluation of Site Effect Using Ambient Noise Survey (A Case Study: Babol City)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>یکی از مهمترین مباحث ژئوتکنیک لرزه &#173;ای، بررسی اثر ساختگاه بر روی مشخصات امواج زمین لرزه می&#8204;باشد. این پدیده در محل&#173; هایی که دارای خاک نرم و لایه &#173;ای هستند، باعث تغییر مشخصات امواج لرزه &#173;ای شده و منجر به تقویت ارتعاشات و افزایش خسارات مالی و جانی می گردد. امروزه روش&#173; های متنوعی برای ارزیابی اثر ساختگاه وجود دارد که در میان آنها، اندازه&#173;&#173; گیری میکروترمورها به دلیل سادگی، هزینه&#8204; پایین و عملیات اجرایی آسان بیش از سایر روش&#173; های دیگر مورد استفاده قرار می&#173; گیرند. در این پژوهش به منظور تخمین فرکانس اساسی و ضریب تقویت ارتعاش در شهر بابل، اندازه&#8204;گیری میکروترمور در 60 ایستگاه صورت پذیرفت. نگاشت&#173; های میکروترمور به کمک روش ناکامورا (نسبت طیفی H/V) و با استفاده از نرم&#8204;افزار Geopsy پردازش گردید&#173; و با معیارهای SESAME صحت&#8204;سنجی شدهند. نتایج نشان می&#173;دهند که فرکانس اساسی بین 0/65 الی 11/4 هرتز تغییر کرده و بخش وسیعی از ناحیه&#8204; مطالعاتی دارای فرکانس اساسی کمتر از 1 هرتز می&#173; باشد؛ همچنین مقدار بیشینه و کمینه&#8204; ضریب تقویت ارتعاش به ترتیب 3/71 و 1/19 ارزیابی شده است. در ادامه برای بررسی توانمندی و دقت این روش، نتایج پردازش میکروترمور با داده&#8204;های ژئوتکنیکی، تحلیل عددی و اطلاعات دستگاه شتاب&#173;&#8204;نگار موجود در منطقه مقایسه گردیدند. این مقایسه نحوه&#8204; تغییرات فرکانس اساسی در ناحیه&#8204; مطالعاتی را تایید و اندازه&#173; گیری میکروترمور را روشی مناسب معرفی کرده است. در انتها با بررسی جنبه&#173; های مختلف می &#173;توان اندازه &#173;گیری میکروترمور را روشی کارآمد و ایده &#173;آل برای ارزیابی اثر ساختگاه شهر بابل در نظر گرفت.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Introduction
Every year, numerous casualties and a large deal of financial losses are experienced due to earthquake events. The losses incurred by an earthquake vary depending on local site effect. Some well-known examples include the earthquake in Caracas 1967, Mexico city 1985, Kalamata 1986, Loma Prieta 1989, Roodbar 1990, Bam 2003, Jammu and Kashmir 2005, Sichuan 2008 and Haiti 2010. Therefore, in order to conquer drastic effects of an earthquake, one should evaluate urban districts in terms of the local site effect. Various methods are available for the evaluation of site effect. One of the most common methods includes ambient noise survey. Today, this approach is being used as fast, applicable, cost-effective method. Ambient seismic noise are feeble ground motions with displacement amplitudes of about 0.1&#8211;1 &#956;m and that can be detected by seismograph with high magniﬁcation. Many investigations have been conducted to determine the nature of ambient noise. One of the possible sources of ambient noise can be human activity, such as trafﬁc, industrial noises and nature activity, such as wind, ocean waves. The Babol city is one of the largest cities in the north of Iran (Mazandaran province). It lies on alluvium beds in the region presenting a high seismic potential. Therefore, comprehensive studies are necessary to introduce suitable solutions for minimizing earthquake damage and loss of life. For this reason, in Babol city, ambient noise survey has been performed at 60 stations and the obtained data were analyzed with Nakamura or H/V method (1989). The results were compared with local geological, geotechnical and seismic data to confirm their reliability for a seismo-stratigraphic.
Methodology and data collection
The analysis of ambient noise was initially proposed by Kanai and Takana (1961). Since then, many researchers have used ambient noise for site effect evaluation. As it is said before, one of the most popular techniques for estimation of site effects in the regions with low seismicity is ambient noise survey by Nakamura or H/V method (1989). Based on the literature review, the Nakamura method (1989) has been used in many places. Many theoretical and experimental studies show that, this method has the capability of estimation of fundamental frequency. Ambient noise survey was carried out at 60 stations in Babol city. Ambient noise was recorded using a velocity meter SARA. Two horizontal and a vertical components of ambient noise at each location are recorded for duration of 15 min with 100 samples per second. Because the environmental noise has an effect on ambient noise they are recoded between 10 p.m. to 6 a.m. The locations were determined by using GPS at the sites. The ambient noise survey in this study was made in compliance with the guidelines of SESAME (2004).
Results and discussion
The maximum and minimum values of fundamental frequency of the present research are 11.4 and 0.65 Hz, respectively. Also, the maximum and minimum values of amplitude of H/V peaks have been calculated as 3.71 and 1.19, respectively. The most significant point is that the fundamental frequency of the major part of Babol city is smaller than 1 Hz in agreement with the previous knowledge of the city geological setting. Another relevant point is the presence of some stations with very high (&#62; 5 Hz) fundamental frequencies. In these cases, ambient noise recording and data analysis were repeated, but similar results were obtained. Considering the lack of sufficient geotechnical data (in some stations), the above phenomena need to be integrated with other methods. For this purpose, the data of electrical resistivity tomography (ERT) were used. The ERT showed that small regions of the north-west, west, and south areas have high resistance values probably related with the presence of hard deposits in the shallow subsoil. Babolrood river diversion in the west part and its return to the previous direction in the northern section is possibly due to the existence of these relatively hard deposits. By comparing these two tests, we observed that the ERT results correlate with the ambient data analysis. Therefore, we can conclude that the high-frequency peaks measured are reliable, but we need direct investigation to associate them to a specific shallow geological layer. To validate the results, fundamental frequencies obtained from ambient noise survey were compared with geotechnical data, numerical analysis and seismic data in the study area. A general review shows that the geotechnical data, equivalent-linear analysis results and seismic data have an acceptable conformity with the results of ambient noise survey.
Conclusion
The results show minimum and maximum fundamental frequencies 0.65 and 11.4 Hz, respectively. Assessment also reveals that the major parts of Babol city have the fundamental frequencies less than 1 Hz, which are in conformity with that of previous research. According to the results of seven cross sections, it can be concluded that fundamental frequency variations are in line with the geotechnical and geological data in the study area. It means that this method is the appropriate way to assess the local site effect in the Babol city. It is also observed that besides the soil layers, the soil stiffness and its shear wave velocity are effective factors in changing the fundamental frequency. Site frequencies were also estimated by preliminary 1-D site modeling using the equivalent-linear method. In general, a reasonable correspondence between the methods was obtained. Using seismic data, the HVSR of two strong ground motions have been calculated and the results have been compared with the nearest ambient noise recording station. Analyzing the spectral ratios demonstrates that the value of the fundamental frequency obtained by the H/V method (1.06 Hz) is very close to that of frequencies obtained by the seismic data (0.95 and 0.90 Hz)../files/site1/files/124/6rezaee%DA%86%DA%A9%DB%8C%D8%AF%D9%87.pdf</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>659</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>686</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>صادق</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رضائی</Family>
				<NameE>Sadegh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rezaei</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی نوشیروانی بابل، دانشکدۀ مهندسی عمران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه صنعتی نوشیروانی بابل</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>s_rezaei1366@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>عسکر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>جانعلیزاده</Family>
				<NameE>Asskar</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Janalizadeh Choobbasti</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی نوشیروانی بابل، دانشکدۀ مهندسی عمران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه صنعتی نوشیروانی بابل</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Asskar@nit.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Site effect</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>H/V spectral ratio</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Ambient noise</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Fundamental frequency</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Amplification factor</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اثر ساختگاه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نسبت طیفی H/V</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>میکروترمور</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>فرکانس اساسی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ضریب تقویت ارتعاش</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>. رضائی ص.، &quot;بررسی اثرات ساختگاه و تخمین خصوصیات جنبش نیرومند زمین با استفاده از داده‌های میکروترمور و مقایسۀ نتایج آن با مدل‌سازی پروفیل خاک (مطالعۀ موردی: شهر بابل) &quot;، پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه صنعتی بابل (1392). 2. Choobbasti A. J., Rezaei S., Farrokhzad F., Heidarzadeh Azar P., &quot;Evaluation of site response characteristics using nonlinear method (Case study: Babol, Iran)&quot;, Frontiers of Structural and Civil Engineering, Vol. 8(1) (2014) 69-82.  3. Rezaei S., Choobbasti A. J., &quot;Liquefaction assessment using microtremor measurement, conventional method and artificial neural network (Case study: Babol, Iran)&quot;, Frontiers of Structural and Civil Engineering, Vol. 8 (3) (2014) 292-307.  4. Del Gaudio V., Muscillo S., Wasowski J., &quot;What we can learn about slope response to earthquakes from ambient noise analysis: an overview&quot;, Engineering Geology, Vol. 182 (2014) 182-200.  5. Panzera F., Lombardo G., Rigano R., &quot;Evidence of topographic effects through the analysis of ambient noise measurements&quot;, Seismological Research Letters, Vol. 82 (2011) 413-419.  6. Molnar S., Ventura C. E., Boroschek R., Archila M., &quot;Site characterization at Chilean strong-motion stations: comparison of downhole and microtremor shear-wave velocity methods&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, Vol. 79 (2015) 22-35.  7. Singh A. P., &quot;Seismic hazard evaluation in Anjar city area of western India: microtremor array measurement&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, Vol. 71 (2015) 143-150.  8. Guo Z., Aydin A., Kuszmaul J. S., &quot;Microtremor recordings in northern Mississippi&quot;, Engineering Geology, Vol. 179 (2014) 146-157.  9. Mundepi A. K., Galiana-Merino J. J., Asthana A. K. L., Rosa-Cintas S., &quot;Soil characterizations in Doon Valley (north west Himalaya, India) by inversion of H/V spectral ratios from ambient noise measurements&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, Vol. 77 (2015) 309-320.  10. Nakamura Y., &quot;A method for dynamic characteristics estimation of subsurface using microtremor on the ground surface&quot;, Quarterly Report of Railway Technical Research Institute, Vol. 30 (1989) 25-33.  11. Chavez-Garcia F. J., Kang T. S., &quot;Lateral heterogeneities and microtremors: limitations of HVSR and SPAC based studies for site response&quot;, Engineering Geology, Vol. 174 (2014) 1-10.  12. Rezaei S., Choobbasti A. J., Kutanaei S. S., &quot;Site effect assessment using microtremor measurement, equivalent linear method, and artificial neural network (case study: Babol, Iran)&quot;, Arabian Journal of Geosciences, Vol.8 (2015) 1453-1466.  13. Choobbasti A. J., Rezaei S., Farrokhzad F., &quot;Evaluation of site response characteristics using microtremors&quot;, Gradevinar, Vol. 65 (2013) 731-741.  14. Choobbasti A. J., Rezaei S., Naghizadeh M., &quot;Liquefaction assessment by microtremor measurements in Babol city&quot;, Proceedings of fifth international conference- GEOMATE2015 Geotechnic, Construction Materials and Environment Osaka, Japan (2015). 15. Burjanek J., Fah D., Pischiutta M., Rovelli A, Calderoni G., Bard P. Y., &quot;NERA-JRA1 working group. Site effects at sites with pronounced topography: overview &amp; recommendations&quot;, Research for EU project NERA (2014). 16. Jongmans D., Baillet L., Larose E., Bottelin P., Mainsant G., Chambon G., Jaboyedoff M., &quot;Application of ambient vibration techniques for monitoring the triggering of rapid landslides&quot;, Engineering Geology for Society and Territory. Springer (2015). 17. Kockar M. K., Akgun H., &quot;Evaluation of the site effects of the Ankara basin, Turkey&quot;, Journal of Applied Geophysics, Vol. 83 (2012) 120-134.  18. Rezaei S., Choobbasti A. J., &quot;Application of the microtremor measurements to a site effect study&quot;, Earthquake Sciences, DOI 10.1007/s11589-017-0187-2 (2017) 19. Navarro M., García-Jerez A., Alcalá F. J., Vidal F., Enomoto T, &quot;Local site effect microzonation of Lorca town (SE Spain)&quot;, Bulletin of Earthquake Engineering, Vol. 12(5) (2014) 1933-1959.  20. Konno K., Omachi T., &quot;Ground motion characteristics estimated from spectral ratio between horizontal and vertical components of microtremors&quot;, Bulletin of the Seismological Society of America, Vol. 88(1) (1998) 228-241.  21. Lachet C., Bard P. Y., &quot;Numerical and theoretical investigations on the possibilities and limitations of Nakamura's technique&quot;, Journal of Physics of the Earth, Vol. 42(5) (1994) 377-397.  22. Fäh D., Kind F., Giardini D., &quot;A theoretical investigation of average H/V ratios&quot;,Geophysical Journal International, Vol. 145 (2) (2001) 535-549.  23. رضائی ص.، &quot;ارزیابی زمین‌لغزش با استفاده از تفسیر داده‌های خردلرزه و ژئوالکتریک&quot;، پروپوزال دکتری، دانشگاه صنعتی بابل (1395). 24. Mukhopadhyay S., Bormann P., &quot;Low cost seismic microzonation using microtremor data: an example from Delhi, India&quot;, Journal of Asian Earth Sciences, Vol. 24 (2004) 271-280.  25. Gue´ Guen P., Cornou C., Garambois S. P., Banton J., &quot;On the limitation of the H/V spectral ratio using seismic noise as an exploration tool: application to the Grenoble valley (France), a small apex ratio basin&quot;, Pure and Applied Geophysics, Vol. 164 (2007) 115-134.  26. Teves-Costa P., Matias L., Bard P. Y., &quot;Seismic behavior estimation of thin alluvium layers using microtremor recordings&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, Vol. 15 (1996) 201-209.  27. Purnachandra Rao, N., Rabi Kumar M., Seshunarayana T., Shukla A. K., Suresh G., Pandey Y., Dharma Raju R., Pimprikar S. D., Chandra D., Kalpna G., Mishra P. S., Harsh G., &quot;Site amplification studies towards seismic microzonation in Jabalpur urban area, central India&quot;, Physics and Chemistry of the Earth, Vol. 36 (2011) 1247-1258. 28. Pilz M., Parolai S., Bindi D., Saponaro A., Abdybachaev U., &quot;Combining seismic noise techniques for landslide characterization&quot;, Pure and Applied Geophysics, Vol. 171 (2014) 1729-1745.  29. Matassoni L., Fiaschi A., Silengo M. C., Lotti A., Saccorotti G., &quot;Preliminary seismic microzonation in a mountain municipality of Tuscany (Italy)&quot;, Open Geosciences, Vol. 7 (2015) 559-571.  30. Bour M., Fouissac D., Dominique P., Martin C., &quot;On the use of microtremor recordings in seismic microzonation&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, Vol. 17 (1998) 465-474.  31. کمیتۀ دائمی بازنگری آیین‌نامه طراحی ساختمان‌ها در برابر زلزله، &quot;آیین‌نامه طراحی ساختمان‌ها در برابر زلزله، استاندارد 2800 (ویرایش چهارم) &quot;، مرکز تحقیقات راه، مسکن و شهرسازی (1393). 32. قلندرزاده ع.، معتمد ر.، &quot;اندازه‌گیری‌های میکروترمور ابزاری مناسب در مطالعات پاسخ ساختگاه&quot;، نشریۀ دانشکدۀ فنی، 38، (1383) 790-777. 33. زارع م.، قیطانچی م.ر.، اسدی ف.ج.، فریدونی ف.، &quot;بررسی اثر ساختگاه با استفاده از اندازه‌گیری‌های میکروترمور و شتاب‌نگاشت‌های ثبت شده در گستره شهر شیراز&quot;، اولین کنفرانس بین‌المللی مقاوم‌سازی لرزه‌ای، تبریز (1387). 34. قلندرزاده ع.، کاوند ع.، &quot;کاربرد اندازه‌گیری‌های نقطه‌ای و آرایه‌ای میکروترمور برای ارزیابی اثرات ساختگاهی در شهرهای ارومیه و بم&quot;، اولین همایش ملی مدیریت بحران زلزله در شهرهای دارای بافت تاریخی، یزد (1385). 35. قلندرزاده ع.، معتمد ر.، سدیدخوی ا.،&quot; ریزپهنه‌بندی لرزه شهر ارومیه با استفاده از اندازه‌گیری-های میکروترمور&quot;، چهارمین کنفرانس بین‌المللی زلزله‌شناسی و مهندسی زلزله، تهران (1382). ##. رضائی ص.، &quot;بررسی اثرات ساختگاه و تخمین خصوصیات جنبش نیرومند زمین با استفاده از داده‌های میکروترمور و مقایسۀ نتایج آن با مدل‌سازی پروفیل خاک (مطالعۀ موردی: شهر بابل) &quot;، پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه صنعتی بابل (1392). ##2. Choobbasti A. J., Rezaei S., Farrokhzad F., Heidarzadeh Azar P., &quot;Evaluation of site response characteristics using nonlinear method (Case study: Babol, Iran)&quot;, Frontiers of Structural and Civil Engineering, Vol. 8(1) (2014) 69-82. ## 3. Rezaei S., Choobbasti A. J., &quot;Liquefaction assessment using microtremor measurement, conventional method and artificial neural network (Case study: Babol, Iran)&quot;, Frontiers of Structural and Civil Engineering, Vol. 8 (3) (2014) 292-307.##  4. Del Gaudio V., Muscillo S., Wasowski J., &quot;What we can learn about slope response to earthquakes from ambient noise analysis: an overview&quot;, Engineering Geology, Vol. 182 (2014) 182-200.##  5. Panzera F., Lombardo G., Rigano R., &quot;Evidence of topographic effects through the analysis of ambient noise measurements&quot;, Seismological Research Letters, Vol. 82 (2011) 413-419. ## 6. Molnar S., Ventura C. E., Boroschek R., Archila M., &quot;Site characterization at Chilean strong-motion stations: comparison of downhole and microtremor shear-wave velocity methods&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, Vol. 79 (2015) 22-35.##  7. Singh A. P., &quot;Seismic hazard evaluation in Anjar city area of western India: microtremor array measurement&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, Vol. 71 (2015) 143-150.##  8. Guo Z., Aydin A., Kuszmaul J. S., &quot;Microtremor recordings in northern Mississippi&quot;, Engineering Geology, Vol. 179 (2014) 146-157.##  9. Mundepi A. K., Galiana-Merino J. J., Asthana A. K. L., Rosa-Cintas S., &quot;Soil characterizations in Doon Valley (north west Himalaya, India) by inversion of H/V spectral ratios from ambient noise measurements&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, Vol. 77 (2015) 309-320.##  10. Nakamura Y., &quot;A method for dynamic characteristics estimation of subsurface using microtremor on the ground surface&quot;, Quarterly Report of Railway Technical Research Institute, Vol. 30 (1989) 25-33. ## 11. Chavez-Garcia F. J., Kang T. S., &quot;Lateral heterogeneities and microtremors: limitations of HVSR and SPAC based studies for site response&quot;, Engineering Geology, Vol. 174 (2014) 1-10.##  12. Rezaei S., Choobbasti A. J., Kutanaei S. S., &quot;Site effect assessment using microtremor measurement, equivalent linear method, and artificial neural network (case study: Babol, Iran)&quot;, Arabian Journal of Geosciences, Vol.8 (2015) 1453-1466.##  13. Choobbasti A. J., Rezaei S., Farrokhzad F., &quot;Evaluation of site response characteristics using microtremors&quot;, Gradevinar, Vol. 65 (2013) 731-741.##  14. Choobbasti A. J., Rezaei S., Naghizadeh M., &quot;Liquefaction assessment by microtremor measurements in Babol city&quot;, Proceedings of fifth international conference- GEOMATE2015 Geotechnic, Construction Materials and Environment Osaka, Japan (2015).## 15. Burjanek J., Fah D., Pischiutta M., Rovelli A, Calderoni G., Bard P. Y., &quot;NERA-JRA1 working group. Site effects at sites with pronounced topography: overview &amp; recommendations&quot;, Research for EU project NERA (2014).## 16. Jongmans D., Baillet L., Larose E., Bottelin P., Mainsant G., Chambon G., Jaboyedoff M., &quot;Application of ambient vibration techniques for monitoring the triggering of rapid landslides&quot;, Engineering Geology for Society and Territory. Springer (2015).## 17. Kockar M. K., Akgun H., &quot;Evaluation of the site effects of the Ankara basin, Turkey&quot;, Journal of Applied Geophysics, Vol. 83 (2012) 120-134. ## 18. Rezaei S., Choobbasti A. J., &quot;Application of the microtremor measurements to a site effect study&quot;, Earthquake Sciences, DOI 10.1007/s11589-017-0187-2 (2017)## 19. Navarro M., García-Jerez A., Alcalá F. J., Vidal F., Enomoto T, &quot;Local site effect microzonation of Lorca town (SE Spain)&quot;, Bulletin of Earthquake Engineering, Vol. 12(5) (2014) 1933-1959.  ##20. Konno K., Omachi T., &quot;Ground motion characteristics estimated from spectral ratio between horizontal and vertical components of microtremors&quot;, Bulletin of the Seismological Society of America, Vol. 88(1) (1998) 228-241.##  21. Lachet C., Bard P. Y., &quot;Numerical and theoretical investigations on the possibilities and limitations of Nakamura's technique&quot;, Journal of Physics of the Earth, Vol. 42(5) (1994) 377-397.##  22. Fäh D., Kind F., Giardini D., &quot;A theoretical investigation of average H/V ratios&quot;,Geophysical Journal International, Vol. 145 (2) (2001) 535-549.##  23. رضائی ص.، &quot;ارزیابی زمین‌لغزش با استفاده از تفسیر داده‌های خردلرزه و ژئوالکتریک&quot;، پروپوزال دکتری، دانشگاه صنعتی بابل (1395). ##24. Mukhopadhyay S., Bormann P., &quot;Low cost seismic microzonation using microtremor data: an example from Delhi, India&quot;, Journal of Asian Earth Sciences, Vol. 24 (2004) 271-280##.  25. Gue´ Guen P., Cornou C., Garambois S. P., Banton J., &quot;On the limitation of the H/V spectral ratio using seismic noise as an exploration tool: application to the Grenoble valley (France), a small apex ratio basin&quot;, Pure and Applied Geophysics, Vol. 164 (2007) 115-134.##  26. Teves-Costa P., Matias L., Bard P. Y., &quot;Seismic behavior ##estimation of thin alluvium layers using microtremor recordings&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, Vol. 15 (1996) 201-209.  27. Purnachandra Rao, N., Rabi Kumar M., Seshunarayana T., Shukla A. K., Suresh G., Pandey Y., Dharma Raju R., Pimprikar S. D., Chandra D., Kalpna G., Mishra P. S., Harsh G., &quot;Site amplification studies towards seismic microzonation in Jabalpur urban area, central India&quot;, Physics and Chemistry of the Earth, Vol. 36 (2011) 1247-1258.## 28. Pilz M., Parolai S., Bindi D., Saponaro A., Abdybachaev U., &quot;Combining seismic noise techniques for landslide characterization&quot;, Pure and Applied Geophysics, Vol. 171 (2014) 1729-1745.##  29. Matassoni L., Fiaschi A., Silengo M. C., Lotti A., Saccorotti G., &quot;Preliminary seismic microzonation in a mountain municipality of Tuscany (Italy)&quot;, Open Geosciences, Vol. 7 (2015) 559-571. ## 30. Bour M., Fouissac D., Dominique P., Martin C., &quot;On the use of microtremor recordings in seismic microzonation&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, Vol. 17 (1998) 465-474.##  31. کمیتۀ دائمی بازنگری آیین‌نامه طراحی ساختمان‌ها در برابر زلزله، &quot;آیین‌نامه طراحی ساختمان‌ها در برابر زلزله، استاندارد 2800 (ویرایش چهارم) &quot;، مرکز تحقیقات راه، مسکن و شهرسازی (1393).## 32. قلندرزاده ع.، معتمد ر.، &quot;اندازه‌گیری‌های میکروترمور ابزاری مناسب در مطالعات پاسخ ساختگاه&quot;، نشریۀ دانشکدۀ فنی، 38، (1383) 790-777.## 33. زارع م.، قیطانچی م.ر.، اسدی ف.ج.، فریدونی ف.، &quot;بررسی اثر ساختگاه با استفاده از اندازه‌گیری‌های میکروترمور و شتاب‌نگاشت‌های ثبت شده در گستره شهر شیراز&quot;، اولین کنفرانس بین‌المللی مقاوم‌سازی لرزه‌ای، تبریز (1387).## 34. قلندرزاده ع.، کاوند ع.، &quot;کاربرد اندازه‌گیری‌های نقطه‌ای و آرایه‌ای میکروترمور برای ارزیابی اثرات ساختگاهی در شهرهای ارومیه و بم&quot;، اولین همایش ملی مدیریت بحران زلزله در شهرهای دارای بافت تاریخی، یزد (1385).## 35. قلندرزاده ع.، معتمد ر.، سدیدخوی ا.،&quot; ریزپهنه‌بندی لرزه شهر ارومیه با استفاده از اندازه‌گیری-های میکروترمور&quot;، چهارمین کنفرانس بین‌المللی زلزله‌شناسی و مهندسی زلزله، تهران (1382). #### ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر نوع ریزدانه بر به‌سازی بیولوژیکی خاک ماسه‌ای</TitleF>
		<TitleE>The Effect of Fines Type on Biological Improvement of Sandy Soil</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>در بسیاری از مناطق در سراسر جهان پیدایش روش&#8204;های جدید و سازگار با محیط&#8204;زیست برای به&#8204;سازی خاک&#8204;ها در حال افزایش است. استفاده &#8204;از سیمانتاسیون زیستی به&#8204;وسیلۀ رسوب میکروبی کربنات&#8204;کلسیم (MICP) برای بهبود خصوصیات مکانیکی خاک&#8204;های ضعیف، روشی &#8204;است که از طریق هیدرولیز اوره به&#8204;وسیلۀ باکتری حاوی آنزیم اوره&#8204;آز و در حضور یون&#8204;های کلسیم محلول منجر به &#8204;ترسیب &#8204;کربنات&#8204;کلسیم بین دانه&#8204;های خاک و درنتیجه اتصال بین آن&#8204;ها می&#8204;شود. در این پژوهش با به&#8204;سازی خاک ماسه انزلی (با ریزدانه بسیار اندک و کم&#8204;تر از یک درصد) و مخلوط&#8204;های جداگانه آن با یک نوع خاک ریزدانه چسبنده و یک نوع خاک ریزدانه غیرچسبنده در درصد وزنی 30 به&#8204;روش MICP و با استفاده &#8204;از آزمایش برش مستقیم کوچک مقیاس (6&#215;6) برای ارزیابی پارامترهای مقاومتی خاک، به بررسی تأثیر افزایش ریزدانه&#8204;ها بر روند&#8204; به&#8204;سازی خاک ماسه انزلی پرداختیم. متوسط تنش برشی حداکثر نمونه&#8204;های به&#8204;سازی&#8204;شده حاصل از تنش&#8204;های قائم 50، 100 و 150 کیلوپاسکال نشان می&#8204;دهد که افزایش ریزدانه چسبنده سبب کاهش مقاومت برشی متوسط نمونه به&#8204;سازی&#8204;شده به&#8204;میزان 9/11 درصد در مقایسه با ماسه انزلی شده &#8204;است، درحالی&#8204;که با افزایش ریزدانه غیرچسبنده مقاومت برشی متوسط نمونه به&#8204;سازی&#8204;شده نسبت&#8204;به ماسه انزلی 8/20 درصد افزایش یافته &#8204;است. در آنالیزهای SEM و EDX که از نمونه خاک ماسه انزلی در شرایط قبل و بعد از به&#8204;سازی گرفته&#8204; شده است، وجود عناصر تشکیل&#8204;دهندۀ رسوب کربنات&#8204;کلسیم در نمونه به&#8204;سازی&#8204;شده تأیید شده و هم&#8204;چنین توزیع مناسب آن در بین دانه&#8204;های خاک مشاهده شده&#8204;است</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Introduction
In many areas of the world, the mechanical properties of soils for utilization of land are not sufficient. For improvement of these lands, soil stabilization such as compacting, installation of nails, elders of piles, mixing soil with lime or cement before or during constructions on the surface or inside of the ground can be useful. Microbially induced carbonate precipitation (MICP), due to its versatility and stable performance, has been recently attracted the attention of many researchers in the field of the geotechnical engineering around the world. MICP is a biological technique that is naturally caused to create a cementation agent, which is known as calcium carbonate or calcite by controlling the metabolism of bacteria. Although there are many biological processes that can be lead to MICP, but the using of urea hydrolysis by bacteria is commonly used more. In this method, aerobic bacteria with the enriched urease enzymes inject into the soil. Hydrolysis of urea occurs when the bacteria speeds up the hydrolysis reaction to produce ammonium and carbonate ions. In the presence of soluble calcium ions, carbonate ions are precipitated and formed the calcium carbonate crystals. When these crystals are formed on a grain of soil or like a bridge between them, they prevent the movement of grains and thus improve the mechanical and geotechnical properties of the soil.
Material and methods
In the present study, the effect of increasing fines on the improvement of Anzali sandy soil, and soil resistance parameters for improving the clean sand and its mixtures with a fine grained cohesive soil and a fine grained cohesionless soil separately in a percentage weight of 30 by MICP and using a small scale of direct shear test (6&#215;6) have been investigated. In the present study the sandy soil was collected from the coast of Bandar Anzali Free Zone and for the preparation of samples of clayey sand and silty sand, Kaolinite clay soils and Firouzkooh broken silt were used, respectively. Anzali sand is poorly graded and had a rounded corner with an average particle size of 0.2 mm, somewhat, sharpening cores are also found in its granulation. In addition, its fine grained content is very small (less than 1%). The Kaolinite clay is also labeled with a liquid limit of 40, a plastic limit of 25, and a plasticity index of 15 as an inorganic clay (CL). The used microorganism in this study is urease positive Sporosarcina pasteurii, which is maintained with the number of PTCC1645 at the Center Collective of Industrial Microorganisms of Iran Scientific and Research Organization. The bacterium was cultured in a culture medium containing 20 g/l yeast extract and 10 g/l ammonium chloride at pH 9 under aerobic conditions in incubator shaker machine at 150 rpm and temperature of 30 &#176;C. The organism was grown to late exponential/early stationary phase and stored at 4 &#176;C before injection in samples. A solution of calcium chloride and urea with a molar ratio of one is also used as a cementation solution. With the direct shear test (6cm&#215;6cm) as a benchmarking of the shear strength in the before and after improvement steps, molds fitted with a shear box made of the galvanized sheet with a thickness of 0.6 mm and it consists of two main parts, the body,&#160; in the middle of which an exhaust pipe was embedded in the injector waste fluid. At the bottom of the samples, a layer of filter paper was placed in order to prevent soil washes, and then all samples with a thickness of 2 cm, with a relative density of 30% at the same weight and height were pressed. In the upper part of the samples, a layer of filter paper is similarly used to prevent the discontinuity of soil particles when injected biological materials are used. Biological solutions are injected from the top to the specimens and allowed to penetrate under the influence of gravitational and capillary forces in the sample and discharge the inhaled fluid from the exhaust pipe. The criterion for determining the volume of the solution to inject into each sample is the pure volume (PV) of soil. The preparation process of the samples was initiated by injection of a PV water unit, followed by a two-layer mixture of bacterial suspensions and cementation solutions, each with a volume of one PV, and then for biological reactions, 24 hours to the sample at laboratory temperature (25 &#177; 2) is given. After the time of incubation, the solution of cementation is injected into the sample for a period of three days and every 24 hours. The processing time of samples is also considered 28 days. In this study, optical density (OD) was selected as a benchmark for estimating the concentration of bacterial cells in the culture medium, and in all stages of development, and precisely before injection of bacteria suspension into soil samples, it was measured by a spectrophotometer device at 600 nm (OD600) wavelength, which was obtained for all bacterial suspensions in the range of 1.7 to 2 before the injection. To determine the activity of urea bacteria, 1 ml of bacterial suspension was added to nine milliliters of 1.11 molar urea solution, and by immersing the electrode of the electrical conductivity in the solution, its conductivity was recorded for 5 minutes at 20 &#177; 2 &#176; C. The rate of urea activity in the pre-treatment stage for all specimens was in the range of 0.8 to 1.23 mS min-1. In order to evaluate the shear strength parameters of soil samples, before and after the improvement operations, a direct shear test was used based on the ASTM D3080 standard. This test was performed for all samples under stresses of 50, 100 and 150 kPa in undrained conditions at a loading speed of 1 mm/min up to a strain of 15%. Also, samples of soil with a moisture content of 7% and a relative density of 30% (as already mentioned) have been restored. SEM analysis was carried out to determine the distribution of sediment between soil particles and EDX analysis in order to identify carbonate calcium sediment formation elements in improved soil samples, by scanning electron microscopy on Anzali sandy soil samples in before and after improvement conditions.
&#160;
&#160;
Conclusions
The effect of the increasing cohesive and cohesionless fines on the bio-treated process of sandy soil is the main subject of this research. For this purpose, three samples of clean sand, sand containing 30% clay and sand mixture with 30% silt in a relative density of 30% were treated with MICP method and their shear strength parameters were evaluated by direct shear test after 28 days of processing. Using the direct shear test and analyses of SEM and EDX data, the results are represented as below:
1.&#160; The microbial sediment of carbonate calcium has greatly improved the resistance properties of all three soil samples.
2. A sample of clayey sand, in spite of a higher improvement compared to the other samples with an average shear strength of 113.7% in comparison to to its untreated state, it has the lowest shear strength among the three improved samples.
3. Increasing the clay content of 30% increases the soil voids. On the other hand, it reduces the friction angle and shear strength of the soil in the pre-treated state and also facilitates easier movement of the bacteria between the pores in the soil. More favorable distribution of sediment calcium carbonate was occurred and, as a result, increased adhesion between soil particles.
4. The increase of cohesionless fine particles creates more bonding points between sand particles and, therefore, calcium carbonate crystals form shorter distances between the soil bridges. As a result, with the end of the improvement process, the shear strength parameters of the sandy soil containing 30% of the silt compared to the clean sand have a higher value.
5. SEM images of the clean sand in both before and after improvement show that the calcium carbonate precipitation occurred with a uniform and thin layer that surrounds sand grains and another part of the sediments formed in the joint of grains.
6. Cube-shaped crystalline sediments confirm that the sediment formed in the soil is a stable type of calcite and that the relative increase in the friction angle of the improvement samples can be attributed to solid particles and multifaceted sediments. Also, the elements of carbon, oxygen, and calcium, which are the main components for the formation of calcium carbonate deposits, have been found in the EDX analysis of improvement sand samples../files/site1/files/124/7sohrabi%DA%86%DA%A9%DB%8C%D8%AF%D9%87.pdf
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>687</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>706</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>نوید</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>سهرابی</Family>
				<NameE>Navid</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Sohrabi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه قم، دانشکدۀ فنی و مهندسی، گروه مهندسی عمران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه قم</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>sohrabinavid2@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهدی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>خداپرست</Family>
				<NameE>Mehdi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Khodaparast</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه قم، دانشکدۀ فنی و مهندسی، گروه مهندسی عمران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه قم</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Khodaparast@qom.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Biocementation</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>clayey sand</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>soil improvement</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>microbially induced carbonate precipitation (MICP)</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>silty sand.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سیمانتاسیون زیستی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ماسهرس‌دار</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>به‌سازی خاک</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>رسوب میکروبی کربنات‌کلسیم</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ماسه‌سیلتی.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1.	Van Paassen L. A., &quot;Biogrout, ground improvement by microbial induced carbonate precipitation&quot;, PhD Thesis, Murdoch University (2009). 2.	Harkes M. P., et al., &quot;Fixation and distribution of bacterial activity in sand to induce carbonate precipitation for ground reinforcement&quot;, Ecological Engineering, 36 (2) (2010) 112-117. 3.	Cheng L., Shahin M. A., Mujah D., &quot;Influence of key environmental conditions on microbially induced cementation for soil stabilization&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering, 143 (1) (2016) 04016083 (1-11). 4.	Whiffin V. S., &quot;Microbial CaCO3 precipitation for the production of biocement&quot;, PhD Thesis, Murdoch University) 2004(. 5.	Whiffin V. S., van Paassen L. A., Harkes M. P., &quot;Microbial carbonate precipitation as a soil improvement technique&quot;, Geomicrobiology Journal, 24 (5) ( 2007) 417-423. 6.	DeJong J. T., Fritzges M. B., Nüsslein K., &quot;Microbially induced cementation to control sand response to undrained shear&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering, 132 (11) (2006) 1381-1392. 7.	Al-Thawadi S., &quot;High strength in-situ biocementation of soil by calcite precipitating locally isolated ureolytic bacteria&quot;, PhD Thesis, Murdoch University (2008). 8.	Van Paassen L., et al., &quot;Scale up of BioGrout: a biological ground reinforcement method&quot;, in Proceedings of the 17th international conference on soil mechanics and geotechnical engineering, Lansdale IOS Press (2009). 9.	DeJong J. T., et al., &quot;Bio-mediated soil improvement. Ecological Engineering, 36 (2) (2010) 197-210. 10.	Cheng L. Cord-Ruwisch R., &quot;In situ soil cementation with ureolytic bacteria by surface percolation&quot;, Ecological Engineering, 42 (2012) 64-72. 11. Tsukamoto M., et al., &quot;Influence of relative density on microbial carbonate precipitation and mechanical properties of sand&quot;, in Proceedings of the 18th International Conference on Soil Mechanics and Geotechnical Engineering, Paris (2013). 12.	Cheng L., et al., &quot;Soil stabilisation by Microbial-Induced Calcite Precipitation (MICP): Investigation into some physical and environmental aspects&quot;, in 7th International Congress on Environmental Geotechnics: iceg 2014 Engineers Australia (2014). 13.	Rowshanbakht K., et al., &quot;Effect of injected bacterial suspension volume and relative density on carbonate precipitation resulting from microbial treatment&quot;, Ecological Engineering, 89 (2016) 49-55. 14.	سجادی م.، حبیب‌آگهی ق.، &quot;بررسی امکان به‌سازی خاک متورم شونده به‌روش بیولوژیکی&quot;، پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد, دانشگاه شیراز (1392). 15.	گل‌محمدی س.، همکاران, &quot;تأثیر دانه‌بندی ماسه بر روی مقاومت برشی نمونه‌های به‌سازی شده به‌روش میکروبیولوژیکی&quot;، نهمین کنگرۀ ملی مهندسی عمران، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد: مشهد، ایران (1395). 16.	محسن‌زاده آ.،و همکاران، &quot;تأثیر رسوب میکروبی کلسیم کربنات بر پارامترهای مقاومت برشی خاک ماسه‌ای. پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه تبریز (1394). 17.	میرمحمدصادقی م. و همکاران، &quot;ارزیابی عوامل مؤثر در به‌سازی زیستی خاک به‌روش تزریق باکتری در خاک های ماسه‌ای&quot;و نشریۀ علوم آب و خاک، شماره77، (1395). 18.	ASTM D 422-63 (Reapproved), &quot;Standard test method for particle-size analysis of soils&quot;, The American Society for Testing and Materials: West Conshohocken, PA 19428-2959, United States (2002). 19.	ASTM D 854-10, &quot;Standard test methods for specific gravity of soil solids by water pycnometer&quot;, The American Society for Testing and Materials: West Conshohocken, PA 19428-2959, United States (2010). 20.	ASTM D 4254-00, &quot;Standard test method for minimum index density and unit weight of soils and calculation of relative density&quot;, The American Society for Testing and Materials: West Conshohocken, PA 19428-2959, United States (2002). 21.	ASTM D 1557, &quot;Standard Test Method for Laboratory Compaction Characteristics of Soil Using Modified Effort&quot;, The American Society for Testing and Materials: West Conshohocken, PA 19428-2959, United States (2012). 22.	ASTM D 4318-10e01, &quot;Standard test method for liquid limit, plastic limit and plasticity index of soils&quot;, The American Society for Testing and Materials: West Conshohocken, PA 19428-2959, United States (2014). 23.	کاهانی م.، &quot;رسوب‌گذاری زیستی کلسیم‌کربنات در خاک‌های ماسه‌ای و تأثیر آن بر افزایش مقاومت خاک. فصلنامه علمی محیط زیست، شمارۀ 52، (1391). 24.	Okwadha G. D., Li J., &quot;Optimum conditions for microbial carbonate precipitation. Chemosphere, 81 (9) (2010) 1143-1148. 25.	ASTM D 3080, &quot;Standard Test Method for Direct Shear Test of Soils Under Consolidated Drained Conditions&quot;, The American Society for Testing and Materials: West Conshohocken, PA 19428-2959, United States (2006). 26.	Tegethoff F. W., Rohleder J., Kroker E., &quot;Calcium carbonate: from the Cretaceous period into the 21st century&quot;, Springer Science &amp; Business Media (2001).  ##1.	Van Paassen L. A., &quot;Biogrout, ground improvement by microbial induced carbonate precipitation&quot;, PhD Thesis, Murdoch University (2009).## 2.	Harkes M. P., et al., &quot;Fixation and distribution of bacterial activity in sand to induce carbonate precipitation for ground reinforcement&quot;, Ecological Engineering, 36 (2) (2010) 112-117.## 3.	Cheng L., Shahin M. A., Mujah D., &quot;Influence of key environmental conditions on microbially induced cementation for soil stabilization&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering, 143 (1) (2016) 04016083 (1-11).## 4.	Whiffin V. S., &quot;Microbial CaCO3 precipitation for the production of biocement&quot;, PhD Thesis, Murdoch University) 2004(. ##5.	Whiffin V. S., van Paassen L. A., Harkes M. P., &quot;Microbial carbonate precipitation as a soil improvement technique&quot;, Geomicrobiology Journal, 24 (5) ( 2007) 417-423.## 6.	DeJong J. T., Fritzges M. B., Nüsslein K., &quot;Microbially induced cementation to control sand response to undrained shear&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering, 132 (11) (2006) 1381-1392. ##7.	Al-Thawadi S., &quot;High strength in-situ biocementation of soil by calcite precipitating locally isolated ureolytic bacteria&quot;, PhD Thesis, Murdoch University (2008).## 8.	Van Paassen L., et al., &quot;Scale up of BioGrout: a biological ground reinforcement method&quot;, in Proceedings of the 17th international conference on soil mechanics and geotechnical engineering, Lansdale IOS Press (2009).## 9.	DeJong J. T., et al., &quot;Bio-mediated soil improvement. Ecological Engineering, 36 (2) (2010) 197-210. ##10.	Cheng L. Cord-Ruwisch R., &quot;In situ soil cementation with ureolytic bacteria by surface percolation&quot;, Ecological Engineering, 42 (2012) 64-72.## 11. Tsukamoto M., et al., &quot;Influence of relative density on microbial carbonate precipitation and mechanical properties of sand&quot;, in Proceedings of the 18th International Conference on Soil Mechanics and Geotechnical Engineering, Paris (2013).## 12.	Cheng L., et al., &quot;Soil stabilisation by Microbial-Induced Calcite Precipitation (MICP): Investigation into some physical and environmental aspects&quot;, in 7th International Congress on Environmental Geotechnics: iceg 2014 Engineers Australia (2014).## 13.	Rowshanbakht K., et al., &quot;Effect of injected bacterial suspension volume and relative density on carbonate precipitation resulting from microbial treatment&quot;, Ecological Engineering, 89 (2016) 49-55.## 14.	سجادی م.، حبیب‌آگهی ق.، &quot;بررسی امکان به‌سازی خاک متورم شونده به‌روش بیولوژیکی&quot;، پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد, دانشگاه شیراز (1392). ##15.	گل‌محمدی س.، همکاران, &quot;تأثیر دانه‌بندی ماسه بر روی مقاومت برشی نمونه‌های به‌سازی شده به‌روش میکروبیولوژیکی&quot;، نهمین کنگرۀ ملی مهندسی عمران، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد: مشهد، ایران (1395).## 16.	محسن‌زاده آ.،و همکاران، &quot;تأثیر رسوب میکروبی کلسیم کربنات بر پارامترهای مقاومت برشی خاک ماسه‌ای. پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه تبریز (1394).## 17.	میرمحمدصادقی م. و همکاران، &quot;ارزیابی عوامل مؤثر در به‌سازی زیستی خاک به‌روش تزریق باکتری در خاک های ماسه‌ای&quot;و نشریۀ علوم آب و خاک، شماره77، (1395).## 18.	ASTM D 422-63 (Reapproved), &quot;Standard test method for particle-size analysis of soils&quot;, The American Society for Testing and Materials: West Conshohocken, PA 19428-2959, United States (2002).## 19.	ASTM D 854-10, &quot;Standard test methods for specific gravity of soil solids by water pycnometer&quot;, The American Society for Testing and Materials: West Conshohocken, PA 19428-2959, United States (2010).## 20.	ASTM D 4254-00, &quot;Standard test method for minimum index density and unit weight of soils and calculation of relative density&quot;, The American Society for Testing and Materials: West Conshohocken, PA 19428-2959, United States (2002).## 21.	ASTM D 1557, &quot;Standard Test Method for Laboratory Compaction Characteristics of Soil Using Modified Effort&quot;, The American Society for Testing and Materials: West Conshohocken, PA 19428-2959, United States (2012). ##22.	ASTM D 4318-10e01, &quot;Standard test method for liquid limit, plastic limit and plasticity index of soils&quot;, The American Society for Testing and Materials: West Conshohocken, PA 19428-2959, United States (2014).## 23.	کاهانی م.، &quot;رسوب‌گذاری زیستی کلسیم‌کربنات در خاک‌های ماسه‌ای و تأثیر آن بر افزایش مقاومت خاک. فصلنامه علمی محیط زیست، شمارۀ 52، (1391). ##24.	Okwadha G. D., Li J., &quot;Optimum conditions for microbial carbonate precipitation. Chemosphere, 81 (9) (2010) 1143-1148.## 25.	ASTM D 3080, &quot;Standard Test Method for Direct Shear Test of Soils Under Consolidated Drained Conditions&quot;, The American Society for Testing and Materials: West Conshohocken, PA 19428-2959, United States (2006).## 26.	Tegethoff F. W., Rohleder J., Kroker E., &quot;Calcium carbonate: from the Cretaceous period into the 21st century&quot;, Springer Science &amp; Business Media (2001).  ## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>شبیه‌سازی رکوردهای زلزله حوزه نزدیک با استفاده از توابع موجک</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Simulation of Near-Field Records using  Wavelet Functions </TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>بررسی مشخصات اصلی جنبش&#8204;های نیرومند زمین، سابقه طولانی دارد. مشاهدات و ارزیابی&#8204;های انجام شده بر خسارات ساره&#8204;ای ایجاد شده پس از زلزله&#8204;های بزرگ نورتریج 1994 کالیفرنیا، کوبه 1995 ژاپن، بم 2003 و طبس 1978 ایران، بیان&#8204;گر اثرات بسیار ویران&#8204;گر رکوردهای نیرومند حوزۀ نزدیک است. مهم&#8204;ترین ویژگی&#8204; این رکوردها که آن&#8204;ها را از رکوردهای حوزۀ دور متمایز می&#8204;کند، توانایی تولید اسپایک&#8204;های پر انرژی و به نسبت کوتاه مدت شتاب همراه با پالس&#8204;هایی با دامنه بزرگ و به نسبت طولانی مدت در تاریخچه زمانی سرعت زمین است. هم&#8204;چنین با توجه به ساختار آماری محدود و وجود کاستی&#8204;های فراوان، پردازش داده&#8204;های طیفی موجود ناتوان از ارائه کامل اطلاعات هستند. با توجه به این&#8204;که زلزله&#8204;های بزرگ دارای دورۀ بازگشت طولانی است و نیز بسیاری از مناطق لرزه&#8204;خیز ایران فاقد ثبت رکوردهای نیرومند زلزله هستند، بدین لحاظ نیاز به تولید و شبیه&#8204;سازی رویدادهای بزرگ محتمل با کاربرد مدل&#8204;های فرم بسته و آنالیز داده&#8204;های موجود احساس می&#8204;شود. در این تحقیق تلاش بر آن است تا با نگرش جامع تحلیلی بر مدل فرم بسته ماورودیس و پاپوجورجیو به ارائۀ یک مدل ریاضی تعمیم یافته به&#8204;منظور شبیه&#8204;سازی پالس&#173;های موجود در رکوردهای حوزۀ نزدیک بپردازیم.
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Introduction
Study on the main characteristics of strong ground motions, has relatively long history. The observations and investigations on the structural damages after strong earthquakes such as Northridge 1994 in California, Kobe 1995 in Japan, Tabas 1978 and Bam 2003 in Iran, are representatives of the destructive effects of strong near-field records. The most important specification of the near-field records which distinguish them from far-field records, is their ability to generate energized and relatively short-duration acceleration spikes as well as high amplitude and long-domain velocity pulses. Moreover, according to the lack of accurate statistical profiles as well as many deficiencies, processing the spectral existent data is not able enough to fully explain the seismic tremors. Based on the fact that the great earthquakes have long recurrence interval and also many high seismic zones of Iran do not possess strong tremors, hence generating and simulating feasible great events is required by applying closed form models and analysis of available data. In this study, in order to simulate the existent pulses in the time history of near-field records, the developed mathematical configuration is presented by analytical comprehensive attitude on the closed form model by Mavroeidis and Papageorgiou (2003).
Material and methods
Simulation of strong ground shakings, especially in areas where there is limited recorded data, plays a key role in assessing dynamic behavior of structures. Owing to unique characteristics of strong near-field ground motions, it is not possible to determine exact effects of these strong records on structures using simplified mathematical models. It is feasible to develop more complicated models which represent much more characteristics of near-field ground motions. Mavroeidis and Papageorgiou (2003) studied the parameters affecting near-fault ground motions. Their studies resulted in introducing a mathematical model capable of interpolating velocity pulses of near-field earthquake records (MP model). This closed-form MP model interpolates long duration pulses using a set of input spectral parameters.
&#160;The pulse period, the pulse amplitude, the number and phase of half cycles are the key parameters that define the shape of velocity pulse. Thus, a four-parameter model has been developed to describe velocity pulses which contain forward directivity effects. In this research, it was observed that by using a combination of cubic and exponential terms, an enhanced model for interpolating the pulses presented in near-field earthquake records could be achieved (EMP model). Figure 1 shows the analytical interpolation of acceleration and velocity time histories using MP and EMP models.
&#160;
Figure 1. Fitting of acceleration time histories with MP and EMP models
&#160;
Results and discussion
Based on the obtained results, it is observed that there is a striking similarity between analytical characteristics obtained by actual earthquake records and mathematical pulses. Moreover, using the enhanced closed-form model (EMP model) reduces discrepancy between the results obtained under actual and the synthetic earthquake records.
Conclusion
Findings of this research reveal that equivalent pulses could be a good representative of actual earthquake records analytically, in order to assess the seismological characteristics of these tremors. It is worth mentioning that modelization of forward directivity pulses displayed in time history of strong ground shakings, is an efficient measure in evaluating seismic response of structures. In addition, due to stochastic nature of earthquakes, computational uncertainties and descriptive limitations of analytical parameters, using closed-form models require a high level of accuracy../files/site1/files/124/8nazari%DA%86%DA%A9%DB%8C%D8%AF%D9%87.pdf
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>707</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>726</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>شیدا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>نظری</Family>
				<NameE>Sheyda</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Nazari</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه خوارزمی، دانشکدۀ فنی و مهندسی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه خوارزمی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>افشین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>مشکوه الدینی</Family>
				<NameE>Afshin</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Meshkat-Dini</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه خوارزمی، دانشکدۀ فنی و مهندسی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه خوارزمی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>جعفر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>کیوانی قمصری</Family>
				<NameE>Jafar</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Keyvani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه خوارزمی، دانشکدۀ فنی و مهندسی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه خوارزمی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>strong ground motion</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>energized spikes</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>high amplitude pulses</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>closed form model </KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>جنبش‌های نیرومند زمین</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اسپایک‌های پرانرژی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پالس‌های با دامنه بزرگ</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدل‌های فرم بسته</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1. Halldórsson B., Mavroeidis G. P., Papageorgiou A. S., &quot;Near-fault and far-field strong ground-motion simulation for earthquake engineering applications using the specific barrier model&quot;, Journal of Structural Engineering, Vol. 137, No. 3 (2011) 433-444.  2. Somerville P. G., :Magnitude scaling of the near fault rupture directivity pulse:, Physics of the Earth and Planetary Interiors, Vol. 137, No.1 (2003) 201-212.  3. Afsary M., Keyvani Ghamsari J., Meshkat-Dini A., &quot;Assessment of nonlinear dynamic response of steel tall buildings with bundled tube structural system subjected to ground motions caused by strike slip faults&quot;, 4th National Conference on Steel &amp; Structure, Tehran, Iran (2014). 4. Somerville P. G., &quot;Engineering characterization of near fault ground motions&quot;, NZSEE Conference, (2005) 5. Kalkan E., Kunnath S. K., &quot;Effects of fling step and forward directivity on seismic response of buildings&quot;, Earthquake Spectra, Vol. 22, No.2 (2006) 367-390.  6. Somerville P. G., Smith N. F., Graves R. W., Abrahamson N. A., &quot;Modiﬁcation of empirical strong ground motion attenuation relations to include the amplitude and duration effects of rupture directivity&quot;, Seismological Research Letters, Vol. 68, No. 1 (1997) 199-222.  7. Somerville P. G., &quot;Development of an improved ground motion representation for near-fault ground motions&quot;, SMIP 98, Seminar on Utilization of Strong Motion Data: Oakland, CA, (1998). 8. Alavi B., Krawinkler H., &quot;Consideration of near-fault ground motion effects in seismic design&quot;, Proceedings of the 12th World Conference on Earthquake Engineering, New Zealand, (2000). 9. Somerville P. G., &quot;New developments in seismic hazard estimation&quot;, Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Seismic Zonation (6ICSZ), Palm Springs, CA, November 12-15, (2000).  10. Rupakhety R., Sigbjörnsson R., &quot;Can simple pulses adequately represent near-fault ground motions?&quot;, Journal of Earthquake Engineering , Vol. 15, No. 8 (2011) 1260-1272. 11. Khaloo A. R., Khosravi H., &quot;Nonlinear interstory drift contours for idealized forward directivity pulses using modified Fish-Bone models&quot;, Advances in Structural Engineering Vol. 18, No. 5 (2015) 603-627. 12. Mavroeidis G. P., Papageorgiou A., &quot;mathematical representation of near-fault ground motions&quot;, Bulletin of the Seismological Society of America, Vol. 93, No. 3 (2003) 1099-1131.  13. Tavakoli H. R., Gilani H., Abdollahzadeh G. R., &quot;Comparative evaluation of seismic parameters for near-fault and far- fault earthquakes&quot;, Department of Civil Engineering Faculty, Noshivani University of Technology, Babol, Iran, (2012). 14. Alavi B., Krawinkler H., &quot;Effects of near-fault ground motions on frame structures&quot;, the John A. Blume earthquake engineering center, Department of civil and environmental engineering Stanford University; Report No.138, (2001) 1-301 15. Ambraseys N. N., Douglas J., &quot;Near-Field horizontal and vertical earthquake ground motions&quot;, Soil dynamics and earthquake engineering, Vol. 23, No. 1 (2003) 1-18. 16. Chopra A. K., Chintanapakdee C., &quot;Comparing response of SDF systems to Near-Fault and Far-Fault earthquake motions in the context of spectral regions&quot;, Earthquake Engineering and Structural Dynamic, Vol. 30, No. 12 (2001) 1769-1789. 17. Vaseghi Amiri J., Davoodi M. R., Sahafi A., &quot;Simulation of near-fault ground motions with equivalent pulses and compare their effects on mrf structures&quot;, The 14th World Conference on Earthquake Engineering October 12-17, Beijing, China, (2008) 18. Bray J. D., Rodriguez-Marek A., &quot;Characterization of forward-directivity ground motions in the near-fault region&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, Vol. 24, No. 11 (2004) 815-828 19. Naeim F.,&quot; The seismic design handbook&quot;, 2th edition, Kluwer Academic Publisher, (2001). 20. Kalkan E., Kunnath S. K., &quot;Effective cyclic energy as a measure of seismic demand&quot;, Journal of Earthquake Engineering, Vol. 11, No. 5 (2007) 725-751.  21. Malhotra P. K., &quot;Response of buildings to near-field pulse like ground motion&quot;, Earthquake Engineering and Structural Dynamic, Vol. 28, No. 11 (1999) 1309-1326.  22. Agrawal A. K.,&quot;A closed-form approximation of near-fault ground motion pulses for flexible structures&quot;, 15th ASCE Engineering Mechanics Conference, June 2-5, Columbia University, New York, NY, (2002). 23. Mavroeidis G. P., Papageorgiou A.,&quot;Near-fault ground motions, and the response of elastic and inelastic single-degree-of-freedom (sdof) systems&quot;, Earthquake Engineering and Structural Dynamics, Vol. 33, No. 9, (2004) 1023-1050.  24. PEER Ground Motion Database, http://peer.berkeley.edu/. 25. Nazari S., Azhdarifar M., Keyvani Ghamsari J., Meshkat-Dini A., &quot;Study on the seismic response parameters of bundled tube structural system subjected to closed form near field records&quot;, The 5th National and International Conference on Modern Materials and Structures in Civil Engineering, Tehran, Iran, (2016). ##1. Halldórsson B., Mavroeidis G. P., Papageorgiou A. S., &quot;Near-fault and far-field strong ground-motion simulation for earthquake engineering applications using the specific barrier model&quot;, Journal of Structural Engineering, Vol. 137, No. 3 (2011) 433-444##.  2. Somerville P. G., :Magnitude scaling of the near fault rupture directivity pulse:, Physics of the Earth and Planetary Interiors, Vol. 137, No.1 (2003) 201-212. ## 3. Afsary M., Keyvani Ghamsari J., Meshkat-Dini A., &quot;Assessment of nonlinear dynamic response of steel tall buildings with bundled tube structural system subjected to ground motions caused by strike slip faults&quot;, 4th National Conference on Steel &amp; Structure, Tehran, Iran (2014). ##4. Somerville P. G., &quot;Engineering characterization of near fault ground motions&quot;, NZSEE Conference, (2005) ##5. Kalkan E., Kunnath S. K., &quot;Effects of fling step and forward directivity on seismic response of buildings&quot;, Earthquake Spectra, Vol. 22, No.2 (2006) 367-390.##  6. Somerville P. G., Smith N. F., Graves R. W., Abrahamson N. A., &quot;Modiﬁcation of empirical strong ground motion attenuation relations to include the amplitude and duration effects of rupture directivity&quot;, Seismological Research Letters, Vol. 68, No. 1 (1997) 199-222.##  7. Somerville P. G., &quot;Development of an improved ground motion representation for near-fault ground motions&quot;, SMIP 98, Seminar on Utilization of Strong Motion Data: Oakland, CA, (1998).## 8. Alavi B., Krawinkler H., &quot;Consideration of near-fault ground motion effects in seismic design&quot;, Proceedings of the 12th World Conference on Earthquake Engineering, New Zealand, (2000). ##9. Somerville P. G., &quot;New developments in seismic hazard estimation&quot;, Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Seismic Zonation (6ICSZ), Palm Springs, CA, November 12-15, (2000).##  10. Rupakhety R., Sigbjörnsson R., &quot;Can simple pulses adequately represent near-fault ground motions?&quot;, Journal of Earthquake Engineering , Vol. 15, No. 8 (2011) 1260-1272. ##11. Khaloo A. R., Khosravi H., &quot;Nonlinear interstory drift contours for idealized forward directivity pulses using modified Fish-Bone models&quot;, Advances in Structural Engineering Vol. 18, No. 5 (2015) 603-627## 12. Mavroeidis G. P., Papageorgiou A., &quot;mathematical representation of near-fault ground motions&quot;, Bulletin of the Seismological Society of America, Vol. 93, No. 3 (2003) 1099-1131.##  13. Tavakoli H. R., Gilani H., Abdollahzadeh G. R., &quot;Comparative evaluation of seismic parameters for near-fault and far- fault earthquakes&quot;, Department of Civil Engineering Faculty, Noshivani University of Technology, Babol, Iran, (2012)## 14. Alavi B., Krawinkler H., &quot;Effects of near-fault ground motions on frame structures&quot;, the John A. Blume earthquake engineering center, Department of civil and environmental engineering Stanford University; Report No.138, (2001) 1-301## 15. Ambraseys N. N., Douglas J., &quot;Near-Field horizontal and vertical earthquake ground motions&quot;, Soil dynamics and earthquake engineering, Vol. 23, No. 1 (2003) 1-18.## 16. Chopra A. K., Chintanapakdee C., &quot;Comparing response of SDF systems to Near-Fault and Far-Fault earthquake motions in the context of spectral regions&quot;, Earthquake Engineering and Structural Dynamic, Vol. 30, No. 12 (2001) 1769-1789.## 17. Vaseghi Amiri J., Davoodi M. R., Sahafi A., &quot;Simulation of near-fault ground motions with equivalent pulses and compare their effects on mrf structures&quot;, The 14th World Conference on Earthquake Engineering October 12-17, Beijing, China, (2008) ##18. Bray J. D., Rodriguez-Marek A., &quot;Characterization of forward-directivity ground motions in the near-fault region&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, Vol. 24, No. 11 (2004) 815-828## 19. Naeim F.,&quot; The seismic design handbook&quot;, 2th edition, Kluwer Academic Publisher, (2001). 20. Kalkan E., Kunnath S. K., &quot;Effective cyclic energy as a measure of seismic demand&quot;, Journal of Earthquake Engineering, Vol. 11, No. 5 (2007) 725-751.##  21. Malhotra P. K., &quot;Response of buildings to near-field pulse like ground motion&quot;, Earthquake Engineering and Structural Dynamic, Vol. 28, No. 11 (1999) 1309-1326.##  22. Agrawal A. K.,&quot;A closed-form approximation of near-fault ground motion pulses for flexible structures&quot;, 15th ASCE Engineering Mechanics Conference, June 2-5, Columbia University, New York, NY, (2002).## 23. Mavroeidis G. P., Papageorgiou A.,&quot;Near-fault ground motions, and the response of elastic and inelastic single-degree-of-freedom (sdof) systems&quot;, Earthquake Engineering and Structural Dynamics, Vol. 33, No. 9, (2004) 1023-1050.  ##24. PEER Ground Motion Database, http://peer.berkeley.edu/.## 25. Nazari S., Azhdarifar M., Keyvani Ghamsari J., Meshkat-Dini A., &quot;Study on the seismic response parameters of bundled tube structural system subjected to closed form near field records&quot;, The 5th National and International Conference on Modern Materials and Structures in Civil Engineering, Tehran, Iran, (2016). ## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>

</ARTICLES>

</JOURNAL>
</XML>
