<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1398</YEAR>
<VOL>12</VOL>
<NO>5</NO>
<MOSALSAL>36</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>212</PAGE_NO>


<ARTICLES>

	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر زبری سطح تماس خاک-ژئوتکستایل در آزمایش برش مستقیم</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Studying the Effect of Roughness on Soil-Geotextile Interaction in Direct Shear Test</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>یکی از روش&#173;های افزایش مقاومت خاک&#173;ها در برابر گسیختگی، تسلیح خاک است. اندرکنش خاک و ژئوسنتتیک&#173;ها اهمیت به&#8204;سزایی داشته و تحت تأثیر اصطکاک و چسبندگی سطح تماس آن&#173;ها قرار می&#8204;گیرد. دانه&#173;بندی خاک، زبری سطح تماس و دانسیتۀ ژئوتکستایل از جمله عوامل مؤثر بر اندرکنش خاک-ژئوتکستایل&#8204;ها هستند. در این تحقیق برای بررسی موارد مذکور از آزمایش برش مستقیم بزرگ مقیاس استفاده شده است که دو نمونه ماسۀ خوب و بد دانه&#173;بندی شده با دانسیتۀ نسبی %80، دو نوع ماسۀ بددانه&#8204;بندی شدۀ تک&#8204;سایز برای افزایش زبری سطح تماس از طریق چسبانیدن به سطح ژئوتکستایل، دو نوع ژئوتکستایل با مقاومت&#173;های کششی و وزن واحد سطح متفاوت، تنش&#173;های قائم 5/12، 25 و 50 کیلوپاسکال و نرخ برش min/mm 1 استفاده شده است. نتایج نشان داده که با افزایش زبری مقاومت برشی سطح تماس خاک-ژئوتکستایل افزایش می&#8204;یابد و بسیج شدن مقاومت کششی ژئوتکستایل به دانه&#173;بندی خاک در سطح تماس بستگی دارد، به&#8204;طوری&#8204;که هر چه ذرات چسبانیده شده به ژئوتکستایل&#8204;ها درشت&#8204;تر از ذرات خاک نمونه باشد، اندرکنش بهتری به&#8204;دست می&#8204;آید.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>One of the methods of increasing soil resistance against failure is soil reinforcement using geosynthetics. Soil-geosynthetic interactions are of great importance and are affected by friction and adhesion at their interface. Soil gradation, contact surface roughness and geotextile density are among the factors affecting soil-geotextiles interaction this study, to investigate the effects of these factors, large-scale direct shear tests have been conducted using a well and a poorly graded sand at a relative density of 80% reinforced with two geotextiles having different tensile strengths and mass per unit area. Samples were subjected to normal pressures of 12.5, 25 and 50kPa and sheared at a rate of 1 mm/min. Geotextile surface roughness was achieved by gluing two different single sized sand particles. Results show that increasing geotextile surface roughness increases shear strength at soil-geotextile interface. Geotextile tensile strength mobilization is shown to depend on soil grain size at the interface. The coarser and more angular the soil particles, the more effective the soil-reinforcement&#160;interactions. Geotextile tensile strength and its mass per unit area are shown to less important factors.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>30</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمودرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>عبدی</Family>
				<NameE>Mahmood Reza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Abdi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی خواجه نصیرالدین طوسی، دانشکده عمران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه صنعتی خواجه نصیرالدین طوسی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>abdi@kntu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهدی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>صفدری سه‌گنبد</Family>
				<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Safdari Seh Gonbad</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی خواجه نصیرالدین طوسی، دانشکده عمران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه صنعتی خواجه نصیرالدین طوسی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>m.safdari@kntu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Geosynthetic</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Geotextile</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Direct shear</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Interaction</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Roughness</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Soil gradation.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ژئوسنتتیک</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ژئوتکستایل</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>برش مستقیم</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اندرکنش</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>زبری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دانه‌بندی خاک</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1. Narejo D. B., &quot;Opening size recommendations for separation geotextiles used in pavements&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 21 (4) (2003) 257-264. 2. Palmeira E. M., Gardoni M. G., &quot;Drainage and filtration properties of non-woven geotextiles under confinement using different experimental techniques&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 20 (2) (2002) 97-115. 3. Faure Y. H., Baudoin A., Pierson P., Ple O., &quot;A contribution for predicting geotextile clogging during filtration of suspended solids&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 24 (1) (2006) 11-20. 4. Chai J. C., Miura N., Nomura T., &quot;Effect of hydraulic radius on long-term drainage capacity of geosynthetics drains&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 22 (2004) 3-16. 5. Moghaddas Tafreshi S. N., Dawson A. R., &quot;Comparison of bearing capacity of a strip footing on sand with geocell and with planar forms of geotextile reinforcement&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 28 (1) (2010) 72-84. 6. Moghaddas Tafreshi S. N., Dawson A. R., &quot;Behaviour of footings on reinforced sand subjected to repeated loading–Comparing use of 3D and planar geotextile&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 28 (5) (2010) 434-447. 7. Moghaddas Tafreshi, S. N., Sharifi, P., Dawson, A. R., &quot;Performance of circular footings on sand by use of multiple-geocell or-planar geotextile reinforcing layers&quot;, Soils and Foundations Vol. 56 (6) (2016) 984-997. 8. Lee K. M., Manjunath V. R., &quot;Soil-geotextile interface friction by direct shear tests&quot;, Canadian Geotechnical Journal Vol. 37 (1) (2000) 238-252. 9. Abdi M. R., Arjomand M. A., &quot;Pullout tests conducted on clay reinforced with geogrid encapsulated in thin layers of sand&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 29 (6) (2011) 588-595. 10. Ghazavi M., Ghaffari J., &quot;Experimental investigation of time-dependent effect on shear strength parameters of sand-geotextile interface&quot;, Iranian Journal of Science and Technology. Transactions of Civil Engineering, Vol. 37 (C1) (2013) 97-109. 11. Abdi M. R., Etefagh M., &quot;The Effect of Soil Particle Size and Reinforcement Aperture Size on the Soil-Geogrid Interaction&quot;, Experimental Research in Civil Engineering Vol. 1(1) (2014) 57-64. (In Persian). 12. Abdi M. R., Zandieh A. R., &quot;Experimental and numerical analysis of large scale pull out tests conducted on clays reinforced with geogrids encapsulated with coarse material&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 42(5) (2014) 494-504. 13. Abdi, M. R., Mirzaeifar, H., &quot;Experimental and PIV evaluation of grain size and distribution on soil–geogrid interactions in pullout test. Soils and Foundations 57 (2017) 1046-1059. 14. Jewell R. A., Millilgan G. W. E., Sarsby R. W., Dubois D., &quot;Interaction Between Soil and Geogrids&quot;, Proc. Sympon Polymer Grid Reinforcement in Civil Engineering, Science and Engineering Research Council and Netlon Limited (1984) 18-30. 15. Cazzuffi D., Picarelli L., Ricciuti A., Rimoldi P., &quot;Laboratory investigations on the shear strength of geogrid reinforced soils&quot;, In Geosynthetic Soil Reinforcement Testing Procedures, ASTM Spec. Tech. Publ. 1190, (1993) 119-137. 16. Liu C. N., Ho Y. H., Huang J. W., &quot;Large scale direct shear tests of soil/PET-yarn geogrid interfaces&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 27(1) (2009) 19-30. 17. Sayeed M. M. A., Janaki Ramaiah B., Amit Rawal, &quot;Interface shear characteristics of jute/polypropylene hybrid nonwoven geotextiles and sand using large size direct shear test&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 42(1) (2014) 63-68. 18. Punetha P., Mohanty P. Samanta P., &quot;Microstructural investigation on mechanical behavior of soil-geosynthetic interface in direct shear test&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 45 (3) (2017) 197-210. 19. Cerato A. B., Lutenegger A. J., &quot;Specimen size and scale effects of direct shear box tests of sands&quot;, Geotechnical Testing Journal Vol. 29 (6) (2006) 1-10 20. ASTM D3080, &quot;Standard test method for direct shear test of soils under consolidated drained conditions&quot;, West Conshohocken, PA: ASTM International (2004). 21. ASTM D5321, &quot;Standard test method for determining the coefficient of soil and geosynthetic or geosynthetic and geosynthetic friction by the direct shear method&quot;, West Conshohocken, PA: ASTM International (2008). 22. ASTM D4253, &quot;Standard test methods for maximum index density and unit weight of soils using a vibratory table&quot;, West Conshohocken, PA: ASTM International (2016). 23. ASTM D4254, &quot;Standard test methods for minimum index density and unit weight of soils and calculation of relative density&quot;, West Conshohocken, PA: ASTM International (2016). 24. ASTM D422, &quot;Standard test method for particle-size analysis of soils&quot;, West Conshohocken, PA: ASTM International (2007). 25. ASTM D2487, &quot;Standard practice for classification of soils for engineering purposes (unified soil classification system)&quot;, West Conshohocken, PA: ASTM International (2011). 26. http:// www.sefidbaft.com 27. Richards E. A., Scott J. D., &quot;Soil geotextile frictional properties&quot;, Proc. 2nd., Canadian Sym. On Geotextile and Geomembrane&quot;, Canadian Geotechnical Society, Edmonton. Alberta (1985) 13-24. 28. Lopes M. L., Silvano, R., &quot;Soil/geotextile interface behavior in direct shear and pullout movements&quot;, Geotechnical and Geological Engineering, 28 (6), (2010) 791-804. 29. Abdi M. R., Mamani K., &quot;Comparison of the Effect of Degree of Compaction (Relative Density) and Grading on Sand-Geogrid and Sand-Geotextile Interaction&quot;, 10th International Congress on Civil Engineering, Tabriz University (2015). (In Persian) 30. Jotisankasa, A., Rurgchaisri, N., &quot;Shear strength of interfaces between unsaturated soils and composite geotextile with polyester yarn reinforcement&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes, 46(3) (2018) 338-353. 31. Markou, I. N., &quot;A study on geotextile-sand interface behavior based on direct shear and triaxial compression tests&quot;, International Journal if Geosynthetics and Ground Engineering, 4 (1) (2018) 8-16.  32. Palmeira E. M. &quot;Soil-geosynthetic interaction: Modelling and analysis&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 27(5) (2009) 368-390. 33. Tatlisoz N., Edil T. B., Benson C. H., &quot;Interaction between reinforcing geosynthetics and soil-tire chip mixtures&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering Vol. 124(11) (1998) 1109-1119. 34. Abu-Farsakh M., Coronel J., Tao M., &quot;Effect of soil moisture content and dry density on cohesive soil–geosynthetic interactions using large direct shear tests&quot;, Journal of Materials in Civil Engineering Vol. 19(7) (2007) 540-549. 35. Abdi M. R., Sadrnejad S. A., Arjomand M. A., &quot;Clay reinforcement using geogrid embedded in thin layers of sand&quot;, International Journal of Civil Engineering Vol. 7(4) (2009) 224-235. 36. Abdi M. R., Sadrnejad A., Arjomand M. A., &quot;Strength enhancement of clay by encapsulating geogrids in thin layers of sand&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 27 (6) (2009) 447-455. 37. Athanasopoulos G. A., &quot;Results of direct shear tests on geotextile reinforced cohesive soil&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 14(11) (1996) 619-644. 38. Chenggang B., &quot;Study on the interaction behavior of geosynthetics and soil in China&quot;, Ningbo Institute of Technology, Zhejiang University, China (2004) 104-115. 39. Liu C. N., Zornberg J. G., Chen T. C., Ho Y. H., Lin B. H., &quot;Behavior of geogrid-sand interface in direct shear mode&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering Vol. 135 (12) (2009) 1863-1871. 40. Athanasopoulos G. A., &quot;Effect of particle size on the mechanical behaviour of sand-geotextile composites&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 12 (3) (1993) 255-273. 41. Tuna S. C., Altun S., &quot;Mechanical behavior of sand-geotextile interface&quot;, Scientia Iranica Vol. 19 (4) (2012) 1044-1051. 42. Ferreira F. B., Vieira C. S., Lopes M., &quot;Direct shear behavior of residual soil–geosynthetic interfaces-influence of soil moisture content, soil density and geosynthetic type&quot;, Geosynthetics International Vol. 22 (3) (2015) 257-272. 43. Mosallanezhad M, Alfaro M. C., Hataf N., Taghavi S. S., &quot;Performance of the new reinforcement system in increasing shear strength of typical geogrid interface with soil&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes, 44(3), (2016) 457-462.  44. Makkar F.M., Chandrakaran S., Sankar N., &quot;Performance of 3-D geogrid reinforced sand under direct shera mode. International Journal of Geotechnical Engineering (2017) 1-9. 45. Abdi M.R., Safdari Seh Gonbad M., &quot;Enhancement of soil geogrid interactions in direct shear mode using attached elements as anchors&quot;, European Journal of Environmental and Civil Engineering (2018) 1-19. ##1. Narejo D. B., &quot;Opening size recommendations for separation geotextiles used in pavements&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 21 (4) (2003) 257-264. 2. Palmeira E. M., Gardoni M. G., &quot;Drainage and filtration properties of non-woven geotextiles under confinement using different experimental techniques&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 20 (2) (2002) 97-115. 3. Faure Y. H., Baudoin A., Pierson P., Ple O., &quot;A contribution for predicting geotextile clogging during filtration of suspended solids&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 24 (1) (2006) 11-20. 4. Chai J. C., Miura N., Nomura T., &quot;Effect of hydraulic radius on long-term drainage capacity of geosynthetics drains&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 22 (2004) 3-16. 5. Moghaddas Tafreshi S. N., Dawson A. R., &quot;Comparison of bearing capacity of a strip footing on sand with geocell and with planar forms of geotextile reinforcement&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 28 (1) (2010) 72-84. 6. Moghaddas Tafreshi S. N., Dawson A. R., &quot;Behaviour of footings on reinforced sand subjected to repeated loading–Comparing use of 3D and planar geotextile&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 28 (5) (2010) 434-447. 7. Moghaddas Tafreshi, S. N., Sharifi, P., Dawson, A. R., &quot;Performance of circular footings on sand by use of multiple-geocell or-planar geotextile reinforcing layers&quot;, Soils and Foundations Vol. 56 (6) (2016) 984-997. 8. Lee K. M., Manjunath V. R., &quot;Soil-geotextile interface friction by direct shear tests&quot;, Canadian Geotechnical Journal Vol. 37 (1) (2000) 238-252. 9. Abdi M. R., Arjomand M. A., &quot;Pullout tests conducted on clay reinforced with geogrid encapsulated in thin layers of sand&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 29 (6) (2011) 588-595. 10. Ghazavi M., Ghaffari J., &quot;Experimental investigation of time-dependent effect on shear strength parameters of sand-geotextile interface&quot;, Iranian Journal of Science and Technology. Transactions of Civil Engineering, Vol. 37 (C1) (2013) 97-109. 11. Abdi M. R., Etefagh M., &quot;The Effect of Soil Particle Size and Reinforcement Aperture Size on the Soil-Geogrid Interaction&quot;, Experimental Research in Civil Engineering Vol. 1(1) (2014) 57-64. (In Persian). 12. Abdi M. R., Zandieh A. R., &quot;Experimental and numerical analysis of large scale pull out tests conducted on clays reinforced with geogrids encapsulated with coarse material&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 42(5) (2014) 494-504. 13. Abdi, M. R., Mirzaeifar, H., &quot;Experimental and PIV evaluation of grain size and distribution on soil–geogrid interactions in pullout test. Soils and Foundations 57 (2017) 1046-1059. 14. Jewell R. A., Millilgan G. W. E., Sarsby R. W., Dubois D., &quot;Interaction Between Soil and Geogrids&quot;, Proc. Sympon Polymer Grid Reinforcement in Civil Engineering, Science and Engineering Research Council and Netlon Limited (1984) 18-30. 15. Cazzuffi D., Picarelli L., Ricciuti A., Rimoldi P., &quot;Laboratory investigations on the shear strength of geogrid reinforced soils&quot;, In Geosynthetic Soil Reinforcement Testing Procedures, ASTM Spec. Tech. Publ. 1190, (1993) 119-137. 16. Liu C. N., Ho Y. H., Huang J. W., &quot;Large scale direct shear tests of soil/PET-yarn geogrid interfaces&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 27(1) (2009) 19-30. 17. Sayeed M. M. A., Janaki Ramaiah B., Amit Rawal, &quot;Interface shear characteristics of jute/polypropylene hybrid nonwoven geotextiles and sand using large size direct shear test&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 42(1) (2014) 63-68. 18. Punetha P., Mohanty P. Samanta P., &quot;Microstructural investigation on mechanical behavior of soil-geosynthetic interface in direct shear test&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 45 (3) (2017) 197-210. 19. Cerato A. B., Lutenegger A. J., &quot;Specimen size and scale effects of direct shear box tests of sands&quot;, Geotechnical Testing Journal Vol. 29 (6) (2006) 1-10 20. ASTM D3080, &quot;Standard test method for direct shear test of soils under consolidated drained conditions&quot;, West Conshohocken, PA: ASTM International (2004). 21. ASTM D5321, &quot;Standard test method for determining the coefficient of soil and geosynthetic or geosynthetic and geosynthetic friction by the direct shear method&quot;, West Conshohocken, PA: ASTM International (2008). 22. ASTM D4253, &quot;Standard test methods for maximum index density and unit weight of soils using a vibratory table&quot;, West Conshohocken, PA: ASTM International (2016). 23. ASTM D4254, &quot;Standard test methods for minimum index density and unit weight of soils and calculation of relative density&quot;, West Conshohocken, PA: ASTM International (2016). 24. ASTM D422, &quot;Standard test method for particle-size analysis of soils&quot;, West Conshohocken, PA: ASTM International (2007). 25. ASTM D2487, &quot;Standard practice for classification of soils for engineering purposes (unified soil classification system)&quot;, West Conshohocken, PA: ASTM International (2011). 26. http:// www.sefidbaft.com 27. Richards E. A., Scott J. D., &quot;Soil geotextile frictional properties&quot;, Proc. 2nd., Canadian Sym. On Geotextile and Geomembrane&quot;, Canadian Geotechnical Society, Edmonton. Alberta (1985) 13-24. 28. Lopes M. L., Silvano, R., &quot;Soil/geotextile interface behavior in direct shear and pullout movements&quot;, Geotechnical and Geological Engineering, 28 (6), (2010) 791-804. 29. Abdi M. R., Mamani K., &quot;Comparison of the Effect of Degree of Compaction (Relative Density) and Grading on Sand-Geogrid and Sand-Geotextile Interaction&quot;, 10th International Congress on Civil Engineering, Tabriz University (2015). (In Persian) 30. Jotisankasa, A., Rurgchaisri, N., &quot;Shear strength of interfaces between unsaturated soils and composite geotextile with polyester yarn reinforcement&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes, 46(3) (2018) 338-353. 31. Markou, I. N., &quot;A study on geotextile-sand interface behavior based on direct shear and triaxial compression tests&quot;, International Journal if Geosynthetics and Ground Engineering, 4 (1) (2018) 8-16.  32. Palmeira E. M. &quot;Soil-geosynthetic interaction: Modelling and analysis&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 27(5) (2009) 368-390. 33. Tatlisoz N., Edil T. B., Benson C. H., &quot;Interaction between reinforcing geosynthetics and soil-tire chip mixtures&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering Vol. 124(11) (1998) 1109-1119. 34. Abu-Farsakh M., Coronel J., Tao M., &quot;Effect of soil moisture content and dry density on cohesive soil–geosynthetic interactions using large direct shear tests&quot;, Journal of Materials in Civil Engineering Vol. 19(7) (2007) 540-549. 35. Abdi M. R., Sadrnejad S. A., Arjomand M. A., &quot;Clay reinforcement using geogrid embedded in thin layers of sand&quot;, International Journal of Civil Engineering Vol. 7(4) (2009) 224-235. 36. Abdi M. R., Sadrnejad A., Arjomand M. A., &quot;Strength enhancement of clay by encapsulating geogrids in thin layers of sand&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 27 (6) (2009) 447-455. 37. Athanasopoulos G. A., &quot;Results of direct shear tests on geotextile reinforced cohesive soil&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 14(11) (1996) 619-644. 38. Chenggang B., &quot;Study on the interaction behavior of geosynthetics and soil in China&quot;, Ningbo Institute of Technology, Zhejiang University, China (2004) 104-115. 39. Liu C. N., Zornberg J. G., Chen T. C., Ho Y. H., Lin B. H., &quot;Behavior of geogrid-sand interface in direct shear mode&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering Vol. 135 (12) (2009) 1863-1871. 40. Athanasopoulos G. A., &quot;Effect of particle size on the mechanical behaviour of sand-geotextile composites&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes Vol. 12 (3) (1993) 255-273. 41. Tuna S. C., Altun S., &quot;Mechanical behavior of sand-geotextile interface&quot;, Scientia Iranica Vol. 19 (4) (2012) 1044-1051. 42. Ferreira F. B., Vieira C. S., Lopes M., &quot;Direct shear behavior of residual soil–geosynthetic interfaces-influence of soil moisture content, soil density and geosynthetic type&quot;, Geosynthetics International Vol. 22 (3) (2015) 257-272. 43. Mosallanezhad M, Alfaro M. C., Hataf N., Taghavi S. S., &quot;Performance of the new reinforcement system in increasing shear strength of typical geogrid interface with soil&quot;, Geotextiles and Geomembranes, 44(3), (2016) 457-462.  44. Makkar F.M., Chandrakaran S., Sankar N., &quot;Performance of 3-D geogrid reinforced sand under direct shera mode. International Journal of Geotechnical Engineering (2017) 1-9. 45. Abdi M.R., Safdari Seh Gonbad M., &quot;Enhancement of soil geogrid interactions in direct shear mode using attached elements as anchors&quot;, European Journal of Environmental and Civil Engineering (2018) 1-19.  ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی عددی اثر وجود لایۀ سست خاک بر گودهای مهار شده با دیوارۀ سپرکوبی‌</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Study of Loose Soil Layer Effects on Excavations Supported by Steel Sheet Pile Walls-A Numerical Study</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>سپری&#173;های فولادی در پروژه&#173;های مهندسی عمران به&#8204;طور گسترده به&#8204;عنوان سازه نگهبان استفاده می&#8204;شوند. گاهی ممکن است لایۀ خاک سست یا نرم در عمق&#173;های مختلف گود وجود داشته باشد. این مسئله موجب اثرات مختلف بر تغییر مکان سطح زمین، نیروها و لنگرهای وارد بر سپری&#173;ها و مهارها در طی فرآیند گودبرداری نسبت به حالتی که خاک به&#8204;طورکلی یک&#8204;نواخت است، می&#173;شود. این تفاوت&#173;ها در روش&#173;های معمول طراحی دیواره&#173;های سپرکوبی شده به&#8204;طور دقیق در نظر گرفته نمی&#173;شود. در این مقاله یک گود عمیق با استفاده از روش اجزای محدود تحلیل می&#173;شود. عمق گود به سه لایۀ مختلف تقسیم شده است. یکی از لایه&#173;ها، خاک سست است که موقعیت آن در سه حالت لایۀ بالایی، میانی و پایین مدل می&#173;شود. نتایج به&#8204;دست آمده از این مدل&#173;ها با مدلی که فاقد لایۀ سست است مقایسه می&#173;شود. تحلیل شبه استاتیکی با اعمال شتاب افقی 3/0 g انجام شده است. نتایج حاصل نشان می&#173;دهد که وقتی لایۀ سست زیر لایه&#173;های سخت قرار می&#173;گیرد، لنگر خمشی وارد بر سپرها و نیروهای برشی به&#8204;ترتیب در حدود 50 تا 100 و 15 تا 50 درصد نسبت به حالتی که لایۀ سست وجود ندارد افزایش می&#173;یابند. هم&#8204;چنین در حالت وجود لایۀ میانی سست موقعیت حداکثر تغییر شکل جانبی دیوارۀ سپرکوبی شده نسبت به سایر مدل&#173;ها متفاوت است.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Steel sheet pile walls are being widely used as earth retaining systems. Sometimes loose or soft soil layers are located in various depths in an excavation. This issue causes different effects on ground surface displacements, forces and moments acting on sheet piles and struts during excavation procedure, compared with a status that soil is totally uniform. These differences are not exactly considered in conventional design methods of sheet pile walls. In this paper, a deep excavation using finite element method is analyzed. Excavation&#8217;s depth is divided into three different layers. One of three layers is a loose soil layer and its position is modeled in three different situations, top, middle and bottom of the model.&#160;Obtained results are compared with results of excavation without the loose layer. The pseudo-static analysis is performed by applying 0.3g horizontal acceleration. The results indicate that when a loose layer is located beneath stiffer layers, bending moments acting on sheet pile wall and shear forces increase about (50~100)% and (15~50)%, respectively. Also, the middle loose layer changes the location of maximum lateral deformation of steel sheet pile wall.
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>31</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>54</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>بهروز</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>احمدپور</Family>
				<NameE>Behrouz</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ahmadpour</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی قم، گروه مهندسی عمران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه صنعتی قم</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>behrouz.ahmadpour@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مسعود</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>عامل سخی</Family>
				<NameE>Masoud</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Amel Sakhi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی قم، گروه مهندسی عمران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>انشگاه صنعتی قم،</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>mamelsakhi@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محسن</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>کمالیان</Family>
				<NameE>Mohsen</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Kamalian</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>پژوهشگاه بین لمللی زلزله شناسی و مهندسی زلزله، پژوهشکده ژئوتکنیک</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>ژوهشگاه بین لمللی زلزله شناسی و مهندسی زلزله،</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>kamalian@iiees.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Excavation</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>sheet piling</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>loose layer</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>strut</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>گودبرداری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سپرکوبی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>لایۀ سست</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مهار</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1. Ahmadpour B., Amel Sakhi M., Kamalian M., &quot;Study of the Effects of Loose Clay Layer Existence on Sheet Piling Excavation Method&quot;, 2nd Iranian Conf. on Soil Mech. and Found. Eng., Qom, Iran, (October 2015) 14-15. 2. Ahmadpour B., Amel Sakhi, M., &quot;Static and pseudo static study of loose clay layer effects on steel sheet pile walls behaviours&quot;, Bulletin of Earthquack Sci. and Engrg., 3(2), 87-100 (2016). (in Persian) 3. Athanasopoulos G., Vlachakis V., Pelekis P., &quot;Installation and Performance of a Steel Sheet Pile Wall for Supporting an Excavation in Urban Environment&quot;, Geo-Frontiers (2011) 3370-3380.  4. Bilgin Ö., &quot;Lateral Earth Pressure Coefficients for Anchored Sheet Pile Walls&quot;, International Journal of Geomechanics. 12(5) (2012) 584-595.  5. Bilgin Ö., Erten M., &quot;Anchored Sheet Pile Walls Constructed on Sloping Ground&quot;, Contemporary Topics in Ground Modification Problem Soils and Geo-Support (2009) 145-152.  6. Das B. M., Sobhan Kh., &quot;Principles of Geotechnical Engineering&quot;, Eighth Edition, CENGAGE Learning, Stamford, USA, (2013). 7. Finno R. J., Calvello M., &quot;Supported Excavations: The Observational Method and Inverse Modeling&quot;, Journal of Geotech. and Geoenvir. Eng. 131(7) (2005) 826-836.  8. Gopal Madabhushi S., Chandrasekaran V., &quot;Rotation of Cantilever Sheet Pile Walls&quot;, Journal of Geotech. and Geoenvir. Eng. 131(2) (2005) 202-212.  9. GuhaRay A., Baidya D., &quot;Reliability-based analysis of cantilever sheet pile walls backfilled with different soil types using the finite-element approach&quot;, Int. J. Geomech., 15 (6) (2015). 10. Gurinsky M., &quot;Long-Term Strength of Sheet Pile Bulkheads with Ground Anchors&quot;, Ports '01(2001) 1-8. 11. Hu Y., Liu G., Zhao Y., &quot;Calculation Method of Deformation and Inner Force of a Sheet Pile Wall with Relieving Platform&quot;, ICTE 2013 (2013) 168-174.  12. Laefer D. F., Ceribasi S., Long J. H., Cording E. J., &quot;Predicting RC frame response to excavation-induced settlement&quot;, Journal of Geotech. and Geoenvir. Eng. 135(11) (2009)1605-1619. 13. Lee S. H., Kim B. I., Han J. T., &quot;Prediction of Penetration Rate of Sheet Pile Installed in Sand by Vibratory Pile Driver&quot;, KSCE Journal of Civil Eng. 16(3) (2012) 316-324.  14. Leonidou E. A., Athanasopoulos G. A., Pelekis P. C., &quot;Deep supported excavation for the underground parking of the Hellenic Parliament: measured vs. predicted behaviour&quot;, Proceedings of the 15th Int. Conf. on Soil Mech. and Geotech. Eng. Instanblul, Turkey, Vol.2 (August 2001) 1493-1496. 15. Long M., &quot;Database for retaining wall and ground movements due to deep excavations&quot;, Journal of Geotech and Geoenvir. Eng. 127 (3) (2001) 203-224. 16. Ma J., Berggren B., Stille H., Hintze S., &quot;Deformation of Anchor-Sheet Pile Wall Retaining System at Deep Excavations in Soft Soils Overlying Bedrock&quot;, Deep and Underground Excavations (2010) 126-131.  17. Mana A. I., Clough G. W., &quot;Prediction of movements for braced cuts in clay&quot;, J. Geotech. Engrg. Div., Vol. 107 (6) (1981) 759-777. 18. Moorman C., &quot;Analysis of wall and ground movements due to deep excavations in soft soil based on a new worldwide database&quot;, Journal of Soils and Found. 44 (1) (2004) 87-98.  19. Ou C. Y., &quot;Deep excavation, theory and practice&quot;, Taylor &amp; Francis, London (2006). 20. Peck R. B. &quot;Deep excavations and tunnelling in soft ground&quot;. Proc., 7th Int. Conf. on Soil Mech. and Found. Eng., State of the Art Volume, (1969) 225-290. 21. Ramsden M., Griffiths T., &quot;Steel Sheet Pile Wall Wale Rehabilitation&quot;, Ports (2010)193-202.  22. Sahajda K., &quot;Ground Anchor Loads Measured on an Excavation Sheet Pile Wall&quot;, Tunnelling and Underground Construction: (2014) 974-983.  23. Sellmeijer J., Cools J., Decker J., Post W., &quot;Hydraulic Resistance of Steel Sheet Pile Joints&quot;, Journal of Geotech. Eng. 121 (2) (1995)105-110.  24. Shao Y., Macari E. J., &quot;Information Feedback Analysis in Deep Excavations&quot;, International Journal of Geomechanics. 8 (1) (2008) 91-103. 25. Son M., Cording E. J., &quot;Estimation of building damage due to excavation induced ground movements&quot;. Journal of Geotech. And Geoenvir. Eng. 131(2) (2005) 162-177. 26. Terzaghi K., Peck R. B., &quot;Soil Mechanics in Engineering Practice&quot;, 3rd ed., John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc., New York, NY (1996). 27. USACE &quot;Design of Pile Foundations&quot;, US Army Corps of Engineers Engineering Manual EM 1110-2-2906 (1991). 28. Underwood C., Greenlee R., &quot;Steel Sheet Pile Used as Permanent Foundation and Retention Systems-Design and Construction&quot;, Earth Retention Conf 3(2010) 129-136.  29. Wong I. H., Poh T. Y., Chuah H. L. &quot;Performance of Excavations for Depressed Expressway in Singapore&quot;, Journal of Geotech. And Geoenvir. Eng. 123(7) (1997) 617-625. 30. Yoo C. S. &quot;Behavior of braced and anchored walls in soils overlying rock&quot;, Journal of Geotech. and Geoenvir. Eng. 127(3) (2001) 225-233. 31. Zekkos D. P., Athanasopoulos A. G., Athanasopoulos G. A. &quot;Deep supported excavation in difficult ground conditions for the construction of a two-story underground parking garage in the city of Patras, Greece&quot;, Proceedings of Fifth Int. Conf on Case Histories in Geotech. Eng. New York, N.Y. (April, 2004). 32. Zdravkovic L., Potts D. M., St John H. D., &quot;Modelling of a 3D excavation in finite element analysis&quot;, Geotechnique, 55 (7) (2005) 497-513. ##1. Ahmadpour B., Amel Sakhi M., Kamalian M., &quot;Study of the Effects of Loose Clay Layer Existence on Sheet Piling Excavation Method&quot;, 2nd Iranian Conf. on Soil Mech. and Found. Eng., Qom, Iran, (October 2015) 14-15. 2. Ahmadpour B., Amel Sakhi, M., &quot;Static and pseudo static study of loose clay layer effects on steel sheet pile walls behaviours&quot;, Bulletin of Earthquack Sci. and Engrg., 3(2), 87-100 (2016). (in Persian) 3. Athanasopoulos G., Vlachakis V., Pelekis P., &quot;Installation and Performance of a Steel Sheet Pile Wall for Supporting an Excavation in Urban Environment&quot;, Geo-Frontiers (2011) 3370-3380.  4. Bilgin Ö., &quot;Lateral Earth Pressure Coefficients for Anchored Sheet Pile Walls&quot;, International Journal of Geomechanics. 12(5) (2012) 584-595.  5. Bilgin Ö., Erten M., &quot;Anchored Sheet Pile Walls Constructed on Sloping Ground&quot;, Contemporary Topics in Ground Modification Problem Soils and Geo-Support (2009) 145-152.  6. Das B. M., Sobhan Kh., &quot;Principles of Geotechnical Engineering&quot;, Eighth Edition, CENGAGE Learning, Stamford, USA, (2013). 7. Finno R. J., Calvello M., &quot;Supported Excavations: The Observational Method and Inverse Modeling&quot;, Journal of Geotech. and Geoenvir. Eng. 131(7) (2005) 826-836.  8. Gopal Madabhushi S., Chandrasekaran V., &quot;Rotation of Cantilever Sheet Pile Walls&quot;, Journal of Geotech. and Geoenvir. Eng. 131(2) (2005) 202-212.  9. GuhaRay A., Baidya D., &quot;Reliability-based analysis of cantilever sheet pile walls backfilled with different soil types using the finite-element approach&quot;, Int. J. Geomech., 15 (6) (2015). 10. Gurinsky M., &quot;Long-Term Strength of Sheet Pile Bulkheads with Ground Anchors&quot;, Ports '01(2001) 1-8. 11. Hu Y., Liu G., Zhao Y., &quot;Calculation Method of Deformation and Inner Force of a Sheet Pile Wall with Relieving Platform&quot;, ICTE 2013 (2013) 168-174.  12. Laefer D. F., Ceribasi S., Long J. H., Cording E. J., &quot;Predicting RC frame response to excavation-induced settlement&quot;, Journal of Geotech. and Geoenvir. Eng. 135(11) (2009)1605-1619. 13. Lee S. H., Kim B. I., Han J. T., &quot;Prediction of Penetration Rate of Sheet Pile Installed in Sand by Vibratory Pile Driver&quot;, KSCE Journal of Civil Eng. 16(3) (2012) 316-324.  14. Leonidou E. A., Athanasopoulos G. A., Pelekis P. C., &quot;Deep supported excavation for the underground parking of the Hellenic Parliament: measured vs. predicted behaviour&quot;, Proceedings of the 15th Int. Conf. on Soil Mech. and Geotech. Eng. Instanblul, Turkey, Vol.2 (August 2001) 1493-1496. 15. Long M., &quot;Database for retaining wall and ground movements due to deep excavations&quot;, Journal of Geotech and Geoenvir. Eng. 127 (3) (2001) 203-224. 16. Ma J., Berggren B., Stille H., Hintze S., &quot;Deformation of Anchor-Sheet Pile Wall Retaining System at Deep Excavations in Soft Soils Overlying Bedrock&quot;, Deep and Underground Excavations (2010) 126-131.  17. Mana A. I., Clough G. W., &quot;Prediction of movements for braced cuts in clay&quot;, J. Geotech. Engrg. Div., Vol. 107 (6) (1981) 759-777. 18. Moorman C., &quot;Analysis of wall and ground movements due to deep excavations in soft soil based on a new worldwide database&quot;, Journal of Soils and Found. 44 (1) (2004) 87-98.  19. Ou C. Y., &quot;Deep excavation, theory and practice&quot;, Taylor &amp; Francis, London (2006). 20. Peck R. B. &quot;Deep excavations and tunnelling in soft ground&quot;. Proc., 7th Int. Conf. on Soil Mech. and Found. Eng., State of the Art Volume, (1969) 225-290. 21. Ramsden M., Griffiths T., &quot;Steel Sheet Pile Wall Wale Rehabilitation&quot;, Ports (2010)193-202.  22. Sahajda K., &quot;Ground Anchor Loads Measured on an Excavation Sheet Pile Wall&quot;, Tunnelling and Underground Construction: (2014) 974-983.  23. Sellmeijer J., Cools J., Decker J., Post W., &quot;Hydraulic Resistance of Steel Sheet Pile Joints&quot;, Journal of Geotech. Eng. 121 (2) (1995)105-110.  24. Shao Y., Macari E. J., &quot;Information Feedback Analysis in Deep Excavations&quot;, International Journal of Geomechanics. 8 (1) (2008) 91-103. 25. Son M., Cording E. J., &quot;Estimation of building damage due to excavation induced ground movements&quot;. Journal of Geotech. And Geoenvir. Eng. 131(2) (2005) 162-177. 26. Terzaghi K., Peck R. B., &quot;Soil Mechanics in Engineering Practice&quot;, 3rd ed., John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc., New York, NY (1996). 27. USACE &quot;Design of Pile Foundations&quot;, US Army Corps of Engineers Engineering Manual EM 1110-2-2906 (1991). 28. Underwood C., Greenlee R., &quot;Steel Sheet Pile Used as Permanent Foundation and Retention Systems-Design and Construction&quot;, Earth Retention Conf 3(2010) 129-136.  29. Wong I. H., Poh T. Y., Chuah H. L. &quot;Performance of Excavations for Depressed Expressway in Singapore&quot;, Journal of Geotech. And Geoenvir. Eng. 123(7) (1997) 617-625. 30. Yoo C. S. &quot;Behavior of braced and anchored walls in soils overlying rock&quot;, Journal of Geotech. and Geoenvir. Eng. 127(3) (2001) 225-233. 31. Zekkos D. P., Athanasopoulos A. G., Athanasopoulos G. A. &quot;Deep supported excavation in difficult ground conditions for the construction of a two-story underground parking garage in the city of Patras, Greece&quot;, Proceedings of Fifth Int. Conf on Case Histories in Geotech. Eng. New York, N.Y. (April, 2004). 32. Zdravkovic L., Potts D. M., St John H. D., &quot;Modelling of a 3D excavation in finite element analysis&quot;, Geotechnique, 55 (7) (2005) 497-513.  ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>پیش‌بینی نشست زمین در تونل‌سازی مکانیزه با استفاده از مدل شبکه عصبی مصنوعی-الگوریتم بهینه‌سازی مبتنی بر جغرافیای زیستی و انفیس مبتنی بر روش‌های خوشه‌بندی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Forecasting Surface Settlement Caused by Shield Tunneling Using ANN-BBO Model and ANFIS Based on Clustering Methods</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>بیشینۀ نشست سطح زمین یکی از پارامترهای مهم در عملیات حفاری مکانیزه از نوع متعادل&#8204;کنندۀ فشار زمین (EPB) است که قبل از حفاری باید تعیین شود. زمانی&#8204;که مدل&#8204;سازی بسیار پیچیده&#8204; می&#8204;شود، روش&#8204;های هوش مصنوعی به&#8204;عنوان یک راه&#8204;حل استفاده می&#8204;شوند. این روش&#8204;ها در ابتدا با استفاده از داده&#8204;های واقعی آموزش می&#8204;بینند و سپس به پردازش اطلاعات ناشناخته می&#8204;پردازند. در این پژوهش برای پیش&#173;بینی نشست زمین در تونل&#8204;سازی مکانیزه از نوع EPB از روش&#8204;های هوش مصنوعی سیستم استنتاج تطبیقی عصبی- فازی (انفیس) و ترکیب شبکۀ عصبی مصنوعی با الگوریتم بهینه&#173;سازی مبتنی بر جغرافیای زیستی استفاده شده است. در این پژوهش دو مدل انفیس شامل انفیس- خوشه&#8204;بندی کاهشی و انفیس- خوشه&#8204;بندی C-means فازی استفاده شده است. برای اثبات توانایی روش&#8204;های مذکور از داده&#8204;های پروژه مترو بانکوک، تایلند استفاده شده است. در این مدل&#8204;ها پارامترهای عمق، فاصله تا سینه کار، سطح آب زیرزمینی، متوسط فشار پشت کاتر، متوسط نرخ نفوذ، زاویه&#8204;ای که درزه&#8204;ها با سینه کار می&#8204;سازند، فشار تزریق و درصد پرشدگی تزریق به&#8204;عنوان ورودی و بیشینۀ نشست سطح زمین به&#8204;عنوان خروجی درنظر گرفته شده است. برای بررسی عملکرد مدل&#8204;ها از&#160; دو شاخص آماری ضریب تعیین (R2) &#160;و میانگین مربعات خطا استفاده شده است که نهایتاً انفیس- خوشه&#8204;بندی کاهشی بهترین عملکرد را در بین سایر مدل&#8204;ها داشته است.
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Maximum surface settlement (MSS) is an important parameter for the design and operation of earth pressure balance (EPB) shields that should determine before operate tunneling. Artificial intelligence (AI) methods are accepted as a technology that offers an alternative way to tackle highly complex problems that can&#8217;t be modeled in mathematics. They can learn from examples and they are able to handle incomplete data and noisy. The adaptive network&#8211;based fuzzy inference system (ANFIS) and hybrid artificial neural network (ANN) with biogeography-based optimization algorithm (ANN-BBO) are kinds of AI systems that were used in this study to build a prediction model for the MSS caused by EPB shield tunneling. Two ANFIS models were implemented, ANFIS-subtractive clustering method (ANFIS-SCM) and ANFIS-fuzzy c&#8211;means clustering method (ANFIS-FCM). The estimation abilities offered using three models were presented by using field data of achieved from Bangkok Subway Project in Thailand. In these models, depth, distance from shaft, ground water level from tunnel invert, average face pressure, average penetrate rate, pitching angle, tail void grouting pressure and percent tail void grout filling were utilized as the input parameters, while the MSS was the output parameter. To compare the performance of models for MSS prediction, the coefficient of correlation (R2) and mean square error (MSE) of the models were calculated, indicating the good performance of the ANFIS-SCM model.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>55</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>84</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>هادی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>فتاحی</Family>
				<NameE>Hadi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Fattahi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی اراک، استادیار دانشکده مهندسی معدن</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه صنعتی اراک،</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>h.fattahi@arakut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>زهره</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>بیات زاده فرد</Family>
				<NameE>Zohreh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Bayatzadehfard</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی اراک، استادیار دانشکده مهندسی معدن</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه صنعتی اراک</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Iron.azar@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Maximum surface settlement</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>EPB shield</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Shield tunneling</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Adaptive network–based fuzzy inference system</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Artificial neural network</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Biogeography-based optimization algorithm.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بیشینۀ نشست سطح زمین</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تونل سازی مکانیزه از نوع EPB</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سیستم استنتاج تطبیقی عصبی-فازی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شبکه عصبی مصنوعی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1. Huayong Y., Hu S., Guofang G., Guoliang H., &quot;Electro-hydraulic proportional control of thrust system for shield tunneling machine. Automat Constr 18 (7) (2009) 950-956. 2. Peila D., Picchio A., Chieregato A., &quot;Earth pressure balance tunnelling in rock masses: Laboratory feasibility study of the conditioning process&quot;, Tunn Undergr Sp Tech 35 (2013) 55-66. 3. Shao C., Lan D., &quot;Optimal control of an earth pressure balance shield with tunnel face stability&quot;, Automat Constr 46 (2014) 22-29. 4. Hu S., Guofang G., Huayong Y., &quot;Control model of earth pressure balance for shield tunneling&quot;, J China Coal Society 33 (3) (2008) 343-346. 5. Finno R. J., Clough G. W., &quot;Evaluation of soil response to EPB shield tunneling&quot; J Geotech Eng 111 (2) (1985) 155-173. 6. Clough G. W., Leca E., &quot;EPB shield tunneling in mixed face conditions&quot;, J Geotech Eng 119 (10) (1993) 1640-1656. 7. Suwansawat S., Einstein H. H., &quot;Artificial neural networks for predicting the maximum surface settlement caused by EPB shield tunneling&quot;, Tunn Undergr Sp Tech 21 (2) (2006) 133-150. 8. Boyacioglu M. A., Avci D., &quot;An adaptive network-based fuzzy inference system (ANFIS) for the prediction of stock market return: the case of the Istanbul stock exchange&quot;, Expert Syst Appl 37 (12) (2010) 7908-7912. 9. Avci E., &quot;Comparison of wavelet families for texture classification by using wavelet packet entropy adaptive network based fuzzy inference system&quot;, Appl Soft Comput 8 (1) (2008) 225-231. 10. Avci E., Akpolat Z. H., &quot;Speech recognition using a wavelet packet adaptive network based fuzzy inference system&quot;, Expert Syst Appl 31 (3) (2006) 495-503. 11. Avci E., Turkoglu I., Poyraz M., &quot;Intelligent target recognition based on wavelet adaptive network based fuzzy inference system. In: Iberian Conference on Pattern Recognition and Image Analysis&quot;, Springer, (2005) 594-603. 12. Avci E., Hanbay D., Varol A., &quot;An expert discrete wavelet adaptive network based fuzzy inference system for digital modulation recognition&quot;, Expert Syst Appl 33 (3) (2007) 582-589. 13. Jang J. S. R., &quot;ANFIS: Adaptive-network-based fuzzy inference system&quot;, IEEE T Syst Man Cyb 23 (3) (1993) 665-685. 14. Chiu S. L., &quot;Fuzzy model identification based on cluster estimation&quot;, J Intell Fuzzy Syst 2 (3) (1994) 267-278. 15. Jassar S., Liao Z., Zhao L., &quot;Adaptive neuro-fuzzy based inferential sensor model for estimating the average air temperature in space heating systems&quot;, Build Environ 44 (8) (2009) 1609-1616. 16. Wei M., Bai B., Sung A. H., Liu Q., Wang J., Cather M. E., &quot;Predicting injection profiles using ANFIS&quot;, Inform Sciences 177 (20) (2007) 4445-4461. 17. Bezdek J. C., &quot;Fuzzy mathematics in pattern classification&quot;, Cornell university, Ithaca (1973). 18. Hornik K., Stinchcombe M., White H., &quot;Multilayer feedforward networks are universal approximators&quot;, Neural Networks 2 (5) (1989) 359-366. 19. Ahmadi M. H., Aghaj S. S. G., Nazeri A., &quot;Prediction of power in solar stirling heat engine by using neural network based on hybrid genetic algorithm and particle swarm optimization&quot;, Neural Comput Appl 22 (6) (2013) 1141-1150. 20. García-Pedrajas N., Hervás-Martínez C., Muñoz-Pérez J., &quot;COVNET: a cooperative coevolutionary model for evolving artificial neural networks&quot;, IEEE T Neural Networ 14 (3) (2003) 575-596. 21. Hossein M., Ahmadi M. A., Ghare S. S., &quot;Prediction of Power in Solar Stirling Heat Engine by Evolving Particle Swarm Optimization and Neural Network&quot;, Int J Comput Appl 34 (1) (2011). 22. Uzlu E., Kankal M., Akpınar A., Dede T., &quot;Estimates of energy consumption in Turkey using neural networks with the teaching-learning-based optimization algorithm&quot;, Energy 75 (2014) 295-303. 23. Toğan V., &quot;Design of planar steel frames using teaching–learning based optimization&quot;, Eng Struct 34 (2012) 225-232. 24. Togan V., &quot;Design of pin jointed structures using teaching-learning based optimization&quot;, Structural Engineering and Mechanics 47 (2) (2013) 209-225. 25. Simon D., &quot;Biogeography-based optimization&quot;, IEEE T Evolut Comput 12 (6) (2008) 702-713. 26. Zhang Y., Phillips P., Wang S., Ji G., Yang J., Wu J., &quot;Fruit classification by biogeography‐based optimization and feedforward neural network&quot;, Expert Systems 33 (3) (2016) 239-253. 27. Hajihassani M., Armaghani D. J., Marto A., Mohamad E. T., &quot;Ground vibration prediction in quarry blasting through an artificial neural network optimized by imperialist competitive algorithm&quot;, Bull Eng Geology Envir 74 (3) (2015) 873-886. 28. Tsou D., MacNish C., &quot;Adaptive particle swarm optimisation for high-dimensional highly convex search spaces. In: Evolutionary Computation&quot;, CEC'03. The 2003 Congress on, IEEE, (2003) 783-789.  ##1. Huayong Y., Hu S., Guofang G., Guoliang H., &quot;Electro-hydraulic proportional control of thrust system for shield tunneling machine. Automat Constr 18 (7) (2009) 950-956. 2. Peila D., Picchio A., Chieregato A., &quot;Earth pressure balance tunnelling in rock masses: Laboratory feasibility study of the conditioning process&quot;, Tunn Undergr Sp Tech 35 (2013) 55-66. 3. Shao C., Lan D., &quot;Optimal control of an earth pressure balance shield with tunnel face stability&quot;, Automat Constr 46 (2014) 22-29. 4. Hu S., Guofang G., Huayong Y., &quot;Control model of earth pressure balance for shield tunneling&quot;, J China Coal Society 33 (3) (2008) 343-346. 5. Finno R. J., Clough G. W., &quot;Evaluation of soil response to EPB shield tunneling&quot; J Geotech Eng 111 (2) (1985) 155-173. 6. Clough G. W., Leca E., &quot;EPB shield tunneling in mixed face conditions&quot;, J Geotech Eng 119 (10) (1993) 1640-1656. 7. Suwansawat S., Einstein H. H., &quot;Artificial neural networks for predicting the maximum surface settlement caused by EPB shield tunneling&quot;, Tunn Undergr Sp Tech 21 (2) (2006) 133-150. 8. Boyacioglu M. A., Avci D., &quot;An adaptive network-based fuzzy inference system (ANFIS) for the prediction of stock market return: the case of the Istanbul stock exchange&quot;, Expert Syst Appl 37 (12) (2010) 7908-7912. 9. Avci E., &quot;Comparison of wavelet families for texture classification by using wavelet packet entropy adaptive network based fuzzy inference system&quot;, Appl Soft Comput 8 (1) (2008) 225-231. 10. Avci E., Akpolat Z. H., &quot;Speech recognition using a wavelet packet adaptive network based fuzzy inference system&quot;, Expert Syst Appl 31 (3) (2006) 495-503. 11. Avci E., Turkoglu I., Poyraz M., &quot;Intelligent target recognition based on wavelet adaptive network based fuzzy inference system. In: Iberian Conference on Pattern Recognition and Image Analysis&quot;, Springer, (2005) 594-603. 12. Avci E., Hanbay D., Varol A., &quot;An expert discrete wavelet adaptive network based fuzzy inference system for digital modulation recognition&quot;, Expert Syst Appl 33 (3) (2007) 582-589. 13. Jang J. S. R., &quot;ANFIS: Adaptive-network-based fuzzy inference system&quot;, IEEE T Syst Man Cyb 23 (3) (1993) 665-685. 14. Chiu S. L., &quot;Fuzzy model identification based on cluster estimation&quot;, J Intell Fuzzy Syst 2 (3) (1994) 267-278. 15. Jassar S., Liao Z., Zhao L., &quot;Adaptive neuro-fuzzy based inferential sensor model for estimating the average air temperature in space heating systems&quot;, Build Environ 44 (8) (2009) 1609-1616. 16. Wei M., Bai B., Sung A. H., Liu Q., Wang J., Cather M. E., &quot;Predicting injection profiles using ANFIS&quot;, Inform Sciences 177 (20) (2007) 4445-4461. 17. Bezdek J. C., &quot;Fuzzy mathematics in pattern classification&quot;, Cornell university, Ithaca (1973). 18. Hornik K., Stinchcombe M., White H., &quot;Multilayer feedforward networks are universal approximators&quot;, Neural Networks 2 (5) (1989) 359-366. 19. Ahmadi M. H., Aghaj S. S. G., Nazeri A., &quot;Prediction of power in solar stirling heat engine by using neural network based on hybrid genetic algorithm and particle swarm optimization&quot;, Neural Comput Appl 22 (6) (2013) 1141-1150. 20. García-Pedrajas N., Hervás-Martínez C., Muñoz-Pérez J., &quot;COVNET: a cooperative coevolutionary model for evolving artificial neural networks&quot;, IEEE T Neural Networ 14 (3) (2003) 575-596. 21. Hossein M., Ahmadi M. A., Ghare S. S., &quot;Prediction of Power in Solar Stirling Heat Engine by Evolving Particle Swarm Optimization and Neural Network&quot;, Int J Comput Appl 34 (1) (2011). 22. Uzlu E., Kankal M., Akpınar A., Dede T., &quot;Estimates of energy consumption in Turkey using neural networks with the teaching-learning-based optimization algorithm&quot;, Energy 75 (2014) 295-303. 23. Toğan V., &quot;Design of planar steel frames using teaching–learning based optimization&quot;, Eng Struct 34 (2012) 225-232. 24. Togan V., &quot;Design of pin jointed structures using teaching-learning based optimization&quot;, Structural Engineering and Mechanics 47 (2) (2013) 209-225. 25. Simon D., &quot;Biogeography-based optimization&quot;, IEEE T Evolut Comput 12 (6) (2008) 702-713. 26. Zhang Y., Phillips P., Wang S., Ji G., Yang J., Wu J., &quot;Fruit classification by biogeography‐based optimization and feedforward neural network&quot;, Expert Systems 33 (3) (2016) 239-253. 27. Hajihassani M., Armaghani D. J., Marto A., Mohamad E. T., &quot;Ground vibration prediction in quarry blasting through an artificial neural network optimized by imperialist competitive algorithm&quot;, Bull Eng Geology Envir 74 (3) (2015) 873-886. 28. Tsou D., MacNish C., &quot;Adaptive particle swarm optimisation for high-dimensional highly convex search spaces. In: Evolutionary Computation&quot;, CEC'03. The 2003 Congress on, IEEE, (2003) 783-789.   ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی عددی ظرفیت باربری شمع‌های در جاریز در خاک های رسی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>A Numerical Approach on Bearing Capacity of Drilled Shafts Embedded in Clay</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>در این پژوهش ظرفیت باربری شمع&#8204;های درجاریز (شمع&#8204;های ریختنی) در خاک&#8204;های رسی با نرم&#8204;افزارFLAC2D به&#8204;صورت عددی بررسی و نتایج حاصل از این پژوهش با نتایج آزمایش سانتریفیوژ صحت&#8204;سنجی شده است. هم&#8204;چنین، نتایج حاصل از روابط موجود در ادبیات فنی با نتایج به&#173;دست آمده از پژوهش حاضر&#160; مقایسه شده است. مجموعه&#8204;ای از آنالیز&#8204;ها به&#8204;منظور بررسی تأثیرات ناشی از پارامتر&#8204;های مختلف خاک و شمع روی مقدار ظرفیت باربری نوک و جدار شمع&#8204;های درجاریز در خاک&#8204;های رسی انجام گرفته است. این پارامترها شامل مدول الاستیسیته خاک، طول و قطر شمع، مقاومت زهکشی نشده رس، وزن مخصوص و ضریب پواسون خاک است. هم&#8204;چنین، تأثیر متقابل مقاومت برشی زهکشی نشده و مدول الاستیسیته رس&#8204;ها روی مقاومت نوک بررسی شده است. نتایج نشان می&#8204;دهند که کاهش مدول الاستیک خاک موجب کاهش تأثیر مقاومت زهکشی نشده رس روی مقاومت نوک می&#8204;شود. آنالیزهای عددی نشان داده&#8204;اند که اگر مقاومت برشی زهکشی نشده از 25 تا 200 کیلو پاسکال افزایش یابد، مقادیر مقاومت نوک در محدودۀ 60 تا 85% افزایش می&#8204;یابد. این آنالیز&#8204;ها برای مقادیر مدول الاستیک ثابت در محدوده 5 تا 180 مگا پاسکال انجام شده است. هم&#8204;چنین، رابطۀ جدیدی برای تخمین ضریب ظرفیت باربری N*c ارائه شده است.&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>This study numerically investigates the bearing capacity of drilled shafts (bored piles) in clay using FLAC2D. The results obtained in this study are compared with centrifuge test results. The results of the empirical relationships available in the literature are compared with the results of the present numerical study. A series of analyses is also conducted to assess the effects of various soil and pile parameters on the magnitude of tip and side resistance of bored piles embedded in clay. These parameters include the soil elastic modulus, pile length and diameter, undrained shear strength, unit weight, and Poisson&#8217;s ratio of soil. Furthermore, the coupling effect of soil undrained shear strength and elastic modulus of soil on tip resistance are investigated. The results show that the lower value of soil elastic modulus results to lower effect of soil undrained shear strength. The effect of soil undrained shear strength on tip resistance is approximately constant (about 83% for a change of soil undrained shear strength between 25 to 200 kPa) for the range&#160;of elastic modulus between 20 and 180 MPa. Also, a new equation is proposed to estimate the bearing capacity factor of N*c.
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>85</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>106</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مجید</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>جاذبی</Family>
				<NameE>Majid</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Jazebi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی شریف، دانشکدۀ مهندسی عمران،  تهران، ایران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه صنعتی شریف</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>majidjazebi@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمد مهدی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>احمدی</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad Mehdi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ahmadi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی شریف، دانشکدۀ مهندسی عمران،  تهران، ایران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه صنعتی شریف</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>mmahmadi@sharif.edu</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Bearing capacity</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Side resistance</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Tip resistance</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Drilled shaft</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Bored pile</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Numerical modelling</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>clay</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Sensitivity analysis</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>FLAC</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ظرفیت باربری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مقاومت جدار</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مقاومت نوک</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شمع درجاریز</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شمع ریختنی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدل سازی عددی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>رس</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>آنالیز حساسیت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نرم افزار FLAC</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Vesic, Aleksandar S. &amp;quot;Design of pile foundations.&amp;quot; NCHRP synthesis of highway practice 42 (1977).##[2] O'Neil MW, Reese LC. “Drilled shafts: Construction procedures and design methods.” No. FHWA-IF-99-025 (1999).##[3] Kulhawy, Fred H., and Christina Stas Jackson. &amp;quot;Some observations on undrained side resistance of drilled shafts.&amp;quot; In Foundation Engineering: Current principles and practices, pp. 1011-1025. ASCE, (1989).##[4] Meyerhof GG. “Bearing capacity and settlemtn of pile foundations.” Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering 102:197-228. (1976).##[5] Shioi, Y., &amp; Fukui, J. “Application of N-value to design of foundations in Japan”. In Proceeding of the second European symposium on penetration testing (Vol. 1, No. 1982, pp. 159-16). (1982)##[6] Decourt, L. “Prediction of load settlement relationships for foundations on the basis of the SPT-T”. Ciclo de Conferencias Inter.“Leonardo Zeevaert”, UNAM, Mexico, 85-104. (1995).##[7] Aoki N, Velloso DD. “An approximate method to estimate the bearing capacity of piles.” InProc., 5th Pan-American Conf. of Soil Mechanics and Foundation Engineering. (1975).##[8] Philipponnat, G. “Méthode pratique de calcul d'un pieu isolé, à l'aide du pénétromètre statique”. Revue Francaise de Geotechnique, (10), 55-64. (1980).##[9] Bustamante, M., &amp; Frank, R. “Design of axially loaded piles in France: National Report”. In International Seminar Design of Axially loaded piles: European Practice (pp. 161-175). (1997)##[10] Bustamante, M., &amp; Gianeselli, L. “Pile bearing capacity prediction by means of static penetrometer CPT”. In Proceedings of the 2-nd European symposium on penetration testing (pp. 493-500). (1982)##[11] Itasca, F. L. A. C. &amp;quot;Fast Lagrangian analysis of continua.&amp;quot; Itasca Consulting Group Inc., Minneapolis, Minn (2000).##[12] Bowles LE. “Foundation analysis and design”, 5th edition. McGraw-hill (1996).##[13] Horikoshi, K., &amp; Randolph, M. F. “Centrifuge modelling of piled raft foundations on clay. Geotechnique”, 46(4), 741-752. (1996).##[14] Horikoshi, K., &amp; Randolph, M. F. “A contribution to optimum design of piled rafts”. Geotechnique, 48(3), 301-317. (1998).##[15] Fleming K, Weltman A, Randolph M, Elson K. “Piling engineering”, 3rd edition. CRC press. (2008).##[16] Whitaker T, Cooke RW. “An investigation of the shaft and base resistance of large bored piles in London clay.” London: Institution of Civil Engineers. (1966).##[17] Reese LC, Wright SJ. “Construction procedures and design for axial loading.” Drilled Shaft Manual HDV-22. (1977).##[18] Peck RB, Terzaghi K. (1967). “Soil mechanics in engineering practice”, 2st edition. Wiley, New York.##[19] Mayne, Paul W., and J. B. Kemper. &amp;quot;Profiling OCR in stiff clays by CPT and SPT.&amp;quot; Geotechnical testing journal 11, no. 2: 139-147. (1988).##[20] Anagnostopoulos, A., G. Koukis, N. Sabatakakis, and G. Tsiambaos. &amp;quot;Empirical correlations of soil parameters based on cone penetration tests (CPT) for Greek soils.&amp;quot; Geotechnical &amp; Geological Engineering 21, no. 4: 377-387. (2003).####1. Vesic, Aleksandar S., &quot;Design of pile foundations&quot; NCHRP synthesis of highway practice, 42 (1977). 2. O'Neil MW, Reese L. C., &quot;Drilled shafts: Construction procedures and design methods&quot;, No. FHWA-IF-99-025 (1999). 3. Kulhawy, Fred H., Christina Stas Jackson, &quot;Some observations on undrained side resistance of drilled shafts&quot;, In Foundation Engineering: Current principles and practices, (1989) 1011-1025. ASCE,. 4. Meyerhof G. G., &quot;Bearing capacity and settlemtn of pile foundations&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering 102: (1976) 197-228. 5. Aoki N., Velloso D. D., &quot;An approximate method to estimate the bearing capacity of piles&quot;, InProc., 5th Pan-American Conf, of Soil Mechanics and Foundation Engineering (1975). 6. Philipponnat G., &quot;Méthode pratique de calcul d'un pieu isolé, à l'aide du pénétromètre statique&quot;, Revue Francaise de Geotechnique, (10) (1980) 55-64. 7. Bustamante M., Frank R., &quot;Design of axially loaded piles in France: National Report&quot;, In International Seminar Design of Axially loaded piles: European Practice, (1997) 161-175. 8. Bustamante M., Gianeselli L., &quot;Pile bearing capacity prediction by means of static penetrometer CPT&quot;, In Proceedings of the 2-nd European symposium on penetration testing, (1982) 493-500. 9. Itasca F. L. A. C., &quot;Fast Lagrangian analysis of continua&quot;, Itasca Consulting Group Inc., Minneapolis, Minn (2000). 10. Bowles L. E., &quot;Foundation analysis and design&quot;, 5th edition. McGraw-hill (1996). 11. Horikoshi K., Randolph M. F., &quot;Centrifuge modelling of piled raft foundations on clay. Geotechnique&quot;, 46(4) (1996) 741-752. 12. Horikoshi K., Randolph M. F., &quot;A contribution to optimum design of piled rafts&quot;. Geotechnique, 48(3) (1998) 301-317.  13. Fleming K., Weltman A., Randolph M., Elson K., &quot;Piling engineering&quot;, 3rd edition. CRC press (2008). 14. Whitaker T, Cooke R. W., &quot;An investigation of the shaft and base resistance of large bored piles in London clay&quot;, London: Institution of Civil Engineers (1966). 15. Reese L. C., Wright S. J., &quot;Construction procedures and design for axial loading&quot;, Drilled Shaft Manual HDV-22. (1977). 16. Mayne Paul W., Kemper J. B., &quot;Profiling OCR in stiff clays by CPT and SPT&quot;, Geotechnical testing journal 11, No. 2, (1988)139-147.  17. Anagnostopoulos A., Koukis G., Sabatakakis N., Tsiambaos G., &quot;Empirical correlations of soil parameters based on cone penetration tests (CPT) for Greek soils&quot;, Geotechnical &amp; Geological Engineering 21, No. 4, (2003) 377-387.  ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر فشار سینۀ کار بر نشست سطح زمین در تونل‌سازی با سپر متعادل کنندۀ فشار زمین (EPB)(مطالعۀ موردی: خط A متروی قم)</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Investigating the Effect of Face Pressure on Ground Settlement in Tunneling with Earth Pressure Balance (EPB) Shield (Case Study: Qom Metro Line A) </TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>عوامل مؤثر در نشست سطح زمین در روش حفاری مکانیزه را می&#8204;توان عمدتاً به چهار دسته عوامل هندسی، عوامل ژئومکانیکی، پارامترهای کاری&#160; ماشین حفاری و پارامترهای مدیریتی و اجرایی تقسیم&#8204;بندی کرد. عوامل هندسی شامل عمق و قطر تونل هستند پارامترهای کاری ماشین شامل فشار وارد بر جبهه حفاری، فشار تزریق در پشت سگمنت&#8204;ها و نیز میزان تغییر قطر (کاهش قطر دستگاه در طول) دستگاه است و پارامترهای ژئومکانیکی شامل مشخصات مکانیکی لایه&#8204;های خاک بین تونل تا سطح زمین است. در تونل&#8204;های مناطق شهری که بیش&#8204;تر در عمق کم و در بستر خاکی حفر می&#8204;شوند، فشار جبهه کار می&#8204;تواند یکی از عوامل پیش&#8204;گیری کنندۀ نشست سطح زمین باشد. در پروژۀ خطA &#160;مترو قم، تونل با ماشین حفاری مکانیزه از نوع متعادل کنندۀ فشار زمین (EPB) حفر می&#8204;شود. در این تحقیق با تمرکز روی پنج مقطع از این تونل، تأثیر فشار جبهه کار بر نشست سطح زمین تحلیل شده است. این پنج مقطع در کیلومترهای مختلف تونل در مکان&#8204;هایی انتخاب شدند که در سطح&#160; زمین پین&#8204;های نشست &#160;سنجی نصب شده&#8204;اند و نتایج مدل&#8204;سازی عددی قابل صحت&#8204;سنجی هستند. برای بررسی اثر فشار سینه&#8204;کار روی حداکثر نشست سطح زمین، چهار سطح فشار 100، 150، 200 و 400 کیلوپاسکال&#160; بررسی شد. این فشارها &#160;به&#8204;ترتیب 1، 5/1، 2، و 4 برابر فشار اولیه جبهۀ کار بودند. نشست سطح زمین در این چهار سطح فشار با استفاده از نرم&#8204;افزار اجزا محدود PLAXIS 3D TUNNEL ارزیابی شده است. اعتبارسنجی نتایج با استفاده از ابزاربندی در سطح زمین (پین&#8204;های نشست سنجی) و روی تمامی این مقاطع انجام شده است. اعتبارسنجی انجام شده نشان داد که نتایج مدل&#8204;سازی تطابق خوبی با نتایج پین&#8204;های نشست&#8204;سنجی دارد. مقایسۀ نتایج نشان می&#8204;دهد افزایش 4 برابری فشار جبهۀ کار، حداکثر سبب کاهش 4.45 میلی متری نشست بیشینه می&#8204;شود. بنابراین افزایش فشار جبهۀ کار، میزان نشست را کاهش می&#8204;دهد اما این مقدار بسیار ناچیز است. هم&#8204;چنین مشخص شد که افزایش بیش از اندازۀ فشار سینۀ کار (بیش از 200 کیلوپاسکال) نه&#8204;تنها حداکثر نشست سطح زمین را کاهش نمی&#8204;دهد بلکه باعث ایجاد شکست غیرفعال (Passive failure) یا همان بالازدگی در جلوی سپر روی سطح زمین زمین می&#8204;شود.
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>In the mechanized boring method, the factors affecting ground surface settlement can be mainly divided into five categories: geometric, geomechanic, boring machines working, operating and management parameters. In urban tunnels bored mainly in shallow soil bed, face pressure can be one of the factors preventing ground settlement. The Line A tunnel in Qom metro project is bored with an EPB (Earth Balance Pressure) mechanized boring machine. The effect of face pressure on ground surface settlement was analyzed in the present study according to five sections of the tunnel. These five sections were selected in different kilometers of the tunnel where settlement gauges were installed and the results could be validated. To investigate the effect of face pressure on maximum ground surface settlement, four pressure levels of 100 kPa, 150 kPa, 200 kPa, and 400 kPa were taken into consideration. These were 1, 1.5, 2, and 4 times of the initial face pressure level, respectively. The ground surface settlement was assessed at four&#160;pressure levels using the finite element software, PLAXIS 3D TUNNEL. The results were validated using ground-level instrumentation (settlement gauges) on all sections. The validation showed that the modeling results are in good agreement with the results obtained from settlement gauges.&#160; Comparison of the results indicated that a 4-fold increase in the face pressure led to a maximum decrease of 4.45 mm in the maximum settlement. Therefore, an increase in the face pressure can reduce settlement, although quite minimally. It was also found that an over-increased face pressure (face pressure over 200kPa) not only did not reduce the maximum ground surface settlement but also may lead to passive failure or uplift of ground surface ahead of the shield.&#160;
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>107</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>134</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>میلاد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>معصومی اقدم</Family>
				<NameE>Milad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Masomi Aghdam</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Imam Khomeini International University</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه بین المللی امام خمینی (ره)</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهدی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>حسینی</Family>
				<NameE>Mehdi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Hosseini</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Imam Khomeini International University</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه بین المللی امام خمینی (ره)</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Settlement</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>EPB</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Qom metro tunnel</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Numerical modeling</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Instrumentation</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>PLAXIS 3D TUNNEL</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نشست</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>EPB</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تونل متروی قم</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدل‌سازی عددی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ابزاربندی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>PLAXIS 3D TUNNEL</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1. Renard Middle M., Hernknesht, Lu.A., &quot;Mechanized shield tunneling&quot;, translated by Sharifzadeh, M., Khademi Hamidi, J., Torkamani Ghotb, A., Tehran University Jihad, Amirkabir unit (2007). 2. Guglielmetti V., Grasso P., Mahtab A., Xu S., &quot;Mechanized tunnelling in urban areas: design, methodology and construction control&quot;, Taylor and Francis (2007). 3. Sattari G.H., &quot;Numerical and analytical estimates of ground surface subsidence due to tunneling by shield tunneling ground balance, (Case Study: Tehran metro line seven)&quot;, PhD Thesis, Azad University (2008). 4. Franzius J. N.,&quot;Behavior of building due to tunnel induced settlement&quot;, Ph.D. dissertation, Imperial College of Science, Technology and Medicine (2003). 5. Vermeer A., Ruse N., Marcher T., &quot;Tunnel heading stability in drained ground&quot;, FELSBAU 20, No. 6 (2002). 6. Höfle R., Fillibech J., Vogt N., &quot;Time dependent deformations during tunnelling and stability of tunnel faces in fine-grained soils under groundwater&quot;, 3 (2008) 309-316. 7. Sun S., Pei H., Zhang S., &quot;Analysis of Face Stability and Ground Settlement in EPB Shield Tunnelling for the Nanjing Metro&quot;, The Geological Society of London, IAEG, (2006) Paper Number 274. 8. Li Y., Emerialut F., Kastner R., Zhang Z. X., &quot;Stability analysis of large slurry shield-driven tunnel in soft clay&quot;, Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology, 24, (2009) 472-481. 9. Mollon G., Dias D., Subra A. H., &quot;Probabilistic analysis of circular tunnels in homogeneous soil using response surface methodology&quot;, ASCE, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenviromental Engineering, (2009) 1314-1325. 10. Greenwood J. D., &quot;Three Dimension Analysis of Surface Settlement in Soft Ground Tunneling&quot;, Master of Engineering Thesis, Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT), Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering (2003).  11. Lambrughi A., Rodríguez L. M., Castellanza R., &quot;Development and validation of a 3D Numerical Model for TBM–EPB Mechanized Excavations&quot;, Computers and Geotechnics Journal, 40 (2012) 97-113.  12. Bethez N., Branque D., Subrin D., Wong H., Humbert E., &quot;Face failure in homogeneous and stratified soft ground: theoretical and experimental approaches on 1g EPBS reduced scale model&quot;, Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology, 30 (2012) 25-37. 13. Chen R. P., Li J., Kong L. G., Tang L. J., &quot;Experimental study on face instability of shield tunnel in sand&quot;, Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology, 33 (2013) 12-21. 14. Kim K., Oh J., Lee H., Choi H., &quot;Critical face pressure and backfill pressure in shield TBM tunneling on soft ground&quot;, the 2017 world congress on advances in structural engineering and mechanics, Seoul, Korea (2017).  15. Sahel Consulting Engineers, &quot;Geological and geotechnical studies of Qom city metro, Line A&quot; (2011). 16. Kheirandish I., Farough hosseini M., Talebi Nezhad A., &quot;Impact of Face Pressure on Surface and Face Deformations in EPB Tunneling&quot;, 8(20) (2014) 37-48. ##1. Renard Middle M., Hernknesht, Lu.A., &quot;Mechanized shield tunneling&quot;, translated by Sharifzadeh, M., Khademi Hamidi, J., Torkamani Ghotb, A., Tehran University Jihad, Amirkabir unit (2007). 2. Guglielmetti V., Grasso P., Mahtab A., Xu S., &quot;Mechanized tunnelling in urban areas: design, methodology and construction control&quot;, Taylor and Francis (2007). 3. Sattari G.H., &quot;Numerical and analytical estimates of ground surface subsidence due to tunneling by shield tunneling ground balance, (Case Study: Tehran metro line seven)&quot;, PhD Thesis, Azad University (2008). 4. Franzius J. N.,&quot;Behavior of building due to tunnel induced settlement&quot;, Ph.D. dissertation, Imperial College of Science, Technology and Medicine (2003). 5. Vermeer A., Ruse N., Marcher T., &quot;Tunnel heading stability in drained ground&quot;, FELSBAU 20, No. 6 (2002). 6. Höfle R., Fillibech J., Vogt N., &quot;Time dependent deformations during tunnelling and stability of tunnel faces in fine-grained soils under groundwater&quot;, 3 (2008) 309-316. 7. Sun S., Pei H., Zhang S., &quot;Analysis of Face Stability and Ground Settlement in EPB Shield Tunnelling for the Nanjing Metro&quot;, The Geological Society of London, IAEG, (2006) Paper Number 274. 8. Li Y., Emerialut F., Kastner R., Zhang Z. X., &quot;Stability analysis of large slurry shield-driven tunnel in soft clay&quot;, Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology, 24, (2009) 472-481. 9. Mollon G., Dias D., Subra A. H., &quot;Probabilistic analysis of circular tunnels in homogeneous soil using response surface methodology&quot;, ASCE, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenviromental Engineering, (2009) 1314-1325. 10. Greenwood J. D., &quot;Three Dimension Analysis of Surface Settlement in Soft Ground Tunneling&quot;, Master of Engineering Thesis, Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT), Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering (2003).  11. Lambrughi A., Rodríguez L. M., Castellanza R., &quot;Development and validation of a 3D Numerical Model for TBM–EPB Mechanized Excavations&quot;, Computers and Geotechnics Journal, 40 (2012) 97-113.  12. Bethez N., Branque D., Subrin D., Wong H., Humbert E., &quot;Face failure in homogeneous and stratified soft ground: theoretical and experimental approaches on 1g EPBS reduced scale model&quot;, Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology, 30 (2012) 25-37. 13. Chen R. P., Li J., Kong L. G., Tang L. J., &quot;Experimental study on face instability of shield tunnel in sand&quot;, Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology, 33 (2013) 12-21. 14. Kim K., Oh J., Lee H., Choi H., &quot;Critical face pressure and backfill pressure in shield TBM tunneling on soft ground&quot;, the 2017 world congress on advances in structural engineering and mechanics, Seoul, Korea (2017).  15. Sahel Consulting Engineers, &quot;Geological and geotechnical studies of Qom city metro, Line A&quot; (2011). 16. Kheirandish I., Farough hosseini M., Talebi Nezhad A., &quot;Impact of Face Pressure on Surface and Face Deformations in EPB Tunneling&quot;, 8(20) (2014) 37-48.  ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>پیش‌بینی نشست سطحی ناشی از حفر تونل با استفاده از شبکه های عصبی مصنوعی؛ مطالعۀ موردی: تونل متروی مشهد</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Prediction of Tunnelling-Induced Surface Settlement with Artificial Neural Networks, Case Study: Mashhad Subway Tunnel </TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>هنگام حفر تونل در فضاهای شهری، جلوگیری از آسیب و تخریب سازه&#173;های مجاور اهمیت ویژه&#8204;ای دارد. برای کاهش این آسیب&#173;ها باید از نشست سطحی زمین جلوگیری کرد. در سال&#173;های اخیر بررسی&#8204;های گسترده&#173;ای در زمینۀ پیش&#173;بینی نشست سطحی زمین در اثر حفر تونل انجام شده است. انتخاب روش مناسب به عوامل مختلفی بستگی دارد. نشست سطحی ناشی از حفر تونل با کمک متغیرهای ورودی که تأثیر فیزیکی چشم&#8204;گیری بر نشست دارند، پیش&#173;بینی شده است. برای ساخت مدل&#173; شبکه&#173;های عصبی از داده&#173;های به&#173;دست آمده از حفر تونل خط 2 متروی مشهد استفاده شده است. نتایج نشان داد که شبکه عصبی پیش&#173;خور که با استفاده از الگوریتم پس انتشار خطا آموزش دیده است و دارای سه لایه با معماری 1-24-7 است، شبکۀ عصبی بهینه ایت. شبکۀ عصبی بهینه دارای ضریب هم&#8204;بستگی و میانگین مربعات خطا برابر با 963/0 و&#160;4-10&#215;41/2 است. هم&#8204;چنین نتایج نشان داد که این شبکۀ عصبی آموزش دیده شده می&#173;تواند برای پیش&#173;بینی نشست سطحی ناشی از حفر تونل به&#173;صورت موفقیت&#173;آمیزی استفاده شود.&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>In urban areas, it is essential to protect the existing adjacent structures and underground facilities from the damage due to tunneling. In order to minimize the risk, a tunnel engineer needs to be able to make reliable prediction of ground deformations induced by tunneling. Numerous investigations have been conducted in recent years to predict the settlement associated with tunneling; the selection of appropriate method depends on the complexity of the problems. This research intends to develop a method based on Artificial Neural Network (ANN) for the prediction of tunnelling-induced surface settlement. Surface settlements above a tunnel due to tunnel construction are predicted with the help of input variables that have direct physical significance. The data used in running the network models have&#160;been obtained from line 2 of Mashhad subway tunnel project. In order to predict the tunnelling-induced surface settlement, a Multi-Layer Perceptron (MLP) analysis is used. A three-layer, feed-forward, back-propagation neural network, with a topology of 7-24-1 was found to be optimum. For optimum ANN architecture, the correlation factor and the minimum of Mean Squared Error are 0.963 and 2.41E-04, respectively. The results showed that an appropriately trained neural network could reliably predict tunnelling-induced surface settlement.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>135</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>158</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حمید</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>مهرنهاد</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه یزد، دانشکدۀ مهندسی عمران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه یزد</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Hmehrnahad@yazd.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهدی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>خلق ذکرآباد</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه یزد، دانشکدۀ مهندسی عمران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه یزد</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Surface Settlement</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Artificial Neural Network</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Mashhad Subway Tunnel</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Prediction of Settlement</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نشست سطحی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شبکۀ عصبی مصنوعی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تونل متروی مشهد</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پیش‌بینی نشست</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1.	Attewell P. B., Farmer I. W., &quot;Ground deformations resulting from shield tunnelling in London clay&quot;, Canadian Geotechnical Journal, 11(3) (1974) 380-395. 2.	Barkhordari Bafghi K., Entezari Zarch H., &quot;Prediction of permanent earthquake induced deformation in earth dams and embankments using artificial neural networks&quot;, Civil Engineering Infrastructures Journal, 48(2) (2015) 289-301. 3.	Behnia D., Ahangari K., Noorzad A., Moeinossadat S. R., &quot;Predicting crest settlement in concrete face rock fill dams using adaptive neuro-fuzzy inference system and gene expression programming intelligent methods&quot;, Journal of Zhejiang University-Science A (Applied Physics &amp; Engineering), 14(8) (2013) 589-602.  4.	Chester D. L., &quot;Why two hidden layers are better than one&quot;, International Joint Conference on Neural Networks, San Diego, (1990) 265-268. 5.	Cybenko G. V., &quot;Approximation by superpositions of a sigmoidal function&quot;, Math. Control Signal System (MCSS), 2(4) (1989) 303-314. 6.	Das S. K., Basudhar P. K., &quot;Undrained lateral load capacity of piles in clay using artificial neural network&quot;, Computers and Geotechnics, 33(8) (2006) 454-459. 7.	Gholamnejad J.,Tayarani N., &quot;Application of artificial neural networks to the prediction of tunnel boring machine penetration rate&quot;, Mining Science and Technology, 20(5) (2010) 727-733. 8.	Hanna A. M., Ural D., Saygili G., &quot;Neural network model for liquefaction potential in soil deposits using Turkey and Taiwan earthquake data&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, 27 (6) (2007) 521-540. 9.	Hornik K., Stinchcombe M., White H., &quot;Multilayer feed-forward networks are universal approximators&quot;, Neural Networks, 2 (1989) 359-366. 10.	Javadi A., Rezania M., Mousavi N. M., &quot;Evaluation of liquefaction induced lateral displacements using genetic programming&quot;, Computers and Geotechnics, 33(4) (2006) 222-233. 11.	Lapedes A., Farber R., &quot;How neural networks work&quot;, Neural Information Processing Systems, American Institute of Physics, (1988). 12.	Lee K. M., Rowe R. K., Lo K. Y., &quot;Subsidence owing to tunnelling I: estimating the gap parameter&quot;, Canadian Geotechnical Journal, 29(6) (1992) 929–940. 13.	Loganathan N., Poulos H. G., &quot;Analytical prediction for tunnelling-induced ground movements in clays&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering, 124(9) (1998) 846–856. 14.	Mahdevari S., Torabi S. R., &quot;Prediction of tunnel convergence using artificial neural networks&quot;, Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology, 28 (2012) 218–228. 15.	Maier H. R., Dandy G. C., &quot;Neural networks for the prediction and forecasting of water resources variables: A review of modeling issues and applications&quot;, Environmental Modeling &amp; Software, 15 (2000) 101-124. 16.	Masters T., &quot;Practical neural network recipes in C++&quot;, Academic Press, San Diego, California, (1993). 17.	Mohammadi N., Mirabedini S. J., &quot;Comparison of particle swarm optimization and backpropagation algorithms for training feed forward neural network&quot;, Journal of Mathematics and Computer Science, 12 (2014) 113-123. 18.	Nomoto T., Imamura S., Hagiwara T., Kusakabe O., Fujii N., &quot;Shield tunnel construction in centrifuge&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering, 125(4) (1999) 289-300. 19.	Ornek M., Laman M., Demir A., Yildiz A., &quot;Prediction of bearing capacity of circular footings on soft clay stabilized with granular soil&quot;, Soils and Foundations, 52(1) (2012) 69-80. 20.	Park H., &quot;Study for application artificial neural networks in geotechnical problem&quot;, Artificial Neural Networks-Application, Available from: http://www.intechopen.com/books/artificial-neural-networks-application (2011). 21.	Peck R. B., &quot;Deep excavation and tunnelling in soft ground&quot;, In: Proceedings of 7th International Symposium on Soil Mechanics Foundation Engineering, Mexico City, (1969) 266-290. 22.	Sagaseta C., &quot;Analysis of undrained soil deformation due to ground loss&quot;, Geotechnique, 37(3) (1987) 301-320. 23.	Shahin M. A., &quot;Modeling axial capacity of pile foundations by intelligent computing&quot;, Proceedings of the BGA International Conference on Foundations, Dundee, Scotland, (2008). 24.	Shahin M. A., Jaksa M., Maier M., &quot;State of the art of artificial neural networks in geotechnical engineering&quot;, Electronic Journal of Geotechnical Engineering, 8 (2008) 1-26. 25.	Stone M., &quot;Cross-validatory choice and assessment of statistical predictions&quot;, Journal of Royal Statistical Society, 36 (1974) 111-147. 26.	Strokova L. A., &quot;Methods of estimating surface settlement during driving of urban tunnels&quot;, Soil Mechanics and Foundation Engineering, 47(3) (2010) 92-95. 27.	Verruijt A., Booker J. R., &quot;Surface settlements due to deformation of a tunnel in an elastic half plane&quot;, Geotechnique, 46(4) (1996) 753-756. 28.	Yang X. L., Wang J. M., &quot;Ground movement prediction for tunnels using simplified procedure&quot;, Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology, 26 (2011) 462-471. 29.	Yoo C., Kim J., &quot;Tunnelling performance prediction using an integrated GIS and neural network&quot;, Computers and Geotechnics, 34(1) (2007) 19-30. 30.	Zhiguo Z., Maosong H., Mengxi Z., &quot;Theoretical prediction of ground movements induced by tunnelling in multi-layered soils&quot;, Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology, 26 (2011) 345-355. ##1.	Attewell P. B., Farmer I. W., &quot;Ground deformations resulting from shield tunnelling in London clay&quot;, Canadian Geotechnical Journal, 11(3) (1974) 380-395. 2.	Barkhordari Bafghi K., Entezari Zarch H., &quot;Prediction of permanent earthquake induced deformation in earth dams and embankments using artificial neural networks&quot;, Civil Engineering Infrastructures Journal, 48(2) (2015) 289-301. 3.	Behnia D., Ahangari K., Noorzad A., Moeinossadat S. R., &quot;Predicting crest settlement in concrete face rock fill dams using adaptive neuro-fuzzy inference system and gene expression programming intelligent methods&quot;, Journal of Zhejiang University-Science A (Applied Physics &amp; Engineering), 14(8) (2013) 589-602.  4.	Chester D. L., &quot;Why two hidden layers are better than one&quot;, International Joint Conference on Neural Networks, San Diego, (1990) 265-268. 5.	Cybenko G. V., &quot;Approximation by superpositions of a sigmoidal function&quot;, Math. Control Signal System (MCSS), 2(4) (1989) 303-314. 6.	Das S. K., Basudhar P. K., &quot;Undrained lateral load capacity of piles in clay using artificial neural network&quot;, Computers and Geotechnics, 33(8) (2006) 454-459. 7.	Gholamnejad J.,Tayarani N., &quot;Application of artificial neural networks to the prediction of tunnel boring machine penetration rate&quot;, Mining Science and Technology, 20(5) (2010) 727-733. 8.	Hanna A. M., Ural D., Saygili G., &quot;Neural network model for liquefaction potential in soil deposits using Turkey and Taiwan earthquake data&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, 27 (6) (2007) 521-540. 9.	Hornik K., Stinchcombe M., White H., &quot;Multilayer feed-forward networks are universal approximators&quot;, Neural Networks, 2 (1989) 359-366. 10.	Javadi A., Rezania M., Mousavi N. M., &quot;Evaluation of liquefaction induced lateral displacements using genetic programming&quot;, Computers and Geotechnics, 33(4) (2006) 222-233. 11.	Lapedes A., Farber R., &quot;How neural networks work&quot;, Neural Information Processing Systems, American Institute of Physics, (1988). 12.	Lee K. M., Rowe R. K., Lo K. Y., &quot;Subsidence owing to tunnelling I: estimating the gap parameter&quot;, Canadian Geotechnical Journal, 29(6) (1992) 929–940. 13.	Loganathan N., Poulos H. G., &quot;Analytical prediction for tunnelling-induced ground movements in clays&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering, 124(9) (1998) 846–856. 14.	Mahdevari S., Torabi S. R., &quot;Prediction of tunnel convergence using artificial neural networks&quot;, Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology, 28 (2012) 218–228. 15.	Maier H. R., Dandy G. C., &quot;Neural networks for the prediction and forecasting of water resources variables: A review of modeling issues and applications&quot;, Environmental Modeling &amp; Software, 15 (2000) 101-124. 16.	Masters T., &quot;Practical neural network recipes in C++&quot;, Academic Press, San Diego, California, (1993). 17.	Mohammadi N., Mirabedini S. J., &quot;Comparison of particle swarm optimization and backpropagation algorithms for training feed forward neural network&quot;, Journal of Mathematics and Computer Science, 12 (2014) 113-123. 18.	Nomoto T., Imamura S., Hagiwara T., Kusakabe O., Fujii N., &quot;Shield tunnel construction in centrifuge&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering, 125(4) (1999) 289-300. 19.	Ornek M., Laman M., Demir A., Yildiz A., &quot;Prediction of bearing capacity of circular footings on soft clay stabilized with granular soil&quot;, Soils and Foundations, 52(1) (2012) 69-80. 20.	Park H., &quot;Study for application artificial neural networks in geotechnical problem&quot;, Artificial Neural Networks-Application, Available from: http://www.intechopen.com/books/artificial-neural-networks-application (2011). 21.	Peck R. B., &quot;Deep excavation and tunnelling in soft ground&quot;, In: Proceedings of 7th International Symposium on Soil Mechanics Foundation Engineering, Mexico City, (1969) 266-290. 22.	Sagaseta C., &quot;Analysis of undrained soil deformation due to ground loss&quot;, Geotechnique, 37(3) (1987) 301-320. 23.	Shahin M. A., &quot;Modeling axial capacity of pile foundations by intelligent computing&quot;, Proceedings of the BGA International Conference on Foundations, Dundee, Scotland, (2008). 24.	Shahin M. A., Jaksa M., Maier M., &quot;State of the art of artificial neural networks in geotechnical engineering&quot;, Electronic Journal of Geotechnical Engineering, 8 (2008) 1-26. 25.	Stone M., &quot;Cross-validatory choice and assessment of statistical predictions&quot;, Journal of Royal Statistical Society, 36 (1974) 111-147. 26.	Strokova L. A., &quot;Methods of estimating surface settlement during driving of urban tunnels&quot;, Soil Mechanics and Foundation Engineering, 47(3) (2010) 92-95. 27.	Verruijt A., Booker J. R., &quot;Surface settlements due to deformation of a tunnel in an elastic half plane&quot;, Geotechnique, 46(4) (1996) 753-756. 28.	Yang X. L., Wang J. M., &quot;Ground movement prediction for tunnels using simplified procedure&quot;, Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology, 26 (2011) 462-471. 29.	Yoo C., Kim J., &quot;Tunnelling performance prediction using an integrated GIS and neural network&quot;, Computers and Geotechnics, 34(1) (2007) 19-30. 30.	Zhiguo Z., Maosong H., Mengxi Z., &quot;Theoretical prediction of ground movements induced by tunnelling in multi-layered soils&quot;, Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology, 26 (2011) 345-355.  ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>ارایۀ یک مدل اجزای محدود برای شبیه‌سازی جریان در اطراف چاه با الگوی مارپیچی مشبک‌کاری‌ها</TitleF>
		<TitleE>A Finite Element Model for Simulating Flow around a Well with Helically Symmetric Perforations</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>در یک چاه مشبک&#8204;کاری شده، سیالات از طریق آرایه&#8204;ای از تونل&#8204;های مشبک&#8204;کاری به درون چاه وارد می&#8204;شوند. معمولاً این مشبک&#8204;کاری&#8204;ها با الگویی مارپیچی در اطراف گمانه چاه توزیع می&#8204;شوند. مدل&#8204;های عددی موجود برای شبیه&#8204;سازی جریان سیالات تولیدی به درون چاه&#8204;های قائم غلاف&#8204;دار مشبک&#8204;کاری شده دارای شرایط مرزی پیچیده&#8204;ای بوده و یا از زیاد بودن هزینه&#8204;های محاسباتی رنج می&#8204;برند. این مقاله یک مدل اجزای محدود ساده و در عین حال کارآمد را برای شبیه&#8204;سازی جریان در اطراف یک چاه با تقارن مارپیچی مشبک&#8204;کاری&#8204;ها را ارایه می&#8204;دهد. در مدل پیشنهادی با استفاده از تقارن فقط لازم است ضخامتی از بازه مشبک&#8204;کاری که شامل یک تونل مشبک&#8204;کاری است مش&#8204;بندی شود. زاویۀ فیزینگ بین مشبک&#8204;کاری&#8204;های مجاور از طریق اعمال شرایط مرزی دوره&#8204;ای به مرزهای بالایی و پایینی ضخامت مفسر مخزن در نظر گرفته شده&#8204; است. این شرایط مرزی شامل بخش&#8204;های فشار-دوره&#8204;ای و سرعت-دوره&#8204;ای است. بر خلاف بخش فشار-دوره&#8204;ای، روش اعمال شرایط سرعت-پریودیک برای مسئله جریان تک متغیره مبهم است. در این راستا ثابت می&#8204;شود که در مدل پیشنهادی شرایط سرعت دوره&#8204;ای به&#8204;صورت خودکار به شکل ضعیف ارضاء می&#8204;شود. دقت و کارایی محاسباتی مدل پیشنهادی از طریق مقایسه با مدل&#8204;های موجود صحت&#8204;سنجی شده است. نتایج مدل در قالب ضریب پوسته با مدل نیمه&#8204;تحلیلی متداول نیز مقایسه شده و انطباق مناسبی مشاهده شده است. مدل پیشنهادی می&#8204;تواند به&#8204;عنوان یک ابزار عددی مناسب برای بررسی جریان ورودی به چاه با آرایش مارپیچی &#160;مشبک&#8204;کاری&#8204;ها استفاده شود.
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>In a perforated well, fluids enter the wellbore through arrays of perforation tunnels. These perforations are typically distributed in a helical pattern around the wellbore. Available numerical models to simulate production flow into cased-and-perforated vertical wells have complicated boundary conditions or suffer from high computational costs. This paper presents a simple and at the same time efficient finite element model to simulate flow around a well with helically symmetric perforations. In the proposed model, by taking advantage of the symmetry, only a thickness of perforated interval containing a single perforation tunnel needs to be meshed. Angular phasing between adjacent perforations is considered by applying periodic boundary conditions on the upper and lower boundaries of the representative reservoir thickness. These boundary conditions involve periodic-pressure and periodic-velocity parts. Unlike the periodic-pressure part, the method of imposing the periodic-velocity condition&#160;within a single-variable flow problem is rather vague. In this regard, it is proved that in the proposed model, periodic-velocity condition is automatically satisfied in a weak sense. The accuracy and the computational efficiency of the proposed model are verified through comparison with available models. The model results, in terms of skin factor, are compared with the common semi-analytical model as well, and good agreement is obtained. The proposed model can readily be used as a numerical tool to study inflow of wells with helically symmetric perforations.
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>159</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>188</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سید امیرالدین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>صدرنژاد</Family>
				<NameE>Seyed Amirodin</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Sadrnejad</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی خواجه نصیرالدین طوسی، دانشکد، عمران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه صنعتی خواجه نصیرالدین طوسی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>sadrnejad@kntu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسن،</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>قاسم‌زاده،</Family>
				<NameE>Hasan</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ghasemzadeh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی خواجه نصیرالدین طوسی، دانشکد، عمران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه صنعتی خواجه نصیرالدین طوسی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>ghasemzadeh@kntu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>احمدعلی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>خدائی اردبیلی</Family>
				<NameE>Ahmadali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Khodaei Ardabili</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی خواجه نصیرالدین طوسی، دانشکد، عمران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه صنعتی خواجه نصیرالدین طوسی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>khodaie@dena.kntu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Cased and perforated well</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Finite element method</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Helical symmetry</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Periodic boundary condition</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Well inflow analysis.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>چاه غلاف‌دار مشبک‌کاری شده</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>روش اجزای محدود</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تقارن مارپیچی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شرط مرزی دوره‌ای</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تحلیل جریان ورودی به چاه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1. Zhan L., Doornbosch F., Martin A., Harvey J., Brenden G., &quot;Perforated Completion Optimization Using a New, Enhanced and Integrated Perforating Job Design Tool,&quot; Presented at the SPE International Symposium and Exhibition on Formation Damage Control, Lafayette, Louisiana, USA, (2012). 2. Hagoort J., &quot;An analytical model for predicting the productivity of perforated wells&quot;, J Petrol Sci Eng. vol. 56 (2007) 199-218. 3. Hashemi S. M., Zamani E., Mahdian A., &quot;Numerical simulation and performance optimization of oil well perforator&quot;, Modares Mechanical Engineering, vol. 16, no. 3, (2016) 17-26 (in Persian) 4. Satti R., Betancourt D., Harvey W, Zuklic S, White R, Ochsner D, Sampson T, Myers W, Gilliat J, &quot;Beginning with the End in Mind: Shaped Charges Designed for Reservoir Conditions&quot;, Presented at the SPE Middle East Oil &amp; Gas Show and Conference, Manama, Kingdom of Bahrain (2017). 5. Karakas M., Tariq S. M., &quot;Semianalytical Productivity Models for Perforated Completions&quot;, SPE Production Engineering. vol. 6, no. 1, (1991) 73-82. 6. Bellarby J., &quot;Well completion design&quot;, Developments in Petroleum Science, vol. 56, Elsevier, Hungary (2009). 7. Harris M. H., &quot;The effect of perforating on well productivity,&quot; J Petrol Technol, vol. 18 (1966) 518-528. 8. Klotz J. A., Krueger F. F., Pye D. S., &quot;Effect of perforating damage on well productivity&quot;, J Petrol Technol, vol. 29, no. 2, (1974) 1303-1314. 9. Locke S., &quot;An Advanced Method for Predicting the Productivity Ratio of a Perforated Well&quot;, J Petrol Technol, vol. 33, (1981) 2481-2488. 10. Dogulu Y. S., &quot;Modeling of Well Productivity in Perforated Completions&quot;, Presented at the SPE Eastern Regional Meeting, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA, (1998). 11. Ansah J., Proett M. A., Soliman M. Y., &quot;Advances in Well Completion Design: A New 3D Finite-Element Wellbore Inflow Model for Optimizing Performance of Perforated Completions&quot;, Presented at the SPE International Symposium and Exhibition on Formation Damage Control, Lafayette, Louisiana (2002). 12. Jamiolahmady M., Danesh A., Sohrabi M., Ataei R., &quot;Gas condensate flow in perforated region&quot;, SPE Journal, vol. 12, no. 1, (2007) 89-99. 13. Byrne M., Jimenez M. A., Chavez J. C., &quot;Predicting Well Inflow Using Computational Fluid Dynamics-Closer to the Truth?&quot;, Presented at the SPE European Formation Damage Conference, Scheveningen, The Netherlands, (2009). 14. Sun D., Li B., Gladkikh M., Satti R., Evans R., &quot;Comparison of Skin Factors for Perforated Completions Calculated with Computational-Fluid-Dynamics Software and the Karakas-Tariq Semianalytical Model&quot;, SPE Drilling &amp; Completion, vol. 28, no, 1, (2013) 21-33. 15. Volonte G., Scarfato F., Brignoli M., &quot;sand prediction: a practical finite-element 3d approach for real field applications,&quot; SPE Production &amp; Operations, vol. 28, no. 1, (2013) 95-108. 16. Wang H., Cardiff P., Sharma M. M., A 3-d poro-elasto-plastic model for sand production around open-hole and cased &amp; perforated wellbores,&quot; Presented at the 50th US Rock Mechanics / Geomechanics Symposium, Houston, Texas, USA, (2016). 17. Segal G., Vuik K., Kassels K., &quot;On the implementation of symmetric and antisymmetric periodic boundary conditions for incompressible flow,&quot; Int. J. Numer. Meth. Fluids. vol. 18, (1994) 1153-1165. 18. Li S. &quot;On the nature of periodic traction boundary condition in micromechanical FE analyses of unit cells&quot;, IMA J. Appl. Math., vol. 77, (2012) 441-450. 19. Yildiz T., &quot;Productivity of Selectively Perforated Vertical Wells&quot;, Presented at the SPE International Oil and Gas Conference and Exhibition in China, Beijing, China, (2000). 20. Xia Z., Zhang Y., Ellyin F., &quot;A unified periodical boundary conditions for representative volume elements of composites and applications&quot;, Int J Solids Struct., vol. 40, (2003) 1907-1921. 21. Tyrus J. M., Gosz M., DeSantiago E., &quot;A local finite element implementation for imposing periodic boundary conditions on composite micromechanical models&quot;, Int J Solids Struct., vol. 44, (2007) 2972-2989. 22. Reddy J. N., &quot;An Introduction to the Finite Element Method&quot;, 3rd ed., Singapore. McGraw-Hill. (2006). 23. Zienkiewicz O. C., Taylor R. L., Zhu J. Z, &quot;The Finite Element Method: Its Basis and Fundamentals&quot;, 7th ed, UK, Elsevier Butterworth-Heinemann (2013). 24. Nguyen V.D., Bechet E., Geuzaine L., Noels L., &quot;Imposing periodic boundary condition on arbitrary meshes by polynomial interpolation&quot;, Electrical Engineering, vol. 55, (2011) 390-409. 25. Sandstom C., Larsson F., Runesson K., &quot;Weakly periodic boundary conditions for the homogenization of flow in porous media&quot;, Adv Model Simul Eng Sci., vol. 2, no. 12, (2014) 1-24. 26. Brooks J.E., &quot;A Simple Method for Estimating Well Productivity&quot;, Presented at the SPE European Formation Damage Conference, The Hague, The Netherlands, (1997). 27. Yildiz T., &quot;Assessment of Total Skin Factor in Perforated Wells&quot;, SPE Reservoir Evaluation &amp; Engineering, vol. 9. no. 1, (2006) 62-76. 28. Jamiolahmady M., Mahdiyar H., Ghahri P., Sohrabi M., &quot;A new method for productivity calculation of perforated wells in Gas condensate reservoirs&quot;, J Petrol Sci Eng, vol. 77, (2011) 263-273. 29. Dake L. P., &quot;Fundamentals of Reservoir##1. Zhan L., Doornbosch F., Martin A., Harvey J., Brenden G., &quot;Perforated Completion Optimization Using a New, Enhanced and Integrated Perforating Job Design Tool,&quot; Presented at the SPE International Symposium and Exhibition on Formation Damage Control, Lafayette, Louisiana, USA, (2012). 2. Hagoort J., &quot;An analytical model for predicting the productivity of perforated wells&quot;, J Petrol Sci Eng. vol. 56 (2007) 199-218. 3. Hashemi S. M., Zamani E., Mahdian A., &quot;Numerical simulation and performance optimization of oil well perforator&quot;, Modares Mechanical Engineering, vol. 16, no. 3, (2016) 17-26 (in Persian) 4. Satti R., Betancourt D., Harvey W, Zuklic S, White R, Ochsner D, Sampson T, Myers W, Gilliat J, &quot;Beginning with the End in Mind: Shaped Charges Designed for Reservoir Conditions&quot;, Presented at the SPE Middle East Oil &amp; Gas Show and Conference, Manama, Kingdom of Bahrain (2017). 5. Karakas M., Tariq S. M., &quot;Semianalytical Productivity Models for Perforated Completions&quot;, SPE Production Engineering. vol. 6, no. 1, (1991) 73-82. 6. Bellarby J., &quot;Well completion design&quot;, Developments in Petroleum Science, vol. 56, Elsevier, Hungary (2009). 7. Harris M. H., &quot;The effect of perforating on well productivity,&quot; J Petrol Technol, vol. 18 (1966) 518-528. 8. Klotz J. A., Krueger F. F., Pye D. S., &quot;Effect of perforating damage on well productivity&quot;, J Petrol Technol, vol. 29, no. 2, (1974) 1303-1314. 9. Locke S., &quot;An Advanced Method for Predicting the Productivity Ratio of a Perforated Well&quot;, J Petrol Technol, vol. 33, (1981) 2481-2488. 10. Dogulu Y. S., &quot;Modeling of Well Productivity in Perforated Completions&quot;, Presented at the SPE Eastern Regional Meeting, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA, (1998). 11. Ansah J., Proett M. A., Soliman M. Y., &quot;Advances in Well Completion Design: A New 3D Finite-Element Wellbore Inflow Model for Optimizing Performance of Perforated Completions&quot;, Presented at the SPE International Symposium and Exhibition on Formation Damage Control, Lafayette, Louisiana (2002). 12. Jamiolahmady M., Danesh A., Sohrabi M., Ataei R., &quot;Gas condensate flow in perforated region&quot;, SPE Journal, vol. 12, no. 1, (2007) 89-99. 13. Byrne M., Jimenez M. A., Chavez J. C., &quot;Predicting Well Inflow Using Computational Fluid Dynamics-Closer to the Truth?&quot;, Presented at the SPE European Formation Damage Conference, Scheveningen, The Netherlands, (2009). 14. Sun D., Li B., Gladkikh M., Satti R., Evans R., &quot;Comparison of Skin Factors for Perforated Completions Calculated with Computational-Fluid-Dynamics Software and the Karakas-Tariq Semianalytical Model&quot;, SPE Drilling &amp; Completion, vol. 28, no, 1, (2013) 21-33. 15. Volonte G., Scarfato F., Brignoli M., &quot;sand prediction: a practical finite-element 3d approach for real field applications,&quot; SPE Production &amp; Operations, vol. 28, no. 1, (2013) 95-108. 16. Wang H., Cardiff P., Sharma M. M., A 3-d poro-elasto-plastic model for sand production around open-hole and cased &amp; perforated wellbores,&quot; Presented at the 50th US Rock Mechanics / Geomechanics Symposium, Houston, Texas, USA, (2016). 17. Segal G., Vuik K., Kassels K., &quot;On the implementation of symmetric and antisymmetric periodic boundary conditions for incompressible flow,&quot; Int. J. Numer. Meth. Fluids. vol. 18, (1994) 1153-1165. 18. Li S. &quot;On the nature of periodic traction boundary condition in micromechanical FE analyses of unit cells&quot;, IMA J. Appl. Math., vol. 77, (2012) 441-450. 19. Yildiz T., &quot;Productivity of Selectively Perforated Vertical Wells&quot;, Presented at the SPE International Oil and Gas Conference and Exhibition in China, Beijing, China, (2000). 20. Xia Z., Zhang Y., Ellyin F., &quot;A unified periodical boundary conditions for representative volume elements of composites and applications&quot;, Int J Solids Struct., vol. 40, (2003) 1907-1921. 21. Tyrus J. M., Gosz M., DeSantiago E., &quot;A local finite element implementation for imposing periodic boundary conditions on composite micromechanical models&quot;, Int J Solids Struct., vol. 44, (2007) 2972-2989. 22. Reddy J. N., &quot;An Introduction to the Finite Element Method&quot;, 3rd ed., Singapore. McGraw-Hill. (2006). 23. Zienkiewicz O. C., Taylor R. L., Zhu J. Z, &quot;The Finite Element Method: Its Basis and Fundamentals&quot;, 7th ed, UK, Elsevier Butterworth-Heinemann (2013). 24. Nguyen V.D., Bechet E., Geuzaine L., Noels L., &quot;Imposing periodic boundary condition on arbitrary meshes by polynomial interpolation&quot;, Electrical Engineering, vol. 55, (2011) 390-409. 25. Sandstom C., Larsson F., Runesson K., &quot;Weakly periodic boundary conditions for the homogenization of flow in porous media&quot;, Adv Model Simul Eng Sci., vol. 2, no. 12, (2014) 1-24. 26. Brooks J.E., &quot;A Simple Method for Estimating Well Productivity&quot;, Presented at the SPE European Formation Damage Conference, The Hague, The Netherlands, (1997). 27. Yildiz T., &quot;Assessment of Total Skin Factor in Perforated Wells&quot;, SPE Reservoir Evaluation &amp; Engineering, vol. 9. no. 1, (2006) 62-76. 28. Jamiolahmady M., Mahdiyar H., Ghahri P., Sohrabi M., &quot;A new method for productivity calculation of perforated wells in Gas condensate reservoirs&quot;, J Petrol Sci Eng, vol. 77, (2011) 263-273. 29. Dake L. P., &quot;Fundamentals of Reservoir ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تأثیر خرده لاستیک‌‌های بازیافتی بر رفتار حالت پایدار ماسه</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Influence of waste tire chips on steady state behavior of sand</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>موادی مانند خرده لاستیک&#8204;های زائد برای بهبود مقاومت خاک به&#8204;طور گسترده استفاده می&#8204;شود. در این تحقیق مقاومت باقی&#8204;مانده یا رفتار حالت پایدار ماسۀ مخلوط شده با خرده لاستیک&#8204;های زائد بررسی شده است. آزمایش&#8204;های سه&#8204;محوری فشاری زهکشی نشده استاتیکی روی نمونه&#8204;های دست&#8204;خورده ماسه و ماسۀ مخلوط با خرده لاستیک در حالت اشباع با درصدهای مختلف خرده لاستیک (صفرتا 4 تا درصد وزن خشک خاک) انجام شده است. تأثیر حضور خرده لاستیک زائد بر مقاومت باقی&#8204;مانده در فشار تحکیمی&#8204;های مختلف (100، 200 و 300 کیلو پاسکال) و تراکم نسبی مخلوط (40، 65 و 80 درصد) ارزیابی شده است. نتایج نشان می&#8204;دهد که با افزایش درصد خرده لاستیک مقاومت باقی&#8204;مانده افزایش یافته و خط حالت پایدار به&#8204;سمت راست نمودارlog Sus-e &#160;حرکت می&#8204;کند. هم&#8204;چنین بهبود مقاومت باقی&#8204;مانده در اثر حضور خرده لاستیک به تراکم نسبی نمونه و فشار تحکیمی نیز بستگی دارد.
&#160;
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Materials such as waste tire chips were widely used to improve the strength of soil. The objective of this study is to discuss the residual strength or steady-state behavior of sand-waste tire chip mixtures. A series of undrained monotonic triaxial compression tests were conducted on reconstituted saturated specimens of sand and sand-tire chip mixtures with variation in the tire-chip contents from 0 to 4 percentages by dry weight of soil. The specimens are prepared using dry deposition method of preparation. The influence on residual resistance of varying confining pressure (100, 200, and 300 kPa) and sand mixture relative density (40, 65, and 80%) were evaluated. Tests results showed that by increasing the tire chip contents, the residual strength increased and steady-state lines move to the right of log Sus-e diagram. Also, the residual resistance improvement induced by tire chip inclusions was found to be sensitive to the relative density of samples and applied confining pressure.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>189</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>212</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهری</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شریفی</Family>
				<NameE>Mehri</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Sharifi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه بین المللی امام خمینی (ره)، گروه مهندسی معدن</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه امام خمینی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Sharifi107@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مریم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>مفتاحی</Family>
				<NameE>maryam</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>meftahi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه بین المللی امام خمینی (ره)، گروه مهندسی معدن</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه امام خمینی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Maryam_meftahi19@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سید ابوالحسن</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>نائینی</Family>
				<NameE>Seyed Abolhasan</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Naeini</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه بین المللی امام خمینی (ره)، گروه مهندسی معدن</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه امام خمینی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Naeini.hasan@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Steady-state strength</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Waste tire chips</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>triaxial test</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Sand</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Relative density</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Confining pressure.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مقاومت حالت پایدار</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>خرده لاستیک زائد</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>آزمایش سه‌محوری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ماسه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دانسیتۀ نسبی و فشار تحکیمی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1. Edil T. B., Bosscher P. J., &quot;Engineering properties of tire chips and soil mixtures&quot;, Geotechnical Testing Journal Vol. 17(4) (1994) 453-464. 2. Foose G. J., Benson C. H., Bosscher P. J., &quot;Sand reinforced with shredded waste tires&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical Engineering Vol. 122(9) (1996) 760-767. 3. Tatlisoz N., Edil T., Benson C., &quot;Interaction between reinforcing geosynthetic and soil-tire chip mixtures&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering Vol. 124(11) (1998) 1109-19. 4. Youwai S., Bergado D. T., &quot;Strength and deformation characteristics of shredded rubber tire-sand mixtures&quot;, Canadian geotechnical journal Vol. 40(2) (2003) 254-264. 5. Edincliler A., Baykal G., Dengili K., &quot;Determination of static and dynamic behavior of recycled materials for highways&quot;, resources. Conserve Recycle Vol. 42: (2004) 223-337. 6. Edincliler A., &quot;Using waste tire-soil mixtures for embankment construction&quot;, In: Hazarika and Yasuhara (eds) Proceedings of the international workshop on scrap tire derived geomaterials-opportunities and challenges, Yokosuka, Japan, (2007) 319-328. 7. Zornberg J. G., Cabral A. R., Viratjandr C., &quot;Behavior of tire shred-sand mixtures&quot;, Canadian geotechnical journal Vol. 41 (2) (2004) 227-241. 8. Ghazavi M., Sakhi M. A., &quot;Influence of optimized tire shreds on shear strength parameters of sand&quot;, International Journal of Geomechanics Vol. 5(1) (2005) 58-65. 9. Rao G. V., Dutta R. K., &quot;Compressibility and strength behaviour of sand–tire chip mixtures&quot;, Geotechnical and Geological Engineering Vol. 24(3) (2006) 711-724. 10. Atom M. F., &quot;The use of shredded waste tires to improve the geotechnical engineering properties of sands&quot;, Environmental Geology Vol. 49(4) (2006) a, 497-503. 11. Kawata S., Hyodo M., Orense R. P., Hazarika H., &quot;Undrained and drained shear behavior of sand and tire chips composite material&quot;, International workshop on scrap tire derived geomaterials- opportunities and challenges, Taylor &amp; Francis Group, (2008) 277-284. 12. Cabalar A. F., &quot;Direct Shear Tests on Waste Tires-Sand Mixtures&quot;, Geotechnical and Geological Engineering, (2011) 1-8. 13. Baleshwar S., Valliapan V., &quot;Influence of Waste Tire Chips on Strength Characteristics of Soils&quot;, Journal of Civil Engineering and Architecture Vol. 5(9) (2011) 819-827. 14. Neaz Sheikh M., Mashiri M., Vinod J., Tsang H. H., &quot;Shear and Compressibility Behavior of Sand-Tire Crumb Mixtures&quot;, Journal of Materials in Civil Engineering Vol. 25(10) (2013) 1366-1374.	 15. Anvari M., Shooshpasha I., &quot;Fine-grained sand reinforced with granulated tire chips&quot;, Journal on Recent and Innovation Trends in Computing and Communication Vol.2 (9) (2014) 2879-2882. 16. Mashiri M. S., Vinod J. S., Sheikh M. N., Tsang H. H., &quot;Shear strength and dilatancy behaviour of sand-tire chip mixtures&quot;, Soils and Foundations Vol. 55(3) (2015) 517-528. 17. Takano D., Chevalier B., Otani J., &quot;Experimental and numerical simulation of shear behavior on sand and tire chips&quot;, 14th IACMAG International Conference (2015). 18. Ersizad A., Soltani-Jigheh H., Asadzadeh M., &quot;Mechanical behavior of clay mixed with tire chips&quot;, Journal of Ferdowsi Civil Engineering Vol. 26(2) (2015), http://www.Civilica.com. 19. Anbazhagan P., Manohar D. R., Rohit D., &quot;Influence of size of granulated rubber and tyre chips on the shear strength characteristics of sand-rubber mix&quot;, journal of Geomechanics and Geoengineering (2016) 1-13 . 20. Qafouri Amirbande S., Saba H. R., Nokandeh M., &quot;To study the effect of crumb size of worn tries in shear strength parameters of sandy soil&quot; Amirkabir Journal of Civil Engineering Accepted Manuscript , Available Online from 03 April (2017). 21. Tajdini M., Zartaj H., Taherkhani H., &quot;Investigating the effect of addition of industrial tire chips on physical and mechanical of Kaolinit clay materials &quot; Sharif Journal of Civil Engineering Accepted paper will be published on line on 22 September (2017).  22. Bosscher P. J., Edil T. B., Kuraoka S., &quot;Design of highway embankments using tire chips&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering Vol. 123(4) (1997) 295-304 23. Lee J. S., Dodds J., Santamarina J.C., &quot;Behavior of rigid-soft particle mixtures&quot;, Journal of Earthquake Engineering Vol. 19(2) (2007) 179-184. 24. Kim H. K., Santamarina J. C., &quot;Sand-rubber mixtures (large rubber chips)&quot;, Canadian Geotechnical Journal Vol. 45 (10) (2008) 1457-1457.  25. ASTM D4767-02, Standard Test Method for Consolidated Undrained Triaxial Compression Test for Soils. ASTM International, USA, (2002). ##1. Edil T. B., Bosscher P. J., &quot;Engineering properties of tire chips and soil mixtures&quot;, Geotechnical Testing Journal Vol. 17(4) (1994) 453-464. 2. Foose G. J., Benson C. H., Bosscher P. J., &quot;Sand reinforced with shredded waste tires&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical Engineering Vol. 122(9) (1996) 760-767. 3. Tatlisoz N., Edil T., Benson C., &quot;Interaction between reinforcing geosynthetic and soil-tire chip mixtures&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering Vol. 124(11) (1998) 1109-19. 4. Youwai S., Bergado D. T., &quot;Strength and deformation characteristics of shredded rubber tire-sand mixtures&quot;, Canadian geotechnical journal Vol. 40(2) (2003) 254-264. 5. Edincliler A., Baykal G., Dengili K., &quot;Determination of static and dynamic behavior of recycled materials for highways&quot;, resources. Conserve Recycle Vol. 42: (2004) 223-337. 6. Edincliler A., &quot;Using waste tire-soil mixtures for embankment construction&quot;, In: Hazarika and Yasuhara (eds) Proceedings of the international workshop on scrap tire derived geomaterials-opportunities and challenges, Yokosuka, Japan, (2007) 319-328. 7. Zornberg J. G., Cabral A. R., Viratjandr C., &quot;Behavior of tire shred-sand mixtures&quot;, Canadian geotechnical journal Vol. 41 (2) (2004) 227-241. 8. Ghazavi M., Sakhi M. A., &quot;Influence of optimized tire shreds on shear strength parameters of sand&quot;, International Journal of Geomechanics Vol. 5(1) (2005) 58-65. 9. Rao G. V., Dutta R. K., &quot;Compressibility and strength behaviour of sand–tire chip mixtures&quot;, Geotechnical and Geological Engineering Vol. 24(3) (2006) 711-724. 10. Atom M. F., &quot;The use of shredded waste tires to improve the geotechnical engineering properties of sands&quot;, Environmental Geology Vol. 49(4) (2006) a, 497-503. 11. Kawata S., Hyodo M., Orense R. P., Hazarika H., &quot;Undrained and drained shear behavior of sand and tire chips composite material&quot;, International workshop on scrap tire derived geomaterials- opportunities and challenges, Taylor &amp; Francis Group, (2008) 277-284. 12. Cabalar A. F., &quot;Direct Shear Tests on Waste Tires-Sand Mixtures&quot;, Geotechnical and Geological Engineering, (2011) 1-8. 13. Baleshwar S., Valliapan V., &quot;Influence of Waste Tire Chips on Strength Characteristics of Soils&quot;, Journal of Civil Engineering and Architecture Vol. 5(9) (2011) 819-827. 14. Neaz Sheikh M., Mashiri M., Vinod J., Tsang H. H., &quot;Shear and Compressibility Behavior of Sand-Tire Crumb Mixtures&quot;, Journal of Materials in Civil Engineering Vol. 25(10) (2013) 1366-1374.	 15. Anvari M., Shooshpasha I., &quot;Fine-grained sand reinforced with granulated tire chips&quot;, Journal on Recent and Innovation Trends in Computing and Communication Vol.2 (9) (2014) 2879-2882. 16. Mashiri M. S., Vinod J. S., Sheikh M. N., Tsang H. H., &quot;Shear strength and dilatancy behaviour of sand-tire chip mixtures&quot;, Soils and Foundations Vol. 55(3) (2015) 517-528. 17. Takano D., Chevalier B., Otani J., &quot;Experimental and numerical simulation of shear behavior on sand and tire chips&quot;, 14th IACMAG International Conference (2015). 18. Ersizad A., Soltani-Jigheh H., Asadzadeh M., &quot;Mechanical behavior of clay mixed with tire chips&quot;, Journal of Ferdowsi Civil Engineering Vol. 26(2) (2015), http://www.Civilica.com. 19. Anbazhagan P., Manohar D. R., Rohit D., &quot;Influence of size of granulated rubber and tyre chips on the shear strength characteristics of sand-rubber mix&quot;, journal of Geomechanics and Geoengineering (2016) 1-13 . 20. Qafouri Amirbande S., Saba H. R., Nokandeh M., &quot;To study the effect of crumb size of worn tries in shear strength parameters of sandy soil&quot; Amirkabir Journal of Civil Engineering Accepted Manuscript , Available Online from 03 April (2017). 21. Tajdini M., Zartaj H., Taherkhani H., &quot;Investigating the effect of addition of industrial tire chips on physical and mechanical of Kaolinit clay materials &quot; Sharif Journal of Civil Engineering Accepted paper will be published on line on 22 September (2017).  22. Bosscher P. J., Edil T. B., Kuraoka S., &quot;Design of highway embankments using tire chips&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering Vol. 123(4) (1997) 295-304 23. Lee J. S., Dodds J., Santamarina J.C., &quot;Behavior of rigid-soft particle mixtures&quot;, Journal of Earthquake Engineering Vol. 19(2) (2007) 179-184. 24. Kim H. K., Santamarina J. C., &quot;Sand-rubber mixtures (large rubber chips)&quot;, Canadian Geotechnical Journal Vol. 45 (10) (2008) 1457-1457.  25. ASTM D4767-02, Standard Test Method for Consolidated Undrained Triaxial Compression Test for Soils. ASTM International, USA, (2002).  ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>

</ARTICLES>

</JOURNAL>
</XML>
