<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1399</YEAR>
<VOL>14</VOL>
<NO>3</NO>
<MOSALSAL>45</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>0</PAGE_NO>


<ARTICLES>

	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی تاثیر  نحوه کابرد ژئوتکستایل بر بهسازی توانایی باربری خاکهای مخلوط رس- شن در لایه های روسازی</TitleF>
		<TitleE></TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>استفاده از ژئوتکستایل در بسیاری از کاربردهای مهندسی و روسازی راه یک روش موثر در اصلاح خاک به شمار می&#173;آید. اضافه شدن رس یا سیلت به ماسه در درصدهای مختلف می&#173;تواند بطور اساسی رفتار ماتریس ماسه و رس را تغییر دهد. هدف اصلی از تحقیق حاضر، بررسی آزمایشگاهی تاثیر نحوه کاربرد ژئوتکستایل در میزان توانایی باربری خاکهای مخلوط رسی و شنی منطقه ی باراندوز جهت کاربرد در لایه های روسازی راه می باشد. &#160;در این مطالعه خاک رسی مورد استفاده با خاک شنی با درصدهای (25، 50 و 75)&#160; مخلوط گردیده است. تاثیر ژئوتکستایل در دو حالت مطالعه گردید: در حالت اول لایه ای ( یک لایه، دولایه و سه لایه در نمونه جایگذاری شده است) و در حالت دوم، ژئوتکستایل به صورت قطعاتی با ابعاد &#160;1&#215;1 و 5&#215;5 سانتیمتر مربع بصورت راندم با با درصد های وزنی 1، 2 و 3 درصد با مصالح مخلوط گردیده و رفتار مصالح مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفته است. جهت انجام تحقیق از آزمون&#173; آزمایشگاهی نسبت باربری کالیفرنیا(CBR) هر دو حالت خشک و اشباع براساس استاندارد ASTM &#160;بهره گرفته شده و&#160; میزان درصد تورم در خاک های ریزدانه اشباع اندازه &#173;گیری شده است. نتایج حاصل از تحقیق نشان میدهد که میزان بهینه ژئوتکستایل مورد نیاز جهت مسلح نمودن مصالح مورد مطالعه بصورت قراردادن 1 لایه در قسمت میانی و یا افزودن 1% وزنی ژئوتکستایل به ابعاد1&#215;1&#160; سانتیمتر مربع میباشد که این میزان در شرایطی که خاک اشباع باشد به طور قابل ملاحظه ای از میزان تورم می کاهد و از آن جلوگیری می نماید.هدف اصلی از تحقیق حاضر، بررسی آزمایشگاهی تاثیر نحوه کاربرد ژئوتکستایل در میزان توانایی باربری خاکهای مخلوط رسی و شنی منطقه&#173;ی باراندوز جهت کاربرد در لایه&#173;های روسازی راه می&#173;باشد. &#160;دراین مطالعه خاک رسی مورد استفاده با خاک شنی با درصدهای (25، 50 و 75)&#160; مخلوط گردیده است. تاثیر ژئوتکستایل در دو حالت مطالعه گردید: درحالت اول بصورت لایه&#173;ای (یک لایه، دولایه و سه لایه در نمونه جایگذاری شده است) و درحالت دوم، ژئوتکستایل به صورت قطعاتی با ابعاد &#160;1&#215;1 و 5&#215;5 سانتیمتر مربع بصورت راندم با درصد های وزنی 1، 2 و 3 درصد با مصالح مخلوط گردیده و رفتار مصالح مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفته است. جهت انجام تحقیق از آزمون&#173; آزمایشگاهی نسبت باربری کالیفرنیا(CBR) هر دو حالت خشک و اشباع براساس استاندارد ASTM D1883 &#160;بهره گرفته شده است. بگونه&#173;ای که طبق استاندارد سرعت بارگذاری mm/min &#160;27/1 انتخاب شده و عدد CBR برای نفوذ پیستون به میزان 5/2 و 5 سانتیمتر برآورد گردیده است. درحالت اشباع میزان درصد تورم در نمونه&#173;ها اندازه &#173;گیری شده است. نتایج حاصل از تحقیق نشان می&#173;دهد که میزان بهینه ژئوتکستایل مورد نیاز جهت مسلح نمودن مصالح مورد مطالعه بصورت قراردادن 1 لایه در قسمت میانی و یا افزودن 1% وزنی ژئوتکستایل به ابعاد1&#215;1&#160; سانتیمتر مربع می&#173;باشد که این میزان در شرایطی که خاک اشباع باشد به طور قابل ملاحظه&#173;ای از میزان تورم می&#173;کاهد و از آن جلوگیری می&#173;نماید.[H1]&#160;




&#160;[H1]طبق نظر داور محترم شماره 1، چکیده اصلاح گردید.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>0</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>0</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سمانه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>قاسم وش اخیر</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>گروه زمین شناسی مهندسی، واحد اهر، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، اهر، ایران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>samaneh.ghasemvash@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>روزیه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>دبیری</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>گروه مهندسی عمران، واحد تبریز، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی ، تبریز،ایران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>rouzbeh_dabiri@iaut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>روسازی راه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ژئوتکستایل</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>آزمایشCBR</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تورم</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مخلوط رس و شن.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##[7]- Shahie, J., Ameri, M. and Khani Sanij, H  “Evaluate the Effect of Geotextile on Life Fatigue of Pavement Asphalt in Iran”, Journal of Transportation Engineering, 2, (2010) 41-51. (In Persian) ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تعیین تنش‌های برجا، شناسایی و تحلیل شکستگی‌ها و گسل‌ها برای تزریق  CO2 جهت ازدیاد برداشت نفت در میدان نفتی گچساران</TitleF>
		<TitleE></TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>تزریق CO2 در سازندهای زمین&#173;شناسی، مانند مخازن تخلیه شده نفت و گاز یکی از روش&#173;های موثر برای ازدیاد برداشت نفت به عنوان ازدیاد برداشت ثالثیه است. همچنین، به عنوان یک روش کاهش انتشار گاز CO2 در نظر گرفته می&#173;شود. در جنوب غرب ایران پتانسیل عظیمی برای ازدیاد برداشت به روش تزریق CO2 و ذخیره&#173;سازی آن در مخازن مخازن تخلیه شده کربناته وجود دارد. در اولین قدم، برای انجام یک پروژه تزریق CO2 یک ارزیابی از وضعیت فشار منفذی مخزن، مقادیر و جهت&#173;گیری تنش&#173;های برجا و وضعیت شکستگی&#173;ها و گسل&#173;ها مورد نیاز است. در این مطالعه، ابتدا فشار منفذی بر اساس روش ایتون تغییر یافته[1] برای 47 چاه برآورد و با داده&#173;های RFT و فشار گل اعتبار سنجی شد. مقادیر تنش&#173;های برجا برای 47 چاه در طول میدان گچساران، با استفاده از روابط پوروالاستیک، تخمین زده و با استفاده از داده&#173;های LOT و XLOT اعتبارسنجی شد. سپس جهت&#173;گیری تنش&#173;های برجای افقی و شکستگی&#173;ها بر استفاده لاگ&#173;های تصویری مورد مطالعه قرار گرفت. رژیم تنش در میدان مورد مطالعه نرمال تعیین شد. در نهایت با استفاده تئوری گسل در حالت تنش بحرانی وضعیت شکستگی&#173;ها و گسل&#173;ها از نطر فعالیت هیدرولیکی و مکانیکی مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفت. در این بررسی گسل&#173;های شماره 15، 6، 10 و 2 به ترتیب مستعدترین گسل&#173;ها برای فعالیت مجدد در طی تزریق CO2 بودند.&#160; 
&#160;

[1] . Modified Eaton</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>0</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>0</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمدکاظم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>امیری</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه فردوسی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>amirimk67@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>غلامرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>لشکری پور</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه فردوسی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>lashkaripour@um.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سیاوش</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>قابزلو</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>2Université Paris-Est, Laboratoire Navier-CERMES, Ecole des Ponts ParisTech, Marne la Vallée, France</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>siavash.ghabezloo@enpc.fr</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>ناصر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>حافظی مقدس</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه فردوسی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>nhafezi@um.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مجتبی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>حیدری تجره</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>شرکت ملی مناطق نفت خیز جنوب</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>heidari61@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تزریق CO2</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>فشار منفذی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تنش‌های برجا</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تحلیل شکستگی‌ها و گسل‌ها</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تئوری گسل در حالت تنش بحرانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##1.	Bachu, S., &amp;quot;Sequestration of CO2 in geological media: criteria and approach for site selection in response to climate change&amp;quot;, Energy Convers Mgmt, 41(9) (2000) 953–970.##2.	Preston, BL., Jones, RN., &amp;quot;Climate change impacts on Australia and the benefits of early action to reduce global greenhouse gas emissions&amp;quot;, Climate Change Impacts on Australia, CSIRO (2006), Available at: http://csiro.au/files/files/ p6fy.pdf.##3.	Herzog, H., Drake, E., Adams, E., &amp;quot;CO2 Capture, Reuse, and Storage Technologies for Mitigating Global Climate Change: A White Paper&amp;quot;, Energy Laboratory, Massachusetts Institute of Technology (1997).##4.	Bachu, S., &amp;quot;Screening and ranking of sedimentary basins for sequestration of CO2 in geological media in response to climate change&amp;quot;, Environ. Geol. 44 (2003),277–289, http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00254-003-0762-9.##5.	Lackner, K., &amp;quot;A guide to CO2 sequestration&amp;quot;, Science 300 (2003) 1677–1678, http://dx.doi.org/10.1126/science.1079033.##6.	Qi, D., Zhang, S., Su, K., &amp;quot;Risk assessment of CO2 geological storage and the calculation of storage capacity&amp;quot;, Petrol. Sci. Technol. 28 (2010) 979-986.##7.	Nordbotten, JM., Celia, MA., &amp;quot;Geological storage of CO2: modeling approaches for large-scale simulation&amp;quot;, John Wiley &amp; Sons (2011).##8.	Bai, M., &amp;quot;Risk assessment for CO2 leakage along abandoned wells using a Monte Carlo simulation in a CO2 sequestration site&amp;quot;, Petrol. Sci. Technol. 32 (2014) 1191-1200.##9.	Bachu, S., &amp;quot;Identification of oil reservoirs suitable for CO2-EOR and CO2 storage(CCUS) using reserves databases, with application to Alberta, Canada&amp;quot;, Int. J. Greenh. Gas Control 44 (2015) 152-165. ##10.	Thomas, S., &amp;quot;Enhanced oil recovery an overview&amp;quot;, Oil Gas Sci. Technol. 63 (2008) 9–19, http://dx.doi.org/10.2516/ogst:2007060.##11.	Lake, L., 2010. Enhanced Oil Recovery. Society of Petroleum Engineers (2010).##12.	Alam, M.M., Hjuler, M.L., Christensen, H.F. and Fabricius, I.L., &amp;quot;Petrophysical and rock-mechanics effects of CO 2 injection for enhanced oil recovery: Experimental study on chalk from South Arne field, North Sea&amp;quot;, Journal of Petroleum Science and Engineering 122 (2014) 468-487.##13.	Seyyedsar, S.M., Farzaneh, S.A. and Sohrabi, M., &amp;quot;Experimental investigation of tertiary CO2 injection for enhanced heavy oil recovery&amp;quot;, Journal of Natural Gas Science and Engineering 34 (2016) 1205-1214.##14.	Kumar, S. and Mandal, A., &amp;quot;A comprehensive review on chemically enhanced water alternating gas/CO2 (CEWAG) injection for enhanced oil recovery&amp;quot;, Journal of Petroleum Science and Engineering 157 (2017) 696-715.##15.	Burck, J., Marten, F., Bals, Ch., &amp;quot;The Climate Change Performance Index&amp;quot;, Results 2016, (2016) 9-29 , This publication can be downloaded at: www.germanwatch.org/en/ccpi.##16.	Iran, Oil.  &amp;quot;Country Analysis Briefs. US Energy Information Administration (EIA)&amp;quot;, 2015.##17.	Shukla, R., Ranjith, P.G., Choi, S.K., Haque, A., &amp;quot;Study of caprock integrity in geosequestration of carbon dioxide&amp;quot;, Int. J. Geomech. 11 (2011) 294-301.##18.	Colucci, F., Guandalini, R., Macini, P., Mesini, E., Moia, F. and Savoca, D., &amp;quot;A feasibility study for CO2 geological storage in Northern Italy&amp;quot;, International Journal of Greenhouse Gas Control 55 (2016) 1-14.##19.	Keatinga, E., Baconb, D., Carrollc, S., Mansoorc, Sunc, Y., Zhengd, L., Harpa, D., Dai, Zh., &amp;quot;Applicability of aquifer impact models to support decisions at CO2 sequestration sites&amp;quot;, Int. J. Greenh. Gas Control 52 (2016) 319–330.##20.	Plumb, R.A., Edwards, S., Pidcock, G., Lee, D., &amp;quot;The mechanical earth model and its application to high-risk well construction projects&amp;quot;, In: Proceedings of the SPE/IADC Drilling Conference New Orleans, Paper SPE 59128 (2000).##21.	Ringrose, PS., Mathieson, AS., Wright, IW., Selama, F., Hansen, O., Bissell, R., Saoula, N., Midgley, J., &amp;quot;The In Salah CO2 storage project: lessons learned and knowledge transfer&amp;quot;, Energy Procedia 37 (2013) 6226-36.##22.	Rutqvist, J., Cappa, F., Rinaldi, AP., Godano, M., &amp;quot;Modeling of induced seismicity and ground vibrations associated with geologic CO2 storage, and assessing their effects on surface structures and human perception&amp;quot;, Int. J. Greenh. Gas Control 24(2014) 64-77.##23.	Barton, C.A., Zoback, M.D. and Moos, D., &amp;quot;Fluid flow along potentially active faults in crystalline rock&amp;quot;, Geology 23(8) (1995) 683-686.##24.	Eaton, B.A., &amp;quot;The equation for geopressure prediction from well logs&amp;quot;, Society of Petroleum Engineers of AIME. Paper SPE 5544 (1975).##25.	Bordenave, M.L. and Hegre, J.A., &amp;quot;Current distribution of oil and gas fields in the Zagros Fold Belt of Iran and contiguous offshore as the result of the petroleum systems&amp;quot;, Geological Society, London, Special Publications 330(1) (2010) 291-353.##26.	Bordenave, M.L., Hegre, J.A., &amp;quot;The influence of tectonics on the entrapment of oil in the Dezful Embayment, Zagros Fold belt&amp;quot;, Iran. Journal of petroleum Geology 28(4) (2005) 339-368.##27.	Salati, S., van Ruitenbeek, F.J., Carranza, E.J.M., van der Meer, F.D. and Tangestani, M.H., &amp;quot;Conceptual modeling of onshore hydrocarbon seep occurrence in the Dezful Embayment, SW Iran&amp;quot;, Marine and petroleum geology 43 (2013) 102-120.##28.	Setudehnia, A., &amp;quot;Iran du sud-ouest. Lexique Stratigraphique International III, Fascicule 9b&amp;quot;, Center National de la, Iran (1972).##29.	Alsharhan, A.S., Nairn, A.E.M., &amp;quot;Sedimentary Basins and Petroleum Geology of the Middle East&amp;quot;, first ed. Elsevier, Amsterdam (1997).##30.	Azadpour, M, Shad Manaman, N., &amp;quot;Determination of Pore Pressure from Sonic Log: a Case Study on One of Iran Carbonate Reservoir Rocks&amp;quot;, Iranian Journal of Oil &amp; Gas Science and Technology 4(3) (2015) 37-50.##31.	Zoback, M.D., Barton, C.A., Brudy, M., Castillo, D.A., Finkbeiner, T., Grollimund, B.R., Moos, D.B., Peska, P., Ward, C.D., Wiprut, D.J., &amp;quot;Determination of stress orientation and magnitude in deep wells&amp;quot;, Int. J. Rock. Mech. Min. Sci. 40(7–8) (2003) 1049–1076.##32.	Zang, A., Stephansson, O., &amp;quot;Stress field of the Earth’s crust&amp;quot;, Springer Science &amp; Business Media (2010).##33.	Ostadhassan, M., Zeng, Z., Zamiran, S., &amp;quot;Geomechanical modeling of an anisotropic formation-Bakken case study&amp;quot;, 46th US Rock Mechanics/Geomechanics Symposium. American Rock Mechanics Association (2012).##34.	Higgins, S.M., Goodwin, S.A., Bratton, T.R. and Tracy, G.W., &amp;quot;Anisotropic stress models improve completion design in the Baxter Shale&amp;quot;, In SPE Annual Technical Conference and Exhibition. Society of Petroleum Engineers. Denver, 21-24 September, SPE 115736 (2008). ##35.	Heidbach, O., Rajabi, M., Reiter, K., Ziegler, M., WSM Team: &amp;quot;World Stress Map Database Release 2016&amp;quot; (2016), GFZ Data Services, doi:10.5880/WSM.2016.001.##36.	Thiercelin, M.J. and R.A. Plumb, &amp;quot;Core based predictions of lithologic stress contrasts in east Texas formations&amp;quot;, J. SPE Formation Evaluation. 9(14) (1994) 251-258.##37.	Kidambi, T., Kumar S.G., &amp;quot;Mechanical Earth Modeling for a vertical well drilled in a naturally fractured tight carbonate gas reservoir in the Persian Gulf&amp;quot;, Journal of Petroleum Science and Engineering 141 (2016) 38–51.##38.	Sepehr, M., Cosgrove, J.W., &amp;quot;Role of the Kazerun Fault Zone in the formation and deformation of the Zagros Fold‐Thrust Belt, Iran&amp;quot;, Tectonics, 24(5) (2005) 1-15.##39.	Jarahi, H., Naraghiaraghi, N., Nadalian, M., &amp;quot;Persian Gulf Fault: new seismotectonic element on seabed&amp;quot;, Can J Basic Appl Sci, 3(3) (2015) 85-92.##40.	Kingdon, A., Fellgett, M.W., Williams, J.D.O., &amp;quot;Use of borehole imaging to improve understanding of the in-situ stress orientation of Central and Northern England and its implications for unconventional hydrocarbon resources&amp;quot; Mar. Pet. Geol. 73 (2016) 1–20. ##41.	Zoback, Mark D. &amp;quot;Reservoir geomechanics&amp;quot;, Cambridge University Press, 2010.##42.	Movahed, Z., Junin, R., Bakhtiari, H.A., Safarkhanlou, Z., Movahed, A.A. and Alizadeh, M., &amp;quot;Introduction of sealing fault in Asmari reservoir by using FMI and RFT in one of the Iranian naturally fractured oil fields&amp;quot;, Arabian Journal of Geosciences 8(12) (2015)10919-10936.##43.	نریمانی، ح. ، &amp;quot;تحلیل هندسی- جنبشی چین‌های ناحیه دو گنبدان؛ زاگرس چین‌خورده-رانده&amp;quot;، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، رشته زمین‌ شناسی گرایش تکتونیک، دانشکده علوم پایه، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس تهران، .1388 ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>اثر کیفیت مایع مستغرق‌کننده بر خواص یک خاک متورم‌شونده در چرخه های های تر و خشک</TitleF>
		<TitleE></TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>در این کار پژوهشی اثر مایع&#173; های مستغرق&#8204;کننده آب مقطر و محلول&#8204;های حاوی غلظت&#8204;های 10 و 20 درصد گلیسرول بر خواص تورمی یک خاک متورم&#8204;شونده تحت سربار ثابت، با اجرای چرخه&#8204;های تر و خشک مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. نمونه&#8204;های خاک متراکم شده به روش تراکم استاتیکی تهیه شد. چرخه&#8204;های تر و خشک با استغراق نمونه&#8204;ها با آب مقطر و محلول&#8204;های 10 و 20 درصد گلیسرول در دستگاه تحکیم اصلاح&#173;شده تحت سربار 10 کیلوپاسکال صورت پذیرفت. نتایج بدست آمده نشان می&#8204;دهد استفاده از محلول&#8204;های گلیسرول باعث کاهش تعداد چرخه&#8204;ها و رسیدن به حالت تعادل در زمان کوتاهتر در مقایسه با آب مقطر می&#8204;شود به&#8204;طوری&#173;که این روند به غلظت گلیسرول بستگی دارد. نتایج تغییرات نسبت تخلخل در مقابل درصد رطوبت، بیانگر به تعادل رسیدن پدیده پسماند با افزایش تعداد چرخه&#8204;ها می&#8204;باشد. مسیرهای تورمی-انقباضی عموماً به شکل S بوده و بیشترین تغییرشکل خاک بین خطوط اشباع 40 و 80 درصد رخ می&#8204;دهد</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>0</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>0</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مسلم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>بابائی</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>babaei.m@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رئیسی استبرق</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>raessi@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>جمال</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>عبدالهی</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>jaabaik@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محدثه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>امینی کلهرودی</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>amini.mohadeseh@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>وکیلی</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>ghvakili5@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>خاک‌های متورم‌شونده</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>گلیسرول</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>چرخه‌های تر و خشک</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مسیرهای تورمی-انقباضی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سربار</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##1. Gourley, C. S., Newill, D., &amp; Schreiner, H. D. (1993, July). Expansive soils: TRL’s research strategy. In Proc., 1st Int. Symp. on Engineering Characteristics of Arid Soils.##2. Jones, D.E., Jones, K.A., 1987. Treating expansive soils. Civil Engineering 57 (8), 62–65.##3. Driscol, R., &amp; Crilly, M. (2000). Subsidence damage to domestic building. Lessons learned and questions remaining. London: Foundation for the Built Environment Report, Construction##Communication.##4. Hanafy, E.A.D.E., 1991. Swelling/shrinkage chatracteristic curve of desiccated expansive lays. Geotechnical Testing Journal 14 (2), 206–211.##5. Fredlund, D.G., Rahardjo, H., 1993. Soil Mechanics for Unsaturated Soils John Wiley &amp; Sons, New York, USA.##6. Marinho, F.A.M., Stuermer, M., 2000. The influence of the compaction energy on the SWCC of a residual soil, Advances in Unsaturated Geotechnics.Geotechnical Special Publication, ASCE, Colorado, Denver, USA,125–141.##7. Ferber, V., Auriol, J.C., Cui, Y.J., Magnan, J.P., 2009. On the swelling potential of compacted high plasticity clays. Engineering Geology 104,200–210.##8. Estabragh, A. R., Rafatjo, H., &amp; Javadi, A. A. 2014. Treatment of an expansive soil by mechanical and chemical techniques. Geosynthetics International, 21(3), 233-243.##9. Rao, K.S.,Satyadas, G.C., 1987. Swelling potential with cycles of swelling and partial shrinkage. In: Proceedings 6th Conference on Expansive Soils,New Delhi, India, vol. 1, pp. 137–147.##10. Chen, F.H., 1988. Foundation on Expansive Soils, 2nd ed. Elsevier Science Publishing Co., New York, USA.##11. Dif, A.F., Blumel, W.F., 1991. Expansive soils under cyclic drying and wetting. Geotechnical Testing Journal 14 (1), 96–102.##12. Tripathy, S., Subba Rao, K.S., Fredlund, D.G., 2002. Water content-void ratio swell-shrink paths of compacted expansive soils. Canadian Geotechnical Journal 39, 938–959.##13. Siddiqua, S., Blatz, J., &amp; Siemens, G. (2011). Evaluation of the impact of pore fluid chemistry on the hydromechanical behaviour of clay-based sealing materials. Canadian Geotechnical Journal, 48(2), 199-213.##14. Estabragh, A. R., Parsaei, B., &amp; Javadi, A. A. (2015). Laboratory investigation of the effect of cyclic wetting and drying on the behaviour of an expansive soil. Soils and Foundations, 55(2), 304-314.##15. Zhao, N. F., Ye, W. M., Chen, Y. G., Chen, B., &amp; Cui, Y. J. (2017). Investigation on swelling-shrinkage behavior of unsaturated compacted GMZ bentonite on wetting-drying cycles. Bulletin of Engineering Geology and the Environment, 1-11.##16. Estabragh, A. R., Soltani, A., &amp; Javadi, A. A. (2018). Effect of pore water chemistry on the behaviour of a kaolin–bentonite mixture during drying and wetting cycles. European Journal of Environmental and Civil Engineering, 1-20.##17. Chen, J., Anandarajah, A., and Inyang, H. (2000). Pore fluid properties and compressibility of kaolinite.Journal of geotechnical and geoenvironmental engineering, 126(9), 798-807.##18. Kaya, A. and Fang, H. Y. (2000). The effects of organic fluids on physicochemical parameters of fine-grained soils. Canadian Geotechnical Journal, 37(5), 943-950.##19. Graham, J., Yuen, K., Goh, T. B., Janzen, P., and Sivakumar, V. (2001). Hydraulic conductivity and pore fluid chemistry in artificially weathered plastic clay. Engineering geology, 60(1), 69-81.##20. Singh, S. K., Srivastava, R. K., and John, S. (2008). Settlement characteristics of clayey oils##contaminated with petroleum hydrocarbons. Soil &amp; sediment contamination, 17(3), 290-300.##21. Di Matteo, L., Bigotti, F., and Ricco, R. (2010). Compressibility of kaolinitic clay contaminated by ethanol-gasoline blends. Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental##Engineering, 137(9), 846-849##22. Singh, S. K., Srivastava, R. K., &amp; John, S. (2009). Studies on soil contamination due to used##motor oil and its remediation. Canadian Geotechnical Journal, 46, 1077–1083.##23. Estabragh, A. R., Beytolahpour, I., Moradi, M., &amp; Javadi, A. A. (2016). Mechanical behavior of a clay soil contaminated with glycerol and ethanol. European Journal of Environmental and Civil Engineering, 20(5), 503-519.##24.Estabragh, A. R., Moghadas, M., &amp; Javadi, A. A. (2016). Hydrochemical Effect of Different Quality of Water on the Behaviour of an Expansive Soil During Wetting and Drying Cycles. Irrigation and Drainage, 65(3), 371-381.##25. Rosenbalm, D., &amp; Zapata, C. E. (2016). Effect of wetting and drying cycles on the behavior of compacted expansive soils. Journal of Materials in Civil Engineering, 29(1), 04016191.##26. McKeen, R. G. (1992, August). A model for predicting expansive soil behavior. In Proc., 7th Int. Conf. on Expansive Soils (Vol. 1, pp. 1-6). Reston, VA: ASCE.##27. Nelson, J. D., &amp; Miller, D. J. 1992. Expansive soils: problems and practices in foundation and pavement engineering. John Wiley &amp; Sons Inc.##28. Lambe, T. W. 1958. The structure of compacted clay. Journal of the Soil Mechanics and##Foundations Division, ASCE, 84: 1-34.##29. Dineen, K., &amp; Ridley, A. M. (1999, August). The soil moisture characteristic curve. The influence of hysteresis on its measurement and interpretation. In Proceedings of the XI Pan-American conference on soil mechnics and foundation engineering. 1013 (Vol. 1018). ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>انتخاب مته حفاری بهینه با استفاده از الگوریتم‌های داده‌کاوی-مطالعه موردی</TitleF>
		<TitleE></TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>انتخاب بهترین مته در شرایط پیچیده حفاری متناظر بـا آن، یکی از مهم&#8204;ترین موضوعاتی است که در حوزه حفاری وجود دارد. زیرا با وجود این که قیمت مته 2 تا 3 درصد هزینه&#8204;های تکمیل یک چاه را در بر می&#8204;گیرد، اما بر 75درصد هزینه&#8204;های کلـی حفـاری بطور غیرمستقیم تاثیرگذار است. در این تحقیق به مدلسازی انتخاب مته حفاری بهینه با استفاده از چاه&#8204;نمودارهای (لاگ) مختلف 7 چاه نفتی موجود در منطقه&#8204;ای در ترکیه پرداخته شد. برای مدلسازی از روش&#8204;های داده&#8204;کاوی شامل درخت تصمیم، قوانین انجمنی، احتمال بیز، مبتنی بر تشابه و سیستم استنتاجی نروفازی تطبیقی استفاده شد. بدین ترتیب که از داده&#8204;های شش چاه به عنوان آموزش مدل&#8204;ها و داده&#8204;های یک چاه دیگر را به عنوان داده&#8204;های آزمون جهت ارزیابی صحت و دقت مدل&#8204;ها مورد استفاده قرار گرفت. در نهایت نتایج مدل&#8204;های مختلف در کنار یکدیگر مقایسه و تحلیل شد. نتایج نشان داد مدل ایجاد شده توسط سیستم استنتاجی نروفازی تطبیقی با اختلاف معنا&#8204;داری از مدل&#8204;های ایجاد شده توسط سایر روش&#8204;ها کاراتر و دقیق&#8204;تر است. اما این بدین معنی نیست که سایر روش&#8204;ها کارا نیستند بلکه تحلیل نتایج نشان می&#8204;دهد دیگر روش&#8204;ها نیز می&#8204;توانند مدلی هرچند در کیفیتی پایین&#8204;تر از مدل سیستم استنتاجی نروفازی تطبیقی اما سودمند و قابل اعتماد ایجاد کنند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>0</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>0</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>هادی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>فتاحی</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی اراک-دانشکده مهندسی علوم زمین</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>h.fattahi@arakut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>یونس</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>افشاری</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی اراک-دانشکده مهندسی علوم زمین</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>iron.azar@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>انتخاب مته حفاری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>چاه‌نمودارهای (لاگ) مختلف</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سیستم استنتاجی نروفازی تطبیقی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>درخت تصمیم</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>قوانین انجمنی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>احتمال بیز</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مبتنی بر تشابه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##1. Bilgesu H, Al-Rashidi A, Aminian K, Ameri S An Unconventional Approach for Drill-Bit Selection. In: SPE Middle East Oil Show, 2001. Society of Petroleum Engineers, ##2. Perrin V, Mensa-Wilmot G, Alexander W Drilling index-a new approach to bit performance evaluation. In: SPE/IADC drilling conference, 1997. Society of Petroleum Engineers, ##3. Suba S, Christopher T (2012) A study on milestones of association rule mining algorithms in large databases. International Journal of Computer Applications (0975–888) 47 (3)##4. Uboldi V, Civolani L, Zausa F Rock strength measurements on cuttings as input data for optimizing drill bit selection. In: SPE Annual Technical Conference and Exhibition, 1999. Society of Petroleum Engineers, ##5. Clegg JM, Barton SP Improved Optimisation of Bit Selection Using Mathematically Modelled Bit Performance Indices. In: IADC/SPE Asia Pacific Drilling Technology Conference and Exhibition, 2006. Society of Petroleum Engineers, ##6. Thomas J Case History: PC Analysis of Bit Records Enhances Drilling Operations in Southern Alabama. In: SPE/IADC Drilling Conference, 1989. Society of Petroleum Engineers, ##7. Adam T, Millheim K, Chenevert M, Young F (1991) Applied drilling engineering. SPE Textbook Series, Dallas, TX 2##8. Bourgoyne Jr A, Millheim K, Chenevert M, Young Jr F (1991) Applied Drilling Engineering, SPE Textbook Series Vol. 2, Second Printing, 152-155. Society of Petroleum Engineers##9. Teale R The concept of specific energy in rock drilling. In: Int J Rock Mech Min Sci, 1965. vol 1. Elsevier, pp 57-73##10. Mason KL (1987) Three-cone bit selection with sonic logs. SPE Drilling Engineering 2 (02):135-142##11. Dumans CFF, Maidla EE PDC bit selection method through the analysis of past bit performances. In: SPE Latin America Petroleum Engineering Conference, 1990. Society of Petroleum Engineers, ##12. Falcao J, Maidla E, Dumans C, Dezen J PDC bit selection through cost prediction estimates using crossplots and sonic log data. In: SPE/IADC Drilling Conference, 1993. Society of Petroleum Engineers, ##13. McAdams SC, Gustafson W, Cooper N Higher Rotary Speeds Applied To Insert Bits Reduce Drilling Costs. In: SPE Annual Technical Conference and Exhibition, 1979. Society of Petroleum Engineers, ##14. Xu H, Tochikawa T, Hatakeyama T A Method for Bit Selection by Modelling ROP and Bit-Life. In: Annual Technical Meeting, 1997. Petroleum Society of Canada, ##15. Rabia H, Farrelly M, Barr M A new approach to drill bit selection. In: European Petroleum Conference, 1986. Society of Petroleum Engineers, ##16. Rabia H (1985) Oilwell drilling engineering: principles and practice. Graham &amp; Trotman, Limited, ##17. Abbas R (2007) Using an optimum bit selection method for determined wells in Northern Iraq. Leeds University, ##18. Borah MJ (2015) Study of specific energy method of bit selection on the basis of drill bit-depth data in upper Assam oil fields. Int J Mech Eng Tech 6 (10):103-114##19. Farrelly M, Rabia H Bit performance and selection: a novel approach. In: SPE/IADC Drilling Conference, 1987. Society of Petroleum Engineers, ##20. Javani D, Hashempour A The Significance of using Geological and Geomechanical Data in Selection of Optimal Bits. In: 13th ISRM International Congress of Rock Mechanics, 2015. International Society for Rock Mechanics, ##21. Fattahi H (2015) Prediction of slope stability state for circular failure: A hybrid support vector machine with harmony search algorithm. Int J Optim Civil Eng 5 (1):103-115##22. Fattahi H (2015) Prediction of earthquake induced displacements of slopes using hybrid support vector regression with particle swarm optimization. Int J Optim Civil Eng 5 (3):267-282##23. Bilgesu H, Al-Rashidi A, Aminian K, Ameri S A new approach for drill bit selection. In: SPE Eastern Regional Meeting, 2000. Society of Petroleum Engineers, ##24. Yιlmaz S, Demircioglu C, Akin S (2002) Application of artificial neural networks to optimum bit selection. Comput Geosci 28 (2):261-269##25. Bataee M, Kamyab M, Ashena R Investigation of various ROP models and optimization of drilling parameters for PDC and Roller-Cone bits in Shadegan Oil field. In: International Oil and Gas Conference and Exhibition in China, 2010. Society of Petroleum Engineers, ##26. Bataee M, Mohseni S Application of Artificial Intelligent Systems in ROP Optimization: a Case Study. In: SPE middle east unconventional gas conference and exhibition, 2011. Society of Petroleum Engineers, ##27. Edalatkhah S, Rasoul R, Hashemi A (2010) Bit selection optimization using artificial intelligence systems. Petrol Sci Technol 28 (18):1946-1956##28. Momeni M, Ridha S, Hosseini S, Liu X, Atashnezhad A, Ghaheri S (2017) Optimum Drill Bit Selection by Using Bit Images and Mathematical Investigation. Int J Eng Trans 30 (11):1807-1813##29. Momeni M, Hosseini SJ, Ridha S, Laruccia MB, Liu X (2018) An optimum drill bit selection technique using artificial neural networks and genetic algorithms to increase the rate of penetration. J Eng Sci Tech 13 (2):361-372##30. Rokach L, Maimon O (2005) Decision trees. In:  Data mining and knowledge discovery handbook. Springer, pp 165-192##31. Breiman L, Friedman J, Olshen R, Stone C (1984) Classification and Regression Trees. Belmont, CA: Wadsworh. Inc, ##32. Chicago I ( (2007)) Clementine 12 User Manual,  . ##33. Hanson R, Stutz J, Cheeseman P (1991) Bayesian classification theory. ##34. Friedman N, Geiger D, Goldszmidt M (1997) Bayesian network classifiers. Machine learning 29 (2-3):131-163##35. Hand DJ (1997) Construction and assessment of classification rules, vol 15. Wiley Chichester, ##36. Cohen WW (1995) Fast effective rule induction. In:  Machine Learning Proceedings 1995. Elsevier, pp 115-123##37. Wu X, Kumar V, Quinlan JR, Ghosh J, Yang Q, Motoda H, McLachlan GJ, Ng A, Liu B, Philip SY (2008) Top 10 algorithms in data mining. Knowledge and information systems 14 (1):1-37##38. Cleary JG, Trigg LE (1995) K*: An instance-based learner using an entropic distance measure. In:  Machine Learning Proceedings 1995. Elsevier, pp 108-114##39. Lin C-T, Lee CSG (1991) Neural-network-based fuzzy logic control and decision system. IEEE T Comput 40 (12):1320-1336##40. Karimpouli S, Fattahi H (2018) Estimation of P-and S-wave impedances using Bayesian inversion and adaptive neuro-fuzzy inference system from a carbonate reservoir in Iran. Neural Comput Appl 29 (11):1059-1072##41. Jang J-S (1993) ANFIS: adaptive-network-based fuzzy inference system. IEEE transactions on systems, man, and cybernetics 23 (3):665-685##42. Fattahi H Indirect estimation of deformation modulus of an in situ rock mass: an ANFIS model based on grid partitioning, fuzzy c-means clustering and subtractive clustering. J Geosci:1-10##43. Fattahi H, Agah A, Soleimanpourmoghadam N (2018) Multi-Output Adaptive Neuro-Fuzzy Inference System for Prediction of Dissolved Metal Levels in Acid Rock Drainage: a Case Study. J AI Data Mining 6 (1):121-132##44. Fattahi H (2017) Prediction of slope stability using adaptive neuro-fuzzy inference system based on clustering methods. J Min Environ 8 (2):163-177##45. Drake JT (2000) Communications phase synchronization using the adaptive network fuzzy inference system (anfis). New Mexico State University, ##46. Kohavi R (1998) Glossary of terms. Special issue on applications of machine learning and the knowledge discovery process 30 (271):127-132 ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تاثیر گسلش بر احتمال وقوع زمین لغزش ها، مطالعه موردی: زمین لغزش های منطقه نرگس چال</TitleF>
		<TitleE></TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>زمین لغزش&#173;ها به عنوان مخاطرات طبیعی، موجب خسارات فراوانی می&#173;شوند، در بسیاری از موارد می&#173;توان با شناخت زمین&#173;شناسی مناطق مختلف، وقوع زمین&#173;لغزش&#173;ها را پیشگویی و با راهکارهای مناسب از وقوع آن جلوگیری کرد. یکی از مناطق مستعد و پرخطر از نظر زمین&#173;لغزش در البرز شرقی، منطقه نرگس&#173;چال می&#173;باشد. در این پژوهش، به کمک روش&#173;های سنجش از دور، GIS و همچنین مشاهدات و اندازه&#173;گیری&#173;های صحرایی اقدام به بررسی عوامل موثر بر زمین&#173;لغزش&#173;ها در منطقه نرگس&#173;چال گردید. در این راستا هفت لایه اطلاعاتی برداری از عوامل موثر بر زمین&#173;لغزش تهیه گردیده و به مقادیر موجود در هر لایه اطلاعاتی وزن داده شده و کلاس&#173;بندی انجام شد. در نهایت با محیط نرم&#173;افزاری GIS نقشه پهنه&#173;بندی خطر زمین&#173;لغزش تهیه شد. نتایج حاصل از تهیه نقشه پهنه&#173;بندی خطر زمین&#173;لغزش نشان می&#173;دهد که الگوی فضایی بیشترین خطرات زمین&#173;لغزش به صورت نواری پهن با امتداد شمال&#173;شرق- جنوب&#173;غربی قابل مشاهده است. نتایج حاصل از بررسی اثر شکستگی&#173;ها (به عنوان عوامل ساختاری) بر پهنه&#173;بندی خطر زمین&#173;لغزش نشان می&#173;دهد که عوامل ساختاری نظیر گسل&#173;های اصلی (و سایر شکستگی&#173;های مرتبط با آنها) به طور غیرمستقیم، با ایجاد شیب&#173;های تند، ایجاد مناطق خردشده و نامقاوم، ایجاد مناطق چشمه&#173;سار و ایجاد زلزله&#173;ها، تعیین&#173;کننده الگوی پراکنش بیشترین خطر زمین&#173;لغزش بوده وتاثیر زیادی بر رخ&#173;داد این بلای طبیعی داشته&#173;اند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>0</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>0</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حجت اله</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>صفری</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه گلستان</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>safari.ho@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حامد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رضایی</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه گلستان</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>rezaiy.hamed@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>افسانه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>قجقی</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه گلستان</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>m.mghojoghi@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>منطقه نرگس چال</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پهنه بندی زمین لغزش</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سنجش از دور</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سامانه اطلاعات جغرافیایی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>گسلش</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##[1] آقانباتی، ع.،. &amp;quot;زمین‌شناسی ایران&amp;quot; انتشارات سازمان زمین‌شناسی و اکتشافات معدنی ایران (1383) 586 صفحه.##[2] علوی پناه، س. ک .، &amp;quot;کاربرد سنجش از دور در علوم زمین (علوم خاک)&amp;quot; انتشارات دانشگاه تهران (1382).##[3] قجقی، ا.، &amp;quot;تاثیر عوامل ساختاری بر زمین لغزش‌های منطقه نرگس‌چال&amp;quot; رساله کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه گلستان، (1396) 116 صفحه.##[4] قجقی، ا.، صفری، ح.، رضایی، ح.، &amp;quot;بررسی اثر گسلش بر زمین‌لغزش‌های یال شمالی البرز شرقی با استفاده از تکنیک‌های سنجش از دور و GIS&amp;quot; سی و چهارمین گردهمایی علوم زمین، تهران (1395)##[5] شریعت جعفری، م.، &amp;quot;زمین لغزش: مبانی و اصول پایداری شیب های طبیعی&amp;quot; انتشارات سازه، (1375) 200 صفحه##[6] حق‌شناس، ا.، &amp;quot;پهنه‌بندی خطر زمین‌لغزش و ارتباط آن با تولید رسوب در طالقان&amp;quot; پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، (1375) 183 صفحه##[7] حائری، س.م.، سمیعی، ا.ج.، &amp;quot;روش جدید پهنه‌بندی مناطق شیب‌دار در برابر خطر زمین‌لغزش با تاکید بر پهنه‌های مازندران&amp;quot; فصلنامه علوم زمین، سال ششم، شماره 24-23، (1376) 15-2.##[8] حافظی مقدس، ن.، &amp;quot;پهنه‌بندی خطر زمین‌لغزش در مناطق لرزه‌خیز&amp;quot; پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس (1372).##[9] محمدخان، ش.، &amp;quot;ارائه مدل منطقه‌ای پهنه‌بندی خطر حرکات دامنه‌ای، مطالعه موردی: حوضه آبخیز طالقان&amp;quot; دانشکده منابع طبیعی، دانشگاه تهران (1380). ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی آزمایشگاهی با روش ABA اصلاح شده جهت ارزیابی پتانسیل تولید آلودگی از باطله های ذخایر سولفیدی با میزبان کربناته و مقایسه با رویکرد کانی شناسی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Laboratory studies with a modified ABA method for evaluation of pollution potential from carbonate hosted sulfide waste dumps and comparison with mineralogical approach</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>یکی از اصلی&#173;ترین مشکلات در ارتباط با باطله&#173;های معدنی، بحث تشکیل پساب&#173;های معدنی بصورت اسیدی تا قلیایی و انتقال فلزات سمی در مناطق پایین دست است. بنابراین ارزیابی پتانسیل آلودگی این نوع باطله&#173;ها امری پر واضح است. مطالعه حاضر با هدف پایش غلظت فلزات سنگین و ارزیابی پتانسیل تولید یا خنثی&#173;سازی آلودگی در باطله&#173;های سرب و روی تیپ سولفیدی با میزبان کربناتی در معدن انگوران می&#173;باشد. در این راستا، تعداد 47 نمونه از بخش&#173;های مختلف سطح دمپ باطله برداشت و غلظت عناصر S، Ca و Mg و همچنین فلزات سنگین همچون As، Cd، Cr، Cu، Ni، Pb و Zn توسط روش ICP-MS آنالیز گردید. از شاخص آلودگی به&#173;منظور پهنه&#173;بندی ریسک آلودگی کل فلزات سنگین استفاده شد و سپس از روش استاتیکی اسید- باز اصلاح شده جهت ارزیابی پتانسیل آلودگی استفاده و نتایج با روش کریجینگ مدل&#173;سازی گردید. با توجه به مقادیر کم سولفور کل (کمتر از 1%)، تمام نمونه&#173;ها پتانسیل خنثی&#173;سازی خالص بالایی با دامنه بین 990-49 کیلوگرم کربنات کلسیم بر تن از خود نشان دادند. به&#173;منظور تعیین منشأ خنثی&#173;سازی و تفسیر بهتر نتایج استاتیکی از رویکرد کانی&#173;شناسی (مجموع غلظت Mg+Ca) استفاده گردید. نتایج رویکرد کانی&#173;شناسی با یک همبستگی بالا (99/0R=)با رویکرد آزمایشگاهی، کانی کلسیت را به عنوان منبع اصلی خنثی&#173;سازی معرفی کرد. به منظور اعتبارسنجی نتایج، آنالیز XRD بر روی 4 نمونه انجام و حضور کانی کلسیت به عنوان فراوانترین و بارزترین منبع خنثی&#173;سازی مورد تأیید قرار گرفت.&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Introduction
&#34;sulfide-carbonate&#34; deposit is a term, which comprises a series of sulfide minerals such as Zn-Pb ore minerals, mainly considered as related to weathering of Zn-Pb sulfide concentrations and influence in sedimentary hosts (carbonate). There are more than 350 Zn-Pb deposits and occurrences in Iran, including world-class deposits such as Angouran, Mehdiabad and Irankouh. Due to the mining activity of these deposits create a significant amount of mine waste that release of these wastes in the environment will cause irreparable problems. One of the main problems is the formation of Acid Mine Drainage (AMD). AMD is produced by oxidation of sulphide minerals, particularly pyrite (FeS2) in waste dump and Due to low pH and the ability to dissolve metals and other compounds, it can host a number of environmental problems. A phenomenon known as natural or alkaline mine drainage (NAMD) occurs at high pH values ​​when the neutralizing minerals are significantly present in the mine waste or when the oxidation of the sulfide minerals is poor. However, the metals and cationic species, such as Cu, Pb and Cd, are more soluble at low pH. In contrast, elements that form anionic species, such as Se, Cr, V, and Mo, tend to be more soluble at high pH and Ni, Zn, Co, As, and Sb, are soluble at near-neutral pH, and can potentially contaminate mine effluents, even without acidic conditions. Therefore Acid or Neutralization potential (AP&#38;NP) of waste dump is significantly affect on the composition, transfer and fate of contaminations transmitted from waste dump. The aim of this study was to monitoring heavy metals concentrations and assessments of pollution potential of waste dumps in Anguran mine by Static method and comparison by mineralogical approach.
Material and methods
The Angouran Zn-Pb deposit is located in the 135 kilometers southwest part of Zanjan Province, NW Iran. This area belongs to the northwestern part of the Sanandaj-Sirjan Zone, a metamorphic belt related to the Zagros orogeny. Angouran mine is one of the most important carbonate hosted Zn-Pb deposits in iran that mining activity has been created a significant amount of waste dump in around pit. To achieve the goals, the 47 samples taken from different surficial parts of the waste dump were analyzed by using the ICP-MS method to determine the concentration of elements and heavy metals. These elements and metals includes: Ca, Mg, S and As, Cd, Cr, Cu, Ni, Pb, Zn. The pollution index (PI) were modeled for heavy metal contamination risk zoning then modified Acid Base Accounting (ABA) static method was used to evaluate of acid and neutralization potential (AP&#38;NP) of the waste dump samples and the results were modeled by Kriging method. At the end, mineralogical approach (Mg + Ca concentration) was used to determine the source of neutralization and to better interpret the static results.
Results and discussion
The results of contamination index showed that zinc, arsenic and cadmium had the highest average contamination index (18.89, 12.13 and 5.8, respectively) and the trend of total metal changes in the region as Zn&#62; As&#62; Cd&#62; Pb &#62; Ni&#62; Cr&#62; Cu was rated.
Datas measured in modified ABA method were modeled in 2D maps using the kiriging method. Due to the low total sulfur content (less than 1%), all of the samples were Net Neutralization Potential (NNP) with a range of 49- 990 kg calcium carbonate per ton, and the study area was classified into three neutralization potential (NP), High (NP) and Very High (NP) levels. The mineralogical approach (Mg + Ca concentration) was used as a useful tool for better interpretation of modified ABA results and determines the neutralizing source. Mineralogical approach results indicate that calcite species are the main source of neutralization and have high correlation coefficient (R = 0.99) with the modified ABA method. In order to validate the results, the presence of mineral calcite was confirmed by XRD analysis on 4 samples.
&#160;
Conclusion
Assessment of AP and NP of sulfide &#8211; carbonate waste dump in this research can be used as a basis model for other similar mines to control environmental problems and identify the behavior and transfer of heavy metals in mine drainage in the future. Mineralogical approach results showed that neutralizing potential and neutralizing source can be obtained without the using expensive mineralogy analyzes in this type of carbonate-sulfide deposit.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>0</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>0</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>مرادزاده</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>a_moradzadeh@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Pollution potential</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>waste dump</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Acid mine drainage</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Sulfide-carbonate</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Static</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پتانسیل آلودگی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دمپ باطله</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>زهاب اسیدی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>باطله سولفیدی با میزبان کربناته</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>آزمایش استاتیکی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##1.	Heyl, A. V. and Bozion, C. N., &amp;quot;Oxidized zinc deposits of the United State&amp;quot;. Part 1. General Geology: U. S. Geological Bulletin 1135-A, (1962) 52p.##2.	Hitzman, M. W., Reynolds, N. A., Sangster, D. F., Allen, C. R. &amp; Carman, C. E., &amp;quot;Classification, genesis, and exploration guides for non-sulfide zinc deposits&amp;quot;. Econ. Geol, Vol. 98, No.4, (2003) pp. 684-714.##3.	Leach, D. L., Bradley, D. C., Huston, D., Pisarevsky, S. A., Taylor, R. D. &amp; Gardoll, S. J., &amp;quot;Sediment-Hosted Lead-Zinc Deposits in Earth History&amp;quot;, Econ. Geol, V. 105, (2010) p. 593–625.##4.	Rajabi, A., Rastad, E., Alfonso, P., Canet, C., &amp;quot;Geology, ore facies and sulfur isotopes of the Koushk vent-proximal sedimentary-exhalative deposit, Posht-eBadam block, Central Iran&amp;quot;, International Geology Review 54, (2012) 1635-1648##5.	Rajabi, A., Rastad, E, Canet, C. &amp; Alfonso, P., &amp;quot;The early Cambrian Chahmir shale-hosted Zn-Pb deposit, Central Iran: an example of vent-proximal SEDEX mineralization&amp;quot;, Miner. Deposita, DOI 10.1007/s00126-014-0556-x, (2015).##6.	Maghfouri S., Hossenzadeh M. R., Rajabi A., Choulet F., &amp;quot; A review of major non sulfide zinc deposits in Iran&amp;quot;, Geoscience Frontiers (2017), pp.1-25.  http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.gsf.2017.04.003##7.	Global Acid Rock Drainage Guide,.http://www.gardguide.com (2018).##8.	Parbhakar-Fox, A.K., Fox, N., Hill, R., Ferguson, T., Maynard, B., &amp;quot;Improved mine waste characterisation through static blended test work&amp;quot;, Minerals Engineering, Volume 116, (2018), 132-142. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mineng.2017.09.011##9.	Hageman, P.L., Seal, R.R., Diehl, S.F., Piatek, N.M., Lowers, H.A., &amp;quot;Evaluation of selected static methods used to estimate element mobility, acid-generating and acidneutralizing potentials associated with geologically diverse mining wastes&amp;quot;, Appl. Geochem. 57, (2015) 125–139.##10.	Plante, B., Benzaazoua, M., Bussière, B., &amp;quot;Predicting Geochemical Behaviour of Waste Rock with Low Acid Generating Potential Using Laboratory Kinetic Tests&amp;quot;, Mine Water Environ, (2010) 20pp. DOI 10.1007/s10230-010-0127-z##11.	Petrini, R., Cidu, R., Slejko, F.F., &amp;quot;Thallium Contamination in the Raibl Mine Site Stream Drainage System (Eastern Alps, Italy)&amp;quot;, Mine Water Environ. 35, (2016) 55–63. doi:10.1007/s10230-015-0346-4##12.	Qishlaqi, A., Moore, F., Forghani, G., &amp;quot;Assessing the Spatial Variability of Total and Available Cadmium in Soils of the Angouran Area, NW Iran&amp;quot;, Soil Sediment Contam. 19, (2010) 707–724. doi:doi:10.1080/15320383.2010.499919##13.	Qishlaqi, A., Moore, F., Forghani, G., &amp;quot;Characterization of metal pollution in soils under two landuse patterns in the Angouran region, NW Iran; a study based on multivariate data analysis&amp;quot;, J. Hazard. Mater. 172, (2009) 374–384. doi:10.1016/j.jhazmat.2009.07.024##14.	Iranian Mines &amp; Mining Industries Development &amp; Renovation Organization (IMIDRO), &amp;quot;Investigation of water and soil contamination around the Lead-Zinc Angouran mine and proposing solutions to reduce the potential risk (in Persian)&amp;quot;, (2014).##15.	Sharafi, A., Doulati, F., Rezaei, B., Sargheini, J., &amp;quot;Environmental geochemistry of near-neutral waters and mineralogy of zinc and lead at the Angouran non-sulphide zinc mine, NW Iran&amp;quot;, Journal of Geochemical Exploration, (2017) 1-52, doi:10.1016/j.gexplo.2017.11.020##16.	قدیمی س.، نباتیان ق.، &amp;quot;بررسی زمین شیمیایی معدن روی- سرب انگوران و اثرات فعالیتهای معدنکاری بر آلودگی منطقه&amp;quot; ، مجله زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته، شماره 13، (1393) ص66-56##17.	Boni M., Gilg A. H., Balassone G., Schneider J., Allen C. R., Moore F., &amp;quot;Hypogene Zn carbonate ores in the Angouran deposit, NW Iran&amp;quot;, Miner Deposita 42, (2007) 799-820. DOI: 10.1007/s00126-007-0144-4##18.	Daliran, F., Pride, K.,Walther, J., Berner, Z.A., Bakker, R.J., &amp;quot;The Angouran Zn (Pb) deposit, NW Iran: evidence for a two stage, hypogene zinc sulfideezinc carbonates mineralization&amp;quot;, Ore Geology Reviews 53, (2013) 373-402. doi:10.1016/j.oregeorev.2013.02.002##19.	Annels, A.A., &amp;quot;New Ideas Concerning the Genesis of the Angouran ZnePb Deposit, NW Iran&amp;quot;, European Science Foundation. Exploratory Workshop “Nonsulfide ZnePb Ores”, Iglesias (Italy), Abstract Volume, 3-4, (2005).##20.	Gazanfari, F., Metamorphic and Igneous Petrogenesis in NE of Takab with Special Regard to Zinc Mineralization in the Angouran Mine (Unpublished MSc Thesis). Teheran University, (1991) 530 pp, (in Farsi). ##21.	Gilg, H.A., Allen, C.R., Balassone, G., Boni, M., Moore, F., &amp;quot;The 3-stage evolution of the Angouran Zn “oxide”-sulfide deposit, Iran&amp;quot;, In: Eliopoulos,D.G., et al. (Ed.),Mineral Exploration and Sustainable Development. Millpress, Rotterdam, (2003)  pp. 77–80.##22.	Gilg H A, Boni M, Balassone G, Allen C R, Banks D, Moore F., &amp;quot;Marble-hosted sulfide ores in the Angouran Zn-(Pb-Ag) deposit, NW Iran: interaction of sedimentary brines with a metamorphic core complex&amp;quot;, Mineralium Deposita, 31, 1, (2006) 1–16.##23.	Evangelou, V.P., Zhang, Y.L., &amp;quot;A review: pyrite oxidation mechanisms and acid mine drainage prevention&amp;quot;, Crit. Rev. Environ. Sci. Technol. 25, (1995) 141–199.##24.	Singh, R.N., Doulati Ardejani, F., &amp;quot;Evaluation of factors affecting pyrite oxidation and subsequent pollutant generation in backfilled open cut coal mines&amp;quot;, 8th International Congress on Mine Water and the Environment, Johannesburg, South Africa, (2003) pp.173-186.##25.	Bond, P.L., Druschel, G.K., Banfield, J.F., &amp;quot;Comparison of acid mine drainage microbial communities in physically and geochemically distinct ecosystems&amp;quot;. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 66, (2000) 4962–4971.##26.	Kuyucak, N., &amp;quot;Role of microorganisms in mining: generation of acid rock drainage and its mitigation and treatment&amp;quot;, Eur. J. Miner. Process. Environ. Prot. 2, (2002) 179–196.##27.	Baker, B.J., Banfield, J.F., &amp;quot; Microbial communities in acid mine drainage&amp;quot;. FEMS Microbiol. Ecol. 44, (2003) 139–152.##28.	Singer, P.C., Stumm, W., &amp;quot;Acidic mine drainage: the rate-determining step&amp;quot;. Science 167, (1970) 1121–1123.##29.	Nowaczyk, K., Domka, F., &amp;quot;Oxidation of Pyrite and Marcasite by Thiobacillus ferrooxidans Bacteria&amp;quot;, Polish Journal of Environmental Studies Vol. 9, No. 2, (2000) pp.87-90.##30.	دولتی ارده جانی، ف.، شفائی تنکابنی، س. ض.، میر حبیبی، ع. و بدیعی، خ.، &amp;quot;بیوتکنولوژی، ژئوشیمی زیست محیطی و مدیریت پساب ها: جلد اول- پساب های معدنی&amp;quot;، پژوهشکده صنایع رنگ ایران، چاپ دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود، (1383). ##31.	Dold, B., &amp;quot;Acid rock drainage prediction: A critical review&amp;quot;, Journal of Geochemical Exploration 172, (2017) 120–132.##32.	Dold, B., &amp;quot;Basic concepts in environmental geochemistry of sulphide minewaste management&amp;quot;, In: Kumar, Sunil (Ed.), Waste Management. INTECH Open Access Publications, (2010)  pp. 173–198 (ISBN 978-953-7619-84-8).##33.	Lottermoser, B.G., &amp;quot;Mine Wastes: Characterization, Treatment and Environmental Impacts&amp;quot;, third ed. Springer-Verlag, Berlin, Heidelberg, (2010) 400 pp.##34.	Parbhakar-Fox, A.K., Lottermoser, B.G., &amp;quot;A critical review of acid rock drainage prediction methods and practices. Miner&amp;quot;, Eng. 82, (2015) 107–124. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.mineng.2015.03.015. 107-124##35.	Broughton L. M., Robertson A., &amp;quot;Modelling of leachate quality from acid generating waste rock dumps&amp;quot;, Preprint for the Second International Conference on the Abatement of Acidic Drainage, Montreal, Quebec, (1991) 18p.##36.	Sherlock, E.J., Lawrence, R.W., Poulin, R., &amp;quot;On the neutralization of acid rock drainage by carbonate and silicate minerals&amp;quot;, Environ. Geol. 25, (1995) 43–54.##37.	Frostad, S., Klein, B., Lawrence, R.W., &amp;quot;Evaluation of laboratory kinetic test methods for measuring rates of weathering&amp;quot;, Mine Water Environ. 21, (2002) 183–192.##38.	Bouzahzah H., Benzaazoua M., Bussiere B., Plante B., &amp;quot;Prediction of Acid Mine Drainage: Importance of Mineralogy and the Test Protocols for Static and Kinetic Tests&amp;quot;, Mine Water Environ (2014) 33:54–65, DOI 10.1007/s10230-013-0249-1##39.	Adam, K., Kourtis, A., Gazea, B., Kontopoulos, A., &amp;quot;Evaluation of static tests used to predict the potential for acid drainage generation at sulfide mine sites&amp;quot;, Transactions of the Institution of Mining and Metallurgy, section A, mining industry 106, (1997) A1–A8.##40.	Day, S.J., &amp;quot;New methods for determination of key mineral species in acid generation prediction by acid base accounting&amp;quot;, MEND report 1.16.1c. MEND, Ottawa,Ontario (1991).##41.	Lawrence, R.W., Poling, G.W., Marchant, P.B., &amp;quot;Investigation of predictive techniques for acid mine drainage&amp;quot;, MEND/NEDEM report 1.16.1a, Canadian Centre for Mineral and Energy Technology, Ottawa, Canada (1989).##42.	Skousen, J., Simmons, J., McDonald, L.M., Ziemkiewicz, P., &amp;quot;Acid–base accounting to predict post-mining drainage quality on surface mines&amp;quot;, Journal of Environmental Quality 31, (2002) 2034–2044.##43.	Weber, P.A., Thomas, J.E., Skinner, W.M., Smart, R.S.C., &amp;quot;Improved acid neutralization capacity assessment of iron carbonates by titration and theoretical calculation&amp;quot;, Applied Geochemistry 19, (2004) 687–694.##44.	Weber, P.A., Thomas, J.E., Skinner, W.M., Smart, R., St, C., &amp;quot;A methodology to determine the acid-neutralization capacity of rock samples&amp;quot;, The Canadian Mineralogist 43, (2005) 1183–1192.##45.	Plante, B., Bussière, B., Benzaazoua, M., &amp;quot;Kinetic Static tests response on 5 Canadian hard rock mine tailings with low net acid-generating potentials&amp;quot;, Journal of Geochemical Exploration 114, (2012) 57–69. doi:10.1016/j.gexplo.2011.12.003##46.	Sobek, A.A., Schuller, W.A., Freeman, J.R., Smith, R.M.,&amp;quot;Field and laboratory methods applicable to overburdens and minesoil&amp;quot;, EPA report no. EPA-600/2-78-054, US Govt Printing Office, Washington, (1978) pp. 47–50.##47.	Frostad SR, Price WA, Bent H., &amp;quot;Operational NP determination—accounting for iron manganese carbonates and developing a site-specific fizz rating&amp;quot;, (2003), In: Spiers G, Beckett P, Conroy H (eds) Mining and the environment, Sudbury. Laurentian University, Sudbury, pp 231–237##48.	Kwong Y.T.J., &amp;quot;Prediction and prevention of acid rock drainage from a geological and mineralogical perspective&amp;quot;, MEND Report 1.32.1, CANMET, Ottawa, ON, Canada, (1993).##49.	Lawrence R.W, Scheske M., &amp;quot; A method to calculate the neutralization potential of mining wastes&amp;quot;, Environ Geol 32, (1997) 100–106##50.	Paktunc A.D., &amp;quot;Characterization of mine wastes for prediction of acid mine drainage&amp;quot;, (1999), In: Azcue JM (ed) Environmental impacts of mining activities. Springer-Verlag, Berlin Heidelberg New York, pp 19–40##51.	White, W.W., Lapakko, K.A., Cox, R.L., &amp;quot;Static-test methods most commonly used to predict acid mine drainage: practical guidelines for use and interpretation&amp;quot;, (1999),  In: Plumlee, G.S., Logsdon, M.J. (Eds.), The Environmental Geochemistry of Ore Deposits. Part A: Processes, Techniques, and Health Issues. Reviews in Economic Geology, pp. 325–338.##52.	Lawrence, R.W., Wang, Y., &amp;quot;Determination of neutralizing potential for acid rock drainage prediction&amp;quot;, MEND/NEDEM report 1.16.3, Canadian Centre for Mineral and Energy Technology, Ottawa, Canada. (1996) 149 pp.##53.	Bezaazoua, B., Bussiere, B., Dagenais, A.M., Archambault, M., &amp;quot;Kinetic tests comparison and interpretation for prediction of the Joutel tailings acid generation potential&amp;quot;,  Environ. Geol. 46, (2004) 1086–1101##54.	Mohammadi Z, Modabberi S, Jafari M. R, Ajayebi K. S., &amp;quot;Comparison of different static methods for assessment of AMD generation potential inmining waste dumps in the Muteh Gold Mines, Iran&amp;quot;, Environ Monit Assess, 187:374, (2015) pp.1-14, DOI 10.1007/s10661-015-4306-z##55.	معتمدی راد، م.، مختاری، ل، گ.، بهرامی، ش.، اسدی، م، ع، ز.، 1397. ارزیابی میزان آلودگی ناشی از عناصر سنگین در رسوبات حوضه کارستی روئین، پژوهشهای دانش زمین، سال نهم، شماره 36، ص166-146. ##56.	Rietveld, H.M., &amp;quot;The Rietveld Method&amp;quot;. In: Young, R.A. (Ed.), Oxford University Press, (1993).##57.	Taylor, J.C., Hinczak, I., &amp;quot;Rietveld made easy: a practical guide to the understanding of the method and successful phase quantifications&amp;quot;, Sietronics Pty Ltd, (2001).##58.	Paktunc, A.D., &amp;quot;ModAn — a computer program for estimating mineral quantities based on bulk composition: windows version&amp;quot;, Computers &amp; Geosciences 27, (2001) 883–886.##59.	Paktunc A.D., &amp;quot; Mineralogical constraints on the determination of neutralization potential and prediction of acid mine drainage&amp;quot;, Environmental Geology 39. Springer-Verlag, (1999) pp 103–112 ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی و برآورد دوام سنگ‌های رسوبی رخنمون یافته منطقه دره شیخان (شمال غربی خرم آباد) در مقابل هوازدگی نمک</TitleF>
		<TitleE></TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>سازند گچساران با سن میوسن، رخنمون وسیعی در برخی نواحی خرم آباد دارد. وجود سنگ ژیپس در این سازند، باعث ایجاد روان آب&#173;های شور در منطقه دره شیخان در شمال غربی خرم آباد شده است. روان آب&#173;ها باعث هوازدگی نمک در رخنمون&#173;های سنگی منطقه شامل ژیپس، کنگلومرا، ماسه سنگ، سنگ آهک، دولومیت، شیل دولومیتی و مارن مربوط به سازند&#173;های گچساران، آسماری، شهبازان، کشکان، تاربور و امیران گردیده است. هدف از پژوهش حاضر بررسی و برآورد دوام سنگ&#173;های منطقه دره شیخان در شمال غربی خرم آباد در مقابل هوازدگی نمک ناشی از روان&#173; آب&#173;های شور است. برای رسیدن به اهداف پژوهش، 8 نمونه سنگ مختلف از رخنمون&#173;های سنگی منطقه برداشت شد و آزمون&#173; دوام وارفتگی در محلول اشباع از نمک تا 15 چرخه انجام شد. علاوه بر این ترکیب کانی&#173;شناسی، خصوصیات فیزیکی و مقاومتی نمونه&#173;ها شامل تخلخل و شاخص بار نقطه&#173;ای تعیین شدند. بر اساس ارزیابی دوام نمونه&#173;ها، ترکیب کانی&#173;شناسی، تخلخل و مقاومت نقش مهمی در دوام نمونه&#173;ها در برابر هوازدگی نمک دارند. مدل آماری حاصل از آنالیز&#173; رگرسیون چند متغیره نشان می&#173;دهد دوام سنگ&#173;ها در مقابل هوازدگی نمک می&#173;تواند با دقت مناسبی (R2=0.95) با استفاده از تخلخل و شاخص بار نقطه&#173;ای برآورد شود. این مدل به دلیل استفاده از پارامترهای ساده تخلخل و شاخص بار نقطه&#173;ای، می&#173;تواند یک ارزیابی سریع و ارزان از دوام طولانی مدت سنگ&#173;ها در مقابل هوازدگی نمک داشته باشد.
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>0</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>0</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>امین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>جمشیدی</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>jamshidi.am@lu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>یاسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>عبدی</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>yassin.abdii@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>بیژن</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>یوسفی یگانه</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>bb.yuosefi@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سنگ رسوبی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دوام</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>هوازدگی نمک</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تخلخل</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شاخص بار نقطه‌ای</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدل آماری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##Angeli, M., Heber, R., Menendez, B., David, C., Bigas, J-P., 2010, Influence of temperature and salt concentration on the salt weathering of a sedimentary stone with sodium sulphate. Engineering Geology, 115: pp 193–199.##Bell, F.G., 1993, Durability of carbonate rock as building stone with comments on its preservation. Environmental Geology, 21: 187–200. ##Benavente, D, Garcia del Cura, M.A, Bernabeu, A, Ordonez, S., 2001. Quantification of salt weathering in porous stones using experimental continuous partial immersion method. Engineering Geology, 59: 313–25. ##Benavente, D, Martinez-Martinez, J, Cueto, N, Ordoez, S, Garcia-del- Cura, M., 2018, Impact of salt and frost weathering on the physical and durability properties of travertines and carbonate tufas used as building material. Environmental Earth Sciences, 77:147##Benavente, D., Garcia del Cura, M.A., Fort, R., Ordonez, S., 1999, Thermodynamic modeling of changes induced by salt pressure crystallization in porous media of stone.  Journal of Crystal Growth, 204:168–178.##Benavente, D., García del Cura, M.A., Fort, R., Ordóñez, S., 2004, Durability estimation of porous building stones from pore structure and strength.  Engineering Geology, 74: 113–127.##Benavente, D., Martinez, J., Cueto, N., Cura, M.A, 2007a, Salt weathering in dual-porosity building dolostones. Engineering Geology, 94: 215–226.##Benavente, D., Martinez-Martinez, J., Garcia del Cura, M.A., Can averas, M.A., 2007b, The influence of petrophysical properties on the salt weathering of porous building rocks. Environmental Geology, 52: 215–224.##Cultrone, G., Luque, A., Sebastián, E., 2012, Petrophysical and durability tests on sedimentary stones to evaluate their quality as building materials. Quarterly Journal of Engineering Geology and Hydrogeology, 45, 415-422.##Dhakal, G., Yoneda, T., Kato, M., and Kaneko, K., 2002. Slake durability and mineralogical properties of some pyroclastic and sedimentary rocks. Engineering Geology, 65, 31-45.##Franklin, J.A., Chandra, A., 1972. The slake durability test. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 9, 325–341.##Ghobadi, M.H., Babazadeh, R., 2015. Experimental studies on the effects of cyclic freezing– thawing, salt crystallization, and thermal shock on the physical and mechanical characteristics of selected sandstones. Rock Mechanics and Rock Engineering 48, 1001–1016.##Gökceoğlu, C., Ulusay, R., and Sönmez, H., 2000. Factors affecting the durability of selected weak and claybearing rocks from Turkey, with particular emphasis on the influence of then number of drying and wetting cycles. Engineering Geology, 57, 215-237.##ISRM, 1978, Suggested methods for the quantitative description of discontinuities in rock masses. International Society for Rock Mechanics, Commission on Standardization##ISRM., 1981. Rock characterization testing and monitoring. ISRM suggested methods. Pergamon Press, Oxford.##Jamshidi, A., Nikudel, M.R., Khamehchiyan, M., 2013, Estimating the durability of building stones against Salt crystallization: considering the physical properties and strength characteristics. Journal of Geopersia 3(2): 35–48. ##Koncagül, E., and Santi, P., 1999. Predicting the unconfined compressive strength of the Breathitt shale using slake durability, Shore hardness and rock structural properties. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 36, 139-153.##Lubelli, B., Hees, R., Groot, C., 2004, The role of sea salts in the occurrence of different damage mechanisms and decay patterns on brick masonry. Construction and Building Materials, 18, 119-124.##Matula, M., Dearman, W.R., Golodkovskaja, G.A., Pahl, A., Radbruch-Hall Dorothy, H., 1979, Part 1: rock and soil materials. Bulletin of Engineering Geology and the Environment, 19, 364–371.##Mottersheada, D., Gorbushinab, A., Lucasc, G., Wrightd, J., 2003, The in uence of marine salts, aspect and microbes in the weathering of sandstone in two historic structures. Building and Environment, 38, 1193 – 1204.##Rodriguez-Navarro, C., Doehne, E., 1999, Salt weathering: influence of evaporation rate, supersaturation and crystallization pattern. Earth Surface Processes and Landforms, 24, 191–209.##Rodriguez-Navarroa, C., Doehnea, E., Sebastianb, E., 2000, How does sodium sulfate crystallize? Implications for the decay and testing of building materials. Cement and Concrete Research, 30: 1527–1534.##Scherer, G., 1999. Crystallization in pores. Cement and Concrete Research, 29: 1347–1358.##Schneider, C., Gommeaux, M., Fronteau, G., Oguchi, C.T., Eyssautier, S., Kartheuser, B., 2011, A comparison of the properties and salt weathering susceptibility of natural and reconstituted stones of the Orval Abbey (Belgium). Environmental Earth Sciences, 63: 1447–1461.  ##Sousa, M.O. Suarez del Rio, M. Calleja, L. Argandona, V. and Rodriguez, A., 2005, Influence of microfractures and porosity on the physico-mechanical properties and weathering of ornamental granites. Engineering Geology, 77, 153-168.##Topal, T., Doyuran, V., 1998, Enginnering geological properties and durability assessment of the Cappadocian tuff. Engineering Geology, 47:175–187.##Torabi‑Kaveh M., Heidari, M.,  Mohseni, H.,  Menendez, B., 2019,  Role of petrography in durability of limestone used in construction of Persepolis complex subjected to artificial accelerated ageing tests. Environmental Earth Sciences, 78:297##Tsui, N., Flatt, R., Scherer, G., 2003, Crystallization damage by sodium sulfate. Journal of Cultural Heritage, 4: 109–115.##Tuğrul, A., Zarif, I.H., 1998, The influence of mineralogical textural and chemical characteristics on the durability of selected sandstones in Istanbul, Turkey. Bulletin of Engineering Geology and the Environment,  57, 185-190. ##Ulusoy, M., 2007. Different igneous masonry blocks and salt crystal weathering rates in the architecture of historical city of Konya. Building and Environment, 42, 3014-3024.##Urosevic, M., Pardo, E., Cardell, C., 2010, Rough and polished travertine building stone decay evaluated by a marine aerosol ageing test. Construction and Building Materials, 24: 1438–1448.##Watt, D., Colston, B., 2000. Investigating the e€ects of humidity and salt crystallisation on medieval masonry. Building and Environment, 35, 737-749.##Winkler, E. M., 1994, Stone in Architecture, properties, durability. Thired Edition, Springer-Verlag Berlin Heidelberg.##Yavuz, A.B., 2006, Deterioration of the volcanic kerb and pavement stones in a humid environment in the city centre of Izmir, Turkey. Environmental Geology, 51: 211–227.##Zalooli, A., Freire-Lista, D.M., Khamehchiyan, M., Nikudel, M.R, Fort, R., Ghasemi, S., 2018, Ghaleh-khargushi rhyodacite and Gorid andesite from Iran: characterization, uses, and durability. Environmental Earth Sciences, 77:315##Zalooli, A., Khamehchiyan, M., Nikudel, M.R., Jamshidi, A., 2017, &amp;quot;Deterioration of Travertine Samples Due to Magnesium Sulfate Crystallization Pressure: Examples from Iran. Geotechnical and Geological Engineering, 35(1), 463–473.##Zedef, V. Kocak, K. Doyen, A. Ozsen, H. and Kekec, B., 2007. Effect of salt crystallization on stones of historical buildings and monuments, Konya, Central Turkey. Building and Environment, 42, 1453-1457. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>مطالعات آزمایشگاهی تاثیر هیبرید نانوذرات در بهسازی خاک‌ اطراف حرم مطهر رضوی</TitleF>
		<TitleE></TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>بهسازی خاک&#173;های مساله&#173;دار در محیط&#173;های شهری و به ویژه کلانشهرها یکی از مهم&#173;ترین چالش&#173;های مهندسین عمران می&#173;باشد. استفاده از نانوذرات بدلیل قابلیت افزایش سطح ویژه ذرات خاک از جمله روش&#173;های نوینی است که در افزایش پارامترهای مقاومت برشی و مکانیکی خاک می&#173;تواند بسیار کارآمد &#173;باشد. در این پژوهش بمنظور دستیابی به هیبریدی با حداکثر مقاومت و ظرفیت باربری، خاک اطراف حرم مطهر رضوی در شهر مشهد ابتدا با نسبت&#173;های وزنی متفاوت نانورس و نانوسیلیکا بهسازی گردید، سپس با تعیین نسبت بهینه هریک از نانوذرات، هیبریدی متشکل از آنها در 4 ترکیب مختلف تهیه و پارامترهای مقاومت برشی و مکانیکی خاک بررسی گردید. نتایج بیانگر تاثیر چشمگیر هیبرید ساخته شده بر پارامترهای فیزیکی و مقاومتی خاک است بطوری که هیبرید ساخته شده از 5% نانورس و 1% نانوسیلیکا به عنوان ترکیب بهینه موجب افزایش 785 درصدی ظرفیت باربری و کاهش 60 درصدی نشست خاک مورد مطالعه شده است.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>0</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>0</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سهیل</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>قره</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>مشهد- بلوار معلم- خ شهید ستاری- دانشگاه پیام نور</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>ghareh_soheil@pnu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>کیمیا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>یزدانی</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>kimiya_yazdany@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>فاطمه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>اخلاقی</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>faakhlaqi@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بهسازی خاک</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>هیبرید نانوذرات</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ظرفیت باربری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نانورس</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نانوسیلیکا</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##[1]	F. Tavenas, S. Leroueil, P. La Rochelle, and M. Roy, “Creep behaviour of an undisturbed lightly overconsolidated clay,” Can. Geotech. J., vol. 15, no. 3, pp. 402–423, 1978.##[2]	B. Simpson and F. Tatsuoka, “Geotechnics: the next 60 years,” Geotechnique, vol. 58, no. 5, pp. 357–368, 2008.##[3]	S. Shukla, N. Sivakugan, and B. Das, “Fundamental concepts of soil reinforcement — an overview,” Int. J. Geotech. Eng., vol. 3, no. 3, pp. 329–342, Jul. 2009.##[4]	K. C. Onyelowe and B. V Duc, “Durability of nanostructured biomasses ash (NBA) stabilized expansive soils for pavement foundation,” Int. J. Geotech. Eng., pp. 1–10, 2018.##[5]	Z. H. Majeed and M. R. Taha, “A Review of Stabilization of Soils by using Nanomaterials,” Aust. J. Basic Appl. Sci., vol. 7, no. 2, pp. 576–581, 2013.##[6]	H. Niroumand, M. F. M. Zain, and S. N. Alhosseini, “The influence of nano-clays on compressive strength of earth bricks as sustainable materials,” Procedia-Social Behav. Sci., vol. 89, pp. 862–865, 2013.##[7]	M. R. Taha and O. M. Taha, “Crack control of landfill liner and cap materials using nano-alumina powder,” 2013.##[8]	A. Kalhor, M. Ghazavi, M. Roustaei, and S. M. Mirhosseini, “Influence of nano-SiO2 on geotechnical properties of fine soils subjected to freeze-thaw cycles,” Cold Reg. Sci. Technol., 2019.##[9]	W.-T. Kuo, K.-L. Lin, W.-C. Chang, and H.-L. Luo, “Effects of nano-materials on properties of waterworks sludge ash cement paste,” J. Ind. Eng. Chem., vol. 12, no. 5, pp. 702–709, 2006.##[10]	J. Li et al., “Effect of Temperature on Shear‐Induced Anisotropic Structure in Polymer Clay Hydrogels,” Macromol. Rapid Commun., vol. 27, no. 20, pp. 1787–1791, 2006.##[11]	M. Jain and K. Matsumura, “Polyampholyte‐and nanosilicate‐based soft bionanocomposites with tailorable mechanical and cell adhesion properties,” J. Biomed. Mater. Res. Part A, vol. 104, no. 6, pp. 1379–1386, 2016.##[12]	C.-L. Huang, N.-S. Hsu, C.-C. Wei, and C.-W. Lo, Using Artificial Intelligence to Retrieve the Optimal Parameters and Structures of Adaptive Network-Based Fuzzy Inference System for Typhoon Precipitation Forecast Modeling, vol. 2015. 2015.##[13]	N. Abbasi, A. Farjad, and S. Sepehri, “The Use of Nanoclay Particles for Stabilization of Dispersive Clayey Soils,” Geotech. Geol. Eng., vol. 36, no. 1, pp. 327–335, 2018.##[14]	N. Kananizadeh and A. Khoshniat, “Behavior of nanoclay as an additive in order to reduce Kahrizak landfill clay permeability,” in Proceeding of 2nd International Conference on Environmental Science and Technology, 2011, pp. 26–28.##[15]	H. Ghazi, M. H. Baziar, and S. M. Mirkazemi, “Assess of the improvement of the behavior of soil strength in the presence of nanoscale additive,” Assas J. Sci. Technol., pp. 45–50, 2011.##[16]	M. Bahari, M. Nikookar, M. Arabani, A. K. Haghi, and H. Khodabandeh, “Stabilization of silt by nanoclay,” in Proc. of 7th National Congress on Civil Engineering, 2013, pp. 7–8.##[17]	M. Nikookar, M. Bahari, H. Nikookar, and M. Arabani, “The Strength Characteristics of Silty Soil Stabilized Using Nano Clay,” Proc. of 7th Symposium on Advances in Science &amp; Technology. 2012.##[18]	S. J. Hosseini and A. Tabarsa, “Effect of Adding Nanoclay on the Mechanical Behaviour of Fine-grained Soil Reinforced with Polypropylene Fibers,” vol. 5, no. 2, pp. 59–67, 2015.##[19]	B. Iranpour, “The influence of Nano-materials on collapsible soil treatment The in fl uence of nanomaterials on collapsible soil treatment,” Eng. Geol., vol. 205, no. January 2019, pp. 40–53, 2016.##[20]	R. Yonekura and M. Miwa, “Fundamental properties of sodium silicate based grout,” in Proceedings of the 11th Southeast Asia Geotechnical Conference, Singapore, 1993, vol. 439, p. e44.##[21]	C. Butrón, M. Axelsson, and G. Gustafson, “Silica sol for rock grouting: Laboratory testing of strength, fracture behaviour and hydraulic conductivity,” Tunn. Undergr. Sp. Technol., vol. 24, no. 6, pp. 603–607, 2009.##[22]	S. H. Bahmani, B. B. K. Huat, A. Asadi, and N. Farzadnia, “Stabilization of residual soil using SiO2 nanoparticles and cement,” Constr. Build. Mater., vol. 64, pp. 350–359, 2014.##[23]	F. Changizi and A. Haddad, “Strength properties of soft clay treated with mixture of nano-SiO2 and recycled polyester fiber,” J. Rock Mech. Geotech. Eng., vol. 7, no. 4, pp. 367–378, 2015.##[24]	E. Yusefi, M. Ghafuri, G. Lashkaripour, and S. L. Talebian, “Investigation of clay minerals in soil of Mashhad City according to its Atterberg limits,” in 05th Iranian Conference of Engineering Geology, 2007.##[25]	N. Hafezi Moghaddas and A. Ghazi, “Geotechnical Zonation and evaluation of ultimate bearing capacity of Mashhad city,” in 05th Iranian Conference of Engineering Geology, 2007.##[26]	F. H. Chen, Foundations on expansive soils, vol. 12. Elsevier, 2012.##[27]	G. Zhang, “Soil nanoparticles and their influence on engineering properties of soils,” in Advances in Measurement and Modeling of Soil Behavior, 2007, pp. 1–13. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>

</ARTICLES>

</JOURNAL>
</XML>
