<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>5</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>8</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>11</volume>
<number>1</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>اصلاح شاخص سایش شیمازک به منظور بهبود کاربرد‌های آن در مهندسی سنگ</title_fa>
	<title>Modification of Schimazek Abrasivity Index for Improving its Application in Rock Engineering</title>
	<subject_fa>ژئوتکنیک (مکانیک خاک و سنگ)</subject_fa>
	<subject>Geotecnic</subject>
	<content_type_fa>مقاله استخراج شده از پایان نامه</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research Paper</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p&gt;تاکنون شاخص&#8204;ها و روش&#8204;های مختلفی برای ارزیابی قابلیت سایندگی سنگ&#8204;ها ارائه شده است. به طور کلی این شاخص&#8204;ها را می&#8204;توان به دو دسته روش&#8204;های مبتنی بر ذات سنگ و روش&#8204;های مبتنی بر ابزار&#8204;های ابتکاری تقسیم&#8204;بندی نمود. روش شاخص شیمازک یکی از قوی&#8204;ترین و پرکاربردترین روش&#8204;های ارزیابی سایندگی سنگ است. این شاخص بر مبنای اندازه&#8204; دانه&#8204;ها، مقاومت کششی برزیلی و میزان کوارتز محتوی معادل ارائه شده است. با توجه به اینکه ارزش هر سه پارامتر فوق در شاخص شیمازک یکسان در نظر گرفته شده است، لذا در بعضی مواقع این شاخص قدرت تشخیص مناسبی را ندارد. در این تحقیق سعی شده است تا با استفاده از روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی دلفی (FDAHP) وزن هر یک از سه معیار فوق در سایندگی سنگ اعمال شده و بر طبق این وزن&#8204;ها شاخص شیمازک اصلاح شود. در مرحله بعد برای اعتبارسنجی شاخص جدید 10 نمونه سنگ ساختمانی مورد مطالعه قرار گرفته و شاخص سایندگی قدیمی و اصلاح شده آن&#8204;ها محاسبه شده است. سپس سرعت برش هر سنگ تبت شده و رابطه ریاضی بین سرعت برش و شاخص قدیمی و شاخص جدید به دست آمده است. نتایج نشان می&#8204;دهد که شاخص سایندگی شیمازک جدید توانایی به مراتب بالاتری نسبت به شاخص قدیمی دارد.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;./files/site1/files/4Extended_Abstract.pdf&quot;&gt;./files/site1/files/4Extended_Abstract.pdf&lt;/a&gt;Extended Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
(Paper pages 73-90)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Up to now, various indexes and methods have been presented for evaluating the abrasivity of rocks. In total, these methods can be divided to two main groups; the methods based on nature of rocks, methods based on heuristic tools. Schimazek F-abrasivity index is one of the most powerful and applicable indexes for evaluating the rock abrasiveness. This index uses the grain size, Brazilian tensile strength and equivalent quartz content for abrasivity analysis. Since the values of these parameters are equal in Schimazek index, therefore, in some cases this index doesn't have suitable ability to distinguish and classify the rock abrasiveness. This paper tries to modify the Schimazek index considering the weights of its applied parameters.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Material and Methods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In this research, Fuzzy Delphi Analytical Hierarchy Process (FDAHP) has been used to calculate the weight of dominant parameters in rock abrasivity. For this purpose several questioners have been distributed and the expert opinions were collected. The results showed that the quartz content, grain size and tensile strength have the weight of 0.4, 0.31 and 0.29 respectively and new Schimazek F-abrasivity index is as presented in equation (1).&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;./files/site1/images/3(1).jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 356px; height: 38px; &quot; &gt;&lt;br&gt;
In the next stage, in order to facilitate the application of new index, a new classification system was developed. This classification and related weighing graphs (Figure 1) help to change the discontinuous classification to continuous one.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Results and discussions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In order to verify the application of the new developed index, ten ornamental stones have been studied and the old and modified Schimazek indexes were calculated for all of them. Then, the cutting rate (sawing rate) of each stone was recorded in laboratory and the mathematical relationships between new and old indexes have been achieved. The results show that the new Schimazek abrasivity index has higher ability to predict the cutting rate than old one (Figure 2).&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;./files/site1/images/1(1).jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 308px; height: 205px; &quot; &gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;Figure1. Continuous weighting for parameters of Schimazek F-abrasivity index&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;./files/site1/images/2(2).jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 356px; height: 129px; &quot; &gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;Figure2. Regression of old and new &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;Schimazek F-abrasivity index with cutting rate of granite ornamental stones&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Generally it could be concluded that, the main weakness of Schimazek F-abrasivity index which is the equality of parameters&amp;rsquo; importance, has been removed by idea developed and confirmed in this study. The different weights which allocated to grain size, Brazilian tensile strength and equivalent quartz content in study, improves the Schimazek index applicability in rock engineering applications specially rock cutting and drilling. Therefore, it is recommended to use new method instead of old one in future applications.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>سنگ, سایندگی, شاخص شیمازک, سرعت برش</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>abrasivity index has higher ability than old one. کلیدواژگان [English]	rock, abrasivity, Schimazek index, cutting rate.</keyword>
	<start_page>73</start_page>
	<end_page>90</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-152-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>M</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ataei</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عطایی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>ataei@shahroodut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846001669</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001669</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود، دانشکده معدن، نفت و ژئوفیزیک</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>sh.</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>hosseini</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سیدهادی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حسینی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001670</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001670</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه صنعتی اصفهان، دانشکده مهندسی معدن</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>S.H</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Hoseinie</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>رضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>میکائیل</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001671</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001671</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه صنعتی ارومیه، دانشکده مهندسی معدن</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
