<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" 

"journalpublishing3.dtd">

<article 
article-type="research-article"
dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en" 
xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
>

<front>

<journal-meta>

  <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher">1</journal-id>
  <issn>2228-6837</issn>

  <publisher>

	<publisher-name>Kharazmi University</publisher-name>
  </publisher>

</journal-meta>



<article-meta>

  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">409</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject></subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Vol.7No.1</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>8</month>

	<year>2013</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>7</volume>

  <issue>1</issue>

  <fpage>1</fpage>

  <lpage>4</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>


</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">408</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject></subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Vol.7No.1</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>8</month>

	<year>2013</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>7</volume>

  <issue>1</issue>

  <fpage>1</fpage>

  <lpage>8</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>


</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">394</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>En. Geology</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Assessment of Landslide Hazard with Knowledge-driven Fuzzy Model & Hybrid Fuzzy-Weight of Evidence Method-A Case Study: Maskoon Area-Jiroft District</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Akbar</surname>
		<given-names>Somaieh</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Ranjbar</surname>
		<given-names>h</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Kariminasab</surname>
		<given-names>S</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Abdolmaleki</surname>
		<given-names>M</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>8</month>

	<year>2013</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>7</volume>

  <issue>1</issue>

  <fpage>1601</fpage>

  <lpage>1622</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The study area is located in Jiroft district, Iran, and is a part of Sahand-Bazman volcanic zone. There are various landslide factors and the importance of each factor are identified qualitatively, based on previous studies and regional specifications. Three landslides were recognized in the study area using direct method (field work) and aerial photographs interpretation. One of these landslides is located in the vicinity of Mohammad Abad of Maskoon Village. The aim of this study is landslide hazard mapping using two integration methods that includes Fuzzy Logic and Hybrid Fuzzy-Weight of Evidence (Hybrid F-W of E). The obtained results of maps from both methods, show a good agreement especially in introducing  high hazard regions. The hybrid method is based on the occurred landslide points and is more rigorous, so hazard regions delineated by this method occupy smaller areas than the areas introduced by fuzzy model. Therefore, hazard maps resulted from Hybrid and Fuzzy methods, can be considered as minimum and maximum limits of landslide hazard in the area, respectively. 
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">399</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>En. Geology</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Site Effect Microzonation of Ardekan City</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>8</month>

	<year>2013</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>7</volume>

  <issue>1</issue>

  <fpage>1623</fpage>

  <lpage>1638</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Evaluation of ground response is one of the most important issues that should be considered in seismic geotechnical engineering field. Alongside the earthquake path associated to regional soil, generally earth movement in places with soft soil is greater than the movement in places with harder soil. This paper is focused to identify local soil condition of Ardekan city which influences on earthquake wave shaking. Therefore after drilling boreholes, implementing geotechnical investigations and down hole geophysical tests, the soil layer characteristics and thicknesses have been obtained. Then shear wave velocity along with soil density have been determined. With using these data it is developed a shaking geotechnical models for different city regions. Finally the ground movement parameters have been determined by   the available data obtained such as density, wave velocity along with using the equivalent linear method employing EERA program. This work was prepared for the return period of 75, 475 and2475 years. It is found that northwest region of city has the most amplification in comparison to other regions.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">389</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>En. Geology</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Seismic Landslides Hazard Zonation of Sarein, Iran (1997) Using Qualitative and Quantitative Methods</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>FatemiAghda</surname>
		<given-names>S. M.</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Bagheri</surname>
		<given-names>V.</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Mahdavifar</surname>
		<given-names>M</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>8</month>

	<year>2013</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>7</volume>

  <issue>1</issue>

  <fpage>1639</fpage>

  <lpage>1668</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

In this research, one of the new methods for seismic landslides hazard zonation (CAMEL) to predict the behavior of these types of landslides have been discussed.  It is also tried to eveluate this method with the proposed Mahdavifar method.  For achieving this result, the influence of  Sarein earthquake (1997), have been selected as a case study. In order to apply seismic hazard zonation, the methodology of Computing with Words (CW), an approach using fuzzy logic systems in which words are used in place of numbers for computing and reasoning is employed. First, the required information which includes disturbance distance, ground strength class, moisture content, shake intensity, slope angle, slope height, soil depth, terrain roughness, and vegetation have been collected using air photos, Landsat Satellite images, geological and topographic maps, and site investigation of the studied region. The data is digitized and weighted using Geological Information System (GIS). At the next step, the hazard rate and areal concentrations with respect to landslide types are calculated using CAMEL program and then, landslides hazard map produced by the above mentioned method is compared with landslides occurred as a result of Sarein earthquake. Finally, for evaluating on prediction of the earthquake-induced landslides, empirical comparison have been done between CAMEL and Mahdavifar methods.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">388</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Geotecnic</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Numerical Analysis of Deformation Modes of Reinforced Soil Walls</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Fakher</surname>
		<given-names>Ali</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic>k</italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Zare</surname>
		<given-names>Hamid</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic>l</italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Farhadi</surname>
		<given-names>Ali</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic>m</italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic>k</italic>

	</sup>Associate Professor of Geotechnical Engineering Faculty of Civil Engineering University of Tehran 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic>l</italic>

	</sup>Msc Student of Geotechnical Engineering Tarbiat Moallem University 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic>m</italic>

	</sup>Assistant Professor Kharazmi University 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>8</month>

	<year>2013</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>7</volume>

  <issue>1</issue>

  <fpage>1669</fpage>

  <lpage>1690</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

In this study using finite element procedure was used to simulate the dynamic behavior of reinforced soil walls, to evaluate their dynamic response on all types of deformation modes, different mechanisms of failure detection and identification of parameters in each of the modes and the mechanisms. Detailed numerical modeling, behavioral models and materials were described and Dynamic response of the physical model has been validated experimentally. Parametric study has been of the wall height of 5 meters by the effective parameters such as hardness, length to height ratio, the vertical reinforcement, wall height, and acceleration inputs. Three modes of deformation were observed. The study showed that occur bulging deformation mode while the use of flexible reinforcement and occur overturning deformation mode while the use of stiffness reinforcement. Stiffness reinforcements have the most effective in changing the type of deformation. Length to height ratio of reinforcements has the minimum effective in changing the type of deformation.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">391</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>En. Geology</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Velocity and attenuation of compressional waves in patchy saturated geomaterials</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>gh</surname>
		<given-names>h</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Sadeghi</surname>
		<given-names>H</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>8</month>

	<year>2013</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>7</volume>

  <issue>1</issue>

  <fpage>1691</fpage>

  <lpage>1706</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Wave velocity and attenuation are among the most important attributes of stress waves that propagate through geomaterials. Utilizing these attributes, it is possible to acquire useful information about porous geomaterials such as soil and rock and also the fluids that saturate the pores of geomaterials. The key point in order to gain this information is to establish an accurate link between field measurements of wave attributes and physical properties of geomaterials’ skeleton and pore fluid. The pore fluids and their inhomogeneous distribution fluid are among factors that affect wave velocity and attenuation to a considerable extent. Patchy saturation of pores which occurs on the scale larger than grains size but smaller than wavelength is one of the reasons that causes inhomogeneity in pore fluid distribution. The influence of such inhomogeneity is studied in present paper. Two different attenuation mechanisms including relative movement of fluid with respect to solid phase and also attenuation caused by grain to grain contact are implemented to fully assess wave attenuation. It is observed that the former attenuation is more dominant at higher frequencies compared to the latter attenuation.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">386</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>En. Geology</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Estimation of required thrust for tunnel excavation using 3D numerical modeling- Beheshtabad water transmission tunnel as a Case Study</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Sadeghi</surname>
		<given-names>H</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Mahdevari</surname>
		<given-names>S</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>8</month>

	<year>2013</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>7</volume>

  <issue>1</issue>

  <fpage>1707</fpage>

  <lpage>1724</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

One of the major challenges in tunneling is the excavation in regions with high potential of squeezing and in the case of application of full face boring machines evaluation of the required thrust in these regions is inevitable. The Beheshtabad water conveyance tunnel with 65 km in length is considered for transferring one billion cubic meter of water annually to the central part of Iran.  According to geological investigation there is a high potential of squeezing in the 19th section of tunnel. In this article, the thrust evaluation methods are investigated and the required penetration force is calculated. Then the numerical procedure applicable to thrust evaluation in the 19th section is discussed and the results are analyzed.  In addition, the required thrust to overcome shield skin frictional resistance using Ramoni's method (2010) is computed and the outputs are compared to numerical ones. As a result of numerical simulation, in order to utilize double shield TBM for the sections of 29030-31600 km and 34900-37490 km, it is required to overcut 3 cm for the favorable geomechanical locations and 10 cm for the unfavorable geomechanical conditions. Decision on the application of full face boring machines in the section of 31600-34900 km could be made providing long term parameters of host rock were determined via performing additional in situ tests in the exploration gallery.  
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">385</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>En. Geology</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Verification of geotechnical data of Qazvin _ Rasht tunnel using back analysis of instrumentation data</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Hedayatnasab</surname>
		<given-names>Kambiz</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>adib</surname>
		<given-names>ahmad</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Msc of mining engineering 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>8</month>

	<year>2013</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>7</volume>

  <issue>1</issue>

  <fpage>1725</fpage>

  <lpage>1742</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Various types of numerical analyses such as   Finite Element Method, Boundary Element Method and Distinct Element Method, are used in rock mechanics and in engineering practices for designing rock structures such as tunnels, underground caverns, slopes, dam foundations and so on. In this paper, the results of back analysis of Koohin tunnel which is located in the first section of Qazvin-Rasht railway have been presented. The main purpose of this paper is to perform the back analysis of the mentioned tunnel with the use of numerical models. For modeling the tunnel, two different sections of 30+150 km and 30+900 km are analyzed with FLAC 2D software.  To perform back analysis the suitable interval of geomechanical parameters according to the tests which were performed on the core drillings has been determined. With the use of direct method in back analysis, the errors of models have been corrected in several steps and finally the geomechanical parameters in 30+150 km station (Elastic Modulus = 0.3 GPa, Cohesion = 0.21 MPa and Internal Angle of Friction = 34°) and in 30+900 km station (Elastic Modulus = 0.3 GPa, Cohesion = 0.21 MPa and Internal Angle of Friction = 35°) have been achieved. The geomechanical parameters which obtained from back analysis are completely in the chosen interval and compliance with the results of tests which performed on core drillings. On the basis of  geomechanical parameters obtained from back analysis with the parameters which used in the design of the tunnel, the tunnel design and the structure method were confirmed.  
</body>

</article>

