<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1389</year>
	<month>8</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2010</year>
	<month>11</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>4</volume>
<number>1</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تعیین موقعیت احتمالی غارهای پنهان در دشت کرمان- باغین با استفاده از معیارهای هیدروژئوشیمیایی</title_fa>
	<title>Likely Position of hidden caves in Kerman -Baghin plain, using hydrogeochemical criteria</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa>علمی پژوهشی</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>s</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>بر اساس پژوهش‌های قبلی انجام شده، فروچاله‌های اختیارآباد و چاه دریای رفسنجان در اثر انحلال گچ‌های زیرزمینی در منطقه کرمان- رفسنجان تشکیل شده‌اند و حاکی از وجود غارهای پنهان در منطقه هستند که به عنوان یک تهدید بالقوه محسوب می‌شوند. سازندهای گچی و اشکال انحلالی موجود در سطح آن‌ها مؤید وجود کارست‌های گچی است. لذا، در این پژوهش با تهیه نقشه‌های هدایت الکتریکی و نمایه انحلال سنگ‌های تبخیری و انطباق آن‌ها با شرایط تغذیه و تحرک آب‌های زیرزمینی، چهار محدوده به عنوان محل‌های مشکوک به وجود غار زیرزمینی شناسایی شدند که محدوده اطراف روستای اختیارآباد به احتمال قریب به یقین حاوی غارهای پنهان است. در یک محل واقع در شمال روستای رباط نیز احتمال وجود غار وجود دارد. در دو محل دیگر (جنوب باغین و جنوب و جنوب باختری کبوترخان ) نیز به لحاظ معیارهای هیدروژئوشیمیایی بکار گرفته شده ممکن است غار وجود داشته باشد، ولی به دلیل نامساعد بودن شرایط هیدرودینامیکی، این احتمال ضعیف بنظر می‌رسد.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>The previous studies underteaken in the region indicate that the Ekhtiarabad and Chah-Darya sinkholes have occurred as a result of dissolution of underground gypsum rocks. Hence, they represent the likelyhood of hidden and threatening caves in the region. The presence of gypsiferous formations having surficial karstic features attest to this supposition. So, in order to determine the possible dissolving sites which may contain caves, the electrical conductivity and evaporite dissolution index maps of Kerman-Baghin aquifier were prepared and matched with groundwater recharge and mobility conditions. Accordingly, four suspected hidden- cave sites were recognized which include a large area around Ekhtiarabad village (as the most suspected site), one spot at the northwest of Baghin Plain and two other areas (south of Baghin and south and southwest or Kabutarkhan). Based on the utilized hydrogeochemical criteria, these last two areas may contain hidden caves, but, due to unsuitable hydrodynamic conditions, the possibility seems weak.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>کارست گچی , غار , فروچاله , دشت کرمان- باغین ,</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Gypsum karst , Cave , Sinkhole , Kerman-Baghin plain ,</keyword>
	<start_page>855</start_page>
	<end_page>878</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-3-54&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Ahmad</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Abbasnejad</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>احمد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عباس نژاد</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600193</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600193</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Shahid Bahonar University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید باهنر</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
