<ici-import>
 <journal 	issn="2228-6837"/>
 <issue number="2" volume="10" year="2016" publicationDate="2016-11-01T10:20:15" numberOfArticles="8">
			<article externalId="A-10-674-1">
			<type>OTHERS_CITABLE</type>
			
					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>مقایسه روش های مختلف تحلیل پاسخ لرزه ای زمین های نرم مستعد روانگرایی در برابر زلزله های میدان دور و نزدیک</title>
						<abstract>با توجه به&#8204; اهمیت روزافزون زمین&#173;شناسی محلی و شرایط زمین&#173;ریخت&#8204;شناسی بر پاسخ لرزه&#173;ای زمین، در این مقاله به&#8204;بررسی جزئیات مربوط به اثر وجود لایه&#173;های روان&#8204;گرا بر پاسخ لرزه&#173;ای سطح زمین می&#8204;پردازیم. به&#8204;منظور بررسی تفاوت&#173; روش&#173;های مختلف تحلیل پاسخ زمین، ابتدا تحلیل بر مبنای روش معادل&#173;خطی مبتنی بر مدل تنش کل در حوزۀ فرکانس و سپس بر اساس روش غیرخطی با مدل&#173;های تنش کل، تنش مؤثر و اعمال افزایش اضافه فشار آب حفره&#8204;ای در حوزۀ زمان انجام شده است. در این راستا از ویرایش پنجم نرم&#173;افزار DEEPSOIL بر مبنای جدیدترین دستاوردها و تکنیک&#173;های مختلف در هردو حوزۀ حل، استفاده شده است. محل بررسی شده برای انجام این تحقیق، پروژۀ بندر LNG عسلویه واقع در جنوب ایران است. با توجه به پژوهش&#8204;های رایج لرزه&#173;خیزی انجام شده و عدم ثبت داده&#173;های واقعی زلزله میدان&#173; نزدیک در محل پروژه به&#8204;ویژه برای گسل محتمل آن، از روش شبیه&#173;سازی مصنوعی زلزله&#160;برای گسل مولد استفاده شده&#173;است. همین&#173;طور بر اساس بررسی&#8204;های عرف لرزه&#173;خیزی در محل، سه زلزله میدان دور نیز برای انجام تحلیل&#173;های پاسخ زمین انتخاب شده&#173;اند. سپس به&#8204;منظور درک&#160;بهتر از پاسخ&#173;های به&#8204;دست آمده، طیف پاسخ&#173;های حاصل با طیف طرح شتاب ارائه شده در برخی از آیین&#173;نامه&#173;های معتبر مقایسه شده&#173;اند. نتایج&#8204; حاصل نشان می&#173;دهد که در نظر گرفتن اثر پالس در مؤلفۀ افقی شتاب در جهت عمود بر راستای گسل برای زلزله&#173;های میدان &#173;نزدیک، پاسخ سطح زمین و محتوای فرکانسی آن را تحت تأثیر قرار می&#173;دهد. به&#8204;طوری&#8204;که پاسخ&#173;های به&#8204;دست آمده در سطح زمین در حوزۀ زمان با توجه به در نظر گرفتن ماهیت رفتار غیرخطی خاک و اعمال افزایش اضافه فشار آب حفره&#173;ای با مقایسۀ پاسخ&#173;ها در حوزۀ فرکانس مبتنی بر روش معادل&#173;خطی، تفاوت&#173;های زیادی دارند.&#160;</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2276-fa.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2016-06-08T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>3379</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>3404</pageTo>
				
							<doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.2.3379</doi>
						<keywords>
<keyword>پاسخ لرزه ای ساختگاه</keyword>
<keyword>روش معادل خطی</keyword>
<keyword>روش غیرخطی</keyword>
<keyword>فشار آب حفره ای</keyword>
<keyword>روانگرایی</keyword>
<keyword></keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				

					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>Comparison the Different Methods of Seismic Response Analysis in Liquefiable sites against Near and Far-Field Earthquakes</title>
						<abstract>Due to the increasing importance of geomorphologic conditions on the seismic ground response, the effect of liquefiable soils on seismic ground surface response is discussed. At first, the equivalent linear analysis based on total stress model in the frequency domain is carried out and then the nonlinear analyses based on total stress, effective stress model and considering the pore water pressure development in time domain are done in order to evaluate the differences between the several types of ground response analysis methods. DEEPSOIL.Ver5 software is used based on the latest achievements and various techniques in both solution domains. LNG port project in Assaluyeh, situated in south of Iran, is considered as a case study. Due to lack of the real data recorded near-field fault at the project site, the simulated method is used in order to create the artificial earthquake. Also three far-field earthquakes have been selected based on conventional seismic hazard studies for the seismic ground response analysis. Then, in order to better understanding of the obtained responses, the resulted responses spectra are compared with the acceleration design spectra provided in some valid codes. The result of this study indicates that the pulse effect in the horizontal component of acceleration perpendicular to the fault plane direction, affects severely the surface ground response of the near-field earthquake. The obtained results of the nonlinear modeling of the soil with excess pore water pressure build-up in the time-domain are extremely different from those of frequency-domain responses based on the equivalent linear method. In addition, because of the inherent linearity of equivalent linear analysis which can lead to spurious resonances in ground responses, the peak ground acceleration in the time-domain is lower than the frequency-domain.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2276-en.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2016-06-08T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>3379</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>3404</pageTo>
				
							<doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.2.3379</doi>
						<keywords>
<keyword>Site seismic response</keyword>
<keyword>Equivalent linear method</keyword>
<keyword>Nonlinear method</keyword>
<keyword>Pore water pressure</keyword>
<keyword>Liquefaction</keyword>
<keyword></keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad</name>
	<surname>Adampira</surname>
	<email>m.adampira@srbiau.ac.ir</email>
	     <order>1</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Hamid</name>
	<surname>Alielahi</surname>
	<email>h.alielahi@iauz.ac.ir</email>
	     <order>2</order>
        <instituteAffiliation>Islamic Azad university, Science and Research Branch, Tehran, Iran</instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mehdi</name>
	<surname>Panji</surname>
	<email>m.panji@srbiau.ac.ir</email>
	     <order>3</order>
        <instituteAffiliation>Islamic Azad University, Zanjan Branch</instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Hamid</name>
	<surname>Koohsari</surname>
	<email>h.koohsari@gmail.com</email>
	     <order>4</order>
        <instituteAffiliation>Islamic Azad University Zanjan Branch</instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	</authors>


	</article>



			<article externalId="A-10-108-1">
			<type>OTHERS_CITABLE</type>
			
					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>تحلیل تراوش در تونل انتقال آب چشمه روزیه در مرحله ساخت و بهره‌برداری با بهره‌گیری از شبیه‌سازی عددی</title>
						<abstract>با توجه به قرارگیری بخش عمدۀ ایران در ناحیۀ خشک و بیابانی حفر تونل&#8204;های انتقال آب امری&#8204; اجتناب&#8204;ناپذیر است. یکی از چالش&#8204;های اساسی در ساخت این تونل&#8204;ها ورود آب به آن در مرحلۀ ساخت و بهره&#8204;برداری است. تونل انتقال آب چشمۀ روزیه به&#8204;طول 3200 متر بخشی از طرح انتقال آب به شهر سمنان است که در 30 کیلومتری شمال شرق سمنان ساخته شده است. بر اساس اطلاعات حاصل از گمانه&#8204;های حفاری شده، تونل از نقطه&#8204;نظر ژئومکانیکی به 8 پهنه تقسیم شده که در این تحقیق بعد از بررسی پارامترهای ژئومکانیکی و هیدروژئولوژیکی تونل با توجه به دبی آب ورودی به تونل در حین ساخت ضریب نفوذپذیری سنگ میزبان تونل در هر پهنه با استفاده از تحلیل برگشتی و بر اساس نتایج شبیه&#8204;سازی عددی ارزیابی شده است. در ادامه برررسی پارامتری بر ضخامت زون تزریق، ضریب نفوذپذیری پوشش و زون تزریق در هر پهنه انجام شده است. بر اساس نتایج این پژوهش، تأثیر تغییرات ضخامت زون تزریق بر دبی آب ورودی به تونل ناچیز است. از این رو، با فرض ضخامت 3 متر برای زون تزریق، ضریب نفوذپذیری سنگ میزبان بعد از تزریق ارزیابی شده است. تزریق سیمان می&#8204;تواند نفوذپذیری سنگ میزبان را از 10 تا 1000 مرتبه بسته به نفوذپذیری اولیه سنگ کاهش دهد. دبی آب ورودی به تونل در هر پهنه با استفاده از تحلیل توأمان هیدرومکانیکی نیز محاسبه شد. نتایج تحلیل نشان داد که دبی ورودی به تونل در تحلیل توأمان 50 تا 70 درصد کم&#8204;تر از تحلیل هیدرولیکی است.&#160;</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2329-fa.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2016-06-08T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>3405</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>3426</pageTo>
				
							<doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.2.3405</doi>
						<keywords>
<keyword>تحلیل توامان هیدرومکانیکی</keyword>
<keyword>شبیه‌سازی عددی</keyword>
<keyword>تونل چشمه روزیه</keyword>
<keyword>تراوش آب</keyword>
<keyword></keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				

					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>Flow analysis of the Rozieh water conveyance tunnel during the construction and operation phase using numerical simulation</title>
						<abstract>Because most part of Iran country is located in a dry climate, construction of water conveyance tunnels is inevitable. One of the major challenges in the construction of these tunnels is inflow of water into the tunnel during the construction and operation phase. The Rozieh water conveyance tunnel whose length is 3200 meters is a part of water conveyance project to the Semnan city and it is located 30 k NE of Semnan city. In accordance with the drilled boreholes, the tunnel route has been classified into eight zones from the geotechnical view. Then the permeability coefficients of host rock were calculated using back analysis approach on the basis of numerical simulation results and water inflow quantity during the construction phase. A parametric study was done on the lining and cement injection zone permeability and the thickness of cement injection zone. According to this study, the effect of injection zone thickness variation on the water inflow quantity is negligible. So with the assumption of 3 meters thickness for the injection zone, the permeability coefficient of host rock after injection were evaluated. Dependent on the initial rock permeability, cement injection could reduce the rock permeability 10 to 1000 times. In addition, the water inflow into the tunnel was calculated using hydro-mechanical coupling analysis. According to this analysis, the water inflow calculated by the hydro-mechanical coupling analysis is 50 to 70 percent less than the hydraulic analysis.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2329-en.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2016-06-08T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>3405</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>3426</pageTo>
				
							<doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.2.3405</doi>
						<keywords>
<keyword>Hydro-Mechanical Coupling Analysis</keyword>
<keyword>Numerical Simulation</keyword>
<keyword>The Rozieh Tunnel</keyword>
<keyword>Flow Analysis</keyword>
<keyword></keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name></name>
	<surname>Ahmadzadeh</surname>
	     <order>1</order>
        <instituteAffiliation>Isfahan University of technology; Mining Engineering Faculty</instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>R</name>
	<surname>Bagherpour</surname>
	<email>bagherpour@yahoo.com</email>
	     <order>2</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Saeed</name>
	<surname>Mahdevari</surname>
	<email>smahdevari@cc.iut.ac.ir</email>
	     <order>3</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	</authors>


	</article>



			<article externalId="A-10-409-1">
			<type>OTHERS_CITABLE</type>
			
					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>بررسی جایگاه سنگ های مارنی در سیستم های طبقه بندی مهندسی توده سنگ مطالعه موردی : ساختگاه سد دوستی</title>
						<abstract>با انتخاب 222 متر از مغزه&#173;های حفاری در محور سرریز ساختگاه سد دوستی از سنگ&#173;های مارنی سازند آب تلخ و انجام طبقه&#173;بندی تودۀ سنگ در سیستم&#173;های RQD، RSR، RMR و Q، نمونه&#173;های بررسی شده در رده&#173;های مختلف طبقه&#173;بندی&#173;های مذکور قرار گرفت و فروانی هریک به&#8204;دست آمد. نتیجه تحقیق نشان می&#173;دهد که طبقه&#173;بندی RMR مناسب&#173;ترین روش ارزیابی تودۀ سنگ مارن بررسی شده است و بیش&#8204;ترین هم&#8204;بستگی را با شاخص RQD نشان می&#173;دهد. اعتبارسنجی روابط مختلف بین Q-RMR با استفاده از نسبت خطا (ER) نشان می&#8204;دهد که رابطۀ کامرون و همکاران (1981) و مورنو (1982) دارای کم&#8204;ترین نسبت خطا است و در سنگ&#173;های مارنی بررسی شده دارای بیش&#8204;ترین اعتبار است. رابطۀ بنیاوسکی (1989) تعیین&#173;کننده حدپایینی منحنی Q-RMR و رابطۀ کامرون و&#160; همکاران (1981) حد بالایی این رابطه در سنگ&#173;های مارنی است.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2325-fa.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2016-06-08T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>3427</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>3444</pageTo>
				
							<doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.2.3427</doi>
						<keywords>
<keyword>طبقه بندی مهندسی توده سنگ</keyword>
<keyword>سنگ های مارنی</keyword>
<keyword>زمین شناسی مهندسی</keyword>
<keyword>سد دوستی</keyword>
<keyword>سازند آب تلخ</keyword>
<keyword></keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				

					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>Investigation of position marlston in rock mass enginnering classification system,case study: Doosti Dam</title>
						<abstract>Marly rocks of Abtalkh formation were classified by Q, RMR, RSR and RQD rock mass classification systems using 222 meters logs from exploratory boreholes in Doosti dam site. The results show that the RMR is the most suitable method for classification of studied rock masses and has highest correlation coefficient with RQD. The validity of different Q-RMR equations was studied using error ratio (ER). Cameron et al. (1981) and Morno (1982) equations have lowest ER and highest validity for studied marlstones. Bieniawski (1989) and Cameron (1981) relationships are lower and higher limits of equations for marly rocks respectively.&#160;</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2325-en.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2016-06-08T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>3427</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>3444</pageTo>
				
							<doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.2.3427</doi>
						<keywords>
<keyword>Engineering classification of rock masses</keyword>
<keyword>marlstones</keyword>
<keyword>geological engineering</keyword>
<keyword>Doosti dam</keyword>
<keyword>Abtalkh formation</keyword>
<keyword></keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>hamed</name>
	<surname>rezaiy</surname>
	<email>rezaiy.hamed@gmail.com</email>
	     <order>1</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name></name>
	<surname></surname>
	     <order>2</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	</authors>


	</article>



			<article externalId="A-10-1036-1">
			<type>OTHERS_CITABLE</type>
			
					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>ارزیابی ریسک محیط زیستی سد پاوه‌رود زنجان در مرحله ساختمانی با استفاده از تلفیق روش های TOPSIS و RAM-D</title>
						<abstract>هدف از انجام این تحقیق، شناخت، بررسی و ارزیابی ریسک سد پاوه&#8204;رود در مرحلۀ ساختمانی است. پس از جمع&#8204;آوری و بررسی اطلاعات مربوط به شرایط محیط&#8204;زیست منطقۀ بررسی شده و شرایط فنی ساخت سد، لیستی از عوامل احتمالی ریسک به&#8204;صورت پرسش&#8204;نامه تهیه و برای بررسی صحت آن&#8204;ها، در اختیار گروهی متخصص شامل نخبگان و اساتید در رشته&#8204;های مرتبط با محیط زیست و عمران سد قرارگرفت. تعداد پرسش&#8204;نامه&#8204;ها بر اساس فرمول کوکران تعیین شد. بدین&#8204;صورت که ابتدا، به&#8204;منظور تحلیل پرسش&#8204;نامه&#8204;های به&#8204;دست آمده و ریسک&#8204;های موجود در منطقه در قالب طیف لیکرت، از گروه کارشناسی در تحقیق خواسته شد تا امتیازدهی کنند. پس از تجزیه و تحلیل امتیازات داده شده با استفاده از یافته&#8204;های روش 1PHA، از روش 2TOPSIS به&#8204;منظور اولویت&#8204;بندی ریسک&#8204;های شناسایی شدۀ سد پاوه&#8204;رود استفاده شد. نتایج به&#8204;دست آمده از این روش نشان داد که از بین 36 عامل ریسک، فرسایش در اولویت اول قرار گرفت.&#160;پس از اولویت&#8204;بندی بین عوامل ریسک، ارزیابی ریسک با استفاده از روش 1RAM-D صورت گرفت که تأثیر بر منطقه حفاظت شده سرخ&#8204;آباد با امتیاز 9، فرسایش با امتیاز 6 و کار در ارتفاع با امتیاز 3 مهم&#8204;ترین ریسک&#8204;های سد پاوه&#8204;رود شناخته شدند. به&#8204;منظور کاهش اثرات ریسک&#8204;های سد در فاز ساختمانی برنامه مدیریت محیط&#8204;زیستی ضروری است و بدین&#8204;منظور برای رویارویی با ریسک&#8204;های شناسایی شده، در انتها گزینه&#8204;های کاهش ریسک پیشنهاد شد.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2328-fa.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2016-06-08T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>3445</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>3464</pageTo>
				
							<doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.2.3445</doi>
						<keywords>
<keyword>ارزیابی ریسک محیط زیستی</keyword>
<keyword>سد</keyword>
<keyword>روش TOPSIS</keyword>
<keyword>روشRAM-D</keyword>
<keyword>ارزیابی مقدماتی ریسک</keyword>
<keyword></keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				

					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>Assessing Environmental Risk Caused by Zanjan’s Paverood Dam in its Construction Stage Using a combination of TOPSIS and RAM-D Methods</title>
						<abstract>Objective of the present research is to identify, analyze, and assess risk of Paveroud Dam during construction phase. Following collection and analysis of the information related to environmental conditions of the area of study and technical specifications of dam construction, a list of probable risk factors was prepared in the form of a questionnaire, and for verification, the questionnaires were provided to a group of specialists consisting of elites and professors specialized at the disciplines relevant to environment and civil engineering. Number of questionnaires was determined based on Cochran&#8217;s formula. In the first step, the expert group in the research was asked to score in Likert scale format so as to analyze the acquired responses and the risks present in the region. Having analyzed the scores using the findings of PHA method, TOPSIS technique was applied to prioritize the identified risks of Paveroud Dam. The results indicated that erosion had the highest priority among 36 risk factors. After prioritization among the risk factors, risk was also assessed using RAM-D technique in which &#8220;impact on Sorkhabad Protected Zone with 9 scores, &#8220;erosion&#8221; with 6 scores, and &#8220;work at high elevation&#8221; with 3 scores were recognized as three major risks of Paveroud Dam. In order to mitigate the effects of dam risks during construction phase, environmental management planning is crucial, and for this purpose, risk mitigation choices were recommended at the end aimed at coping with the identified risks.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2328-en.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2016-06-08T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>3445</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>3464</pageTo>
				
							<doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.2.3445</doi>
						<keywords>
<keyword>Environmental risk Assessment</keyword>
<keyword>Dam</keyword>
<keyword>TOPSIS method</keyword>
<keyword>RAM-D method</keyword>
<keyword>PHA method</keyword>
<keyword></keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>sahar</name>
	<surname>rezaian</surname>
	<email>s_rezaian@yahoo.com</email>
	     <order>1</order>
        <instituteAffiliation>دانشیار گروه محیط زیست، دانشکده فنی و مهندسی،دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران شمال</instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>seyed ali</name>
	<surname>jozi</surname>
	<email>sajozi@yahoo.com</email>
	     <order>2</order>
        <instituteAffiliation>Assistant Professor, Department of Environment, Faculty of Science, Islamic Azad University, Shahrood Branch, Iran</instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>sadaf</name>
	<surname>ataee</surname>
	<email>sadaf_ataee@yahoo.com</email>
	     <order>3</order>
        <instituteAffiliation>M.Sc. of Environmental Assessment, Islamic Azad University, science and Research Branch, Tehran, Iran</instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	</authors>


	</article>



			<article externalId="A-10-936-1">
			<type>OTHERS_CITABLE</type>
			
					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>رسوب ‌شناسی ترکیب نهشته‌های رودخانه شربیان به عنوان ماده اولیه آسفالت گرم و بهینه‌سازی آن با استفاده از آهک هیدراته</title>
						<abstract>رودخانۀ شربیان در استان آذربایجان&#173;شرقی، شهرستان سراب،&#173;&#173;&#173;&#173;&#173;&#173;&#173;&#173; دهستان شربیان واقع است. رسوبات این رودخانه از واحدهای سنگی متعلق به الیگومیوسن و میوسن تأمین می&#173;شود که شامل واحدهای سنگی کنگلومرا، ماسه&#173;سنگ، آهک، مارن و شیل است. این رسوبات مواد اولیۀ آسفالت دو کارخانۀ آسفالت گرم را که در مجاورت رودخانه ساخته شده&#173;اند، تأمین می&#173;کند و آسفالت تهیه شده عمدتاً در استان&#173;های مجاور استفاده می&#173;شود که آب و هوای نسبتاً سرد دارند. آنالیز ترکیبی این رسوبات بیان&#8204;گر میزان سیلیس زیاد (60 درصد) است و آسفالت&#173;هایی که از این رسوبات تهیه می&#173;شوند، در فصول سرد سال مستعد پدیدۀ عریان&#173;شدگی می&#8204;شوند. طی این فرایند، با نفوذ رطوبت به&#8204;داخل مصالح سنگی و مخلوط آسفالتی، اتصال قیر- مصالح تضعیف شده و زمینه برای تخریب آسفالت فراهم می&#173;گردد. با توجه به این&#8204;که نقش رسوبات و تأثیر آن در کیفیت آسفالت در این منطقه بررسی نشده است، از این رو، در این پژوهش علاوه بر پرداختن به&#8204;علت رسوب&#173;شناسی تخریب آسفالت، راه&#173;حل&#8204;های مقابله با این پدیده نیز بررسی و ارائه شده است. این تحقیق بر اساس روش&#173;های مرسوم رسوب&#173;شناسی، استانداردهای مختلف ASTM،AASHTO و نیز آیین&#173;نامه&#173;های راه&#8204;سازی و دستورالعمل&#173;های وزارت راه و شهرسازی صورت گرفته است. در این پژوهش برای مقابله با پدیدۀ عریان&#173;شدگی، از تأثیر توأم آهک هیدراته (فیلر آهکی) و فیلر طبیعی مصالح سنگی با نسبت&#8204;های متفاوت (با 3-5/1 درصد آهک&#160;هیدراته) استفاده شده و پارامترهای استحکام، نرمی، مقاومت کششی غیرمستقیم به&#8204;عنوان معیارهایی برای ارزیابی کیفیت و دوام آسفالت در مقابل پدیدۀ عریان&#8204;شدگی ارزیابی شده است. نتایج تحقیق بیان&#8204;گر آن است که با اضافه کردن افزودنی&#173;های مذکور در نسبت&#173;های مختلف، پارامترهای مذکور تغییر یافته و نسبت به حالت اولیه بهتر می&#173;گردند. از این رو، آسفالت تولیدی دارای کیفیت و دوام بیش&#8204;تری نسبت به&#8204;روش&#8204;ها و طرح&#8204;های گذشته است. بر اساس این نتایج، درجه عریان&#8204;شدگی در حداکثر حالت این نسبت یعنی با ترکیب 3 درصد آهک، به عدد 1 رسیده و با افزایش و بهبود سایر پارامترها، پدیدۀ عریان&#8204;شدگی تقریباً از بین می&#173;رود. بر این اساس، به&#8204;کارگیری نتایج این تحقیق می&#173;تواند از تخریب جاده&#173;های آسفالتی بکاهد و از لحاظ اقتصادی بسیار مطلوب واقع گردد.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2291-fa.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2016-06-08T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>3465</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>3482</pageTo>
				
							<doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.2.3465</doi>
						<keywords>
<keyword>آسفالت گرم</keyword>
<keyword>آهک هیدراته</keyword>
<keyword>استحکام و نرمی</keyword>
<keyword>عریان‌شدگی</keyword>
<keyword>مقاومت کششی غیر‌مستقیم</keyword>
<keyword></keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				

					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>Sedimentology of fluvial deposits composition of Sharbyan River as raw material for hot asphalt and its optimization using hydrated lime</title>
						<abstract>The Sharbyan river is located in the Sharbyan village, Sarab, East Azarbaijan province. This river alluvials are supplied from rock units belonging to Oligo-miocene and Miocene, including conglomerate, sandy lime, limestone, marl and shale. These deposits are used as raw materials of producing hot asphalt in two asphalt plants that have been built in the vicinity of this river, and the produced asphalt is used mainly in the neighbor provinces that have rather cold climate. Combined analysis of the sediments indicate high level of silica, around 60 percent, for which&#160; the prepared asphalt&#160; is prone to stripping phenomenon in the cold seasons. During this process, the moisture penetration in aggregates and asphalt mixtures, causes weakening bitumen-asphalt materials bounding and finally asphalt demolition.&#160; The role of sediments and its impact on the quality of asphalt has not been studied in this area, therefore, the solutions for dealing with this phenomenon is also examined and presented. This study is based on the conventional sedimentology methods, different standards of ASTM, AASHTO and Ministry of Roads and Urban Development guidelines. In this study, the combined effects of hydrated lime (lime filler) and natural filter materials with different proportions was used to deal with the stripping phenomenon, and&#160; the parameters of strength, softness, indirect tensile strength, asphalt quality and durability criteria, have been appraised. The results show that these parameters are improved using additives in various proportions and the produced asphalt quality and durability is better. The results illustrate, when the lime is used in its maximum ratio of 3%, stripping score is 1 and is disappeared by other parameters improvement</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2291-en.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2016-06-08T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>3465</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>3482</pageTo>
				
							<doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.2.3465</doi>
						<keywords>
<keyword>Hot Asphalt</keyword>
<keyword>Hydrated Lime</keyword>
<keyword>Indirect Tensile Strength</keyword>
<keyword>Stability and Flow</keyword>
<keyword>Stripping</keyword>
<keyword></keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>abbas</name>
	<surname>zeighmi</surname>
	<email>tsml_54@yahoo.com</email>
	     <order>1</order>
        <instituteAffiliation>Expert Soil Mechanics / Soil Mechanics Laboratory Company</instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name></name>
	<surname></surname>
	<email>1234@yahoo.com</email>
	     <order>2</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	</authors>


	</article>



			<article externalId="A-10-1032-1">
			<type>OTHERS_CITABLE</type>
			
					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>پهنه بندی خطرزمین لغزش در محدوده پی و مخزن سد پلرود با روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی (AHP)</title>
						<abstract>مقاله حاضر نتیجۀ ارزیابی و پهنه&#8204;بندی خطرناپایدار&#8204;های دامنه&#8204;ای در محدودۀ بدنه و دریاچه سد پلرود را ارائه می&#8204;کند. سد مخزنی پلرود یکی از سدهایی است که در منطقۀ گیلان و در فاصلۀ 29 کیلومتری جنوب رودسر بر رودخانۀ پلرود در حال بررسی و ساخت است. شرایط ریخت&#8204;شناسی طبیعی از یک&#8204;سو و وجود نهشته&#8204;های تحکیم نیافته و سازندهای سنگی خرد شده ناشی از گسل&#8204;های موجود در ساختگاه سد از سوی دیگر، محل احداث بدنه سد و دریاچه آن را مستعد ناپایداری&#8204;های دامنه&#8204;ای ساخته است. بررسی سابقه تاریخی منطقه نیز بیان&#8204;گر پتانسیل زیاد دامنه&#8204;های منطقه برای ناپایداری&#8204;های دامنه&#8204;ای است. از جمله این ناپایداری&#8204;ها می&#173;توان به زمین&#8204;لغزش بزگ رخ داده در سال 1374 اشاره کرد که سبب خسارت&#8204;های فراوانی در منطقه شده است. از این&#8204;رو، تعیین مناطق پرخطر محدوده مخزن و ساختگاه پیش از آب&#8204;گیری آن ضرورت زیادی دارد. در این پژوهش با استفاده از عمده عوامل مؤثر در وقوع زمین&#173;لغزش، شامل درصد شیب، جهت&#160; شیب، لیتولوژی، فاصله از گسل، فاصله از جاده، فاصله از آبراهه، ارتفاع، پوشش گیاهی و میزان بارندگی، نقشۀ پهنه&#8204;بندی خطرزمین لغزش تهیه شده است. برای وزن&#8204;دهی به این عوامل، روش تحلیل مراتبی(AHP) در سیستم اطلاعات جغرافیایی(GIS)، استفاده شده&#173;است. نتایج این پژوهش نشان می&#8204;دهد که حدود 26 درصد از شیب&#8204;های مشرف به دریاچۀ سد در منطقه با خطر زیاد قرار می&#173;گیرند. هم&#8204;چنین مشخص شد که از بین عوامل 9&#8204;گانه که به&#8204;نحوی در وقوع زمین&#8204;لغزش منطقه نقش ایفا می&#8204;کنند، تأثیر جهت شیب و لیتولوژی نسبت به دیگر عوامل بیش&#8204;تر است</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2327-fa.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2016-06-08T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>3483</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>3500</pageTo>
				
							<doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.2.3483</doi>
						<keywords>
<keyword>سد پلرود</keyword>
<keyword>زمین ‌لغزش</keyword>
<keyword>پهنه‌بندی مدل AHP</keyword>
<keyword>سیستم اطلاعات جغرافیایی</keyword>
<keyword></keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				

					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>Landslide hazard zonatoin of Polroud Dam site using Analytic Hierarchical Process (AHP) method</title>
						<abstract>This paper presents landslide assessment and landslide hazard zonation of the Polroud Dam area. Polroud Dam is one of the largest dams that are in construction, 29 km south of Roudsar in Gilan Province. Considering to geomorphology and geological conditions of the area, the site is susceptible to landslide hazard. Field survey shows many evidences of the instabilities especially in the slopes overlooking to the dam and the reservoir. The historical record also demonstrates high potential of the region to slope instabilities. A large landslide that occurred in 1996 discern that the frequency of the hazard in the region. Therefore, Identification of the landslide potential hazard is vital before impounding the reservoir. In this study, we investigated landslide hazard in the site and we have prepared landslide hazard zonation map using the main parameters. These parameters include; slope percent, slope aspect, lithology, fault, roads, drainage catchment, elevation, vegetation and precipitation amount. Analytic Hierarchical Process (AHP) has been used to prepare and to cross the maps. The results show that about 26 percent of the slopes are situated in highly hazard zones. It was determined also that lithology and slope aspects play main role in occurring of the landslides in the study area.
&#160;</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2327-en.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2016-06-08T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>3483</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>3500</pageTo>
				
							<doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.2.3483</doi>
						<keywords>
<keyword>Polroud Dam</keyword>
<keyword>landslide hazard</keyword>
<keyword>AHP</keyword>
<keyword>GIS</keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name></name>
	<surname></surname>
	<email>keshavarzm@yahoo.com</email>
	     <order>1</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>M</name>
	<surname>Fallah</surname>
	     <order>2</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	</authors>


	</article>



			<article externalId="A-10-841-1">
			<type>OTHERS_CITABLE</type>
			
					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>بررسی آزمایشگاهی تاثیر زاویه شیب کناره و دانه بندی ذرات بر فرسایش نشتی سواحل رودخانه</title>
						<abstract>جریان زیرسطحی به&#8204;عنوان بخش چشم&#8204;گیری از جریان آبراهه و عامل مهمی در بار رسوبی رودخانه&#173;ها است. هدف این تحقیق بررسی فرسایش نشتی کنارۀ رودخانه&#8204;ها در لایۀ ماسه&#8204;ای با دانه&#8204;بندی متفاوت در کنارۀ رودخانه است. در این تحقیق به مطالعه و بررسی آزمایشگاهی تأثیر اندازۀ ذرات خاک و هم&#8204;چنین شیب کنارۀ رودخانه بر فرسایش نشتی پرداخته شده است. بدین&#8204;منظور تعدادی آزمایش در یک لایسی&#8204;متر برای چهار شیب&#173;های مختلف و دانه&#8204;بندی&#173;های مختلف انجام شد. نتایج نشان داد که عدد رینولدز محیط متخلخل نقش اساسی در عمق حفره آبشستگی لایۀ غیرچسبنده دارد. هم&#8204;چنین مشاهده شد که زمان شروع به حرکت ذرات با افزایش قطر مشخصه آن&#8204;ها کاهش پیدا می&#173;کند.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2197-fa.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2016-06-08T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>3501</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>3516</pageTo>
				
							<doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.2.3501</doi>
						<keywords>
<keyword>جریان زیرسطحی</keyword>
<keyword>فرسایش نشتی</keyword>
<keyword>شیب کناره رودخانه</keyword>
<keyword>عمق آبشستگی</keyword>
<keyword></keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				

					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>Experimental Investigation of Bank Angle and Grain Size ِDistribution Effects on Seepage Erosion of River Banks</title>
						<abstract>Subsurface flow contributes considerably to river flow and plays an important role in river sediment loads. This research has been focused on investigation of soil properties and bankstream slope on seepage erosion. For this purpose a series of lysimeter experiments were performed for four different slopes of bankstream by varying the soil grain sizes. The obtained results indicate that Reynolds number in porous medium plays an effective role in depth of scour hole in noncohesive layer. It was observed that the time of beginning of sediment motion decreases with an increase in the soil grain size.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2197-en.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2016-06-08T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>3501</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>3516</pageTo>
				
							<doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.2.3501</doi>
						<keywords>
<keyword>Subsurface Flow</keyword>
<keyword>Seepage Erosion</keyword>
<keyword>Bankstream Slope</keyword>
<keyword>Depth of Scour Hole</keyword>
<keyword></keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Azam</name>
	<surname>Masoodi</surname>
	<email>a_masoodi@sbu.ac.ir</email>
	     <order>1</order>
        <instituteAffiliation>Shahid Beheshti University- Shahid Abbaspur</instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Reza</name>
	<surname>Majdzadeh Tabatabi</surname>
	<email>m_majdzadeh@sbu.ac.ir</email>
	     <order>2</order>
        <instituteAffiliation>Assistant Professor/ Shahid Abbaspur College of Shahid Beheshti University</instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Ali</name>
	<surname>Noorzad</surname>
	<email>a_noorzad@sbu.ac.ir</email>
	     <order>3</order>
        <instituteAffiliation>Assistant Professor Shahid Abbaspur College of Shahid Beheshti University</instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	</authors>


	</article>



			<article externalId="A-10-217-1">
			<type>OTHERS_CITABLE</type>
			
					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>طراحی بهینه دیوار‌های خاکی میخ‌کوبی شده بر‌مبنای تغییر مکان تحت بار‌های لرزه‌ای</title>
						<abstract>میخ&#8204;کوبی خاک از روش&#173;های رایج برای پایدارسازی گود&#173;برداری&#173;ها به&#8204;صورت موقت و دائم است که در صورت استفاده از آن به&#8204;صورت سازه دائم، بررسی لرزه&#173;ای این سازه&#173;ها اهمیت دارد. برای بررسی رفتار دیوار&#173;های خاکی میخ&#8204;کوبی شده تحت بار زلزله چند مدل&#8204;سازی فیزیکی انجام شده و اطلاعات محدودی موجود است. برای بررسی اثرات انواع پارامتر&#8204;ها بر پایداری و عملکرد دیوارهای خاکی میخ&#8204;کوبی شده می&#8204;توان از مدل&#173;سازی عددی استفاده کرد که در پژوهش حاضر از این روش استفاده شده است. در این تحقیق، به بررسی تأثیر پارامتر&#173;های مختلفی از جمله فاصله، چیدمان و طول میخ&#173;ها و ارتفاع دیوار بر تغییر مکان لرزه&#8204;ای دیوار&#173;های خاکی میخ&#8204;کوبی شده تحت شتاب&#173;نگاشت&#8204;های مختلف زلزله پرداخته شده است. برای بررسی اثر چیدمان و طول میخ&#173;ها در عملکرد این سازه&#173;ها، دو چیدمان یک&#8204;نواخت و متغیر در ارتفاع استفاده شده است. برای بررسی تأثیر فاصلۀ میخ&#173;ها و ارتفاع دیوار، فواصل 2 و 5/1 متر، و ارتفاع&#8204; 14، 20 و 26 متر در نظر گرفته شده &#160;است. تحلیل&#8204;های لرزه&#173;ای با استفاده از نرم&#173;افزار المان محدود دوبعدی Plaxis صورت گرفته است. برای محاسبۀ طول میخ&#173;ها، ضریب اطمینان پایداری مدل&#8204;های مختلف ثابت در نظر گرفته شده و از نرم&#173;افزار تعادل حدی GeoSlope بهره برده شده است. پس از تعیین طول میخ&#8204;ها بر اساس ضریب اطمینان پایداری ثابت، تغییر شکل مدل&#8204;ها تحت شتاب نگاشت&#8204;های مختلف محاسبه شده و توصیه&#8204;هایی در زمینه کاهش تغییر مکان لرزه&#8204;ای دیوارهای میخ&#8204;کوبی شده ارائه شده است.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2561-fa.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2016-10-04T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>3517</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>3536</pageTo>
				
							<doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.2.3517</doi>
						<keywords>
<keyword>دیوار خاکی میخکوبی شده</keyword>
<keyword>رفتار لرزه‌ای</keyword>
<keyword>مدل‌سازی اجزای محدود</keyword>
<keyword>تغییر مکان لرزه‌ای</keyword>
<keyword>تحلیل تاریخچه زمانی</keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				

					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>Optimum Design of Soil Nailed Walls Based on Deformation Criterion under Seismic Loads</title>
						<abstract>Soil nailing is a prevalent method for temporary or permanent stabilization of excavations which, if it is used for permanent purposes, the seismic study of these structures is important. There are a few physical models, with limited information available, for the study of behavior of soil nailed walls under earthquake loading. Numerical methods may be used for the study of effects of various parameters on the performance of soil nailed walls, and this technique has been used in the current paper. In this research, the effects of various parameters such as the spacing, configuration, and lengths of nails, and the height of wall on seismic displacement of soil nailed walls under the various earthquake excitations were studied. To investigate the effects of the configuration and the lengths of nails on the performance of these structures, two configurations of uniform and variable lengths of nails have been used. To study the effects of the spacing between nails and the height of the wall the spacings of 2 and 1.5 meters and the heights of 14, 20, and 26 meters have been considered. The seismic analysis has been carried out using the finite element software Plaxis 2D. To analyze the lengths' of nails, it was assumed that the safety factors of stability of different models are constant, and the limit equilibrium software GeoSlope was used. After specification of the lengths of nails based on constant safety factor of stability, the deformations of the models under several earthquakes records were analyzed, and recommendations were made on minimizing the deformations of soil nailed walls under seismic loading.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2561-en.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2016-10-04T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>3517</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>3536</pageTo>
				
							<doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg.10.2.3517</doi>
						<keywords>
<keyword>Soil-nailed wall</keyword>
<keyword>Seismic behaviour</keyword>
<keyword>Finite element modeling</keyword>
<keyword>Seismic displacement</keyword>
<keyword>Time history analysis</keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>P</name>
	<surname>Naghshin</surname>
	     <order>1</order>
        <instituteAffiliation>Department of Civil Eng., Faculty of Eng., Kharazmi University</instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>H</name>
	<surname>Shahir</surname>
	<email>shahir@khu.ac.ir</email>
	     <order>2</order>
        <instituteAffiliation>Department of Civil Eng., Faculty of Eng., Kharazmi University</instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	</authors>


	</article>


	</issue>
 </ici-import>
 
  
  
  
  
 