<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1386</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2008</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>2</volume>
<number>2</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی پتانسیل آلودگی آب زیرزمینی دشت باغملک با استفاده از روش AVI و مدل های GOD و DRASTIC در محیط GIS</title_fa>
	<title>Pollution potential assessment of Baghmalek plain groundwater with use of AVI method, GOD and DRASTIC models in GIS media</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>یکی از روش های مدیریت کیفی منابع آب زیرزمینی ارزیابی پتانسیل آلودگی است که با توجه به آن می توان حریم کیفی منابع آب زیرزمینی را تعیین و مدیریت مناسبی جهت کاربری اراضی مرتبط با سفره آبدار اعمال کرد. با توجه نفوذپذیری منطقه تغذیه در بخش عمده ای از دشت باغملک و مصرف زیاد کودهای کشاورزی در این منطقه، پتانسیل آلودگی آب زیرزمینی بررسی شده است. در این تحقیق برای ارزیابی پتانسیل آلودگی آب زیرزمینی دشت باغملک از روش AVI و مدل هایGOD و دراستیک (DRASTIC) استفاده شده است. نتایج حاصل از این تحقیق نشان می دهد که علیرغم درشت‌دانه بودن رسوبات سطحی در بخش نسبتاً وسیعی از دشت، پتانسیل آلودگی در محدوده وسیعی از منطقه پژوهش کم است. این موضوع با میزان نیترات موجود در آب زیرزمینی نیز مطابقت می‌کند. با توجه به پارامترهای به‌کار رفته در ارزیابی پتانسیل آلودگی منطقه پژوهش، مهم‌ترین عامل مؤثر در رابطه با کاهش آلودگی در منطقه پژوهش، ضخامت نسبتاً زیاد رسوبات ریزدانه ای است که در بخش وسیعی از منطقه در زون غیراشباع سفره آبدار قرار گرفته است.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>(Paper pages 431-450) One of the quality management methods of groundwater resources is assessment of pollution potential, where with regard to that the boundary of groundwater resources quality is being determined, and proper management for land efficiency in touch with aquifer could be applied. In present investigation, with regard to permeability of recharge zone in dominant part of the Baghmalek plain and use of considerable amount of agricultural fertilizers, pollution potential of groundwater has been assessed. In order to evaluate the pollution potential of groundwater in the area, AVI method, GOD and DRASTIC models have been taken into account. The collected results has indicated that in spite of sedimentary surfacial coarse grain distribution in relatively vast part of the area, the pollution potential is low in major parts of the area under investigation. The main influential factor for low pollution potential in tremendous part of the area is the fine and relatively thickness of vadose zone.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>پتانسیل آلودگی منطقه پژوهش , مهم‌ترین عامل مؤثر در ,</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>AVI method , GOD and DRASTIC models have ,</keyword>
	<start_page>431</start_page>
	<end_page>450</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-3-42&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
