<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1390</year>
	<month>2</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2011</year>
	<month>5</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>4</volume>
<number>2</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ارزیابی و اصلاح معیار شیمیایی تشخیص پتانسیل واگرایی خاک‌های رسی</title_fa>
	<title>Evaluation and modificationof chemical criterion for determining dispersive potential of clay</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa>علمی پژوهشی</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>s</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>از جمله روش¬های تشخیص پتانسیل واگرایی خاک¬های رسی، آزمایش‌های شیمیایی هستند. این آزمایش‌ها بر اساس تأثیر یون سدیم به‌عنوان عامل شیمیایی اصلی در واگرایی خاک رس، بنا نهاده شده¬اند. بررسی¬های انجام شده نشان می¬دهند که بین نتایج آزمایش‌ها فیزیکی و معیارهای شیمیایی تشخیص پتانسیل واگرایی خاک¬های رسی، تطابق چشم‌گیری وجود ندارد. در پژوهش حاضر پس از تهیۀ نتایج آزمایش‌های انجام شده بر روی 18 منابع قرضه مصالح رسی سدهای خاکی، ابتدا هم‌خوانی معیار شیمیایی دکتر رحیمی با نتایج آزمایش پین هول بررسی شده و سپس با مبنا قرار دادن نتایج آزمایش پین هول، معیار اصلاح شده در شکل کلی معیار پیشنهادی توسط معیار شیمیایی دکتر رحیمی پیشنهاد شده¬ است. نتایج بررسی¬های انجام شده در محدودۀ اطلاعات آزمایشگاهی موجود در این پژوهش نشان می¬دهند در حالی که میزان تطابق معیار شیمیایی دکتر رحیمی با نتایج آزمایش پین هول 63% است، میزان تطابق معیار اصلاح شده پیشنهادی با نتایج آزمایش پین هول 74% است. شایان ذکر است که معیار شیمیایی دکتر رحیمی بر اساس نتایج 24 نمونه آزمایشگاهی تدوین شده در حالی‌که معیار پیشنهادی در پژوهش حاضر بر اساس نتایج 234 نمونه آزمایشگاهی تدوین شده است.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>One of the main methods of determining dispersive potential of clay is chemical tests. These tests are found on the basis of sodium ion as a main chemical element in dispersive clay. The examinations show that there is no correlations between results of physical tests and chemical criterions. In present research after preparing the results of tests on 18 borrow pit sources of clay materials of earth dams, we investigate the Dr. Rahimi's criterion with results of Pinhole Test and then bases on pinhole test results, we suggested the modified criterion of Dr. Rahimi's proposed general criterion. The results of investigations on the range of laboratory data shows that the correlations of Dr. Rahimi's proposed criterion with pinhole test is 63%, while this rate is 74% for our suggested modified criterion. Also it should be considered that Dr. Rahimi's criterion compiled according the results of 24 laboratory samples while suggested criterion in present research compiled according the results of 234 laboratory samples.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>  سد خاکی , واگرایی , معیار شیمیایی , آزمایش پین هول ,</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Earth dams , Dispersive , Chemical Criterion , Pinhole Test , </keyword>
	<start_page>917</start_page>
	<end_page>942</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-3-20&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
