<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1389</year>
	<month>1</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2010</year>
	<month>4</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>3</volume>
<number>2</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی رفتار اتساع و مقاومت برشی مخلوط‌های شن و ماسه در مقادیر شن دانه بالاتر از آستانه شناوری</title_fa>
	<title>Shear strength characteristics of sand-gravel mixtures in high gravel contents</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>شرایط شناوری در خاک مخلوط شن و ماسه‌ای، به حالتی اطلاق می‌شود که شن دانه‌ها درصد اندکی از مخلوط را تشکیل داده، در بخش ماتریس ماسه شناور بوده و تماس اندکی بین آن‌ها برقرار است. در این حالت، مقاومت و خصوصیات تغییر شکل خاک تحت تأثیر بخش ریزتر یعنی ماسه خواهد بود. با افزایش مقدار شن تماس بین ذرات شن دانه ایجاد شده و ماسه فقط فضای خالی ما بین آن ها را پر خواهد نمود. این وضعیت حالت غیرشناوری شن دانه ها را نشان می‌دهد. مقاومت و خصوصیات تغییر شکل خاک در این حالت توسط بخش درشت‌تر مخلوط یعنی شن کنترل می‌شود. در تحقیق حاضر برای ارزیابی رفتار مقاومت برشی مخلوط‌های شن و ماسه در شرایط غیرشناوری شن دانه ها، از دستگاه آزمایش برش مستقیم بزرگ مقیاس با ابعاد جعبه برش 160 ×300×300 میلی‌متر استفاده شده است. شن با دانه‌بندی یک‌نواخت و حداکثر اندازه 5/12 میلی‌متر با شکل گردگوشه به عنوان بخش درشت‌تر به کار رفته است. برای قسمت ریزتر نیز از ماسه بد دانه‌بندی شده سواحل بابلسر استفاده شده است. نمونه‌های مخلوط شن و ماسه به صورت کاملاً خشک در چهاردرصد وزنی شن متفاوت 70، 80، 90 و 100 و در سه تراکم نسبی 35، 60 و 85 درصد آماده و تحت سربار‌های 100، 200 و 300 کیلو پاسکال آزمایش شده اند. نتایج این تحقیق نشان می‌دهد که ازدیاد تراکم نسبی و درصد شن دانه سبب افزایش مقاومت برشی خاک های مخلوط شن و ماسه می‌شود. همچنین نرخ تغییرات مقاومت برشی یا زاویه اصطکاک خاک با درصد شن دانه، در مقادیر پایین‌تر از حد شناوری که رفتار توسط ماتریس ماسه ای ریزتر کنترل می‌شود شدیدتر از مقادیر نظیر در بالاتر از حد شناوری است که رفتار خاک مخلوط به‌وسیله بخش درشت‌تر شنی کنترل می‌شود.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>(Paper pages 735-756) Shear behavior of sand-gravel mixtures is an important issue in geotechnical engineering due to extensive use in earth dams, borrow materials and slope stability problems of natural or man made slopes. Experimental study of behavior of this type of material is usually difficult due to problems associated with use of large testing apparatus or large specimens. Several researchers have proposed methods for the test of these materials by removing larger fraction of them and testing finer matrix. In this research, a regular set of large direct shear tests with a 300*300*160 mm shear box performed to determine shear strength and dilation characteristics of sand-gravel mixtures in high gravel contents. Bad graded fine sand was used besides uniform gravel grains with maximum grain size of 12.5 mm as testing materials. The tests conducted on mixtures prepared in four gravel contents of 70, 80, 90 and 100 percents. Samples constructed in three relative densities of 35, 60 and 85% and tested by different surcharge pressures of 100, 200 and 300 kPa. Experiments conducted on completely dry samples in consolidated drained condition. Shear strength behavior of mixtures was investigated and it was concluded that both shear strength and friction angle increases with gravel content, relative density and surcharge pressure. However, dilation increases by increase in gravel content and relative density and reduces with increase in surcharge pressure. Results were compared with previous experiments on mixtures with less gravel contents and it was observed that in little gravel contents the behavior is controlled by the both sandy matrix and gravel grains. However, as gravel content increases from floating limit, the behavior is mainly controlled by gravelly part of mixture and sand fraction has little effects on its behavior.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>زاویه اصطکاک خاک با درصد شن دانه , در ,</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Sand-gravel mixtures , shear behavior , dilation , floating limit , Gravel content , </keyword>
	<start_page>735</start_page>
	<end_page>756</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-3-60&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
