<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1386</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2008</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>2</volume>
<number>2</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>الگوی جدید بارش- رواناب حوضه آبریز هلیل رود با استفاده از مدل هیبرید شبکه عصبی- موجکی</title_fa>
	<title>New Pattern of Halil River Basin’s Rainfall-Runoff by Using of Hybrid Neural Wavelet Network Model</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>برآورد سیلاب و مدیریت آن از دیرباز مورد توجه کارشناسان و مدیران علوم محیطی بوده است. برای این امر روش‌‌های بسیاری وجود دارد که یکی از چشم‌گیرترین آن‌‌ها استفاده از شبکه‌‌های عصبی مصنوعی است. در این تحقیق، مدل بارش- رواناب حوضه آبریز رودخانه هلیل رود در جنوب‌شرق ایران ارائه شده است. ظهور تئوری‌های توانمند مانند منطق فازی و شبکه‌‌های عصبی مصنوعی(ANN)، الگوریتم ژنتیک و موجک تحولی عظیم در تحلیل رفتار سیستم‌‌های دینامیک در علوم مختلف مهندسی ایجاد کرده است. در این مقاله با استفاده از تئوری موجک و شبکه عصبی، شبکه عصبی- موجکی طراحی شده است. در واقع عمل‌کرد شبکه عصبی پرسپترون چند لایه(MLP)، با استفاده از موجک بهبود داده شده و با استفاده شبکه عصبی- موجکی الگوی جدیدی در بارش- رواناب ارائه شده است. نتایج به‌دست آمده از این مدل با نتایج شبکه عصبی انتشار برگشتی و بنیادی شعاعی مقایسه شده است. در الگوی ارائه شده، داده‌ها در گروه‌های همگن با توجه به میزان بارش و رواناب و به‌کارگیری آن‌ها توسط شبکه عصبی- موجکی، دسته‌بندی شده است. کنترل دقت محاسبات با محاسبه ضریب همبستگی R، و ریشه میانگین مربعات خطا(RMSE) صورت گرفته است. نتایج حاکی از بهبود بسیار خوب عمل‌کرد شبکه عصبی- موجکی با استفاده از داده‌های تقسیم‌بندی شده با الگوی جدید است.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>(Paper pages 451-472) Flood management and flood prediction are taken into account for a long time. There are many methods to estimate the magnitude of the flood. One of the most recent methods is using Artificial Neural Networks. In this paper, a Neural-Wavelet Network (NWN) using wavelet theory and Artificial Neural Networks (ANN) for Halil river basin in SE of Iran is reported. Furthermore, a new rainfall-runoff pattern is reported. This pattern ncludes the classification of data in the harmonic data groups and the use of Neural-Wavelet Network.The introduced pattern is analyzed by the NWN model and results are prepared with Artificial Neural Networks Back propagation and Radial Base Function (RBF) model results. Halil basin was selected to used for our model. The calculations of the R-square and root mean square error (RMSE) can control the accuracy of our computations. The calculations showed that the accuracy of the results of the Artificial Neural Wavelet Network is more desirable than ANN and RBF. It is showed that the classification of data in harmonies data and using of new pattern increase the efficiency of the models operations as well.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>با توجه به میزان بارش و رواناب ,</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>desirable than ANN and RBF. It is showed ,</keyword>
	<start_page>451</start_page>
	<end_page>472</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-3-51&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
