<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>10</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>1</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>11</volume>
<number>3</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>en</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>فشار فعال لرزه‌ای ناشی از خاکریز مسلح ژئوسنتتیکی با عرض کم بر رویۀ صلب</title_fa>
	<title>Seismic Active Earth Pressure of Narrow Geosynthetic-Reinforced Backfill on Rigid Facing</title>
	<subject_fa>ژئوتکنیک (مکانیک خاک و سنگ)</subject_fa>
	<subject>Geotecnic</subject>
	<content_type_fa>مقاله مستقل</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Original Manuscript</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11.0pt;&quot;&gt;در دیوارهای خاک مسلح ژئوسنتتیکی با عرض کم، یک دیوار پایدار پشتی در فاصلۀ کمی از رویۀ دیوار وجود دارد به&#8204;گونه&amp;shy;ای&#8204;که فضای کافی برای امتداد دادن مسلح کننده با طول کافی وجود ندارد. در این&#8204;حالت احتمال واژگونی دیوار حائل بالاخص تحت بارهای لرزه&amp;shy;ای افزایش می&amp;shy;یابد. برای افزایش پایداری دیوار، مسلح کننده&amp;shy;ها را می&amp;shy;توان به دیوار پایدار پشتی متصل کرد. روش دیگر، استفاده از رویۀ بتنی در جاریز برای تمام ارتفاع دیوار است تا فشار خاک با عملکرد مشترک مقاومت بیرون&#8204;کشیدگی مسلح&#8204;کننده&amp;shy;ها و مقاومت خمشی رویۀ دیوار تحمل شود.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11.0pt;&quot;&gt;از سؤال&#8204;های&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b lotus;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11.0pt;&quot;&gt;اساسی در مورد این نوع دیواره&#8204;ها، میزان سهمی از فشار خاک است که به&#8204;وسیلۀ رویۀ بتنی تحمل می&amp;shy;شود. در این تحقیق، فشار فعال لرزه&#8204;ای ناشی از خاکریز مسلح با عرض کم بر رویۀ صلب با استفاده از روی&#8204;کرد تعادل حدی و روش قطعات افقی برآورد شده است. برای این منظور فرض شده است که سطح لغزش بحرانی به&#8204;صورت خطی از پای دیوار تا سطح پایدار پشتی امتداد یافته و سپس روی سطح پشتی تا سطح خاکریز ادامه می&amp;shy;یابد. تأثیر پارامترهای مختلف مانند نسبت عرض به ارتفاع دیوار بررسی شده است. نتایج به&#8204;دست آمده بیان&#8204;گر آن است که فشار وارد بر رویۀ در قسمت&amp;shy;های فوقانی دیوار طبق رابطۀ مونونوبه-اوکابه افزایش می&amp;shy;یابد ولی در قسمت&amp;shy;های تحتانی، روند گراف عوض شده و مقدار فشار وارده بر دیوار کاهش می&amp;shy;یابد تا به مقدار صفر در پای دیوار برسد. نتایج آنالیزها نشان می&amp;shy;دهد که فشار وارده بر رویۀ دیوار با کاهش عرض خاکریز، افزایش می&amp;shy;یابد.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>In the narrow geosynthetic-reinforced retaining walls a stable rear wall exists in a short distance and &lt;s&gt;so&lt;/s&gt; there is no enough space to extend appropriate length of reinforcements. In this case, the probability of overturning of retaining wall increases especially when subjected to earthquake loading. To increase the stability of the wall, reinforcements may be connected to the stable rear surface. Alternative solution is the utilization of full-height cast in-place concrete facing in order to resist the earth pressure by combined actions of reinforcements pullout capacity and facing flexural rigidity. One of the main questions about this type of walls is the portion of earth pressure resisted by the facing. In this study, the seismic earth pressure of narrow geosynthetic-reinforced backfill on rigid facing was evaluated using limit equilibrium approach and horizontal slices method. The critical failure surface was assumed to extend linearly from the wall toe to the rear surface and then moves&amp;nbsp;along the interface of the backfill and rear surface up to the backfill surface. The effects of various parameters such as wall aspect ratio have been investigated. The obtained results show that the applied soil pressure on wall facing will be increased with depth in the upper part of the wall according to the Mononobe-Okabe equation, but its pattern is inversed in the lower part of the wall and it decreases until it reaches to zero at the wall toe. The results of analyses indicate that the attracted soil thrust by the facing increases with lessening of backfill width.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>دیوار خاک مسلح ژئوسنتتیکی, خاکریز با عرض کم, نمای صلب, فشار لرزه‌ای خاک, روش قطعات افقی.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Geosynthetic-reinforced soil wall, Narrow backfill, Full-height rigid facing, Seismic earth pressure, Horizontal slices method.</keyword>
	<start_page>53</start_page>
	<end_page>80</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-217-5&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Fariborz </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Dehghani</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>فریبرز</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>دهقانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001751</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001751</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Hadi </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Shahir</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>هادی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>شهیر</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001752</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001752</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name> Ali </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ghanbari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>قنبری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001753</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001753</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
