<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1398</YEAR>
<VOL>13</VOL>
<NO>4</NO>
<MOSALSAL>41</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>726</PAGE_NO>


<ARTICLES>

	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>طیف پاسخ زلزله‌های میدان نزدیک با احتساب اثر محتوای فرکانسی بر رفتار خاکCH/SC با ملاحظه سرعت موج برشی صحرایی و آزمایشگاهی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Design Spectrum for Near Fault Ground Motions Considering Frequency-Dependence of CH/SC Material Behavior Regarding Laboratory and Field Shear Wave Velocity (Vs)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>در تحلیل خطی معادل یک&#8204;بعدی که به&#8204;طور وسیع در برآورد اثر شرایط محلی ساختگاه به&#8204;کار می&#8204;رود، عموماً رفتار خاک مستقل از فرکانس بارگذاری زلزله فرض می&#173;شود. این در حالی است که مدول برشی (G) و نسبت میرایی (D)، متأثر از فرکانس بارگذاریند. در این پژوهش با استفاده از روش تحلیل خطی معادل، طیف پاسخ شتاب در سه سطح خطر (PGA=0.1g, 0.35g, 1g) برای دو ستون خاک CH/SC به&#8204;ارتفاع 30 و 60 متری تحت اثر مؤلفه&#173;های هشت رکورد زلزله میدان نزدیک استخراج شده است. علاوه بر منحنی&#173;های رفتاری متداول، در مدل&#8204;سازی رفتار خاک از منحنی&#173;های رفتاری مستخرج از روش آزمون مشخصات دینامیکی تحت اثر فرکانس&#173;های بارگذاری 5/0، 1، 2، 5 و Hz 10 و در سطوح تنش محدودکننده 1، 2 و  &#160;5 نیز استفاده شده است. طی انجام 1728 تحلیل خطی معادل، مقادیر طیف پاسخ شتاب، ضریب بزرگ&#8204;نمایی طیف و نسبت شتاب طیفی استخراج شده است. براساس نتایج حاصل، ملحوظ کردن اثر فرکانس بارگذاری در منحنی رفتاری مصالح بر مقدار پاسخ شتاب طیفی، نسبت شتاب طیفی و ضریب شکل طیف مؤثر است. در هر دو حالت ستون خاک 30 و 60 متری، افزایش فرکانس بارگذاری منجر به کاهش نسبت شتاب طیفی و متوسط ضریب بزرگ&#8204;نمایی طیف، خصوصاً در دوره&#8204;های کوتاه می&#173;شود. مقایسۀ متوسط ضریب شکل حاصل از تحلیل&#173;ها با، ضریب شکل (B) طیف طرح استاندارد 2800 نشان می&#173;دهد که به&#8204;منظور احتساب اثر فرکانس غالب زلزله&#173;های میدان نزدیک لازم است در خاک نوع  و مقدار  &#160;طیف طرح استاندارد 2800 ایران به&#8204;ترتیب به مقدار 5/0 و 1 ثانیه افزایش یابد.&#160;
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Introduction
One-dimensional site response analysis is widely performed to account for local site effects during an earthquake. Most of these approaches assume that dynamic soil properties are frequency independent. Laboratory test results as well as in-situ testing show that shear modulus and damping ratio are dependent on the frequency of loading. Although the amplification factor at ground surface with respect to frequency dependent dynamic properties of mixed alluvium materials under different near-fault motions with various velocity period is recognized, it is not well characterized and quantified.
Material and analysis methods
In this study, the tests results of samples which obtained from the drilling borehole (BH14) form Pardis city in Iran, are used. The soil is classified as clayey of high plasticity/clayey sand (CH/SC) and almost uniform and similar in the whole log profile.
Shear modulus and damping ratios versus shear strain curves (ASTM D3999) of CH/SC natural materials at effective confining pressures of 1, 2 and 5 kg/cm2 with frequency of 0.5, 2, 5, and 10 Hz were used in one dimension response analyses using EERA Code.
Generally the damping ratio versus shear strain of the studied materials under low loading frequency (i.e. 0.5 Hz) almost falls in the range identified in literature. However, at higher loading frequencies (5 and 10 Hz) the damping ratios completely fall above the known upper bound trend. It is observed that, in general, the G and D values increase as loading frequency increases. Moreover, at certain strain G/Gmax ratio decreases as loading frequency is increased.
Different dynamics behaviour curves were used in analyses, in isotropic consolidation conditions. In order to assess the amplification, acceleration spectra, acceleration spectra ratio, coefficient of B, at ground surface under eight well-known near-fault ground motions, 1728 one dimensional analyses were carried out with EERA code. The analyses have been performed for three base acceleration levels, namely, 0.1 g, 0.35 g and 1 g, using the simple time history scaling method. Field and laboratory test results of shear wave velocity were used in the analyses.
In this study, several well-known near-fault motion records are utilized for ground response analyses. Near-fault earthquakes records were selected from the strong motion database of the Pacific Earthquake Engineering Research Center (PEER) and Iran Strong Motion Network&#160;(ISMN) for specific reasons of location of the near faults sites.
In current building codes, the upper 30 m soil deposits overlying the higher impedance earth crust are regarded as the most relevant and significant in characterizing the seismic behavior of a site. Therefore, it is useful to accomplish investigations for obtaining their amplification and spectral acceleration for 30 m and even thicker (e.g. 60 m, for usual deep excavation in Iran), in order to have economical and safe designs and constructions.
Results and discussion
Figure 1 presents a comparison of normalized spectral acceleration (B factor) versus period for 30 m and 60 m thick profiles and Vs testing for frequencies dependent and independent analyses under input base acceleration of 0.35g for longitudinal component of used earthquakes. B factor of Iranian Standard 2800 and UBC97 also has been presented in the figure. The spectral acceleration at short period for frequency dependent analysis is higher than that of the frequency independent analysis. The &#160;increases in frequency dependent analysis and higher thick profile (i.e. 60 m).
Conclusion
Results show that the effect of loading frequency has a considerable influence on the acceleration response at the ground surface. For both 30 m and 60 m soil columns, the increase of the loading frequency, decreases the amplification factor especially in the short period zone of the spectra. Based on the acceleration response spectra of near field strong motions derived for soils types of I and IV in this study, the period corresponding to &#160;in the design spectrum of Iranian Standard 2800 should increase to 0.5 and 1.4, respectively. Therefore, selection of the appropriate G and D curves measured at frequency similar to those of the anticipated cyclic loading (e.g. seismic) has a paramount importance../files/site1/files/134/1.pdf</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>541</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>570</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>عطا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>آقایی آرایی</Family>
				<NameE>Ata</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Aghaei Araei1</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>مرکز تحقیقات راه، مسکن و شهرسازی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>مرکز تحقیقات راه، مسکن و شهرسازی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>aghaeiaraei@bhrc.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>ناهید</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>عطارچیان</Family>
				<NameE>Nahid</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Attarchian</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>مرکز تحقیقات راه، مسکن و شهرسازی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>مرکز تحقیقات راه، مسکن و شهرسازی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>n.attarchian@bhrc.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>احمد رضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>قدرتی قزاانی</Family>
				<NameE>Ahmadreza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ghodrati Ghazaani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>مرکز تحقیقات راه، مسکن و شهرسازی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>مرکز تحقیقات راه، مسکن و شهرسازی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>a.ghodrati@bhrc.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>حداد</Family>
				<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Haddad</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تکنولوژی سیدنی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>مرکز تحقیقات راه، مسکن و شهرسازی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>hossein.haddad@student.uts.edu.au</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>امیر سعید</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>سلامت</Family>
				<NameE>Amir Saeid</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Salamat</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>مرکز تحقیقات راه، مسکن و شهرسازی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>مرکز تحقیقات راه، مسکن و شهرسازی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>salamat@bhrc.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>حسنی</Family>
				<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Hasani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>مرکز تحقیقات راه، مسکن و شهرسازی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>مرکز تحقیقات راه، مسکن و شهرسازی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>hasani@bhrc.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>acceleration response spectrum</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>near fault</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>damping ratio</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>shear modulus</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>loading frequency</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>triaxial apparatus.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>طیف پاسخ شتاب</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>زلزله میدان نزدیک</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نسبت میرایی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدول برشی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>فرکانس بارگذاری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دستگاه سه‌محوری دینامیکی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Idriss I. M., Seed H. B., &quot;Seismic response of horizontal soil layers. Journal of the Soil Mechanics and Foundations Division&quot;, ASCE, 94 (4) (1968) 1003-1031.## 2. Idriss I. M., &quot;Response of soft soil sites during earthquakes. In Proceedings of the Symposium to Honor Professor H. B. Seed&quot;, Berkeley, May (1990) 273-289. ## 3. Sugito M., Goda H., Masuda T., &quot;Frequency-dependent equ-linearized technique for seismic response analysis of multi-layered ground&quot;, Proceedings of JSCE, No.493/III-27 (1994) 49-58 (in Japanese). ## 4. Sugito M., &quot;Frequency-dependent equivalent strain for equi-linearized technique. Proceedings of the First International Conference on Earthquake Geotechnical Engineering&quot;, Balkena, Rotterdam, the Netherlands (1995) 655-660. ## 5. Yoshida N., Kobayashi S., Suetomi I., Miura K., &quot;Equivalent linear method considering frequency dependent characteristics of stiffness and damping. Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, Elsevier, 22 (3) (2002) 205-222. ## 6. Assimaki D., Kausel E., &quot;An equivalent linear algorithm with frequency and pressure-dependent moduli and damping for the seismic analysis of deep sites&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering. 22 (9-12) (2002) 959-965. ## 7. Zhang J., Andrus R., Juang C. H., &quot;Normalized shear modulus and material damping ratio relationships&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering, ASEC. 130 (4) (2005) 453-464. ## 8. آقایی‌آرایی ع.، رازقی ح.، هاشمی طباطبایی س.، قلندرزاده ع.، &quot;ارزیابی اثر فرکانس بر مشخصات خاک‌های شنی&quot;، گزارش گ-630، مرکز تحقیقات ساختمان و مسکن (1391). ## 9. آقایی آرایی ع.، هاشمی طباطبایی س.، قلندرزاده ع.، &quot;مدول برشی و نسبت میرایی مصالح شنی&quot;، گ-548. مرکز تحقیقات ساختمان و مسکن (1390). ## 10. Meng J. &quot;Earthquake ground motion simulation with frequency-dependent soil properties, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering&quot;, 27(3) (2007) 234-241. ## 11. Park D., Hashash Y. M. A., &quot;Rate-dependent soil behavior in seismic site response analysis&quot;, Can. Geotechnical Journal. 45 (4) (2008) 454-469## 12. Rodriguez-Marek A., Bray J. D., &quot;Seismic site response for near-fault forward directivity ground motions&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering. 132 (12) (2006) 1611-1620. ## 13. Bray J. D., Rodriguez-Marek A., &quot;Characteristics of forward-directivity ground motions in the near-fault region&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering. 24 (11) (2004) 815-828. ## 14. آیین‌نامۀ طراحی ساختمان‌ها در برابر زلزله، استاندارد 2800.، ویرایش 4. شمارۀ نشر: ض- (1393) 253. ## 15. Razeghi H. R., Aghaei Araei A., Ghalandarzadeh A., Hashemi Tabatabaei S., &quot;Rate-dependence of rockfill behavior on propagated near fault ground motions&quot;, Scientia Iranica, 21(4) (2014) 1263-1280. ## 16. قدرتی قزاانی ا.، &quot;ارزیابی رفتار دینامیکی خاک مخلوط با استفاده از دستگاه سه‌محوری قطر بزرگ&quot;، پایانامۀ دکتری. مرکز تحقیقات راه، مسکن و شهرسازی (1396) 150. ## 17. آقایی آرایی ع. قدرتی قزاانی ا.، هاشمی طباطبایی س. قلندرزاده ع.، &quot;ارزیابی رفتار دینامیکی مصالح خاکی با استفاده از دستگاه سه‌محوری بزرگ مقیاس&quot;، پروژه تحقیقاتی، مرکز تحقیقات ساختمان و مسکن (1394). ## 18. ASTM D3999, &quot;Standard test methods for the determination of the modulus and damping properties of soils using the cyclic triaxial apparatus&quot; (2011). ## 19. Ishihara K. G., &quot;Soil behavior in Earthquake Geotechnics&quot;, Oxford Science Punlication. New York (1996). ## 20. Hatanaka M., Vchida A., &quot;Effects of test methods on the cyclic deformation charachteristics of high quality undistribed gravel samples, static and dynamic properties of gravelly soils&quot;, Geotechnical Special publication 56 (1995) 136-151. ## 21. Vucetic M., Dobry R., &quot;Effect of soil plasticity on cyclic response, Journal of Geotechnical Engineering, 117 (1991) 89-107. ## 22. Somerville P., &quot;Magnitude scaling of near fault rupture directivity pulse&quot;, Physics of Earth and Planetary Interiors&quot;, 137 (1-4) (2003) 201-212. ## 23. &quot;پروژه‌های تحقیقاتی ریزپهنه‌بندی ژئوتکنیک لرزه‌ای شهرهای بم&quot;، پردیس، سرخه، سمنان، شاهرود، بسطام، مهدیشهر و بستک (1386-1396)، مرکز تحقیقات راه، مسکن وشهرسازی. ## 24. &quot;Pacific Earthquake Engineering Research Center&quot;, PEER strong motion database, [Online] (2008). Available: http://peer.berkeley.edu/smcat/.## 25. Bardet J. P., Ichii K., Lin C. H., &quot;EERA, Equivalent linear earthquake site response analysis of layered soils deposits&quot;, User's manual, University of Southern California, Department of Civil Engineering (2000). ## 26. The Uniform Building Code, UBC-97 (1997). ##  ##Idriss I. M., Seed H. B., &quot;Seismic response of horizontal soil layers. Journal of the Soil Mechanics and Foundations Division&quot;, ASCE, 94 (4) (1968) 1003-1031.## 2. Idriss I. M., &quot;Response of soft soil sites during earthquakes. In Proceedings of the Symposium to Honor Professor H. B. Seed&quot;, Berkeley, May (1990) 273-289. ## 3. Sugito M., Goda H., Masuda T., &quot;Frequency-dependent equ-linearized technique for seismic response analysis of multi-layered ground&quot;, Proceedings of JSCE, No.493/III-27 (1994) 49-58 (in Japanese). ## 4. Sugito M., &quot;Frequency-dependent equivalent strain for equi-linearized technique. Proceedings of the First International Conference on Earthquake Geotechnical Engineering&quot;, Balkena, Rotterdam, the Netherlands (1995) 655-660. ## 5. Yoshida N., Kobayashi S., Suetomi I., Miura K., &quot;Equivalent linear method considering frequency dependent characteristics of stiffness and damping. Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, Elsevier, 22 (3) (2002) 205-222. ## 6. Assimaki D., Kausel E., &quot;An equivalent linear algorithm with frequency and pressure-dependent moduli and damping for the seismic analysis of deep sites&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering. 22 (9-12) (2002) 959-965. ## 7. Zhang J., Andrus R., Juang C. H., &quot;Normalized shear modulus and material damping ratio relationships&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering, ASEC. 130 (4) (2005) 453-464. ## 8. آقایی‌آرایی ع.، رازقی ح.، هاشمی طباطبایی س.، قلندرزاده ع.، &quot;ارزیابی اثر فرکانس بر مشخصات خاک‌های شنی&quot;، گزارش گ-630، مرکز تحقیقات ساختمان و مسکن (1391). ## 9. آقایی آرایی ع.، هاشمی طباطبایی س.، قلندرزاده ع.، &quot;مدول برشی و نسبت میرایی مصالح شنی&quot;، گ-548. مرکز تحقیقات ساختمان و مسکن (1390). ## 10. Meng J. &quot;Earthquake ground motion simulation with frequency-dependent soil properties, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering&quot;, 27(3) (2007) 234-241. ## 11. Park D., Hashash Y. M. A., &quot;Rate-dependent soil behavior in seismic site response analysis&quot;, Can. Geotechnical Journal. 45 (4) (2008) 454-469## 12. Rodriguez-Marek A., Bray J. D., &quot;Seismic site response for near-fault forward directivity ground motions&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering. 132 (12) (2006) 1611-1620. ## 13. Bray J. D., Rodriguez-Marek A., &quot;Characteristics of forward-directivity ground motions in the near-fault region&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering. 24 (11) (2004) 815-828. ## 14. آیین‌نامۀ طراحی ساختمان‌ها در برابر زلزله، استاندارد 2800.، ویرایش 4. شمارۀ نشر: ض- (1393) 253. ## 15. Razeghi H. R., Aghaei Araei A., Ghalandarzadeh A., Hashemi Tabatabaei S., &quot;Rate-dependence of rockfill behavior on propagated near fault ground motions&quot;, Scientia Iranica, 21(4) (2014) 1263-1280. ## 16. قدرتی قزاانی ا.، &quot;ارزیابی رفتار دینامیکی خاک مخلوط با استفاده از دستگاه سه‌محوری قطر بزرگ&quot;، پایانامۀ دکتری. مرکز تحقیقات راه، مسکن و شهرسازی (1396) 150. ## 17. آقایی آرایی ع. قدرتی قزاانی ا.، هاشمی طباطبایی س. قلندرزاده ع.، &quot;ارزیابی رفتار دینامیکی مصالح خاکی با استفاده از دستگاه سه‌محوری بزرگ مقیاس&quot;، پروژه تحقیقاتی، مرکز تحقیقات ساختمان و مسکن (1394). ## 18. ASTM D3999, &quot;Standard test methods for the determination of the modulus and damping properties of soils using the cyclic triaxial apparatus&quot; (2011). ## 19. Ishihara K. G., &quot;Soil behavior in Earthquake Geotechnics&quot;, Oxford Science Punlication. New York (1996). ## 20. Hatanaka M., Vchida A., &quot;Effects of test methods on the cyclic deformation charachteristics of high quality undistribed gravel samples, static and dynamic properties of gravelly soils&quot;, Geotechnical Special publication 56 (1995) 136-151. ## 21. Vucetic M., Dobry R., &quot;Effect of soil plasticity on cyclic response, Journal of Geotechnical Engineering, 117 (1991) 89-107. ## 22. Somerville P., &quot;Magnitude scaling of near fault rupture directivity pulse&quot;, Physics of Earth and Planetary Interiors&quot;, 137 (1-4) (2003) 201-212. ## 23. &quot;پروژه‌های تحقیقاتی ریزپهنه‌بندی ژئوتکنیک لرزه‌ای شهرهای بم&quot;، پردیس، سرخه، سمنان، شاهرود، بسطام، مهدیشهر و بستک (1386-1396)، مرکز تحقیقات راه، مسکن وشهرسازی. ## 24. &quot;Pacific Earthquake Engineering Research Center&quot;, PEER strong motion database, [Online] (2008). Available: http://peer.berkeley.edu/smcat/.## 25. Bardet J. P., Ichii K., Lin C. H., &quot;EERA, Equivalent linear earthquake site response analysis of layered soils deposits&quot;, User's manual, University of Southern California, Department of Civil Engineering (2000). ## 26. The Uniform Building Code, UBC-97 (1997). ##   ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>پیش‌بینی منحنی مشخصه آب- خاک ماسه بادی تثبیت‌شده با پلیمر SBR و باکتری باسیلوس پاسته اوری در منطقه جبل‌کندی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Prediction of the soil-water characteristic curve of dune sand stabilized with SBR polymer and MICP process in the Jabal Kandi area</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>یکی از مهم&#8207;ترین داده&#173;های کاربردی در مکانیک خاک غیراشباع، منحنی مشخصه آب- خاک (SWCC) است. این منحنی به شکل تابع سیگموید است و رابطۀ بین درصد رطوبت حجمی (Ө) و یا درصد رطوبت وزنی (w) را با مکش کالبدی خاک مشخص می&#8207;کند و در حالت کاهش درصد رطوبت با افزایش مکش، شاخه خشک&#8204;شدگی و در حالت افزایش درصد رطوبت با کاهش مکش، شاخه ترشدگی خاک را نشان می&#8207;دهد. در این پژوهشتأثیر دو نوع تثبیت&#8204;کنندۀ پلیمر SBR و میکروارگانیسم باسیلوس پاسته اوری روی منحنی مشخصه آب- خاک ماسۀ بادی منطقه جبل کندی، کانون ریزگرد غرب دریاچۀ ارومیه ارزیابی شده است. درصدهای مواد تثبیت کننده 5-10 و 15 بودند. نتایج این پژوهش بیان می&#8207;کند که با افزایش درصد مواد تثبیت کننده، شیب منحنی مشخصه از شکل تک&#8204;مدل به&#8204;&#8204;صورت دو مدل تبدیل می&#8207;شود. به&#8204;علاوه مقدار ورود هوا و مقدار آب باقی&#8204;مانده با افزایش درصد مواد تثبیت کننده افزایش می&#8207;یابد و در نتیجه منجر به افزایش ظرفیت نگه&#8204;داشت آب می&#8207;شود. شکل دو مدل منحنی مشخصه آب- خاک، حضور دو سطح اندازۀ حفره&#8204;ها، به&#8204;نام ماکرو و میکرو حفره&#8204;های را بیان می&#8207;کند. برای 10 و 15 درصد از مواد تثبیت&#8207;کننده، ماکرو حفره&#8204;های گستره وسیعی از منحنی مشخصه از 5/0 تا 100 کیلوپاسکال را نشان می&#173;دهد. نتایج به&#8204;دست آمده نشان داد که منحنی مشخصه ماسه تثبیت شده با پلیمر و میکروارگانیسم به&#8204;شدت به بافت و توزیع اندازه حفره&#8204;های ماسه تثبیت&#8204;شده وابسته است و در نتیجهتأثیر مهمی روی ویژگی&#8207;های هیدرولیکی آن دارد. هم&#8204;چنین میزان نگه&#8204;داشت آب در خاک و افزایش مکش در تثبیت نمونه با پلیمر چشم&#8204;گیرتر از تثبیت با میکروارگانیسم است.&#160;
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Introduction
The geotechnical engineering problems involving unsaturated soils are included water flow, shear strength and volume change. Soil-water characteristic curve (SWCC) describes the constitutive relationship between soil suction and soil water content. SWCC may be determined directly or indirectly in the laboratory. Because of the various difficulties involved in the direct measurements, a simple and economical laboratory method namely filter paper method is of considerable value. The filter paper method is a laboratory technique that has recently been accepted as a standard method of measuring soil potential, reaching far higher ranges of water potential in comparison to other techniques, and is based on the principle of moisture absorption by filter paper until there is a balance in potential between filter paper and soil.
This paper presents an experimental investigation performed to evaluate the soil water characteristic curves of dune sand stabilized with SBR polymer and MICP processes (Sporosarcina pasteurii bacteria with CaCl2 and urea) with contact filter paper method in the Jabal Kandi area.
Material and methods
The dune sand used in this study was obtained from the surface (0&#8211;10 cm depth) of Jabal kandi area, located on the south-west of Urmia Lake. SBR polymer is prepared from Paya Resin Company in Esfahan. In the MICP processes, S. pasteurii from Persian Type Culture Collection (PTCC 1645) was used as the urease positive bacterium. Cultivation of the microorganism was conducted in a medium containing 20 g l-1 yeast extract, 10 g l-1 NH4Cl at a pH value of 8. Sporsarcina pasteurii was grown to late exponential phase to final concentration of 1.5 g dry weight l-1 and urease activity of 2.2 mM urea min-1 under aerobic batch conditions. Broth cultures were incubated in a shaker incubator operated at 120 rpm. Cementation solution of MICP consisted of CaCl2 and urea. All experiments were performed at an ambient temperature of 25oC &#177; 2.
For the tests with Whatman No. 42 filter paper, three different soil samples were prepared (dune sand, dune sand stabilized with (5-10-15) % SBR polymer and dune sand stabilized with (5-10-15) % MICP process). Residual water content is 2.5% and the residual dry density is 15 kN/m3. The soil is mixed with the right quantity of water and placed in a sealed plastic bag for 24 hours to allow the hydric equilibrium to establish. The contact filter paper tests were carried out on soil specimens stabilized with SBR polymer and MICP process to the residual water content (2.5%) and nearly residual dry density (15 kN/m3). The soil specimen sizes were 50 mm in diameter and 20 mm height. The test procedure involves placing a piece of initially air dry filter paper against the soil specimen whose matric suction is required and sealing the whole to prevent evaporation. The filter paper was wetted to water content in equilibrium with the magnitude of the soil matric suction, and careful measurement of the water content of the filter paper enables the soil matric suction to be obtained from a previously established correlation. This provides a measure of the matric suction. ASTM D-5298-93 standard is used for the filter paper method.
Results and discussion
The SWCCs for dune sand stabilized with SBR polymer and MICP process under different SBR polymer and MICP process contents are illustrated in this study. Gradual transition from a unimodel SWCC to a bimodal SWCC was observed as SBR polymer and MICP process content increases. The unimodel SWCC is characterized by having two bends defining the air entry value and residual water content. The air entry value is defined as the matric suction above which air commence to enter the soil pores. The residual water content is defined as the water content beyond which no significant decrease in water content occurs. The bimodal SWCC is characterized by having four distinct bindings: two air entry values and two residual water contents. For SBR polymer and MICP process content equal to or less than 5 percent, the SWCC shows a unimodal form of SWCC. With the increase of SBR polymer and MICP process content greater than 5%, the SWCC indicate a bimodal form. It is further observed that the residual water content and the air entry value increases with the increase of SBR polymer and MICP process content. These observations are attributed to the presence of smaller pore size developed as a result of SBR polymer and MICP process particles filling the voids between sand particles. Bimodal SWCC are generally observed for gap-graded soils as well as soils that include two levels of pore sizes defined as macro pores and micro pores. Therefore, it can be inferred that the increase of SBR polymer and MICP process content, resulted in the formation of micro pores within the dune sand stabilized with SBR polymer and MICP process. The portion of the soil water characteristic curves representing macro pore sizes range between matric suction of 0.1 to 100 kPa. Whereas, the portion of the SWCC representing micro pore sizes lies between matric suction of 200 and 1500 kPa.
Summary and Conclusions
In this study, the effect of SBR polymer and MICP process content on the soil water characteristic curves of dune sand was evaluated. SBR polymer and MICP process contents considered include 0%, 5%, 10% and 15%. Results from this study indicated that, as the SBR polymer and MICP process content increased, the shape of the SWCC transforms from a unimodal form to a bimodal form. Furthermore, the air entry value and residual water content were observed to increase with increase in SBR polymer and MICP process content signifying increase in water retention capacity. The bimodal form of the SWCC indicates the presence of two levels of pore sizes; namely macro pores and micro pores. For 10% and 15% SBR polymer and MICP process content, the macro pores are considered the dominant pore size covering a broad range of the SWCC from 0.1 to 100 kPa. Therefore, it is inferred that the SWCC of dune sand stabilized with SBR polymer and MICP process are strongly related to the texture and pore size distribution of the dune sand stabilized with SBR polymer and MICP process which in turn, has a significant impact on its hydraulic characteristics.
./files/site1/files/134/2.pdf</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>571</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>598</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>فرزانه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>دوزالی جوشین</Family>
				<NameE>Farzaneh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Douzali Joushin</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه ارومیه، گروه مهندسی عمران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه ارومیه</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>کاظم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>بدو</Family>
				<NameE>Kazem</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Badv</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه ارومیه، گروه مهندسی عمران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه ارومیه</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محسن</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>برین</Family>
				<NameE>Mohsen</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Barin</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه ارومیه، دانشکده کشاورزی، گروه خاک‌شناسی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه ارومیه</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>سلطانی جیقه</Family>
				<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Soltani Jigheh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه شهید مدنی آذربایجان، گروه مهندسی عمران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه شهید مدنی آذربایجان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Unsaturated soil</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Suction</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>SBR polymer</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Dune sand</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Sporosarcina pasteurii bacteria</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText> خاک غیراشباع</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مکش</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پلیمرSBR</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ماسه بادی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>باکتری باسیلوس پاسته اوری.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>. Frydman S., Baker R., &quot;Theoretical soil-water characteristic curves based on adsorption, cavitation, and a double porosity model&quot;, International Journal of Geomechanical Engineering, Vol. 9. No. 6 (2009) 250-257. ## 2. Alonso E. E., Gens A., Josa A., &quot;A constitutive model for partially saturated soils&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical Engineering, Vol. 8. No. 40 (1990) 405-430. ## 3. Bishop A. W., Blight G. E., &quot;Some aspects of effective stress in saturated and partly saturated soils&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical Engineering, Vol. 7. No. 13 (1963) 177-197. ## 4. Yang H., Rahardjo H., Leong E.C., Fredlund D.G., &quot;Factors affecting drying and wetting soil-water characteristic curves of sandy soils&quot;, Canadian Geotechnical Journal, Vol. 7. No. 41 (2004) 908-920. ## 5. Rawls W. J., Gish T. J., Brakensiek D. L., &quot;Estimating soil water retention from soil physical properties and characteristics&quot;, Journal of Soil Science, Vol. 8. No. 16 (1991) 213- 234. ## 6. Arya L. M., Paris J. F., &quot;A physicoempirical model to predict the soil moisture characteristic from particle-size distribution and bulk density data&quot;, Journal of Soil Science, Vol. 45. No. 6 (1981) 1023–1030. ## 7. حقشناس گرگابی م.، بیگی هرچگانی ح.، &quot;اثر زئولیت میانه بر ظرفیت نگه‌داری آب و ضرایب مدل‌های منحنی رطوبتی دو بافت خاک شنی و لوم رسی&quot;، مجلۀ پژوهش آب ایران، جلد هفتم، شمارۀ 6 (1389) 35-42. ## 8. حق‌وردی ا.، قهرمان ب.، جلینی م.، خشنود یزدی ع. ا.، عرب ز.، &quot;مقایسۀ روش‌های مختلف هوش مصنوعی در مدل‌سازی منحنی مشخصه رطوبتی خاک مطالعۀ موردی: شمال و شمال شرق ایران&quot;، مجلۀ پژوهش‌های حفاظت آب و خاک، جلد هجدهم، شمارۀ 2 (1390) 65-84. ## 9. دشت بزرگ ع.، صیاد غ. ع.، کاظمی نژاد ا.، &quot;بررسی اثر نوع ماده جاذب آب بر ظرفیت نگه‌داری آب خاک&quot;، مجلۀ علمی کشاورزی، جلد سی و پنجم، شمارۀ 4 (1391) 33-38. ## 10. رمضانی م.، صالحی خشک رودی ش.، لیاقت ع.، غلامی سفید کوهی م. ع.، &quot;برآورد منحنی مشخصه رطوبتی خاک با استفاده از اندازه‌گیری 2 نقطه‌ای&quot;، مجلۀ پژوهش آب در کشاورزی، جلد بیست و هفتم، شمارۀ 3 (1392) 35-43. ## 11. باباییان ا.، همایی م.، نوروزی ع. ا.، &quot;عملکرد توابع انتقالی طیفی پارامتریک و نقطه ای برای برآورد منحنی مشخصه رطوبتی خاک&quot;، مجلۀ تحقیقات آب و خاک ایران، جلد چهل و پنجم، شمارۀ 4 (1393) 475-490. ## 12. بایرام م.، ابراهیمی ا.، &quot;تأثیر نوع خاک و وضعیت تراکم بر منحنی مشخصه رطوبتی خاک&quot;، نشریۀ حفاظت منابع آب و خاک، جلد نهم، شمارۀ 4 (1394) 65-77. ## 13. جهانشاهی ر.، قاسمی م.، توفیق و.، &quot;ارزیابی تأثیر شرایط غیراشباع بر مشخصات مکانیکی خاک‌های تثبیت شده با آهک هیدراته&quot;، مجلۀ مهندسی زیرساخت‌های حمل و نقل، جلد هفتم، شمارۀ 9 (1396) 23-38. ## 14. صفاری ر. حبیب آگهی ق. نیکویی ا. نیازی ع.، &quot;تأثیر تثبیت بیولوژیکی خاک بر منحنی نگه‌داشت آب- خاک»، دهمین کنگره بین المللی مهندسی عمران&quot;، دانشکدۀ، مهندسی عمران، دانشگاه تبریز (1394). ## 15. جوهری ع. فرخ نژاد س. جوکار ع.، &quot;پیش‌بینی منحنی مشخصه آب- خاک با استفاده از روش آماری&quot;، ششمین کنگرۀ ملی مهندسی عمران&quot;، دانشکدۀ مهندسی عمران، دانشگاه سمنان (1390). ## 16. Choudhary M. I., Shalaby A. A., Al-Omran A. M., &quot;Water holding capacity and evaporation of calcareous soils as affected by four synthetic polymers&quot;, Communications in Soil Science and Plant Analysis, Vol.6. No. 66 (1995) 350-355. ## 17. Ivanov V., Chu J., &quot;Applications of Microorganisms to Geotechnical Engineering for Bioclogging and Biocementation of Soil In-situ,&quot; Review in Environmental Science and Biotechnology, Vol. 7. No.3 (2008) 139-153. ## 18. Vanapalli S. K., Fredlund D. G., Pufahl, D. E., &quot;The influence of soil structure and stress history on the soil-water characteristics of a compacted till&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical Engineering, Vol. 49. No. 2 (1999) 143-159. ## 19. &quot;ASTM Standard D 6836-02, Test Methods for Determination of the Soil-Water Characteristic Curve for Desorption Using a Hanging Column, Pressure Extractor, Chilled Mirror Hygrometer, and/or Centrifuge Annual Book of ASTM Standards&quot;, Vol. 4. No. 8 (2003). ## 20. Houston S. L., Houston W. N., Wagner A., &quot;Laboratory filter paper suction measurements&quot;, Geotechnical Testing Journal, Vol. 17. No. 3 (1994) 185-194. ## 21. Gupta S.C., Larson W.E., &quot;Estimating of soil- water rention characteristics from particle size disturbition&quot;, Organic matter percent, and bulk density, Water Resources Research Journal, Vol. 15. No. 6 (1979) 1633-1635. ## 22. Fredlund D.G., Sheng D., Zaho J., &quot;Estimation of soil suction from the soil water characteristic curve&quot;, Can. Geotech, Vol. 48. No. 4 (2011) 186–198. ## 23. Johari A., Habibagahib G., Ghahramanib A., &quot;Prediction of SWCC using artificial intelligent systems: A comparative study&quot;, Scientia Iranica, Vol. 18. No. 5 (2011) 1002–1008. ## 24. Garg A., Garg A., Tai K., Barontini S., Stokes A., &quot;A computational intelligence-based genetic programming approach for the simulation of soil water retention curves&quot;, Transp. Porous Media, Vol. 103. No. 3 (2014) 497–513. ## 25. Fredlund D. G., Rahardjo H., &quot;Soil Mechanics for Unsaturated Soils&quot;, New York: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc, (1993). ## 26. Gardner R., &quot;A method of measuring the capillary tension of soil moisture over a wide moisture range&quot;, Soil Science, vol. 43. No. 3 (1937) 277-283. ## 27. ASTM D5298-92, &quot;Standard test method for measurement of soil potential (suction) using filter paper&quot;, American Society of Testing and Materials. Annual Book of ASTM Standards, Philadelphia, Vol. 15. No. 9 (1992) 156–161. ## 28. Kiatkamjornwong S., &quot;Super absorbent polymer and super absorbent polymer composites&quot;, Journal of Scienceasia, Vol. 33. No. 1 (2007) 39- 43. ## ##. Frydman S., Baker R., &quot;Theoretical soil-water characteristic curves based on adsorption, cavitation, and a double porosity model&quot;, International Journal of Geomechanical Engineering, Vol. 9. No. 6 (2009) 250-257. ## 2. Alonso E. E., Gens A., Josa A., &quot;A constitutive model for partially saturated soils&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical Engineering, Vol. 8. No. 40 (1990) 405-430. ## 3. Bishop A. W., Blight G. E., &quot;Some aspects of effective stress in saturated and partly saturated soils&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical Engineering, Vol. 7. No. 13 (1963) 177-197. ## 4. Yang H., Rahardjo H., Leong E.C., Fredlund D.G., &quot;Factors affecting drying and wetting soil-water characteristic curves of sandy soils&quot;, Canadian Geotechnical Journal, Vol. 7. No. 41 (2004) 908-920. ## 5. Rawls W. J., Gish T. J., Brakensiek D. L., &quot;Estimating soil water retention from soil physical properties and characteristics&quot;, Journal of Soil Science, Vol. 8. No. 16 (1991) 213- 234. ## 6. Arya L. M., Paris J. F., &quot;A physicoempirical model to predict the soil moisture characteristic from particle-size distribution and bulk density data&quot;, Journal of Soil Science, Vol. 45. No. 6 (1981) 1023–1030. ## 7. حقشناس گرگابی م.، بیگی هرچگانی ح.، &quot;اثر زئولیت میانه بر ظرفیت نگه‌داری آب و ضرایب مدل‌های منحنی رطوبتی دو بافت خاک شنی و لوم رسی&quot;، مجلۀ پژوهش آب ایران، جلد هفتم، شمارۀ 6 (1389) 35-42. ## 8. حق‌وردی ا.، قهرمان ب.، جلینی م.، خشنود یزدی ع. ا.، عرب ز.، &quot;مقایسۀ روش‌های مختلف هوش مصنوعی در مدل‌سازی منحنی مشخصه رطوبتی خاک مطالعۀ موردی: شمال و شمال شرق ایران&quot;، مجلۀ پژوهش‌های حفاظت آب و خاک، جلد هجدهم، شمارۀ 2 (1390) 65-84. ## 9. دشت بزرگ ع.، صیاد غ. ع.، کاظمی نژاد ا.، &quot;بررسی اثر نوع ماده جاذب آب بر ظرفیت نگه‌داری آب خاک&quot;، مجلۀ علمی کشاورزی، جلد سی و پنجم، شمارۀ 4 (1391) 33-38. ## 10. رمضانی م.، صالحی خشک رودی ش.، لیاقت ع.، غلامی سفید کوهی م. ع.، &quot;برآورد منحنی مشخصه رطوبتی خاک با استفاده از اندازه‌گیری 2 نقطه‌ای&quot;، مجلۀ پژوهش آب در کشاورزی، جلد بیست و هفتم، شمارۀ 3 (1392) 35-43. ## 11. باباییان ا.، همایی م.، نوروزی ع. ا.، &quot;عملکرد توابع انتقالی طیفی پارامتریک و نقطه ای برای برآورد منحنی مشخصه رطوبتی خاک&quot;، مجلۀ تحقیقات آب و خاک ایران، جلد چهل و پنجم، شمارۀ 4 (1393) 475-490. ## 12. بایرام م.، ابراهیمی ا.، &quot;تأثیر نوع خاک و وضعیت تراکم بر منحنی مشخصه رطوبتی خاک&quot;، نشریۀ حفاظت منابع آب و خاک، جلد نهم، شمارۀ 4 (1394) 65-77. ## 13. جهانشاهی ر.، قاسمی م.، توفیق و.، &quot;ارزیابی تأثیر شرایط غیراشباع بر مشخصات مکانیکی خاک‌های تثبیت شده با آهک هیدراته&quot;، مجلۀ مهندسی زیرساخت‌های حمل و نقل، جلد هفتم، شمارۀ 9 (1396) 23-38. ## 14. صفاری ر. حبیب آگهی ق. نیکویی ا. نیازی ع.، &quot;تأثیر تثبیت بیولوژیکی خاک بر منحنی نگه‌داشت آب- خاک»، دهمین کنگره بین المللی مهندسی عمران&quot;، دانشکدۀ، مهندسی عمران، دانشگاه تبریز (1394). ## 15. جوهری ع. فرخ نژاد س. جوکار ع.، &quot;پیش‌بینی منحنی مشخصه آب- خاک با استفاده از روش آماری&quot;، ششمین کنگرۀ ملی مهندسی عمران&quot;، دانشکدۀ مهندسی عمران، دانشگاه سمنان (1390). ## 16. Choudhary M. I., Shalaby A. A., Al-Omran A. M., &quot;Water holding capacity and evaporation of calcareous soils as affected by four synthetic polymers&quot;, Communications in Soil Science and Plant Analysis, Vol.6. No. 66 (1995) 350-355. ## 17. Ivanov V., Chu J., &quot;Applications of Microorganisms to Geotechnical Engineering for Bioclogging and Biocementation of Soil In-situ,&quot; Review in Environmental Science and Biotechnology, Vol. 7. No.3 (2008) 139-153. ## 18. Vanapalli S. K., Fredlund D. G., Pufahl, D. E., &quot;The influence of soil structure and stress history on the soil-water characteristics of a compacted till&quot;, Journal of Geotechnical Engineering, Vol. 49. No. 2 (1999) 143-159. ## 19. &quot;ASTM Standard D 6836-02, Test Methods for Determination of the Soil-Water Characteristic Curve for Desorption Using a Hanging Column, Pressure Extractor, Chilled Mirror Hygrometer, and/or Centrifuge Annual Book of ASTM Standards&quot;, Vol. 4. No. 8 (2003). ## 20. Houston S. L., Houston W. N., Wagner A., &quot;Laboratory filter paper suction measurements&quot;, Geotechnical Testing Journal, Vol. 17. No. 3 (1994) 185-194. ## 21. Gupta S.C., Larson W.E., &quot;Estimating of soil- water rention characteristics from particle size disturbition&quot;, Organic matter percent, and bulk density, Water Resources Research Journal, Vol. 15. No. 6 (1979) 1633-1635. ## 22. Fredlund D.G., Sheng D., Zaho J., &quot;Estimation of soil suction from the soil water characteristic curve&quot;, Can. Geotech, Vol. 48. No. 4 (2011) 186–198. ## 23. Johari A., Habibagahib G., Ghahramanib A., &quot;Prediction of SWCC using artificial intelligent systems: A comparative study&quot;, Scientia Iranica, Vol. 18. No. 5 (2011) 1002–1008. ## 24. Garg A., Garg A., Tai K., Barontini S., Stokes A., &quot;A computational intelligence-based genetic programming approach for the simulation of soil water retention curves&quot;, Transp. Porous Media, Vol. 103. No. 3 (2014) 497–513. ## 25. Fredlund D. G., Rahardjo H., &quot;Soil Mechanics for Unsaturated Soils&quot;, New York: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc, (1993). ## 26. Gardner R., &quot;A method of measuring the capillary tension of soil moisture over a wide moisture range&quot;, Soil Science, vol. 43. No. 3 (1937) 277-283. ## 27. ASTM D5298-92, &quot;Standard test method for measurement of soil potential (suction) using filter paper&quot;, American Society of Testing and Materials. Annual Book of ASTM Standards, Philadelphia, Vol. 15. No. 9 (1992) 156–161. ## 28. Kiatkamjornwong S., &quot;Super absorbent polymer and super absorbent polymer composites&quot;, Journal of Scienceasia, Vol. 33. No. 1 (2007) 39- 43. ##  ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تحلیل دینامیکی اندرکنش روکش بتنی و بخش سنگ‌ریز سدهای سنگ‌ریز با روکش بتنی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>A Dynamic Analysis of the Interaction of Concrete Face and Rockfill Part in Concrete Faced Rockfill Dams</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>سدهای سنگ&#8204;ریز با روکش بتنی به&#8204;دلیل نداشتن وابستگی زیاد به بستر و شکل دره و نیز تکنولوژی ساده&#173;ترساخت، در سال&#8204;های اخیر بیش از انواع دیگر سدها مورد توجه قرارگرفته است. رفتار این نوع سازه&#173;&#173;ها تحت بارگذاری زلزله به عوامل زیادی مانند روکش بتنی و اصطکاک آن با سنگ&#8204;دانه&#8204;ها و شرایط تکیه&#8204;گاهی آن بستگی دارد و برای تعیین دقیق این رفتار نیاز به تحقیقات عددی با انجام تحلیل&#173;&#173;های دینامیکی تاریخچۀ زمانی است. در این پژوهش با مدل&#8204;سازی در محیط نرم&#8204;افزار آباکوس، رفتار لرزه&#173;&#173;ای سدهای سنگ&#8204;ریز با روکش بتنی با در نظر گرفتن پارامترهای ذکر شده بررسی شده است. به این منظور دو رکورد از زلزله&#8204;های نزدیک گسل انتخاب شده و تحلیل دینامیکی غیرخطی انجام شده است. نتایج نشان می&#173;دهد با افزایش ضریب اصطکاک روکش بتنی، جذب انرژی به&#8204;میزان اندکی افزایش می&#173;یابد. هم&#8204;چنین با مقیدکردن روکش بتنی به بخش سنگ&#8204;ریز تفاوت چشم&#8204;گیری در تاریخچۀ تغییرمکان نسبی تاج سد مشاهده می&#173;شود و در این شرایط تغییرمکان تاج سد در هر دو رکورد کاهش می&#173;یابد. در شرایط مقیدکردن روکش بتنی به بخش سنگ&#8204;ریز، جذب انرژی به&#8204;طور چشم&#8204;گیری افزایش یافته و روکش بتنی در انتهای رکورد دچار خرابی کامل شده است. به&#8204;علاوه با افزایش تراز آب، تغییرشکل تاج سد در جهت اعمال رکورد زلزله افزایش چشم&#8204;گیری نشان می&#173;دهد، به&#8204;گونه&#173;ای که در حالت پر، بیشینه تغییرمکان نسبت به حالت خالی به&#8204;طور میانگین30% افزایش یافته است.
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Introduction
Concrete faced rockfill dams have been considered in recent years more than other types of dams due to their low dependency on the bed and the shape of the valley, as well as the simpler construction technology. In this regard, rockfill dams are a suitable substitute for embankment dams because of higher stability of the body and the availability of rock aggregates. On the other hand, because the permeability of rock aggregates is much higher than other materials, different methods are used to seal these types of dams. One of these methods is the use of non-impermeable concrete facing in the upstream of these dams. This particular type of gravel dams is called Concrete-Faced Rockfill Dams (CRFD). In this study, a contact element with a definition of elastic-plastic failure in the modeling process is proposed to simulate the surface separation and re-contact of the concrete face with the rockfill surface of the dam.
Method
In this paper, behavior of a concrete faced rockfill dam under earthquake loads is investigated. For this purpose, near-field earthquake records with focal depth lower than 15 km (for example Tabas earthquake 1978, M=7.4, and San Fernando earthquake 1970, M=6.6) are used. Moreover, to study the dam behavior under dynamic loads, interaction between concrete face and rockfill part of the dam is investigated and finally, some parameters including displacement, absorbed energy and base shear are evaluated. So, finite element method and Abaqus software is used for the study. Verification of the models is carried out using the results of previous researches by conducting modal analysis and determining natural vibration period. Then, the interaction between the concrete face and rockfill part as well as the effect of water level changes in stability of dam under dynamic load is investigated. Concrete behavior is simulated using concrete damaged plasticity. Therefore, concrete density, compressive strength and tensile strength and elasticity modulus are 2350 kg/m3, 25 MPa, 3 MPa and 29 GPa, respectively. Poisson&#8217;s ratio is assumed to be 0.2. Furthermore, 4-node shell elements are used to simulate concrete face and Drucker-Prager constitutive model is used to define rockfill material behavior.
The density and Poisson&#8217;s ratio for 2B, 3C and 3B layers are 2150 kg/m3 and 0.35, respectively. The shear modulus values for these layers are respectively 8.93, 2.89, and 3.85 GPa. In order to perform the simulation, the part of the dam structure beside the bed rock and the surrounding rock is considered as fixed bearing, and only the rockfill part and concrete face of the dam is simulated. Based on this assumption that the bed is rigid, there is no need to consider the dam foundation. This method is frequently used in literature review.
All the surfaces of the dam and bed rock are considered as fixed bearing to simulate the real condition where the dam is attached to bed rock and the surrounding rock. The interaction between dam layers is defined as tie. For defining the interaction between rockfill body and concrete face, tangential and normal contacts are defined using penalty method with friction coefficient equal to 0.5. In the next step, the model is meshed using 4-node shell elements for concrete face, 8-node brick and 4-node pyramid solid elements for rockfill body. Rayleigh damping is used to simulate the structure damping. The effective length of the dam reservoir has been determined by conducting several analyzes, so that the minimum required length for reservoir is reached in order to decrease the number of elements of the model.
Results and discussion
1. Interaction between concrete face and rockfill body 
The results show that the increase of friction coefficient between concrete face and rockfill part from 0.5 to 0.7 has not affect the displacement of dam crown along the earthquake direction. However, when the concrete face is fixed to the rockfill part, significant changes are induced in dam crown displacement time history. In all cases, the deflection due to the dam weight is increased when the concrete face is attached to the rockfill body. The reason can be attributed to the tied interaction between these layers which results in similar deflection of concrete face with rockfill body and higher deflection of concrete dam crown. However, after the application of earthquake load, the displacement of the dam crown decreased in both analyses when tie interaction is defined between concrete face and rockfill body. In this study, due to the very high volume of analysis and its timeliness, it was not possible to examine the dam behavior in the free vibration regime, and therefore, it is not possible to assume the last displacement values at the end of analyses as the permanent displacement of dam. Figure 1 shows the relative displacement of the dam for the two selected earthquakes with a friction coefficient equal to 0.5 between the concrete face and the gravel body. According to Figure 1, the maximum displacement induced by the earthquake is related to Tabas and then, San Francisco earthquake. Furthermore, the high energy content of the Tabas record has been more effective in inducing greater displacement than the other record.
&#160;
Figure 1. Lateral displacement of dam crown relative to the dam base for the selected earthquakes; Tabas and San Fernando.
The results also indicate that when the friction coefficient between concrete face and rockfill body is 0.5, the lowest damage occurs in the dam compared to that happens when friction coefficient is 0.7 or when the surfaces are tied. When the tied surfaces are used, the most damages takes place in concrete face, since all rockfill body displacement transmits to concrete face which results in much more concrete damages compared to the other interaction cases.
2. Effect of water level in reservoir on dam behavior
In this section, the effect of water level on seismic behavior of dam is investigated. For this purpose, the dam reservoir is analyzed in three cases including empty, half full and full (90% of dam height). Each study cases are examined under San Fernando and Tabas earthquakes. Figure 2 shows the relative displacement of dam crown in the three water level case for San Fernando and Tabas earthquakes.
&#160;
Figure 2. Relative displacement of dam crown in three water level cases of empty, half and full for (a) Tabas and (b) San Fernando earthquakes
According to Figure 2, for both earthquakes, the dam crown displacement along the earthquake direction is significantly increased by increasing the water level, so that the maximum displacement in full case is 50% higher than empty case.
Conclusion
In this study, using the finite element method and simulation by Abaqus, the seismic behavior of concrete face rockfill dams has been investigated. For this purpose, the verification is firstly carried out using previous research results in literature. In the next step, nonlinear dynamical analysis is carried out, taking into account large displacements for the models under the earthquake record acceleration. The results illustrate that increasing the friction coefficient between the concrete face and the rockfill body from 0.5 to 0.7 has no significant effect on the displacement of the dam crown under earthquake load. Moreover, by using tie interaction between the concrete layer and the rockfill body, there is a substantial difference in the history of the relative displacement of the dam, and the displacement of the dam due to its weight has been increased. Furthermore, the results of this study exhibit that, with increasing the water level in dam reservoir, the deformation of the crown of the dam along the earthquake application direction has had a relatively significant increase, such that in the full state, the maximum displacement is increased by about 50% compared to that of the empty case. This is while the most damage of concrete is observed in the case when half height of dam in filled by water. Due to the more destructive power of near-field earthquakes and their impact nature, only near-fault earthquakes have been used in this research. Therefore, the results of this study are valid only for the behavior of dam under near-field earthquakes.
./files/site1/files/134/3.pdf</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>599</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>616</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی محمد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رجبی</Family>
				<NameE>Ali M</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rajabi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران، گروه زمین‌شناسی مهندسی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>انشگاه تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>amrajabi@ymail.com; amrajabi@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علیرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>سجده</Family>
				<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Sajdeh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه قم، دانشکدۀ مهندسی عمران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه قم</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>alireza.sajdeh@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Concrete faced rockfill dams</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Dynamic Analysis</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Finite element</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Interaction</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Water level</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText> سد سنگ‌ریز با روکش بتنی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تحلیل دینامیکی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اجزای محدود</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اندرکنش</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تراز آب.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1.	Bayraktar A., Haciefendioglu K., Muvafik M., &quot;Asynchronous seismic analysis of concrete-faced rockfill dams including dam-reservoir interaction&quot;, Canadian Journal of Civil Engineering. Vol. 32, No. 5 (2005).## 2.	Bayraktar A., Kartal M. E., &quot;Linear and nonlinear response of concrete slab on CFR dam during earthquake&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering. Vol. 30, No. 10 (2010). ## 3.	Haeri S. M., Karimi M., &quot;Three dimensional response of concrete faced rockfill dams to strong earthquakes considering dam-foundation interaction and spatial variable ground&quot;, 1st European conference on earthquake engineering and seismology, Vol. 43, No. 11 (2006) 143-154. ## 4.	Bilici Y., Bayraktar A., Soyluk K., Haciefendioglu K., Ates S., Adanur S., &quot;Stochastic dynamic response of dam–reservoir-foundation systems to spatially varying earthquake ground motions&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering. Vol. 29, No. 3 (2009) 444-58. ## 5.	Hunter G., Fell R., &quot;Rockfill modulus and settlement of concrete face rockfill dam&quot;, Geotechnical and Geoenviromental Engineering. Vol. 129, No. 10 (2003) 909-917. ## 6.	Zhang G., Zhang J. M., &quot;Numerical Modeling of Soil–Structure Interface of a Concrete-Faced Rockfill Dam&quot;, Computers and Geotechnics. Vol. 36, No. 5 (2009) 762-772. ## 7.	Liu J., Liu F., Kong X., Yu L., &quot;Large-Scale Shaking Table Model Tests of Aseismic Measures for Concrete Faced Rock-Fill Dams&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, 61-62 (2014) 152-163. ## 8.	Bin X., Zou D., Liu H., &quot;Three-Dimensional Simulation of the Construction Process of the Zipingpu Concrete Face Rockfill Dam Based on a Generalized Plasticity Model&quot;, Computers and Geotechnics, Vol. 43, No. 3 (2012) 143-154. ## 9.	Areias P. M. A., Belytschko T., &quot;Analysis of Three-Dimensional Crack Initiation and Propagation Using the Extended Finite Element Method&quot;, International Journal for Numerical Methods in Engineering. Vol. 63, No. 55 (2005) 760-788. ## 10.	Han G., Kong X., Li J., &quot;Dynamic experiments and numerical simulations of model concrete faced rockfill dams&quot;, 9th world conference on earthquake engineering. Japan Association for Earthquake Disaster Prevention, Tokyo (1988). ## 11.	ABAQUS finite element software, Ver. 6.14.2, Simulia, (2014). ## 12.	Atluri S. N., Shen S., &quot;The Meshless Local Petrov-Galerkin (MLPG) Method&quot;, Tech Science Press, USA, (2002). ## 13.	Justo J. L., Segovia F., Jarmillo A., &quot;Three dimensional joint elements applied to concrete-faced dams&quot;, International Journal for Numerical and Analytical Methods in Geomechanics, Vol. 19, No. 9 (1995) 615-36. ## 14.	Udwadia F. E., Trifunac M. D., &quot;Ambient Vibration Test of Full Scale Structures&quot;, 5th World Conf. On Earthquake Engineering. Rome, (1973). ## 15.	سالمی س.، میرقاسمی ع. ا.، &quot;بررسی اندرکنش رویۀ بتنی با بستر سنگ‌ریز در تحلیل دینامیکی سه‌بعدی سدهای سنگ‌ریز با رویۀ بتنی&quot;، پنجمین کنفرانس ملی زلزله و سازه (1393). ## 16.	Dakoulas P., &quot;Nonlinear seismic response of tall concrete-faced rockfill dams in narrow canyons&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, Vol. 34, No. 1 (2012) 11-24. ##  ##1.	Bayraktar A., Haciefendioglu K., Muvafik M., &quot;Asynchronous seismic analysis of concrete-faced rockfill dams including dam-reservoir interaction&quot;, Canadian Journal of Civil Engineering. Vol. 32, No. 5 (2005).## 2.	Bayraktar A., Kartal M. E., &quot;Linear and nonlinear response of concrete slab on CFR dam during earthquake&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering. Vol. 30, No. 10 (2010). ## 3.	Haeri S. M., Karimi M., &quot;Three dimensional response of concrete faced rockfill dams to strong earthquakes considering dam-foundation interaction and spatial variable ground&quot;, 1st European conference on earthquake engineering and seismology, Vol. 43, No. 11 (2006) 143-154. ## 4.	Bilici Y., Bayraktar A., Soyluk K., Haciefendioglu K., Ates S., Adanur S., &quot;Stochastic dynamic response of dam–reservoir-foundation systems to spatially varying earthquake ground motions&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering. Vol. 29, No. 3 (2009) 444-58. ## 5.	Hunter G., Fell R., &quot;Rockfill modulus and settlement of concrete face rockfill dam&quot;, Geotechnical and Geoenviromental Engineering. Vol. 129, No. 10 (2003) 909-917. ## 6.	Zhang G., Zhang J. M., &quot;Numerical Modeling of Soil–Structure Interface of a Concrete-Faced Rockfill Dam&quot;, Computers and Geotechnics. Vol. 36, No. 5 (2009) 762-772. ## 7.	Liu J., Liu F., Kong X., Yu L., &quot;Large-Scale Shaking Table Model Tests of Aseismic Measures for Concrete Faced Rock-Fill Dams&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, 61-62 (2014) 152-163. ## 8.	Bin X., Zou D., Liu H., &quot;Three-Dimensional Simulation of the Construction Process of the Zipingpu Concrete Face Rockfill Dam Based on a Generalized Plasticity Model&quot;, Computers and Geotechnics, Vol. 43, No. 3 (2012) 143-154. ## 9.	Areias P. M. A., Belytschko T., &quot;Analysis of Three-Dimensional Crack Initiation and Propagation Using the Extended Finite Element Method&quot;, International Journal for Numerical Methods in Engineering. Vol. 63, No. 55 (2005) 760-788. ## 10.	Han G., Kong X., Li J., &quot;Dynamic experiments and numerical simulations of model concrete faced rockfill dams&quot;, 9th world conference on earthquake engineering. Japan Association for Earthquake Disaster Prevention, Tokyo (1988). ## 11.	ABAQUS finite element software, Ver. 6.14.2, Simulia, (2014). ## 12.	Atluri S. N., Shen S., &quot;The Meshless Local Petrov-Galerkin (MLPG) Method&quot;, Tech Science Press, USA, (2002). ## 13.	Justo J. L., Segovia F., Jarmillo A., &quot;Three dimensional joint elements applied to concrete-faced dams&quot;, International Journal for Numerical and Analytical Methods in Geomechanics, Vol. 19, No. 9 (1995) 615-36. ## 14.	Udwadia F. E., Trifunac M. D., &quot;Ambient Vibration Test of Full Scale Structures&quot;, 5th World Conf. On Earthquake Engineering. Rome, (1973). ## 15.	سالمی س.، میرقاسمی ع. ا.، &quot;بررسی اندرکنش رویۀ بتنی با بستر سنگ‌ریز در تحلیل دینامیکی سه‌بعدی سدهای سنگ‌ریز با رویۀ بتنی&quot;، پنجمین کنفرانس ملی زلزله و سازه (1393). ## 16.	Dakoulas P., &quot;Nonlinear seismic response of tall concrete-faced rockfill dams in narrow canyons&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, Vol. 34, No. 1 (2012) 11-24. ##   ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی ضرایب سایندگی و شکنندگی سنگدانه‌های مسیر مترو تبریز</TitleF>
		<TitleE>The Abrasion and Brittleness Coefficients of Tabriz’s Metro Aggregates</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>حفر تونل&#8204;های طویل غالباً به&#8204;صورت مکانیزه و با ماشین حفاری تونل TBM انجام می&#8204;شود. یکی از عوامل مهم در حفاری این تونل&#173;ها اثر سایندگی خاک و سنگدانه&#8204;ها بر ابزارهای برشی و سایر بخش&#173;های دستگاه حفار تونل است که باعث کاهش چشم&#8204;گیری در راندمان حفاری پروژه می&#8204;شود. محققان عوامل مختلفی که باعث ایجاد سایش در ابزار حفاری می&#8204;شوند را بررسی کرده&#8204;اند. در تحقیق حاضر 32 نمونه از سنگ&#8204;دانه&#8204;های مسیر تونل خط دو مترو تبریز انتخاب شده و میزان سایندگی و شکنندگی این سنگ&#8204;دانه&#8204;ها برای بخش&#8204;های مختلف مسیر تعیین شده است. هم&#8204;چنین از بین مهم&#8204;ترین عوامل مؤثر، تأثیر پارامترهای وجود و میزان آب، جنس، اندازه و شکل سنگ&#8204;دانه&#8204;ها، نوع و میزان فوم حفاری بر میزان ضریب سایندگی و شکنندگی سنگ&#8204;دانه&#8204;های مسیر بررسی شده، قرار گرفته است. بدین&#8204;منظور نیز حدود 130 نمونه از سنگ&#8204;دانه&#8204;ها شامل 20 نمونه برای بررسی تأثیر وجود و میزان آب، 15 نمونه برای جنس، 20 نمونه برای اندازۀ دانه&#173;ها، 30 نمونه برای شکل و 42 نمونه برای تأثیر نوع و میزان فوم مصرفی تهیه شده است. روش&#173;های زیادی برای آزمایش سایندگی خاک و خرده سنگ&#173;ها در بخش&#173;های حفاری به&#8204;وسیلۀ محققان ارایه شده است که یکی از معتبرترین و متداول&#8204;ترین این آزمایش&#8204;ها آزمون LCPC است.&#160; بر اساس نتایج حاصل برای بررسی تأثیر میزان آب بر سایندگی، روی سه جنس آندزیت، ماسه سنگ و کنگلومرای مسیر از حالت خشک تا وجود آب به میزان 30% وزنی نمونه آزمایش انجام شده است که در دو جنس ماسه سنگ و کنگلومرا با افزایش میزان آب سایندگی بیش&#8204;تر شده ولی در آندزیت از 20% به بعد کاهش سایندگی مشاهده می&#173;شود، میزان ضریب شکنندگی نیز در کل با افزایش میزان آب کاهش می&#173;یابد. از لحاظ سنگ&#8204;شناسی بیش&#8204;ترین تأثیر بر سایندگی را کنگلومرا داشته و از نظر شکنندگی هم آندزیت شکننده&#173;ترین است. در تأثیر اندازۀ دانه&#173;ها، با افزایش اندازۀ دانه&#173;ها سایش زیادتر و شکنندگی کم&#8204;تر می&#173;شود. تأثیر فوم بر سایندگی به این صورت است که تا حد خیس&#8204;&#173;شدگی سایندگی کاهش یافته و بیش&#8204;تر از آن باعث افزایش سایندگی می&#173;شود. از بین فوم&#8204;های مختلف آزمایش&#8204;شده نیز فوم شیمی بتن دارای حداقل سایندگی است.
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Introduction
Urban development and rapid extension of cities have been accompanied by a considerable growth in mechanized tunneling. The abrasivity of rock and even soil is a factor with considerable influence on the wear of tools. Soil abrasion and the resulting tool wear has a major impact on machine operation, utilization, and tunneling costs and time. One of the problematic aspects of working in abrasive grounds is the frequent need for the replacement of cutting tools, especially in pressurized face tunnel boring machines (TBMs). The effect of worn and damaged TBM cutter heads has been documented for numerous tunnel projects around the world. However, the lack of a standard or universally accepted test for soil abrasivity in geotechnical investigations has made the prediction of tool wear a difficult task.
Material and methods
A reliable prognosis of the abrasiveness of soils on a project would be of great benefit for designers, clients, and contractors. Many abrasion tests exist for rocks, and some have been proposed for soils; however, there is no universally accepted or international standard test for soil abrasivity testing. One of the most important and available tests in this field is LCPC abrasivity test which was developed by the Laboratoire Central des Ponts et Chauss&#233;es in the 1980&#8217;s. The LCPC Abrasivity Coefficient (ABR or LAC) can be used as a measure for both the abrasivity of the soil material and the influence of the grain size. The&#160; abrasivity&#160; testing&#160; of&#160; rock&#160; is&#160; controlled&#160; by well-known parameters, whereas in soils many factors are influencing the abrasivity such as in-situ soil conditions, sedimentary petrology and technical&#160;&#160; properties.
Tabriz metro line 2 Project about 22 km in length that will connect eastern part of the Tabriz city to its western part, considered as a case study. The project comprises a single tunnel which has been constructed using two earth pressure balance EPB-TBM with a cutting-wheel diameter of 9.49 m. In this study, based on geological and geotechnical properties, the tunnel route was divided into four parts and the abrasion and brittleness coefficients of alluviums determined by LCPC test. Besides that, the influences of some factors such as moisture content, mineralogy, grain size and shape, type and amount of foam have been studied.
Results and discussion
Based on more than 130 LCPC test results, in general, the Tabriz Metro&#8217;s line-2 route alluviums have the abrasion in the range of low to very high and the brittleness in the range of high to very high. In order to measure the effect of moisture content on abrasion and brittleness coefficient, the LCPC test was done on some samples related to the tunnel route in dried and moistened modes (5%, 0%, 15%, 20%, 25%, and 30%). Three types of sandstone, andesite, and conglomerate of the route were used to test the effect of moisture and petrology on abrasion. In a moisture range of 0 to 5%, in all types of materials, abrasion was increased. In a moisture range of 5 to 10%, abrasion was decreased in all three types, and this shows that a moisture level of 10% is a normal moisture content to create minimum abrasion. The behavior of sandstone and conglomerate is similar at higher moisture contents, and an increase in moisture content to 30% can increase abrasion of materials in both types. In conglomerate, abrasion at higher moisture levels is significantly more than in other modes. In andesite, an increase in moisture content to 20% can increase abrasion, although the abrasion is decreased with a moisture content of over 20%. In most samples, increase in moisture content led to decrease in brittleness of materials. In general, the highest abrasion level was related to conglomerate and the lowest level was related to sandstone. Moreover, andesite was at a lower level than conglomerate and a higher level than sandstone in terms of abrasion. Also, the results show that increased grain size led to increased abrasion, and the changes in andesite were greater than in sandstone.
In order to test the effectiveness of foam on abrasion, the foam used in workshops (A 168) made by Komeil Company Kashan was used for four types of petrography: conglomerate, andesite, sandstone, and silica. This test was conducted in the range of dried to 100 ml foam. In all types, decreased abrasion is observed from 0 to 20 ml and increased abrasion is observed from 20 to 100 ml.
Conclusion
The following conclusions are drawn from this research.
- With regard to the effect of grain size, increased size of grains could lead to more abrasion and less brittleness
- In terms of the effect of mineralogy, the conglomerate had the most effect on abrasion. In terms of brittleness, andesite was the most brittle.
- When the foam is moisturized in the sample, minimum abrasion is observed and above this level, the abrasion is increased.
./files/site1/files/134/4.pdf</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>617</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>644</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>امیر حسن</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رضایی فرعی</Family>
				<NameE>Amirhasan</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rezaei Farei</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه شهید مدنی آذربایجان، دانشکدۀ فنی و مهندسی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه شهید مدنی آذربایجان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>rezaei.ah@azaruniv.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مسعود</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>مصطفایی</Family>
				<NameE>Masoud</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Mostafaei</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تبریز</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سید کاظم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رضوی</Family>
				<NameE>Kazem</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Razavi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تبریز، دانشکدۀ مهندسی عمران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه تبریز</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText> LCPC test</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>soil abrasion</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Tabriz metro aggregates</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>foam.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText> ضریب سایندگی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شکنندگی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>آزمون LCPC</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>فوم حفاری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>آبرفت‌های مسیر خط 2 مترو تبریز.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1.	1.Nilsen B., Dahl F., Holzhäuser J., Raleigh P., &quot;Abrasivity testing for rock and soils&quot;, Tunnels &amp; Tunneling International (April 2006) 47-49.## 2.	آیتی ف.، مهدوری س.، &quot;تخمین تراست مورد نیاز حفاری در تونل انتقال آب بهشت آباد&quot;، نشریۀ زمین‌شناسی ‌مهندسی، ۷ (۱) (1392) 1707-۱۷۲۴.## 3.	Tarigh azali S., Moammeri H., &quot;EPB-TBM tunneling in abrasive ground, Esfahan Metro Line 1&quot;, WTC ITA-AITES 2012 World Tunnel Congress, Thailand (2012). ## 4.	Plinninger R. J., Spaun G., Thuro K., &quot;Predicting tool wear in drill and blast&quot;, Tunnel and Tunnelling International (April 2002) 38-41. ## 5.	Thuro K., Plinninger R. J., &quot;Hard rock tunnel boring, cutting, drilling and blasting, ISRM-Technology road maps for rock maps&quot;, south African institute of mining and metallurgy (2003). ## 6.	Plinninger R. J., Spaun G., Thuro K., &quot;Prediction and classification of tool wear in drilling and blasting tunneling&quot;, Engineering Geology for Developing Countries, Proceedings of 9th congress of the International Association for Engineering Geology and the Environment, Durban, South Africa (2002) 2226-2236. ## 7.	Frenzel Ch., Käsling H., Thuro K., &quot;Factors Influencing Disc Cutter Wear&quot;, Geomechanics and Tunneling 1(1) (2008) 55-60. ## 8.	Thuro K., Singer J., Kasling H., Bauer M., &quot;Determining abrasiveness with the LCPC Test&quot;, Proceedings of the 1st Canada-U.S. Rock Mechanics Symposium, Vancouver B.C (2007). ## 9.	West G., &quot;Rock abrasiveness testing for tunneling&quot;, International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Science, Vol. 26 (2) (1989) 151-160. ## 10.	همزبان م.ت.، معماریان ح.، رستمی ج.، &quot;مقایسۀ روش‌های مختلف تعیین سایندگی سنگ‌ها&quot;، نشریهۀ مهندسی معدن، 8 (19)، (1392) 87-106. ## 11. Nilsen B., Dahl F., Holzhauser J., Raleigh P., &quot;New test methodology for estimating the abrasiveness of soils for TBM tunneling&quot;, RETC Proceedings (2007) 104-116. ## 12. Cerchar, &quot;Cerchar tests for the measurement of hardness and abrasivity of rocks&quot;, Centre Study Research, French Coal Industry, Document 73-59 (1973) 1-10. ## 13. Thuro K., Singer J., Käsling H., Bauer M., &quot;Soil abrasiveness assessment using the LCPC testing device&quot;, Felsbau 24 (2006) 37-45## 14. Mostafaei M., Rezaei Far A.H., Rastegarnia A., &quot;Assessment of the impact of case parameters affecting abrasion and brittleness factors in alluviums of Tabriz line 2 subway, Iran&quot;, Bull Eng Geol Environ, 78 (2019) 3851-3861. ## 15.Drucker P., &quot;Validity of the LCPC abrasivity coefficient through the example of a recent Danube gravel&quot;, Geomechanics and Tunnelling, Vol. 4(6) (2011) 41-50. ## 16. هاشمنژاد آ.، غفوری م.، لشکری‌پور غ.، طریق ازلی ص.، &quot;بررسی پارامترهای زمین‌شناسی مؤثر بر میزان سایندگی کانی‌ها به‌کمک دستگاه LCPC&quot; نشریۀ زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، 8 (۲) (1393) ۲۲۲۳-۲۲۴۳.## 17. میرمحرابی ح.، غفوری م.، لشکری‌پور غ.، &quot;ارزیابی تأثیر پارامترهای عملکردی بر سایش ابزارآلات حفاری مکانیزه با استفاده از نمونه‌های سیلیسی&quot;، نشریۀ زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، ۹ (۳)، (1394) ۳۰۳۳-۳۰۵۰.## 18. Gharahbagh E. A., Rostami J., Talebi, K, &quot;Experimental study of the effect of conditioning on abrasive wear and torque requirement of full face tunneling machines&quot;, Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology, 41 (2014) 127-136. ## 19. برزگری ق.، &quot;ارزیابی سایندگی خاک‌ها در حفاری مکانیزه تونل به‌روش تعادل فشار زمین (مطالعۀ موردی: خط یک متروی تبریز)&quot;، رسالۀ دکتری، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس (1391). ## 20. اصغری ا.، حیدری ب.، &quot;بررسی سایندگی خاک‌های مسیر تونل خط 2 مترو تبریز&quot;، ششمین همایش زمین‌شناسی مهندسی و محیط زیست ایران، تهران، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس (1388). ## 21. Thuro K., Kasling H., &quot;Classification of the abrasiveness of soil and rock&quot;, Geomechanics and Tunnelling, Vol. 2 (2) (2009) 179-188. ## 22. Plinninger R. J., Restner U., &quot;Abrasiveness Testing, Quo vadis- A Commented Overview of Abrasiveness Testing Methods&quot;, Geomechanik und tunnelbau. Vol. 1(1) (2008) 61-70. ## 23. Käsling H., Thuro K., &quot;Determining abrasivity of rock and soil in the laboratory Engineering Geology&quot;, Technische Universität München, (2010). ## 24. پژوهش عمران راهوار، &quot;گزارش نهایی مطالعات ژئوتکنیک مرحلۀ اول پروژه خط 2 قطار شهری تبریز&quot; (1387). ## 25. صاحب خواجه م.، برزگری ق.، &quot; بررسی خصوصیات زمین‌شناسی مهندسی و ژئوتکنیکی مسیر خط 2 متروی تبریز&quot;، دومین کنفرانس ملی مهندسی ژئوتکنیک ایران، کرمانشاه (1393). ## 26. Krumbein W. C., Sloss L. L., &quot;Stratigraphy and Sedimentation&quot;, W. H.Freeman and Co., San Francisco (1963) 660. ## ##1.	1.Nilsen B., Dahl F., Holzhäuser J., Raleigh P., &quot;Abrasivity testing for rock and soils&quot;, Tunnels &amp; Tunneling International (April 2006) 47-49.## 2.	آیتی ف.، مهدوری س.، &quot;تخمین تراست مورد نیاز حفاری در تونل انتقال آب بهشت آباد&quot;، نشریۀ زمین‌شناسی ‌مهندسی، ۷ (۱) (1392) 1707-۱۷۲۴.## 3.	Tarigh azali S., Moammeri H., &quot;EPB-TBM tunneling in abrasive ground, Esfahan Metro Line 1&quot;, WTC ITA-AITES 2012 World Tunnel Congress, Thailand (2012). ## 4.	Plinninger R. J., Spaun G., Thuro K., &quot;Predicting tool wear in drill and blast&quot;, Tunnel and Tunnelling International (April 2002) 38-41. ## 5.	Thuro K., Plinninger R. J., &quot;Hard rock tunnel boring, cutting, drilling and blasting, ISRM-Technology road maps for rock maps&quot;, south African institute of mining and metallurgy (2003). ## 6.	Plinninger R. J., Spaun G., Thuro K., &quot;Prediction and classification of tool wear in drilling and blasting tunneling&quot;, Engineering Geology for Developing Countries, Proceedings of 9th congress of the International Association for Engineering Geology and the Environment, Durban, South Africa (2002) 2226-2236. ## 7.	Frenzel Ch., Käsling H., Thuro K., &quot;Factors Influencing Disc Cutter Wear&quot;, Geomechanics and Tunneling 1(1) (2008) 55-60. ## 8.	Thuro K., Singer J., Kasling H., Bauer M., &quot;Determining abrasiveness with the LCPC Test&quot;, Proceedings of the 1st Canada-U.S. Rock Mechanics Symposium, Vancouver B.C (2007). ## 9.	West G., &quot;Rock abrasiveness testing for tunneling&quot;, International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Science, Vol. 26 (2) (1989) 151-160. ## 10.	همزبان م.ت.، معماریان ح.، رستمی ج.، &quot;مقایسۀ روش‌های مختلف تعیین سایندگی سنگ‌ها&quot;، نشریهۀ مهندسی معدن، 8 (19)، (1392) 87-106. ## 11. Nilsen B., Dahl F., Holzhauser J., Raleigh P., &quot;New test methodology for estimating the abrasiveness of soils for TBM tunneling&quot;, RETC Proceedings (2007) 104-116. ## 12. Cerchar, &quot;Cerchar tests for the measurement of hardness and abrasivity of rocks&quot;, Centre Study Research, French Coal Industry, Document 73-59 (1973) 1-10. ## 13. Thuro K., Singer J., Käsling H., Bauer M., &quot;Soil abrasiveness assessment using the LCPC testing device&quot;, Felsbau 24 (2006) 37-45## 14. Mostafaei M., Rezaei Far A.H., Rastegarnia A., &quot;Assessment of the impact of case parameters affecting abrasion and brittleness factors in alluviums of Tabriz line 2 subway, Iran&quot;, Bull Eng Geol Environ, 78 (2019) 3851-3861. ## 15.Drucker P., &quot;Validity of the LCPC abrasivity coefficient through the example of a recent Danube gravel&quot;, Geomechanics and Tunnelling, Vol. 4(6) (2011) 41-50. ## 16. هاشمنژاد آ.، غفوری م.، لشکری‌پور غ.، طریق ازلی ص.، &quot;بررسی پارامترهای زمین‌شناسی مؤثر بر میزان سایندگی کانی‌ها به‌کمک دستگاه LCPC&quot; نشریۀ زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، 8 (۲) (1393) ۲۲۲۳-۲۲۴۳.## 17. میرمحرابی ح.، غفوری م.، لشکری‌پور غ.، &quot;ارزیابی تأثیر پارامترهای عملکردی بر سایش ابزارآلات حفاری مکانیزه با استفاده از نمونه‌های سیلیسی&quot;، نشریۀ زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، ۹ (۳)، (1394) ۳۰۳۳-۳۰۵۰.## 18. Gharahbagh E. A., Rostami J., Talebi, K, &quot;Experimental study of the effect of conditioning on abrasive wear and torque requirement of full face tunneling machines&quot;, Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology, 41 (2014) 127-136. ## 19. برزگری ق.، &quot;ارزیابی سایندگی خاک‌ها در حفاری مکانیزه تونل به‌روش تعادل فشار زمین (مطالعۀ موردی: خط یک متروی تبریز)&quot;، رسالۀ دکتری، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس (1391). ## 20. اصغری ا.، حیدری ب.، &quot;بررسی سایندگی خاک‌های مسیر تونل خط 2 مترو تبریز&quot;، ششمین همایش زمین‌شناسی مهندسی و محیط زیست ایران، تهران، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس (1388). ## 21. Thuro K., Kasling H., &quot;Classification of the abrasiveness of soil and rock&quot;, Geomechanics and Tunnelling, Vol. 2 (2) (2009) 179-188. ## 22. Plinninger R. J., Restner U., &quot;Abrasiveness Testing, Quo vadis- A Commented Overview of Abrasiveness Testing Methods&quot;, Geomechanik und tunnelbau. Vol. 1(1) (2008) 61-70. ## 23. Käsling H., Thuro K., &quot;Determining abrasivity of rock and soil in the laboratory Engineering Geology&quot;, Technische Universität München, (2010). ## 24. پژوهش عمران راهوار، &quot;گزارش نهایی مطالعات ژئوتکنیک مرحلۀ اول پروژه خط 2 قطار شهری تبریز&quot; (1387). ## 25. صاحب خواجه م.، برزگری ق.، &quot; بررسی خصوصیات زمین‌شناسی مهندسی و ژئوتکنیکی مسیر خط 2 متروی تبریز&quot;، دومین کنفرانس ملی مهندسی ژئوتکنیک ایران، کرمانشاه (1393). ## 26. Krumbein W. C., Sloss L. L., &quot;Stratigraphy and Sedimentation&quot;, W. H.Freeman and Co., San Francisco (1963) 660. ##  ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>ارزیابی عددی تفاضل محدود پدیدۀ روان‌گرایی به روش تنش مؤثر و تخمین عددی روانگرایی پروژه مسجد جامع بندرعباس  (مطالعۀ موردی)</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Finite Difference Numerical Evaluation of Liquefaction with Effective Stress Method and Numerical Estimation of Liquefaction in Bandar Abbas’s Mosque Project (Case Study)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>تخمین روان&#8204;گرایی یکی از اهداف مهم در مهندسی ژئوتکنیک است. بدین&#8204;منظور روش&#8204;های آزمایشگاهی و عددی مختلفی ارائه شده&#8204;اند. یکی از گام&#8204;های مهم در پیش&#8204;بینی روان&#8204;گرایی، پیش&#8204;بینی اضافه فشار آب حفره&#8204;ای ایجاد شده است. وقتی که بارگذاری لرزه&#8204;ای به خاک ماسه&#8204;ای اشباع اعمال می&#8204;شود، فشار آب حفره&#8204;ای تا زمانی که به فشار محصورکنندۀ اولیه برسد، افزایش می&#8204;یابد و موجب وقوع روان&#8204;گرایی می&#8204;شود. به&#8204;طورکلی دو روش مهم برای تحلیل&#8204;های دینامیک خاک وجود دارد: روش&#8204;های غیروابستۀ تنش کل و روش وابسته تنش مؤثر. هدف مهم این پژوهش ارزیابی ظرفیت مدل موجود در نرم&#8204;افزار تفاضل محدود فلک بر پایۀ روش&#8204;های تجزیه و تحلیل تنش مؤثر برای پیش&#8204;بینی اضافه فشار آب حفره&#8204;ای در طول بارگذاری لرزه&#8204;ای است. برای کالیبره کردن مدل عددی، آزمایش سانتریفوژ شمارۀ یک پروژه ولاکس که روی ماسۀ نوادا با تراکم 40% انجام شده، مدل&#8204;سازی &#8204;شده است. پس از صحت سنجی مدل عددی، خاک محل احداث پروژه مسجد جامع شهر بندرعباس، برای بررسی روان&#8204;گرایی با استفاده از روش&#8204; عددی مدل&#8204;سازی شده است. برای مدل&#8204;سازی، از نتایج آزمایش&#8204;های عمومی مکانیک خاک انجام شده روی نمونه&#8204;های خاک محل و آزمایش نفوذ استاندارد انجام شده در سایت، برای کالیبره کردن پارامترها و انتخاب ثابت&#8204;های مدل بهره گرفته شده است. نتایج حاصل از مدل عددی با نتایج حاصل از آزمایشگاه تقریباً مطابقت دارد. بنابراین با انتخاب دقیق پارامترهای مدل عددی می&#8204;توان به&#8204;طورکلی با استفاده از نتایج مدل&#8204;سازی دید کلی از تشکیل فشار آب حفره&#8204;ای و تخمین عمق روان&#8204;گرایی داشت.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Introduction
Estimation of Liquefaction is one of the main objectives in geotechnical engineering. For this purpose, several numerical and experimental methods have been proposed. An important stage to predict the liquefaction is the prediction of excess pore water pressure at a given point. In general, there are two important methods for soil dynamics analyses, fully coupled effective stress and uncoupled total stress analysis. The main purpose of this study is to evaluate the model capacity of the finite difference software, FLAC, based on effective stress analysis methods to predict the excess pore water pressure during seismic loading. A level ground centrifuge test conducted during the VELACS project on the Nevada sand with a density of 40%, was utilized to calibrate the numerical model. After the validation of the numerical model, a model was conducted to predict excess pore pressure and consequently the liquefaction for the site of Bandar Abbas Mosque. 
Theoretical bases 
A fully coupled u&#8211;P formulation, where pore pressures and displacements are computed simultaneously and interactively at each time step, is used in FLAC software. This feature is used to simulate the excess pore water pressure time histories during cyclic loading.
The finite difference based software, FLAC, used the Finn model that incorporates two equations correlating the volumetric strain induced by the cyclic shear strain and excess pore water pressure produced during cyclic loading. As mentioned above, the pore water pressure generation can be computed from two sets of equations: Martin et al. (1975) and the Byrne (1991) formulations in which the volumetric strain that was produced in any cycle of loading is depended on the shear strain that was formed during that cycle as well as the previously accumulated volumetric strain.
Modeling and Results
The VELACS model # 1 centrifuge test representing a level ground site constituted of the Nevada sand at 40% relative density has been numerically simulated in the current study to validate the numerical model. The centrifuge model contains a laminar box with slipping &#8220;rings&#8221; that allows differential horizontal displacements. This was simulated in the FLAC model by free-field boundary conditions which prevent reflection of the waves in the side walls. Figure 1 shows comparison of EPWP time histories ratio of numerical modeling and centrifuge test. Static analysis was carried out before dynamic analysis in order to find initial stress and strain state. At the next stage, the dynamic loads were applied at the base of the model and dynamic analysis was performed.

	
		
			&#160;
			&#160;
		
		
			&#160;
			&#160;
		
		
			&#160;
		
	

The Bandar Abbas mosque project is located approximately 500 meters from the coast. In the project, due to the groundwater level and the existence of loose layers of silt, investigating the potential of liquefaction is necessary.
For numerical modeling the results of the general soil mechanics test on soil samples and standard penetration test performed on the site were used to calibrate the parameters and select the model constants.
Conclusion
The results of numerical modeling have been matched to experimental results of the centrifuge test using both Martin and Byrne formulations, except for the case of 5 m the numerical model has predicted lower excess pore water pressure values than the experimental values. This may be originated from the fundamental assumption of the Martin et al. (1975) EPWP theory, in which excess pore water pressure is directly related to the relevant volume changes. On the other hand, the Martin et al. (1975) model was adopted for one-dimensional measures of shear strain, while, in a 2D analysis under both horizontal and vertical shakings, there are three strain rate measures. FLAC uses some assumptions to solve this problem and it can affect the results.
The results of the numerical model showed liquefaction to a depth of about 5 meters that is almost compatible with the results from the lab, which has declared that the depth 2 to 5 m is liquefiable.
With careful selection of numerical model parameters one can generally use the simulation results to have a general sense on the pore water pressure generation and liquefaction prediction.
./files/site1/files/134/5.pdf</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>645</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>676</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>عادل</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>عساکره</Family>
				<NameE>Adel</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Asakereh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه هرمزگان، دانشکده فنی مهندسی، گروه عمران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه هرمزگان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>asakereh@hormozgan.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهدیه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شعبانی</Family>
				<NameE>Mahdieh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>shabani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه هرمزگان، دانشکده فنی مهندسی، گروه عمران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه هرمزگان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>shabani.mhdh@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText> Soil liquefaction</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>excess pore water pressure</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>centrifuge test</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>numerical approach</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>constitutive model.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText> روان‌گرایی خاک</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اضافه فشار آب حفره‌ای</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>آزمایش سانتریفوژ</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>روش عددی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدل رفتاری خاک.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1. A. Rahmani A., Ghasemi Fare O., Pak A. &quot;Investigation of the influence of permeability coefficient on the numerical modeling of the liquefaction phenomenon&quot;, Department of Civil Engineering, Sharif University of Technology, Tehran, Iran, Scientia Iranica A 19 (2) (2012) 179-187. ## 2. Seed H. B., Idriss I. M., &quot;Ground motions and soil liquefaction&quot;, Earth quake Engineering Research Institute, university of California, Berkeley (1983). ## 3. No. 525, &quot;Guideline for Assessment of Soil Liquefaction Potential, Consequences and Mitigation Methods&quot;, Office of Deputy for Strategic Supervision Department of Technical Affairs, Iran, in Persian (2012). ## 4. Martin G. R., &quot;Fundamentals of liquefaction under cyclic loading&quot; J. Geotech. Div, ASCE, 101(GT5) (1975) 423-438. ## 5. Taboada V., &quot;Centrifuge modeling of earth quake-induced lateral spreading in sand using laminar box&quot;, Thesis submitted for the degree of Doctro of Philosophy, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, NewYork, Aug. (1995). ## 6. Arulmoli K., Muraleetharan K. K., Hossain M. M., Fruth L. S., &quot;VELACS -Laboratory testing program- soil data report&quot;, The earth technology corporation, Project No. (1992) 90-0562. ## 7. Nabili S., Jafarian Y., Baziar M. H., &quot;Evaluation of the Martin et al. (1975) pore pressure build up model using laboratory test data&quot;, 6th International Conference on Case Histories in Geotechnical Engineering, Arlington, paper No. 3.41 (2008). ## 8. Cook H. G., &quot;Ground improvement for liquefaction mitigation at an existing highway bridge&quot;, Thesis submitted for the degree of Doctor of Philosophy, Virginia polytechnic institute and state university, (2000). ## 9. Shahir H., Mohammadi-Haji B., Ghassemi A., &quot;Employing a variable permeability model in numerical simulation of saturated sand behavior under earthquake loading&quot;, Computers and Geotechnics 55 (2014) 211-223,. ## 10. Byrne P. M., &quot;A cyclic shear-volume couplinh and pore pressure model for sand proceeding&quot;, second conference on recent advances in geotechnical earthquake engineering and soil dynamics, March (1991) 11-15. ##  11. Finn W. D. L., &quot;An effective stress model for liquefaction&quot;, J. Geotech Div, ASCE, Vol. 6 (1977). ## 12. Zamiran S. Modeling and analysis of soil and rock structures in FLAC with practical examples&quot;, Noavar, Tehran, Iran, In Persian (2013). ## 13. Seed H. B. and Idriss I. M., &quot;Soil moduli and damping factor for dynamic response analyses&quot;, Report EERC 70-10, Earth quake engineering research center, university of California, Berkeley, CA, (1970). ## 14. Quak/w example file, &quot;Level ground response analysis&quot;, Geo-Slope International Ltd., Calgary, Alberta, Canada, www.geo-slope.com. ## 15. Gazatas G.m., &quot;Foundation vibrations&quot;, Foundation Engineering Handbook, H-Y.Fang, second edition, chapter 15 (1990). ## 16. Bowles J. E., &quot;Foundation analysis and design&quot;, fifth edition, Peoria, Illinois (2006). ## 17. Dobry R., Oweis I., Urzua A., &quot;simplified procedures for estimating the fundamental period of soil profile&quot;, Bulletin of the seismological society of America, Vol. 66 (1976) 1293-1321. ## 18. Kuhlmeyer R. L., Lysmer J., &quot;Finite element method accuracy for wave propagation problems&quot;, Jornal of the soil mechanics and foundation division, ASCE, Vol. 99, No. SM5 (1973) 421-427. ## 19. &quot;Soil investigation report of BandarAbbas’s central Mosque&quot;, Kavosh Azama Persia consultant engineering (2012). ##  ##1. A. Rahmani A., Ghasemi Fare O., Pak A. &quot;Investigation of the influence of permeability coefficient on the numerical modeling of the liquefaction phenomenon&quot;, Department of Civil Engineering, Sharif University of Technology, Tehran, Iran, Scientia Iranica A 19 (2) (2012) 179-187. ## 2. Seed H. B., Idriss I. M., &quot;Ground motions and soil liquefaction&quot;, Earth quake Engineering Research Institute, university of California, Berkeley (1983). ## 3. No. 525, &quot;Guideline for Assessment of Soil Liquefaction Potential, Consequences and Mitigation Methods&quot;, Office of Deputy for Strategic Supervision Department of Technical Affairs, Iran, in Persian (2012). ## 4. Martin G. R., &quot;Fundamentals of liquefaction under cyclic loading&quot; J. Geotech. Div, ASCE, 101(GT5) (1975) 423-438. ## 5. Taboada V., &quot;Centrifuge modeling of earth quake-induced lateral spreading in sand using laminar box&quot;, Thesis submitted for the degree of Doctro of Philosophy, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, NewYork, Aug. (1995). ## 6. Arulmoli K., Muraleetharan K. K., Hossain M. M., Fruth L. S., &quot;VELACS -Laboratory testing program- soil data report&quot;, The earth technology corporation, Project No. (1992) 90-0562. ## 7. Nabili S., Jafarian Y., Baziar M. H., &quot;Evaluation of the Martin et al. (1975) pore pressure build up model using laboratory test data&quot;, 6th International Conference on Case Histories in Geotechnical Engineering, Arlington, paper No. 3.41 (2008). ## 8. Cook H. G., &quot;Ground improvement for liquefaction mitigation at an existing highway bridge&quot;, Thesis submitted for the degree of Doctor of Philosophy, Virginia polytechnic institute and state university, (2000). ## 9. Shahir H., Mohammadi-Haji B., Ghassemi A., &quot;Employing a variable permeability model in numerical simulation of saturated sand behavior under earthquake loading&quot;, Computers and Geotechnics 55 (2014) 211-223,. ## 10. Byrne P. M., &quot;A cyclic shear-volume couplinh and pore pressure model for sand proceeding&quot;, second conference on recent advances in geotechnical earthquake engineering and soil dynamics, March (1991) 11-15. ##  11. Finn W. D. L., &quot;An effective stress model for liquefaction&quot;, J. Geotech Div, ASCE, Vol. 6 (1977). ## 12. Zamiran S. Modeling and analysis of soil and rock structures in FLAC with practical examples&quot;, Noavar, Tehran, Iran, In Persian (2013). ## 13. Seed H. B. and Idriss I. M., &quot;Soil moduli and damping factor for dynamic response analyses&quot;, Report EERC 70-10, Earth quake engineering research center, university of California, Berkeley, CA, (1970). ## 14. Quak/w example file, &quot;Level ground response analysis&quot;, Geo-Slope International Ltd., Calgary, Alberta, Canada, www.geo-slope.com. ## 15. Gazatas G.m., &quot;Foundation vibrations&quot;, Foundation Engineering Handbook, H-Y.Fang, second edition, chapter 15 (1990). ## 16. Bowles J. E., &quot;Foundation analysis and design&quot;, fifth edition, Peoria, Illinois (2006). ## 17. Dobry R., Oweis I., Urzua A., &quot;simplified procedures for estimating the fundamental period of soil profile&quot;, Bulletin of the seismological society of America, Vol. 66 (1976) 1293-1321. ## 18. Kuhlmeyer R. L., Lysmer J., &quot;Finite element method accuracy for wave propagation problems&quot;, Jornal of the soil mechanics and foundation division, ASCE, Vol. 99, No. SM5 (1973) 421-427. ## 19. &quot;Soil investigation report of BandarAbbas’s central Mosque&quot;, Kavosh Azama Persia consultant engineering (2012). ##   ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تعیین اندیس کار باند با استفاده از پارامترهای فیزیکی-مکانیکی سنگ به‌روش سطح پاسخ</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Application of Response Surface Method to the Estimation of Bond Work Index</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>بخش اعظم انرژی مصرفی در کارخانه&#8204;های فرآوری مواد معدنی و تولید سیمان، اختصاص به انرژی مصرفی آسیای مواد معدنی خام و کلینیکر دارد. به&#173;طور عمده کاهش انرژی مصرفی خردایش و آسیا در بهینه&#173;سازی آسیا مدنظر قرار می&#173;گیرد. به&#173;دلیل وجود بانک داده&#173;های متعدد در یک قرن گذشته، آسیای آزمایشگاهی باند به&#173;عنوان مبنای بزرگ&#173;مقیاس&#173;سازی و بهینه&#173;سازی آسیاهای صنعتی به&#173;کار گرفته شده است. با توجه به پیچیده و وقت&#173;گیر بودن آزمون باند، اندیس کار مربوط به آن و اهمیت موضوع، در این مقالۀ به توسعۀ مدلی کارا به&#173;منظور ارائۀ تخمینی از انرژی مصرفی آسیای باند در هفت نمونه سنگ مختلف و بر مبنای پارامترهای فیزیکی-مکانیکی سنگ توجه شده است. از آن&#8204;جاکه اندازه&#173;گیری پارامترهای فیزیکی-مکانیکی در فازهای ابتدایی پروژه&#173;های معدنی مرسوم و از سادگی لازم برخوردار است، ارائۀ مدل مناسب تخمین انرژی خردایش مبتنی بر این پارامترها حائز اهمیت است؛ از این&#8204;رو با استناد به داده&#173;های اندازه&#173;گیری شده مربوط به آزمایش&#173;های مقاومت فشاری تک&#8204;محوره سنگ، مدول الاستیسیته، شاخص سختی و سایش سنگ و با استفاده از روش سطح پاسخ ارتباط بین این پارامترها در قالب متغیر مستقل و اندیس کار باند در قالب متغیر وابسته بررسی شده و در نهایت مدل مناسب با حداکثر دقت (ضریب همبستگی برابر با یک) بدست آمده است.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Introduction
The main objective of this contribution is to focus on the portion of the comminution process which deals with the prediction of the energy consumption due to the comminution portion of the milling processes.
The comminution energy in mineral processing and cement industry is usually determined by empirical Bond Work Index (BWI), regardless of the mechanical properties of a rock. The BWI is a measure of ore resistance against grinding and is determined by using the Bond grindability test. Determining the BWI value is quite complicated and time consuming. Its value constitutes ore characteristic and is used for industrial commination plants designing and optimization. The BWI is deﬁned as the calculated speciﬁc energy (kW h/t) applied in reducing material of inﬁnite particle size to 80% passing 100 &#181;m. The higher the value for BWI, the more energy is required to grind a material in a ball mill. The energy consumed in the process of comminution depends on both the mechanism of comminution and the mechanical properties of the materials being ground. It is interesting to study the effect of the essential ones of these properties on the energy efficiency of grinding process.
Material and methods
Several attempts have been made to obtain and optimize the comminution energy. An efficient Response Surface Method, (RSM)-based method for the BWI approximate value determination, which is based on physico-mechanical tests, is presented in this paper.
BWI and some physico-mechanical tests on 8 typical rock samples and its correlation are studied; it would be beneficial to examine this relation based on physical concept. The database including Uniaxial Compressive Strength (UCS), Abrasion (AT), Hardness (HT) and Modulus of Elasticity (ME) are assembled by collecting data from Haffez experiments.
Results and discussion
The determination of the BWI from RSM- based multivariate model is almost matched with measured Bond&#8217;s work index. As a result of analysis the best equation obtained from RSM-based model is formulized in Equation 1:
&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; (1)
Standard statistical evaluation criteria are used to evaluate the performances of predictive models.
Conclusion
The performance of the estimator models can be controlled by R2, VAF, RMSE, MAPE, VARE and MEDAE. The RSM- based model with higher VAF as well as lower RMSE, MAPE, VARE, MEDAE shows better performance in comparison to the Haffez single-variable models. AT and ME have the greatest effect on the value of BWI; and also HT has the least impact../files/site1/files/134/6.pdf</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>677</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>700</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>عارف</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>علی پور</Family>
				<NameE>Aref</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Alipour</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی ارومیه، دانشکدۀ معدن</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه صنعتی ارومیه</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>aref.alipour@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مجتبی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>مختاریان اصل</Family>
				<NameE>Mojtaba</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Mokhtarian</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی ارومیه، دانشکدۀ معدن</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه صنعتی ارومیه</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>m.mokhtarian@uut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText> Bond work index</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>milling energy</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>RSM</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>انرژی مصرفی آسیا</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اندیس کار باند</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>روش سطح پاسخ.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1.	Bond F. C., &quot;Comminution exposure constant by the third theory&quot;, Transactions of AIME, Mining Engng, Vol. 8, No. 9 (1957) 1372-1376.## 2.	Deniz V., Ozdag H., &quot;A new approach to Bond grindability and work index: dynamic elastic parameters&quot;, Minerals engineering, Vol. 16, No. 3, (2003) 211-217. ## 3.	Free K., McCarter M., King R., &quot;Evaluation of a new method for work index estimation using single particle impact tests&quot;, Minerals and Metallurgical Processing, Vol. 22, No. 2 (2005) 96-100. ## 4.	Swain R., Rao R. B., &quot;Alternative approaches for determination of Bond work index on soft and friable partially laterised Khondalite rocks of Bauxite mine waste materials&quot;, Journal of Minerals and Materials Characterization and Engineering, Vol. 8, No. 09 (2009) 729. ## 5.	Gent M., Menendez M., Toraño J., Torno S., &quot;A correlation between Vickers Hardness indentation values and the Bond Work Index for the grinding of brittle minerals&quot;, Powder Technology, Vol. 224 (2012) 217-222. ## 6. Magdalinović N., &quot;Abbreviated test for quick determination of Bond’s Work index&quot;, Journal of Mining and Metallurgy A: Mining, Vol. 39, No. 1-4 (2003) 1-10. ## 7.	Gharehgheshlagh H. H., &quot;Kinetic grinding test approach to estimate the ball mill work index&quot;, Physicochemical Problems of Mineral Processing, Vol. 52 (2016). ## 8.	Williams O., Eastwick C., Kingman S., Giddings D., Lormor S., Lester E., &quot;Investigation into the applicability of Bond Work Index (BWI) and Hardgrove Grindability Index (HGI) tests for several biomasses compared to Colombian La Loma coal&quot;, Fuel, Vol. 158 (2015) 379-387. ## 9.	Todorovic D., Trumic M., Andric L., Milosevic V., &quot;A quick method for Bond work index approximate value determination&quot;, Physicochemical Problems of Mineral Processing, Vol. 53 (2017). ## 10. حسنی صدرآبادی س.، پرنده ل.، دهقانی ع.، &quot;ارزیابی روش های ساده و غیر مستقیم تخمین اندیس کار باند (مطالعۀ موردی: سنگ آهن چغارت)، &quot;نشریۀ علمی-پژوهشی مهندسی معدن، دورۀ 7، شمارۀ 14(1391) 63-68. ## 11. Ahmadi R., Shahsavari S., &quot;Procedure for determination of ball Bond work index in the commercial operations&quot;, Minerals engineering, Vol. 22, No. 1(2009) 104-106. ## 12. Haffez G. S. A., &quot;Correlation between Bond work index and mechanical properties of some Saudi ores,&quot; J. Eng. Sci., Vol. 40, No. 1, (2012) 271-280. ## 13. Hudson J. A., Harrison J. P., &quot;Engineering rock mechanics: an introduction to the principles&quot;, Elsevier (2000). ## 14. Atkinson R., et al., &quot;Suggested methods for determining hardness and abrasiveness of rocks&quot;, International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, Vol. 15, No. 3 (1978) 89-97. ## 15. Mwanga A., Rosenkranz J., Lamberg P., &quot;Testing of Ore Comminution Behavior in the Geometallurgical Context-A Review&quot;, Minerals, Vol. 5, No. 2 (2015) 276-297. ## 16. West G., &quot;A review of rock abrasiveness testing for tunnelling&quot;, in ISRM International Symposium: International Society for Rock Mechanics (1981). ## 17. Bhushan B., &quot;Modern tribology handbook&quot;, two volume set. CRC press (2000). ## 18. همزبان م. ت.، معماریان ح.، رستمی ج.، &quot;مقایسه روش‌های مختلف تعیین سایندگی سنگ‌ها، &quot; نشریۀ علمی-پژوهشی مهندسی معدن، دورۀ 8، شمارۀ 19 (1392) 87-106. ## 19. Farooq Anjum M., Tasadduq I., Al-Sultan K., &quot;Response surface methodology: A neural network approach&quot;, European Journal of Operational Research, Vol. 101, No. 1 (1997) 65-73. ## 20. Kwak J.-S., &quot;Application of Taguchi and response surface methodologies for geometric error in surface grinding process&quot;, International Journal of Machine Tools and Manufacture, Vol. 45, No. 3, (2005) 327-334. ## 21. Baş D., Boyacı İ. H., &quot;Modeling and optimization I: Usability of response surface methodology&quot;, Journal of Food Engineering, Vol. 78, No. 3 (2007) 836-845. ##  ##1.	Bond F. C., &quot;Comminution exposure constant by the third theory&quot;, Transactions of AIME, Mining Engng, Vol. 8, No. 9 (1957) 1372-1376.## 2.	Deniz V., Ozdag H., &quot;A new approach to Bond grindability and work index: dynamic elastic parameters&quot;, Minerals engineering, Vol. 16, No. 3, (2003) 211-217. ## 3.	Free K., McCarter M., King R., &quot;Evaluation of a new method for work index estimation using single particle impact tests&quot;, Minerals and Metallurgical Processing, Vol. 22, No. 2 (2005) 96-100. ## 4.	Swain R., Rao R. B., &quot;Alternative approaches for determination of Bond work index on soft and friable partially laterised Khondalite rocks of Bauxite mine waste materials&quot;, Journal of Minerals and Materials Characterization and Engineering, Vol. 8, No. 09 (2009) 729. ## 5.	Gent M., Menendez M., Toraño J., Torno S., &quot;A correlation between Vickers Hardness indentation values and the Bond Work Index for the grinding of brittle minerals&quot;, Powder Technology, Vol. 224 (2012) 217-222. ## 6. Magdalinović N., &quot;Abbreviated test for quick determination of Bond’s Work index&quot;, Journal of Mining and Metallurgy A: Mining, Vol. 39, No. 1-4 (2003) 1-10. ## 7.	Gharehgheshlagh H. H., &quot;Kinetic grinding test approach to estimate the ball mill work index&quot;, Physicochemical Problems of Mineral Processing, Vol. 52 (2016). ## 8.	Williams O., Eastwick C., Kingman S., Giddings D., Lormor S., Lester E., &quot;Investigation into the applicability of Bond Work Index (BWI) and Hardgrove Grindability Index (HGI) tests for several biomasses compared to Colombian La Loma coal&quot;, Fuel, Vol. 158 (2015) 379-387. ## 9.	Todorovic D., Trumic M., Andric L., Milosevic V., &quot;A quick method for Bond work index approximate value determination&quot;, Physicochemical Problems of Mineral Processing, Vol. 53 (2017). ## 10. حسنی صدرآبادی س.، پرنده ل.، دهقانی ع.، &quot;ارزیابی روش های ساده و غیر مستقیم تخمین اندیس کار باند (مطالعۀ موردی: سنگ آهن چغارت)، &quot;نشریۀ علمی-پژوهشی مهندسی معدن، دورۀ 7، شمارۀ 14(1391) 63-68. ## 11. Ahmadi R., Shahsavari S., &quot;Procedure for determination of ball Bond work index in the commercial operations&quot;, Minerals engineering, Vol. 22, No. 1(2009) 104-106. ## 12. Haffez G. S. A., &quot;Correlation between Bond work index and mechanical properties of some Saudi ores,&quot; J. Eng. Sci., Vol. 40, No. 1, (2012) 271-280. ## 13. Hudson J. A., Harrison J. P., &quot;Engineering rock mechanics: an introduction to the principles&quot;, Elsevier (2000). ## 14. Atkinson R., et al., &quot;Suggested methods for determining hardness and abrasiveness of rocks&quot;, International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, Vol. 15, No. 3 (1978) 89-97. ## 15. Mwanga A., Rosenkranz J., Lamberg P., &quot;Testing of Ore Comminution Behavior in the Geometallurgical Context-A Review&quot;, Minerals, Vol. 5, No. 2 (2015) 276-297. ## 16. West G., &quot;A review of rock abrasiveness testing for tunnelling&quot;, in ISRM International Symposium: International Society for Rock Mechanics (1981). ## 17. Bhushan B., &quot;Modern tribology handbook&quot;, two volume set. CRC press (2000). ## 18. همزبان م. ت.، معماریان ح.، رستمی ج.، &quot;مقایسه روش‌های مختلف تعیین سایندگی سنگ‌ها، &quot; نشریۀ علمی-پژوهشی مهندسی معدن، دورۀ 8، شمارۀ 19 (1392) 87-106. ## 19. Farooq Anjum M., Tasadduq I., Al-Sultan K., &quot;Response surface methodology: A neural network approach&quot;, European Journal of Operational Research, Vol. 101, No. 1 (1997) 65-73. ## 20. Kwak J.-S., &quot;Application of Taguchi and response surface methodologies for geometric error in surface grinding process&quot;, International Journal of Machine Tools and Manufacture, Vol. 45, No. 3, (2005) 327-334. ## 21. Baş D., Boyacı İ. H., &quot;Modeling and optimization I: Usability of response surface methodology&quot;, Journal of Food Engineering, Vol. 78, No. 3 (2007) 836-845. ##   ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>مدل‌سازی ریاضی پالس‌های نیرومند سرعت زمین با رویکرد تجزیه طیفی و اثرات جهت‌داری</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Mathematical Modeling of Strong Ground Velocity Pulses Using Spectral Decomposition and Forward Directivity Effects</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>در این پژوهش، شناخت پارامترهای اساسی لرزه&#8204;شناسی مربوط به ساختارهای پالس&#8204;گونه موجود در تاریخچۀ زمانی رکوردهای نیرومند حوزۀ نزدیک، با هدف مدل&#8204;سازی ریاضی بررسی شده است. پارامترهای مشخصه این ساختارهای پالس شکل، عبارت از دامنه، دوره و بازۀ زمانی متناظر آن هستند. با استفاده از این عوامل و جای&#8204;گذاری آن&#8204;ها در روند برازش تحلیلی مربوط به یک فرمولاسیون فرم بسته، مدل&#8204;های ریاضی توصیف کننده پالس&#8204;های مشخص سرعت حاصل شده که می&#8204;توانند ویژگی&#173;های اصلی لرزه&#8204;شناسی مربوط به رکوردهای حوزۀ نزدیک را به&#8204;خوبی نمایش دهند. هدف از این مدل&#173;سازی، ایجاد گسترۀ وسیعی از نگاشت&#8204;های مصنوعی نیرومند و پرانرژی است که با توجه به معدود بودن رکوردهای حوزۀ نزدیک در بررسی عملکرد انواع سازه&#8204;ها کاربرد دارد. محتوای فرکانسی (تواتر) رکوردهای ثبت شده در زلزله&#8204;ها را می&#8204;توان به دو بخش باند فرکانس&#8204;های بالا و باند فرکانس&#8204;های پایین تفکیک کرد. نتایج پژوهش&#173;های لرزه&#8204;شناسی بیان&#173;گر آن است که نمود مشخص&#173;ترین ویژگی&#8204;های رکوردهای نیرومند حوزۀ نزدیک را باند فرکانسی پایین ایجاد می&#8204;کند. همین موضوع باعث شده است که در روند مدل&#8204;سازی فرم بسته نیز توجهات تحلیلی بیش&#8204;تر به باند فرکانسی پایین صورت گیرد. بر این اساس، مدل&#8204;های فرم بسته ریاضی حاصل از این روند نیز تطابق قابل قبولی با رکورد&#8204;های نیرومند حوزۀ نزدیک داشته و ویژگی&#8204;های طیفی اصلی را به&#8204;خوبی نمایش می&#8204;دهد.&#160; &#160;
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Introduction
The nature of near-field earthquake records is very complicated and uncertain. Due to this complexity, the prediction of the real structural responses has become very difficult. Based on the analysis of the physical characteristics of near-field records, it is possible to use the simplified mathematical models. Near-field ground motions which are often associated with a progressive directional phenomenon due to their particular type of the causative fault, have much more destructive effects on the structures than the other quake tremors. The related research results show that under the influence of a strong near-field ground motion which contains forward directivity effects, the structural responses would be entered to a great nonlinear domain. On the other hand, due to the limited number of available near-field records, it is needed to prepare artificial acclerograms which can simulate the characteristics of the strong ground motions. Thus, it is possible to achieve a vast data base corresponding to wide range of powerful ground motions using mathematical wavelets. As a result, it provides a general overview of these types of artificial quake tremors and prepares an extended knowledge on the performance of structures in confronting these destructive movements.
Material and methods
The results obtained from the seismological studies on strong near-field records indicate that the most of these tremors contain large amounts of kinetic energy corresponding to the content of low frequency band. Additionally, by ignoring the high-frequency band the coherent velocity pulses can be detected with acceptable accuracy. In order to separate the high and low frequency bands, the empirical mode decomposition (EMD) method is used based on programming in MATLAB software. Various methods have been proposed for simulation of near-field records which most of them is based on using harmonic functions and the spectral assessment of the low frequency band of earthquake records.
In this regards, one of the best closed form evaluation has been performed by Mavroeidis and Papageorgiou (2003) which is to be formulated by making parametric changes to the so-called Gabor wavelet and replacing a simpler function instead of the Gaussian curve with a more efficient algebraic statement. Ghodrati Amiri et al. (2012) proposed another efficient formulation matched either of the benefits of Mavroeidis&#8217;s and Gabor wavelets. Both of the aforementioned models are based on the preparing of an efficient multi-statement parametric configuration of harmonic wavelets as noted above. In this study, in addition to calibrate the desired closed-formulations on the velocity pulses of the selected strong records, the accuracy of the notified simulation has also been investigated from the spectral and energy point of views.

Results and discussion
The band of high frequencies corresponding to the spectral content of strong near-field records can be ignored appropriately. This is because the major amount of the related kinetic energy is usually transmitted in the form of a low frequency pulse along with a number of high frequency spikes. Generally, these features are displayed over a relatively short time domain. In this study, the analytical attention to this subject is concentrated on the simulation of coherent multiple pulses via EMD method. The purpose of such simulation is to create a wide range of powerful and high-energy artificial motions. Moreover, due to the limited availability of natural near-field earthquake records, the proposed pulses can be used to evaluate the structural seismic performance.
Conclusion
Generally, strong near-field records contain a few consecutive pulses with different periods and spectral configurations. The essential effects of these pulses must not be ignored in conducting of nonlinear dynamic time history analyses. Obviously, the effects of these type of earthquake records on the seismic response of mid-to-high rise structures (with a large periodic range) will be significant. Furthermore, the probable occurrence of the resonant mode, may cause destructive effects on the seismic response of structural skeletons. The proposed pulses in this study were formulated through the EMD method as well as performing an analytical calibration process related to both bands of high and low frequencies. The spectral evaluations of the fitted mathematical closed-form pulses were accomplished for the selected earthquake records. The obtained results indicate a good analytical convergence and correlation with the physical parameters of the natural ground motions.


./files/site1/files/134/7.pdf</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>701</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>726</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سعید</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>ولیان</Family>
				<NameE>Saeid</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Valian</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه خوارزمی، دانشکدۀ فنی مهندسی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه خوارزمی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>saeid_valian@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>افشین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>مشکوه الدینی</Family>
				<NameE>Afshin</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Meshkat-Dini</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه خوارزمی، دانشکدۀ فنی مهندسی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه خوارزمی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>meshkat@khu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>جعفر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>کیوانی قمصری</Family>
				<NameE>Jafar</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Keyvani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه خوارزمی، دانشکدۀ فنی مهندسی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه خوارزمی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>jkeyvani@khu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>near-field record</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>high amplitude pulse</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>closed form model</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>frequency band</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>empirical mode decomposition.*Corresponding Author:</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>حوزه نزدیک</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پالس سرعت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدل فرم بسته</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>محتوای فرکانسی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>باند فرکانس پابین</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1.	Amiri J. V., Davoodi M. R., Sahafi A., &quot;Simulation of near-fault ground motions with equivalent pulses and compare their effects on MRF structures&quot;, 14th World Conference on Earthquake Engineering, Beijing, China (2008) 12-17.## 2.	Khaloo A. R., Khosravi H., &quot; Multi-mode response of shear and flexural buildings to pulse-type ground motions in near-field earthquakes&quot;, Journal of Earthquake Engineering, 12 (4) (2008) 616-630. ## 3.	نظری ش.، کیوانی ج.، مشکوه‌الدینی ا.، &quot;شبیه‌سازی رکوردهای زلزله حوزۀ نزدیک با استفاده از تابع موجک&quot;، نشریۀ زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه خوارزمی، (1396) (پذیرفته شده). ## 4.	Nazari S., Keyvani J., Meshkat-Dini A., Azhdarifar M., &quot;Study on the seismic response of mid-rise bundled tube resistant systems under simulated closed-form near-field records&quot;, Asian Journa; of Civil Engineering (BHRC), Tehran, Iran, 18 (6) (2017)961-976. ## 5.	Tavakoli, H. R., Gilani H., Abdollahzadeh G. R., &quot;Comparative evaluation of seismic parameters for near-fault and far-fault earthquakes&quot;, 15th World Conference on Earthquake Engineering, Lisbon, Portugal 24-28 (2012). ## 6.	Bray J. D., Rodriguez-Marek A., &quot;Characterization of forward-directivity ground motions in the near-fault region&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, 24 (11) (2004)815-828. ## 7.	Agrawal A. K., He W. L., &quot;A close-form approximation of near-fault ground motion pulses for flexible structures&quot;, ASCE Engineering Mechanics Conference, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., (2002). ##  8.	Kalkan E., Kunnath S. K., &quot;Effects of fling step and forward directivity on seismic response of buildings&quot;, Earthquake Spectra, 22 (2) (2006) 367-390,. ## 9.	ولیان س.، کیوانی ج.، &quot;بررسی رفتار دینامیکی سازۀ فولادی با سیستم مقاوم جانبی دوگانه تحت اثرمدل‌های ریاضی رکوردهای حوزه نزدیک&quot;، دهمین کنگرۀ ملی مهندسی عمران، دانشکدۀ مهندسی عمران، دانشگاه صنعتی شریف 30 و 31 فروردین) 1396.( ## 10.	Burks L. S., Baker J. W., &quot;A predictive model for fling-step in near-fault ground motions based on recordings and simulations&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, 80 (2016) 119-126. ## 11.	Kalkan E., Kunnath S. K., &quot;Effects of fling step and forward directivity on seismic response of buildings&quot;, Earthquake Spectra, 22 (2) (2006) 367-390. ## 12.	Durucan C., Durucan A. R., &quot;Ap/Vp specific inelastic displacement ratio for the seismic response estimation of SDOF structures subjected to sequential near fault pulse type ground motion records&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, 89 (2016) 163-170. ## 13.	Hatzigeorgiou G. D., &quot;Behavior factors for nonlinear structures subjected to multiple near-fault earthquakes&quot;, Computers and Structures, 88 (5) (2010) 309-321. ## 14.	Zhang Y., Hu Y., Zhao F., Liang J., Yang C.,&quot; Identification of acceleration pulses in near-fault ground motion using the EMD method&quot;, Earthquake Engineering and Engineering Vibration, 4 (2) (2005) 201-212. ## 15.	Kedadouche M., Thomas M., Tahan A., &quot;A comparative study between empirical wavelet transforms and empirical mode decomposition methods: Application to bearing defect diagnosis&quot;, Mechanical Systems and Signal Processing, 81 (2016) 88-107. ## 16.	Mavroeidis G. P., Papageorgiou A. S., &quot;A mathematical representation of near-fault ground motions&quot;, Bulletin of the Seismological Society of America (BSSA) 93 (3) (2003)1099-1131. ## 17.	Mollaioli F., Bosi A., &quot;Wavelet analysis for the characterization of forward-directivity pulse-like ground motions on energy basis&quot;, Meccanica, 47 (1) (2012) 203-219. ## 18.	Vaez S. H., Sharbatdar M. K., Amiri G. G., Naderpour H., Kheyroddin A., &quot;Dominant pulse simulation of near fault ground motions&quot;, Earthquake Engineering and Engineering Vibration, 12 (2) (2013) 267-278,. ## 19.	Mukhopadhyay S., Gupta V. K., &quot;Directivity pulses in near-fault ground motions-II: Estimation of pulse parameters&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, 50 (2013) 38-52. ## 20.	MATLAB Programm, http://mathworks.com/products/matlab. ## 21.	Xu Z., Agrawal A. K., He W. L., Tan P., &quot;Performance of passive energy dissipation systems during near-field ground motion type pulses&quot;, Engineering Structures, 29 (2) (2007) 224-236. ## 22.	Zhai C., Chang Z., Li S., Chen Z., Xie L., &quot;Quantitative identification of near‐fault pulse‐like ground motions based on energy&quot;, Bulletin of the Seismological Society of America (BSSA), 103 (5) (2013) 2591-2603. ## 23.	PEER Ground Motion Database, http://peer.berkeley.edu/.## ##1.	Amiri J. V., Davoodi M. R., Sahafi A., &quot;Simulation of near-fault ground motions with equivalent pulses and compare their effects on MRF structures&quot;, 14th World Conference on Earthquake Engineering, Beijing, China (2008) 12-17.## 2.	Khaloo A. R., Khosravi H., &quot; Multi-mode response of shear and flexural buildings to pulse-type ground motions in near-field earthquakes&quot;, Journal of Earthquake Engineering, 12 (4) (2008) 616-630. ## 3.	نظری ش.، کیوانی ج.، مشکوه‌الدینی ا.، &quot;شبیه‌سازی رکوردهای زلزله حوزۀ نزدیک با استفاده از تابع موجک&quot;، نشریۀ زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه خوارزمی، (1396) (پذیرفته شده). ## 4.	Nazari S., Keyvani J., Meshkat-Dini A., Azhdarifar M., &quot;Study on the seismic response of mid-rise bundled tube resistant systems under simulated closed-form near-field records&quot;, Asian Journa; of Civil Engineering (BHRC), Tehran, Iran, 18 (6) (2017)961-976. ## 5.	Tavakoli, H. R., Gilani H., Abdollahzadeh G. R., &quot;Comparative evaluation of seismic parameters for near-fault and far-fault earthquakes&quot;, 15th World Conference on Earthquake Engineering, Lisbon, Portugal 24-28 (2012). ## 6.	Bray J. D., Rodriguez-Marek A., &quot;Characterization of forward-directivity ground motions in the near-fault region&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, 24 (11) (2004)815-828. ## 7.	Agrawal A. K., He W. L., &quot;A close-form approximation of near-fault ground motion pulses for flexible structures&quot;, ASCE Engineering Mechanics Conference, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., (2002). ##  8.	Kalkan E., Kunnath S. K., &quot;Effects of fling step and forward directivity on seismic response of buildings&quot;, Earthquake Spectra, 22 (2) (2006) 367-390,. ## 9.	ولیان س.، کیوانی ج.، &quot;بررسی رفتار دینامیکی سازۀ فولادی با سیستم مقاوم جانبی دوگانه تحت اثرمدل‌های ریاضی رکوردهای حوزه نزدیک&quot;، دهمین کنگرۀ ملی مهندسی عمران، دانشکدۀ مهندسی عمران، دانشگاه صنعتی شریف 30 و 31 فروردین) 1396.( ## 10.	Burks L. S., Baker J. W., &quot;A predictive model for fling-step in near-fault ground motions based on recordings and simulations&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, 80 (2016) 119-126. ## 11.	Kalkan E., Kunnath S. K., &quot;Effects of fling step and forward directivity on seismic response of buildings&quot;, Earthquake Spectra, 22 (2) (2006) 367-390. ## 12.	Durucan C., Durucan A. R., &quot;Ap/Vp specific inelastic displacement ratio for the seismic response estimation of SDOF structures subjected to sequential near fault pulse type ground motion records&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, 89 (2016) 163-170. ## 13.	Hatzigeorgiou G. D., &quot;Behavior factors for nonlinear structures subjected to multiple near-fault earthquakes&quot;, Computers and Structures, 88 (5) (2010) 309-321. ## 14.	Zhang Y., Hu Y., Zhao F., Liang J., Yang C.,&quot; Identification of acceleration pulses in near-fault ground motion using the EMD method&quot;, Earthquake Engineering and Engineering Vibration, 4 (2) (2005) 201-212. ## 15.	Kedadouche M., Thomas M., Tahan A., &quot;A comparative study between empirical wavelet transforms and empirical mode decomposition methods: Application to bearing defect diagnosis&quot;, Mechanical Systems and Signal Processing, 81 (2016) 88-107. ## 16.	Mavroeidis G. P., Papageorgiou A. S., &quot;A mathematical representation of near-fault ground motions&quot;, Bulletin of the Seismological Society of America (BSSA) 93 (3) (2003)1099-1131. ## 17.	Mollaioli F., Bosi A., &quot;Wavelet analysis for the characterization of forward-directivity pulse-like ground motions on energy basis&quot;, Meccanica, 47 (1) (2012) 203-219. ## 18.	Vaez S. H., Sharbatdar M. K., Amiri G. G., Naderpour H., Kheyroddin A., &quot;Dominant pulse simulation of near fault ground motions&quot;, Earthquake Engineering and Engineering Vibration, 12 (2) (2013) 267-278,. ## 19.	Mukhopadhyay S., Gupta V. K., &quot;Directivity pulses in near-fault ground motions-II: Estimation of pulse parameters&quot;, Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering, 50 (2013) 38-52. ## 20.	MATLAB Programm, http://mathworks.com/products/matlab. ## 21.	Xu Z., Agrawal A. K., He W. L., Tan P., &quot;Performance of passive energy dissipation systems during near-field ground motion type pulses&quot;, Engineering Structures, 29 (2) (2007) 224-236. ## 22.	Zhai C., Chang Z., Li S., Chen Z., Xie L., &quot;Quantitative identification of near‐fault pulse‐like ground motions based on energy&quot;, Bulletin of the Seismological Society of America (BSSA), 103 (5) (2013) 2591-2603. ## 23.	PEER Ground Motion Database, http://peer.berkeley.edu/.##  ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>

</ARTICLES>

</JOURNAL>
</XML>
