<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1391</year>
	<month>1</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2012</year>
	<month>4</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>5</volume>
<number>2</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>پیش‌بینی جابجایی‌های زمین اطراف تونل در اثر حفاری با ماشین‌های EPB (مطالعه موردی: خط 3 متروی تهران)</title_fa>
	<title>Prediction of ground movements around tunnel due to excavation by EPB machines (Case study three line of Tehran subway)</title>
	<subject_fa>زمین شناسی مهندسی</subject_fa>
	<subject>En. Geology</subject>
	<content_type_fa>علمی پژوهشی</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>s</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>رشد و توسعه شهرهای بزرگ نیازمند استفاده از شبکه‌های زیرزمینی در ایجاد زیرساخت‌ها و تسهیلات حمل و نقل شهری است. ساخت تونل در زمین‌های نرم معمولاً جابجایی خاک را به دنبال دارد که می‌تواند تاثیر جدی در پایداری و سلامت سازه‌های موجود داشته باشد. به منظور کاهش این جابجایی‌ها به ویژه در نواحی شهری، مجریان در ساخت تونل‌ها بیش از پیش از ماشین‌های حفر تونل (TBM) استفاده می‌کنند. از اینرو در نواحی شهری، پیش‌بینی جابجایی‌های زمین ناشی از حفر تونل چالش بزرگ مهندسی به شمار می‌رود. در این مقاله به منظور پیش‌بینی جابجایی‌های خاک که در حین ساخت بخشی از تونل خط 3 متروی تهران با استفاده از ماشین حفاری EPB (فشار تعادلی زمین) ایجاد می‌شوند، از یک مدل عددی سه بعدی و نرم افزار ABAQUS استفاده شده است. این بررسی شامل اکثر مؤلفه‌های تونل‌سازی سپری مانند فشار سینه کار، فشار تزریق، ماشین حفاری و تماس اصطکاکی سپر و خاک است. نتایج نشان می دهد که نشست سطحی ماکزیمم در این قسمت 5/2 سانتیمتر است که 5/0 سانتیمتر از حد مجاز آن بیشتر می‌باشد. همزمان با نشست‌های سطحی جابجایی‌های افقی در داخل توده خاک به وجود می‌آیند، که در دو جهت افقی شکل متفاوتی داشته و با افزایش عمق افزایش پیدا می‌کنند.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>The development of large cities requires the use the underground networks for the construction of transportation infrastructures and facilities. Construction of tunnels in soft grounds induces generally soil movement, which could seriously affect the stability and integrity of existing structures. In order to reduce such movements, in particular in urban areas, contractors use more and more the tunnel boring machines (TBM) for the construction of tunnels. Hence in urban environment, Prediction of the ground movements caused by the tunnel excavation is a major engineering challenge. In this paper is used a three-dimensional numerical model and ABAQUS cod for the prediction of soil movements induced during tunnel construction in part of the line 3 of Tehran subway using EPB excavation machine. This investigation include most shield tunneling components such as face pressure, the grouting pressure, excavation machine and frictional contact with soil and shield. Observations of the results demonstrate that the maximum surface settlement in this section is 2.5 cm that is 0.5 cm more than the its allowable value. Simultaneously with surface settlements occur horizontal movements within soil mass, which have different forms in two horizontal directions, and with the expansion of depth they increasing.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>تونل‌های شهری , تونلسازی سپری EPB , جابجایی‌های زمین , مدلسازی سه بعدی , </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Urban tunnels , EPB Shield tunneling , ground movements , 3D modeling , ABAQUS , </keyword>
	<start_page>1235</start_page>
	<end_page>1250</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-106-4&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سعید</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حسینی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>saeed.hosseini63@gmail.com</email>
	<code>100319475328460098</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460098</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد واحد تهران جنوب</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>کورش</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>شهریار</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>k.shahriar@aut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>100319475328460099</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460099</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه امیرکبیر</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مسعود</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>منجزی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>monjezi@modares.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600100</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600100</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
