<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title> Journal of  Engineering Geology  </title>
<link>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</link>
<description>Journal of Engineering Geology - Journal articles for year 2013, Volume 6, Number 2</description>
<generator>Yektaweb Collection - https://yektaweb.com</generator>
<language>en</language>
<pubDate>2013/4/12</pubDate>

					<item>
						<title>Vol.6No.2</title>
						<link>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_id=407&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description></description>
						<author></author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Vol.6No.2</title>
						<link>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_id=406&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description></description>
						<author></author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Mathematical Analysis of Lateral Earth Pressure Distribution on Rigid Retaining Walls</title>
						<link>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_id=379&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;span class=&quot;longtext1&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The shape of slip surface of the wedge creating lateral thrust on rigid retaining walls plays an important role in the magnitude, distribution, and height of point of application of lateral thrust.  Considering the shape of slip surface as linear, circular, logarithmic spiral, or a combination of them has been used in the literature. In the Coulomb lateral earth pressure method, a linear distribution of soil pressure on retaining walls is tentatively assumed and thus the point of application of total thrust is placed at one third of the wall height from the wall bottom. However, some experimental studies have revealed non-linear distribution of lateral earth pressures and that the point of application of resultant thrust is placed upper than one third of the wall height. In the present study, a plasticity equation is used to determine the reaction of the stable soil on cohesionless backfill supported by a retaining wall using an empirical equation derived from experiments performed in the field by others. A new analytical solution for determining the total resultant thrust on the wall is introduced and the distribution of pressures and the point of application of total thrust are computed. The results have been compared with some analytical methods, experimental data, and also with available data reported from field, demonstrating the accuracy and capability of the developed method. The results show that the distribution of the active lateral earth pressure is nonlinear and the point of application of total thrust is located about 0.42H from the wall bottom (H=wall height). In addition, the application&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; point&lt;span class=&quot;longtext1&quot;&gt; of total thrust is nonlinear function of soil-soil, wall-backfill soil friction angels and the height of the wall&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description>
						<author>Mahmoud Ghazavi</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>A New Approach to Evaluate Seismic Stability of Asphaltic Core Rockfill Dams</title>
						<link>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_id=393&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>Construction of asphaltic core dams is a relatively novel method especially in Iran. Iran is located in a region with high seismicity risk. Therefore, many researchers have focused on the behavior of such types of dams under earthquake loading. In this research, the behavior of asphaltic core rockfill dams (ACRD) has been studied under earthquake loading using nonlinear dynamic analysis method and a new method is presented to assess seismic stability of these types of dams in earthquake conditions. Based on nonlinear dynamic analysis, the current study attempts to provide an appropriate criterion for predicting the behavior of earth and rockfill dams considering real behavior of materials together with actual records of earthquake loading. In this method, the maximum acceleration of the earthquake record (PGA) increases until instability conditions. Finally, a new criterion is presented for evaluating seismic safety of ACRDs via demonstrating curves of the crest's permanent settlement and maximum shear strain against maximum earthquake acceleration. Results of the proposed criteria can assist designers of asphaltic core dams to predict dam stability during earthquake event</description>
						<author>Ali Ghanbari</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Constitutive modeling of cemented gravely sands including the effects of cement type</title>
						<link>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_id=364&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>In this paper, a constitutive model is proposed for prediction of the shear behavior of a gravely sand cemented with different cement types. The model is based on combining stress-strain behavior of uncemented soil and cemented bonds using deformation consistency and energy equilibrium equations. Cement content and cement type are considered in a model as two main parameters. Based on the proposed method, the behavior of cemented soil with different cement types is predicted for conventional triaxial test condition. Porepressure developed during undrained loading besides volumetric strains in drained condition are also modeled according to this framework. Comparison of model results with experimental data indicates its reasonable accuracy.</description>
						<author></author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Evaluation of rockburst potential in second part of Karaj-Tehran water conveyance tunnel</title>
						<link>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_id=373&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>One of the geotechnical hazards in the tunnels under high overburden and high in situ stresses is the phenomenon of rock burst. Rock burst is a typical geologic phenomenon caused by excavation in rock masses. In this phenomenon, because of stress released and explosion in rock masses, they are broken as large and small pieces and are distributed, so that leads to damage of peoples or equipments. Therefore, familiar with this phenomenon and its mechanism of occurrence, is need to analyze this issue. The second part of water supply Karaj-Tehran tunnel with a length of 14 km and about 4.5 m diameter is located in Tehran province. Rock burst analysis has been carried out in the tunnel from kilometer 6 to 9.5 that is critical section because of high overburden (up to 800 m) and presence of faults and crushed zones. In this paper, for predicting rock burst in the critical section of second part of Karaj-Tehran tunnel, four criteria including, Strain energy, Rock brittleness, Seismic energy and Tangential stress criterion are used. Analysis results show that units with high overburden have high possibility of rock burst. </description>
						<author>Gh Khanlari</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Uncertainty in Shear Wave Velocity Based on Standard Penetration Test by Using Error Least Square Model</title>
						<link>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_id=392&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>Shear wave velocity (Vs) is a basic engineering soil property implemented in evaluating the soil shear modulus. Due to a few limitations, sometimes it is preferable to determine Vs indirectly by in situ tests, such as standard penetration test (SPT). However, inaccuracies in measurement or estimation of the influencing parameters have always been a major concern, and thus various statistical approaches have been proposed to subdue the effect of such inaccuracies in predictions of future events. In this article, an innovative approach based on robust optimization has been utilized to enumerate the effect of such uncertainties. In order to assess the merits of the proposed approach a database containing 326 data points of case histories from Adapazari, Turkey were gathered from renowned references. The identification technique used in this article is based on the robust counterpart of the least square problem which is a second order cone problem and is efficiently solved by interior point method. A definition of uncertainty based on frobenius norm of the data is introduced and examined against correlation coefficient of various correlation parameters and optimum values are determined. Finally the results of new correlation are compared with those utilizing a commonly used statistical method and the advantages and possibilities of the proposed correlation over the conventional method are highlighted</description>
						<author>Hossein Mola-Abasi</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Effect of Matching Period-Interval Variation on Strong Ground Motion Scaling</title>
						<link>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_id=390&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;span&gt;Time history analyses as crucial means in many earthquake engineering applications are highly dependent to characteristics of the seismic excitation record so that the resulting responses may vary from case to case. Strong ground motion scaling is a known codified solution to reduce such a dependency and increase reliability of time history analyses. The well-known code practice may result in highly non-economic designs due to considerable error in the spectra scaled to match the target code spectrum. This problem is formulated here in an optimization framework with the scaling coefficients as the design variables. Harmony search as a recent meta-heuristic algorithm is utilized to solve the problem and is applied to the treated examples. Using a variety of target period ranges the scaling error is evaluated and studied after more unified via optimization. The effect of base structural period and interval variation on the scaling error is then studied in addition to considerable error decrease with respect to traditional code-based procedure. The results also show dependency of spectral matching error to the period-interval elongation/variation, the base-structural period and more error sensitivity for narrow-band resonance with the filtered records on softer soil types&lt;/span&gt;</description>
						<author>Mohsen Shahrozi</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
	</channel>
</rss>
