<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of  Engineering Geology </title>
<title_fa>نشریه زمین شناسی مهندسی</title_fa>
<short_title>jeg</short_title>
<subject>Engineering &amp; Technology</subject>
<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2228-6837</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.18869/acadpub.jeg</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai></journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science></journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1394</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2015</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>9</volume>
<number>1</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ارزیابی خطر گسلش و رده ندی گسل های فعال اطراف سد شهید رجایی ساری براساس میزان فعالیت</title_fa>
	<title>Evaluating of Faulting Hazard and Classification of Active Faults in Shahid Rajai Dam of Sari Region, Based Activity Rate</title>
	<subject_fa>زمین شناسی مهندسی</subject_fa>
	<subject>En. Geology</subject>
	<content_type_fa>علمی پژوهشی</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>s</content_type>
	<abstract_fa> تعیین میزان فعالیت گسل­ها از جمله مهم‌ترین پارامترهای ارزیابی خطر گسلش است. در این مقاله گسل­های فعال محدودۀ سد شهیدرجایی ساری به شعاع 100 کیلومتر بر مبنای بُعد فرکتالی گسلش و زمین‎لرزه و هم‌چنین ارزیابی میزان لغزش رده­بندی شده و میزان فعالیت آن‌ها بررسی شد. به‌منظور تعیین بُعد فرکتالی گسلش و زمین­لرزه از روش مربع شمار&lt;sup&gt;1 &lt;/sup&gt;  استفاده شد. برای برآورد میزان لغزش ابتدا پارامترهای لرزه‎خیزی (a,b) محدوده بررسی شده تعیین، سپس این پارامترها برای هر گسل نرمالیزه شدند. براساس روابط موجود و با داشتن a و b برای هر گسل، میزان گشتاور لرزه­ای گسل محاسبه شد. در نهایت طبق روابط موجود برای محاسبۀ میزان گشتاور لرزه‎ای، میزان لغزش هر گسل تعیین و گسل­های محدودۀ بررسی شده بر این اساس رده‎بندی شدند. با درجه‎بندی براساس ابعاد فرکتالی، گسل­های شمال البرز، دامغان و گرمسار طی 100 سال گذشته از فعال­ترین گسل­های محدودۀ بررسی شده بوده­اند و براساس برآورد میزان فعالیت گسلش و زمین­لرزه به‌روش تحلیل فرکتالی، عموماً در ردۀ BD قرار گرفته و فعال بودن آن‌ها تأیید شده است. گسل‎های با میزان لغزش خیلی‌کم و با دورۀ بازگشت طولانی رویداد زمین‎لرزه­ها،  سبب وقوع زمین‎لرزه‎های بزرگی می‌شوند که زمین­لرزه 235 خورشیدی (856 میلادی) کومس و گسل مسبب آن یعنی گسل دامغان نمونه­ای از این گسل­ها است. گسل­های آستانه، رمه و چشمه‌علی میزان لغزش کم است و در نتیجه می­توانند گشتاور لرزه­ای بزرگتری ایجاد نمایند. با توجه به رویداد زمین­لرزه­ها در حریم گسل‎های جدید معرفی شده (خرم آباد، مجید و ...)، میزان فعالیت زیاد این گسل­ها منطقی به‌نظر می­رسد.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Determination of Faults activity rate is among the most important parameters of evaluating faulting hazards. In this paper, active faults on region of Shahid Rajai dam of Sari with radius 100 km based on fractal dimension of faulting and earthquake as well as evaluation of slip rate were classified and those Activity rate were assessed. In order to determine of fractal dimension of faulting and earthquake, Box-counting method was used. For estimate of slip rate beginning the seismicity parameters (a&amp;b) of study area was estimation. Then these parameters were normalized for each fault. Based on the existing relationships and having a&amp;b for each fault, the seismic moment of fault was calculated. Finally according to extant relations for evaluation of seismic moment rate, slip rate of each fault was determined and the faults of study area were classified accordingly. By grading based on fractal dimensions, the faults of North- Alborz, Damghan and Garmsar have been the most active faults in the study area during the last 100 years and according to evaluations of active rate of faulting and earthquake based on fractal dimensions, generally set in category BD and their activity approved. The faults with very low slip rate and with long return period of earthquake, are possible causes of occurrence large earthquakes (856 AD) Gomes and inducement fault namely Damghan Fault is an example of these faults. The faults of Astaneh, Rameh and Cheshmeh-ali have been low slip rate and thereupon be able to develop high seismic moment rate. According to earthquake events in privacy of New faults introduced (Khorram-abad, Majid,…), the high activity rate of these faults seem logical</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>سد شهید رجایی , ساری , بُعد فرکتالی , ممان لرزه‌ای , نرخ لغزش , </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Shahid Rajai Dam , Sari , fractal dimension , seismic moment , slip rate , </keyword>
	<start_page>2653</start_page>
	<end_page>2674</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jeg.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-559-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Ramezan</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ramezani omali</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>رمضان</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رمضانی اومالی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Ramazani43@shahroodut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600312</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600312</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>هیأت علمی دانشگاه شاهرود</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>mehdi</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>saeidian</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مهدی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سعیدیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>m.saeidian@gmail.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600313</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600313</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>فارغ التحصیل</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Naser</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Hafezimoghadas</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ناصر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حافظی مقدس</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>nhafezi@um.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600314</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600314</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>هیأت علمی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
