<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Model for Electronic Good Governance in Electronic Learning Sector of Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی مدل حکمرانی خوب الکترونیک در حوزۀ آموزش الکترونیک ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>591</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>620</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">59091</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2016.59091</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Alireza</FirstName>
					<LastName>Moghaddasi</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof., Faculty of Management, Imam Reza International University, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Amir</FirstName>
					<LastName>Manian</LastName>
<Affiliation>Associate Prof., Faculty of Management, Tehran University, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Rahmatollah</FirstName>
					<LastName>Gholipoor</LastName>
<Affiliation>Associate Prof., Faculty of Management,Tehran University, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Alireza</FirstName>
					<LastName>Hasanzadeh</LastName>
<Affiliation>Associate Prof., Faculty of Management and Economic,Tarbiat Moddares University,Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Despite the various models and frameworks on electronic good governance are introduced, the multiple dimensions model of electronic good governance in the field of e-Learning has not been reviewed this subject in a integrated, comprehensive, process-oriented and systematic model. In this article, in order to explain the process of electronic good governance, by a systematic review of the related literature and backgrounds, all factors were identified using meta-synthesis methodology. Then, based on grounded theory methodology and Strauss and Corbin paradigmatic approach, the open, axial and selective coding were conducted. In the following, by using survey method, we determined the importance and priority of all proposed factors. It was also indicated that this research was innovative in the fields of methodology, results and the proposed model which had not been considered in the previous researches. So that, the proposed model resolved the shortcomings of past researches and made it possible for the public sector, private and civil society organizations to consider the process of establishing electronic good governance in e-Learning sector in Iran as a dynamic process.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Electronic good governance</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Electronic governance</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Electronic learning</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Good Governance</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Governance</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_59091_dec97f4e5438b1e8f2991e55d0246b27.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
