<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Synergy Management Model of the Holding by Fuzzy Approach; The Role of Information Technology in its Implementation</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارائۀ سیستم فازی به‎منظور کشف فرصت‌های هم‌افزایی در شرکت‎های مادر</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>22</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">53551</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.53551</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Adel</FirstName>
					<LastName>Azar</LastName>
<Affiliation>Professor, Industry Management, Faculty of Management, Tarbiyat Modares University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2123-7579</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mohammad</FirstName>
					<LastName>Sangi</LastName>
<Affiliation>PhD Candidate, Industry Management, Faculty of Economic and Management, University of Semnan, Semnan, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mohammad Mahdi</FirstName>
					<LastName>Izadkhah</LastName>
<Affiliation>PhD Candidate, International Marketing, Faculty of Economic and Management, University of Semnan, Semnan, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
					<LastName>Anvari</LastName>
<Affiliation>PhD Candidate, Industry Management, Faculty of Management, Tarbiyat Modares University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Interactions between smaller companies in order to share capabilities and weaknesses coverage are very common in holding companies. Although holding value creation by creating synergies among subsidiaries, easy looks but unpleasant practical experiences show that in some organizations the lack of precise identification of opportunities for synergies between the companies, leading to the establishment of relationships between companies that are not only useful, but it can lead to major problems. Accordingly, the main objective of this paper is to provide a fuzzy system is to explore opportunities for synergy in holding, so that the potential opportunities and synergies between related companies specified and the organization existing information system must be developed. Therefore, based on the possible links between the activities and manageability of these relations in associated companies of holding, fuzzy matrix of exploration opportunities for synergy designed and the position of all the subsidiaries to be determined in the matrix. Finally, according to the points earned by firms in synergy matrix, identifying opportunities and improve the synergy between the companies and the managers will be announced.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">fuzzy measures</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Information Technology</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">synergy matrix</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">synergy opportunity</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_53551_b1bb480ae37ccde4f95ed9c670e61884.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Novel Decision Support System for Discrete Cost-CO2 Emission Trade-off in Construction Projects: The Usage of Imitate Genetic Algorithm</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارائۀ سیستم پشتیبانی تصمیم نوین به‎منظور موازنۀ هزینه ـ انتشار دی‌اکسیدکربن گسسته در پروژه‌های ساخت: کاربردی از الگوریتم ژنتیک الگوبرداری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>23</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>48</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">53552</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.53552</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mohammad Ali</FirstName>
					<LastName>Beheshti-Nia</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof., Faculty of Material and Industrial Engineering, University of Semnan, Semnan, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Nahid</FirstName>
					<LastName>Farazmand</LastName>
<Affiliation>MSc. Student in MBA, Faculty of Material and Industrial Engineering, University of Semnan, Semnan, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>13</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Under an intensive competitive environment, the construction industry is facing pressure to meet the higher customer expectations under a tighter budget. On the other hand, construction is one of the main sectors generating greenhouse gases. According to published statistics, construction industry is one of the most important resources of greenhouse emissions in the world. Therefore, based on the growing attention to the environment situation and according to the enabler capabilities of the decision support systems, in this paper, a genetic algorithm-based decision support system for solving a trade-off problem between the cost and the amount of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions in construction projects is proposed. The genetic algorithm proposing here, is the new algorithm, named “imitate genetic algorithm”. For showing the reliability of the proposed algorithm, the results of its application have been compared with the results of classic genetic algorithm for 108 problems with different sizes. The results show the excellence of the proposed algorithm in comparison with classic genetic algorithm.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">carbon dioxide emission</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">cost-CO2 emission trade-off</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">decision support system</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Genetic Algorithm</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_53552_280d95d80a25000d0ca1745a89e5b9bd.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Developing and Identifying Possibility &amp; Plausibility of E-Government Services Scenarios in Iran by 1404</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تدوین و شناسایی سناریوهای امکان‎پذیرآیندۀ خدمات دولت الکترونیک ایران در افق 1404</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>49</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>68</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">53239</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.53239</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Fateme</FirstName>
					<LastName>Sghafi</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof., Interdisciplinary Department of Technology, Faculty of New Sciences and Technologies, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Alireza</FirstName>
					<LastName>Aliahmadi</LastName>
<Affiliation>Prof., Faculty of Industries, Iran University of Science and Technology, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Seyed Sepehr</FirstName>
					<LastName>Ghazi Noory</LastName>
<Affiliation>Associate Prof., Economic and Management Dept., Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mansoureh</FirstName>
					<LastName>Hourali</LastName>
<Affiliation>Ph.D. Candidate, Industry Engineering, Payam-E Noor University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Many documents in the field of e-government services in Iran have been developed and recently approved, but these documents were ignored future trends and scenarios. The aim of research is developing futures scenario of e-government services by 1404. In this study, using the global network business and success factors, the important uncertainties are identified by expert’s opinions. Population is of 50 Iranian e-government experts and futurists. The current research is the compound research. Using questionnaires and analysis of documents and expert panel, the required data are gathered. Validity of the questionnaire assessed using the panel of experts and the Cronbach&#039;s alpha was used for validation. With determination of three uncertainty composed of trust, interoperability and world trade market entry according to the expert&#039;s views as the main scenario, eight scenarios were extracted. Then, with the help of experts, four scenario with higher degree of feasibility were selected which allows policymakers to deal with the best possible of future situation.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">e-government scenario method</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Futures Studies</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">uncertainty</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_53239_c79fe6038a72c706de10b966ae5aedd2.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigation and Prioritizing Outsourcing of Information and Communication Technology (ICT) Projects (Case Study: ICT Infrastructure Projects)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی و اولویت بندی مخاطرات برون سپاری پروژه های فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات (ICT) (مطالعۀ موردی: پروژه های زیرساخت فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>69</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>84</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">53553</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.53553</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Seyed Ehsan</FirstName>
					<LastName>Khansarizadeh</LastName>
<Affiliation>MSc. Graduated In Information Technology Management, Institude of Higher Education of Mehralborz, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mehdi</FirstName>
					<LastName>Shirmohammadi</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof ,Management Group ,Institude of Higher Education of Ershad, Damavand, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>12</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Outsourcing IT functions is being developed as a replacement for implementing IT projects or rendering IT services within organizations. Organizations’ past experiences in outsourcing indicate that this process poses variety of risks and problems. This study is aimed to identify and prioritize the risks of outsourcing IT infrastructure projects. Classifying risks of outsourcing along with incorporating thematic experts’ experiences through the Delphi method, reveals various risks associated with the employer and the contractor as the primary sources of risks as well as general risks and chronological risks which occur in the periods before, during and after contracts. A total of 22 main risks were identified and categorized. Afterwards, based on the opinions obtained from thematic experts and using the Analytic Hierarchy Process, different types of risks were prioritized. The results suggest that those risks arising due to failings of structure and content are more important than those of technical and contextual knowledge.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">AHP</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Contract</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Delphi</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">IT outsourcing</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Risk Management</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_53553_9fc45424ade969d62d1367b600a05d88.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Designing an Adaptive Nuero-Fuzzy Inference System for Evaluating the Business Intelligence System Implementation in Software Industry</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی سیستم استنتاج فازی ـ عصبی انطباقی برای ارزیابی استقرار سیستم هوشمندی کسب‎وکار در صنعت تولید نرم‌افزار</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>85</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>104</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">53554</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.53554</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Iman</FirstName>
					<LastName>Raeesi Vanani</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof., Industrial  Management, Allameh Tabataba’i University, Management and Accounting College ,Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Fatemeh</FirstName>
					<LastName>Ganjalikhan Hakemi</LastName>
<Affiliation>MSc., Information Technology Management, University of Tehran, Management College, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>30</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The main goal of research is designing an adaptive nuero-fuzzy inference system for evaluating the implementation of business intelligence systems in software industry. Iranian software development organizations have been facing a lot of problems in case of implementing business intelligence systems. This system would be helpful in recognizing the conditions and prerequisites of success or failure. Organizations can recalculate the neuro-fuzzy system outputs with some considerations on various inputs to figure out which inputs have the most effect on the implementation outputs. By resolving the problems on inputs, organizations can achieve a better level of implementation success. The designed system has been trained by a data set and afterwards, it has been evaluated. The trained system has reached the error value of 0.08. Eventually, some recommendations have been provided for software development firms on the areas that might need more considerations and improvements.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">adaptive nuero-fuzzy inference system</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Business Intelligence</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Critical Success Factors</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">system implementation</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_53554_836cb21c23cb72440ce5b49b34ac826e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Measuring Enterprise Systems Benefits in Contractor Companies Procurement Process, Using Action Research Strategy</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>سنجش مزایای سیستم‌های سازمانی در فرایند تأمین شرکت‌های پیمانکاری با استفاده از اقدام‎پژوهی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>105</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>124</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">53326</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.53326</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Reza</FirstName>
					<LastName>Sarkhosh</LastName>
<Affiliation>MSc  in Management of Information Technology, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The benefits of Enterprise Systems (ES) are very varied and have been studied by scientists in this field over the years. But one aspect that is less noticed is the benefit result of the ES implementation in the procurement process, which is very important to the contractor companies. The main objective and the purpose of this research is to address this important issue. Other objective of the study is to find out the main reason for accepting ES and to provide a benefit evaluation framework using the balanced scorecard framework. This article seeks to provide a framework using a full review of the literature, and the proposed framework will be assessed in the contractor company projects through action research strategy and finally the benefit of the implementation will be offered. Except of localized definition of ES benefits framework and assessment of the benefits, the findings of present study includes the mixed research methodology with two positivism and interpretativism approaches through two full cycles of action research.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">action research</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">contractor copmpanies</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">enterprice systems</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">measuring benefits</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">procurement process</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_53326_d8907782cd05090f43a5373f9824c758.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>IRAN E-GOVERNMENT MODEL IN 2025</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مدل توسعۀ دولت الکترونیک در ایران 1404</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>125</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>142</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">53240</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.53240</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mahdi</FirstName>
					<LastName>Faghihi</LastName>
<Affiliation>Ph.D. Student in public Administration, Faculty of Management and Economic, Islamic Azad University, sciences and researches Branch,Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Gholamreza</FirstName>
					<LastName>Memar-Zadeh</LastName>
<Affiliation>Associate Prof., Faculty of Management and Economic, Islamic Azad University, sciences and researches Branch,Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In this research by applying the theoretical framework of socio-technical systems and literature review using the form of e-government has been identified as a core component. To realize the model results and the results indicated that each of the six components of e-government in 1404 particularly in the areas of communication and access to digital content. Based on the results of the highest priority among the components of e-government development infrastructure is owned by the component, based on interviews with managers and theme analysis performed on each component of the realization of e-government development has been proposed.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">E-Government</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">socio-technical systems</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Theme Analysis</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">vision document</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_53240_62545e47664395644a092208c593492d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Method for Developing Enterprise Architecture Frameworks: An Interpretive Phenomenology Study</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تدوین روش توسعۀ چارچوب معماری سازمانی: مطالعۀ پدیدارشناسی تفسیری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>143</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>162</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">52456</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.52456</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
					<LastName>Moeini</LastName>
<Affiliation>Associate Prof., Faculty of Engineering, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Ehsan</FirstName>
					<LastName>Merati</LastName>
<Affiliation>Ph.D. Candidate in Systems  Management, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Nowadays, many of organizations, who are involved in enterprise architecting, make their own architecture framework or customize existing frameworks. These endeavors are based on the knowledge and the experience of each organization, and there is no defined method for developing the enterprise architecture framework. Therefore, a method for developing architecture framework is presented in this qualitative research. For this reason, 15 versions of 5 most used architecture frameworks are analyzed based on the interpretive phenomenology. Based on this analysis, a method for developing architecture frameworks is introduced which contains 8 disciplines and 6 phases. Analyzing the qualitative data of the research and also the validation of the research are carried out using the guidelines of Van Manen in the interpretive phenomenology.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">architecture framework</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">enterprise architecture</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">enterprise architecture development method</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">interpretive phenomenology</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">method</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_52456_7cd00b81086d515fa4f91fedcd134bc2.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identifying Organizational Information Security Risks Using Fuzzy Delphi</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی ریسک‌های امنیت اطلاعات سازمانی با استفاده از روش دلفی فازی در صنعت بانکداری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>163</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>184</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">53555</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.53555</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Parisa</FirstName>
					<LastName>Mousavi</LastName>
<Affiliation>MSc. Student, Information Technology Management, Faculty of Accounting and  Management, Kharazmi University of Tehran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Reza</FirstName>
					<LastName>Yousefizenouz</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof., Faculty of Accounting and  Management, Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Akbar</FirstName>
					<LastName>Hasanpoor</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof., Faculty of Accounting and  Management, Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>13</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Most organizations need to information systems to survive and thrive. Therefore, they should seriously protect their information assets. Creating structured and justifiable exchanges between cost, security and mission control systems security risks is essential. This is important in the planning and development of such systems. Initial appropriate decisions can reduce costs and increase ease of control risk. The first step in the risk management process is the identification of risk. The purpose of this study is identifying the most important enterprise information security risks. This study is application and view research method is descriptive. In this study, a model is presented to identify information security risks, according to ISO 27002 and cobit 4 and study the documents and using by fuzzy Delphi method and opinions of experts, which include 10 of the IT professionals of the Bank, have been presented. In this template 6 factors and 20 subfactors of information security risk factors have been identified for the Bank.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Fuzzy Delphi</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">information security</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">risk identifying</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Risk Management</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_53555_e7d253571231a0e9a2c9ef8db5456a67.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Estimation of Monetary Value of Information on the Internet</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>برآورد ارزش پولی اطلاعات در اینترنت</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>185</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>198</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">51911</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.51911</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mohsen</FirstName>
					<LastName>Nazari</LastName>
<Affiliation>Associate Prof., Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2861-2052</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Seyed Vahid</FirstName>
					<LastName>Tabatabaie Kalejahi</LastName>
<Affiliation>Ph.D. Candidate, Marketing Management, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This research estimates the monetary value of internet information for each type of information and services by using Hedonic pricing method. The statistic social of this research is high-speed internet users in Tehran. Based on the results, high speed internet users of Tehran consider a positive monetary value for some information types in the internet, in descendent respect, such as film downloading, gaming, News, social network, and music. Also, the results indicates that people with higher education level and people who are subscribed to high speed internet earlier than other people consider more monetary value to use the internet. For generalizing the result of this research, it’s suggested to do this research at other cities of Iran. At last, some applicable suggestions made.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Hedonic pricing</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Information Value</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Internet</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">information goods</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_51911_cafdc196327a904774c5294b30bfef0b.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Leadership Style and Organizational Climate on the Knowledge Management; The Role of Organizational Structure and Social Reaction (Survey about the Mellat Bank Headquarters)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر سبک رهبری و جو سازمانی بر مدیریت دانش با توجه به نقش میانجی ساختار سازمانی و تعامل اجتماعی (پیمایشی پیرامون بخش ستادی بانک ملت)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>199</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>216</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">53318</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.53318</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Hamidreza</FirstName>
					<LastName>Yazdani</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof., Faculty of Management &amp; Accounting , pardis compus tehran university, Qom, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
					<LastName>Hamidizadeh</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Professor, Faculty of Management &amp; Accounting , pardis compus tehran university, Qom, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Alireza</FirstName>
					<LastName>Kameli</LastName>
<Affiliation>MSc. Student, Faculty of Management &amp; Accounting, Farabi Campus University of Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Leadership style and organizational climate are considered as a substructure framework in successful performance of knowledge management. The purpose of this research is investigating both the effect of leadership style and organizational climate on knowledge management and the moderate role of organization structure and social interaction in affecting leadership style and organizational climate on knowledge management. This study has been done as a sample of 210 main employers of Tehran Mellat bank office. The descriptive- survey research is management type and used tool is questionnaire. We used modeling method of structural equations by Lisrel software data analysis. Research findings show leadership style doesn’t effect on knowledge management positively but organization climate has a positive effect on knowledge management. On other word, leadership style has a positive effect on organization structure and its own has a positive effect on social interaction. But, in this research, moderate variable couldn’t play an easy role in affecting leadership style over knowledge management.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Knowledge Management</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">leadership style</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Organizational climate</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Organizational structure</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">social interaction</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_53318_459b5e91cc8e8095c1064dd5ef759ba5.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
