<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Providing a Model for Setting Priorities in KM for Improving Customer Relationship Management 
(Case study: Sepah Bank)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مدلی برای اولویت‎دهی عوامل مدیریت دانش در بهبود عملکرد مدیریت ارتباط با مشتری (مطالعه موردی: بانک سپه)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>63</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>82</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">36504</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2013.36504</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Narges</FirstName>
					<LastName>Rezaei-Malek</LastName>
<Affiliation>M.Sc.in Information Technology Management, Azad University, E Campus, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Reza</FirstName>
					<LastName>Radfar</LastName>
<Affiliation>Associate Prof. in Industrial Management, Azad University, Science &amp; Research Branch, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In recent decade, with increasing competition, attracting and retaining customers are known as the most valuable competitive tool for many organizations. Customers have a key role in success of businesses, so the managing of customers&#039; relationship is one of organization priorities. Although some organizations have customer relationship management, they are not able to absorb customer satisfaction. With formation of private banks in Iran, state banks were exposed with many problems in marketing. This article has attempted to present a model of improving customer relationship management with knowledge management by managing efficiency and priority knowledge of the organization. Therefore knowledge management factors including customer knowledge, staff knowledge, knowledge of the market that are called independent variables and customer relationship management variables (management services, complaints, suggestions) were identified as dependent variables, were selected. Bank Sepah was chosen as the sample. For data analysis, structure equation model and lisrel software are used.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Knowledge Management</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Customer relationship management</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Customer Knowledge</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Market knowledge</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Staff Knowledge</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_36504_7e305afa0e4bc70111822609db712819.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
