<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Designing fuzzy expert system for chief privacy officer in government and businesses E-transactions</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی سیستم خبره فازی برای مدیر عالی حریم‌خصوصی در حوزۀ تبادلات الکترونیکی دولت و کسب‌وکارها</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>511</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>530</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">54073</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.54073</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Sha’ban</FirstName>
					<LastName>Elahi</LastName>
<Affiliation>Associate Prof., Information Technology Management Department, Faculty of Management and Economic, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mostafa</FirstName>
					<LastName>Rashidi</LastName>
<Affiliation>MSc. in Information Technology Management, Faculty of Management and Economic, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mahmoud</FirstName>
					<LastName>Sadeghi</LastName>
<Affiliation>Associate Prof., Private Law Department, Faculty of Law, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The Chief Privacy Officers (CPO) are faced with many and varied responsibilities and roles. In this paper, a fuzzy expert system is designed, called &quot;Chief Privacy Officer Fuzzy Expert System (CPOFEX)&quot;, to inform the Chief Privacy Officer about &quot;the Status of the Privacy of Government and Businesses (G-B) E-Transactions&quot;. To develop the research model and knowledge base of the mentioned expert system, the concepts of “the Chief Privacy Officers (CPO) Capability“, “Electronic Crimes Intents“, “Type of Government and Business E-Transactions“, “Professional Ethics-Orientation in E-Transactions Parties“, “Privacy Protector Technologies in Enterprise“ were identified, as components of &quot;the Status of the Privacy of Government and Businesses E-Transactions&quot;. To validate the mentioned expert system, the outputs of the system were compared with the experts views. This system can help to analyze &quot;the status of the privacy of government and businesses e-transactions&quot;, and provide more accurate advices.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">chief privacy officer</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Expert system</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Fuzzy logic</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">government and businesses e-transactions</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_54073_d0135808f5e0ab7c814068c4da23d7e7.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
