<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identifying the Applications of Internet of Things in the Smart Home by Using Meta synthesis Method</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle></VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>659</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>678</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">63104</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2017.227832.1967</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Manochehr</FirstName>
					<LastName>Ansari</LastName>
<Affiliation>Associate Prof. in MBA, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Ayoub</FirstName>
					<LastName>Mohammadian</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof. in IT, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Ehsan</FirstName>
					<LastName>Nevisande</LastName>
<Affiliation>MSc. in MBA, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>24</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>There is quite huge annual energy consumption in Iran in household, commercial, and public sectors. In addition, the index of population aging manifests a great increase in recent years. Concurrent to all these, smart houses which are equipped with Internet of Things (IoT) can help us maintain sustainable developments with functionalities such as improvements in energy consumption and health, to name but a few. Accordingly, in this thesis, we aimed to identify the usage and functions of IoT in smart houses. This research is an applied research in nature and it would be classified as qualitative regarding data collection. In order to identify the usages of IoT in smart houses with the help of meta-synthesis approach, we have examined 371 researches among which only 85 have been selected for the final analysis. 122 factors have been extracted based on these 85 researches which have been combined into 7 main usages of “electricity consumption management”, “Heating, ventilation and air conditioning System”, “water consumption control”, “security empowerment for the buildings and the neighborhood”, “health monitoring”, “crisis management”, and home appliance automation.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Internet of things application</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Internet of Things</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Metasynthesis</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Smart building</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Smart houses</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_63104_1c5c82da78a134a6a75a726867e35e4c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
