<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The relationship between corporate governance and IT governance in public organizations</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رابطه حاکمیت فناوری اطلاعات و حاکمیت شرکتی میان سازمان های دولتی حوزه فناوری اطلاعات</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>615</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>634</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">54329</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.54329</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mohammad Hossein</FirstName>
					<LastName>Ronaghi</LastName>
<Affiliation>Ph.D. Candidate in Information Technology Management, Faculty of Management University of Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6060-3370</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Jafar</FirstName>
					<LastName>Mahmoudi</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Professor, Imam Hussein University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Corporate governance is the system by which corporations are directed and controlled. Corporate governance also provides the structure through which company objectives are established, the means to achieve these objectives, and how to monitor their performance. ICTs have the potential to make organization and its services more transparent by providing easy access to information. This research aims to evaluate the relationship between information technology governance and corporate governance. The survey sample population consisted of 178 randomly taken managers and employees who work in public organizations. To examine the hypothesis, we use canonical correlation analysis. An important part of results from canonical correlation analysis indicated that there is a proper linear mixture between the variables of canonical effective factors on corporate governance and its components.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">COBIT</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Corporate governance</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">IT governance</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_54329_98870b6ad01666c29050637ecc16179d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
