<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Effective Factors in the Implementation of the ٍE.R.P using the Q.F.D approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی و اولویت‌بندی عوامل موثر در فرایند پیاده‌سازی سیستم برنامه‌ریزی منابع سازمان با رویکرد گسترش عملکرد کیفیت در گروه صنعتی بهمن دیزل</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>697</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>714</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">53888</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.53888</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Jalal</FirstName>
					<LastName>Haghighat Monfared</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mehran</FirstName>
					<LastName>Khalaj</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Arash</FirstName>
					<LastName>Mohammad Alian</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mohammad Reza</FirstName>
					<LastName>Kabaran Zadeh Ghadim</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Researches have always been seeking those factors that deserve to be studied to reduce the risk involved in the process of enterprise resource planning implementation and increase the opportunity of achieving the implementation objective. In addition, by knowing the priority of the factors, they could carry out the resources allocation in a goal-directed way. By seeking the opinions of the senior managers and advisors Bahman Diesel Industrial Group, 34 critical success factors whichhad been already noted in the precedent studies were identified. However , due to the difference in the type of organizations and lack of priority, there was no justification in using the already identified raw critical success factors. Therefore; by considering the prioritization of the managers in different sectors, as the main customers of the products yield through enterprise resource planning, the critical success factors were classified, prioritizes and named by benefiting from experts view with regards to the priorities set by the managers and employing the factorial analysis scientific method, those factors were divided into seven new clusters that could be named as the new seven localized critical success factors ; followed by using them in the quality table boxes to serve as voice of customer. 18 tangible technical factors were then determined in in relation with those item and prioritization was performed accordingly by using QFD approach .</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Enterprise resource planning</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">critical success factor</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Exploratory Factor Analysis</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">quality function deployment</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_53888_3e5cfd895846a72e846b2724254e1542.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identifying the Effective Factors in Making Trust in Online Social Networks on the perspective of Iranian experts Using Fuzzy ELECTRE</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی عوامل مؤثر بر اعتمادسازی در شبکه‌های اجتماعی برخط به‎کمک روش الکترۀ فازی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>715</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>740</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">54750</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.54750</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Elham</FirstName>
					<LastName>Haghighi</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Gholam Ali</FirstName>
					<LastName>Montazer</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>24</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>this paper attempts to rank the effective factors in making trust in social networks to provide the possibility of attracting and increasing users’ trust on these social networks for providers and designers of online social networks. Identifying the effective factors in making trust in social networks is a multi-criteria decision making problem and most of effective factors are ambiguous and uncertain, thereby this article uses Fuzzy ELECTRE to rank them. By implementing Fuzzy ELECTRE on gathered data, respectively «usability factor», «supporting up to date technology factor», «integrity» and «the rate of ethics factor» are on the top of effective factors in making trust in users. In general, «web features» and «technology features» have a higher degree of importance than «security features», «individual-social features» and «cultural features». Ranking of Fuzzy ELECTRE comparison ranking of Fuzzy TOPSIS and Fuzzy ELECTRE method becomes validate because Spearman correlation coefficients is 0/867. Result of sensitivity analysis on changing weight of criteria shows that Fuzzy ELECTRE isn’t affected by ambiguity and uncertainty in inputs.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Fuzzy ELECTRE</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Fuzzy theory</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">online social networks</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">trust</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_54750_88e65733cc95d16d926df4e84ba4b036.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The effects of information technology based retail channels integration on retail stores performance: mediating role of organizational Ambidexterity (case study: Rasht stores)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر یکپارچگی کانال‌های خرده‌فروشی مبتنی بر فناوری اطلاعات بر عملکرد فروشگاه‌های خرده‌فروشی با میانجی‌گری دوسوتوانی سازمانی (مطالعۀ موردی: فروشگاه‌های شهر رشت)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>741</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>768</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">55356</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.55356</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mohamadrahim</FirstName>
					<LastName>Ramazanian</LastName>
<Affiliation>University of Guilan</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Yaghoob</FirstName>
					<LastName>Mombiniy</LastName>
<Affiliation>University of Guilan</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mahmoud</FirstName>
					<LastName>Moradi</LastName>
<Affiliation>University of Guilan</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>25</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Information technology is a critical tool for companies to achieve the competitive advantage and organizational innovation. IT capability provides an appropriate opportunity for retailers to improve their relationships with customers and progress firms’ performance. Comes with advances in technology, retail industry by using Information technology has changed its business process from traditional to online channels. This paper, investigates the effects of IT based retail channel integration on retail stores performance, furthermore the mediating role of organizational ambidexterity as organizational capability in exploitation and exploration of growth opportunities has been examined. Research data has been collected from the retailer sales chains in Rasht city. Data was collected through questionnaires and analyzed by structural equation modeling and partial least squares algorithm. Findings show that retail channel integration based on information technology by mediated organizational ambidexterity influence on performance.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">retail channel integration</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Organizational Ambidexterity</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">retail stores</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">firm performance</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_55356_3f8263b19547da99217765cd2ab5bcda.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identifying and Prioritizing Factors Affecting the Adoption of BYOD in Organization Using a Fuzzy Approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی و اولویت بندی عوامل موثر بر پذیرش BYOD در سازمان ها با رویکردی فازی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>769</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>788</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">55355</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.55355</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Khodakaram</FirstName>
					<LastName>Salimifard</LastName>
<Affiliation>Persian Gulf University</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Abbas</FirstName>
					<LastName>Abbasizad</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Reza</FirstName>
					<LastName>Siavashi</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In the wake of rapid growth in information technology, modern organizations seeking to increase the access and exchange data with minimal costs. BYOD is an emergent policy under which employees are allowed to use their personal devices such as smart phones, tablets and laptops to perform tasks. In this study, a model to prioritize the factors influencing the organizational adoption of BYOD is proposed. The model has two main criteria, each of which has ten subcriteria. Using ICT experts’ views and Improved Fuzzy Analytical Hierarchy Process technique, the model criteria were weighted. The two main factors, political factors identified as foremost important factor and behavioral intention to use IT were in the second priority. The model can be used as a basis for further research and successful implementation of BYOD by the organizations.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">BYOD</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Technology Acceptance</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">technology adotion</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Fuzzy Analytical Hierarchy Process</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_55355_006ffe66f864d72d6949afbd3acc95c9.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Studying the Effect of Competitive Intelligence on Organizational Performance in Commercial Banks: A Survey on Commercial Banks</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر هوشمندی رقابتی بر عملکرد سازمان در بانک های تجاری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>789</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>804</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">55719</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.55719</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Sonia</FirstName>
					<LastName>Sarami</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Asadollah</FirstName>
					<LastName>Kordnaeich</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Asghar</FirstName>
					<LastName>Moishabaki Esfahani</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The importance of obtaining market information via organization’s competitive intelligence considering the extensive changes which companies are experiencing in different areas like increased pressure of competition, emerging new technologies, privatisation in thier competitive environment is now more than ever and can highly affect organizational performance. Hence this study assessed the effect of competitive intelligence on organizational performance in commercial banks. This research was an applied research in terms of purpose and correlational descriptive in terms of data gathering method. The statistical population of the study is the 22 commercial banks that 14 banks cooperated with this research and from the cooperating banks we gathered a sample of 174 participants. Data were gathered by questionnaire and At the end, by using Structural equation modeling and SmartPLS and SPSS softwares hypothesis were tested. Research findings showed that competitive intelligence affects organizational performance.Its indicators which are, competitors,technologic, strategic-social and market intelligence also affect organizational performance respectively.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Commercial Banks</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Competitive intelligence</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Efficiency</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">performance</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_55719_0280590ba419fab11086f54aa805b7c0.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Reducing the Break-even Time by Smart Power Managing in Data Center with Renewable Energy</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>کاهش زمان بازگشت سرمایه از طریق مدیریت هوشمند توان مصرفی در مرکز دادۀ دارای انرژی خورشیدی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>805</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>824</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">54270</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.54270</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Somayyeh</FirstName>
					<LastName>Taheri</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Maziar</FirstName>
					<LastName>Goudarzi</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Due to the increasing cost and environmental impacts of fossil fuel consumption, using the renewable energies in data center has become an important and essential priority. Although using renewable energies has less environmental harmful effects, but the high investment needed for their installations as well as their fluctuating power production characteristic, restricts their usage such that most of data centers&#039; managers prefer to use brown energy instead. In this paper, the power management and cost reduction techniques, with the aim of reducing break-even time, like using the electricity pricing models&#039; opportunity and distributed Uninterruptable Power Supply (UPS) has been considered. In each time slot, the proposed Smart Power Manager Unit (SPMU) specifies the optimized distribution of power between available power supplies based on available solar energy, the price of electricity and the status of distributed UPS batteries; it also manages batteries charging and discharging. Results show that proposed method reduces the break-even time of investment cost on solar power installation to 0/8- 1/2 years that is 36% shorter than conventional method on average.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Data Center</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Distributed UPS</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Electricity Pricing Model</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Renewable Energy source</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_54270_0e9cdd3be3f7be9c7d26566eea12091e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>abnormal data detection and learning their behavior by abnormality  and satisficing theory</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>کشف و یادگیری پدیده های استثنایی با بکارگیری تئوری استثنائات و رضایتمندی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>825</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>844</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">55639</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.55639</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Masood</FirstName>
					<LastName>Abessi</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Elahe</FirstName>
					<LastName>Hajigol Yazdi</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Learning of abnormalities is a considerable challenge in data mining and knowledge discovery. Exceptional phenomena detect among huge records of the database which contains a large number of normal records and very few abnormal ones. This is important to promote confidence to a limited number of records for effective learning of abnormality. In this study, a new approach based on the abnormality theory and satisficing theory presented for confidence improvement of abnormal data detection and learning. First, the borders of abnormal and normal behavior clear using a combination approach based on abnormality theory then, satisfied solution extracted by means of satisficing theory. Modified RISE method as a bottom-up learning approach implemented to extract Normal and abnormal knowledge. The efficiency of the proposed model determined by using it, for abnormal stock selection from the Iran stock market. The superior of the proposed method results toward the results of applying decision tree and support vector machine is considerable. Accuracy of proposed method measure by g-means index. The results show the capability of proposed approach in abnormality detection and learning.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Data Mining</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Abnormality theory</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Satisficing theory</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Bottom-up learning</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_55639_f6b049d36513760c8ba1504e87c90630.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identify factors affecting the development and use of electronic services in the tourism industry (studied Ardebil)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر گسترش و استفاده از خدمات الکترونیک در صنعت گردشگری (موردمطالعه: استان اردبیل)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>845</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>864</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">53829</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.53829</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Vahide</FirstName>
					<LastName>Alipour</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mohammad</FirstName>
					<LastName>Bashukouh</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mitra</FirstName>
					<LastName>Shekasteband</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>26</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present study aimed identifies factors affecting the development and use of electronic services in the tourism industry. Population of the study of those tourists who have traveled in April 2013 in the city of Ardabil. The population sample of 384 randomly selected. To gather data, researchers used a combination of questionnaires and questionnaire containing 51 questions was designed. The validity and reliability of the variables considered in the study as it was very good. Research questions investigated through descriptive and inferential statistics were performed using SPSS, Lisrel. The results of the analysis show that variable behavioral intention to make use of the technology has 84% rate, technology acceptance model it 79% of the impact, trust has 86 percent of the impact and the dissemination of innovation has a 67 percent impact on the plan to use the electronic services. In the meantime the trust of the organization and trust of the technology variables impact among other factors is more.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Tourism</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">e-tourism</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">electronic services</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">factor analysi</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_53829_12b0483aef4e13a55c2dcbec8907d878.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A New Model to Evaluate the Performance of Information and Communication Technology Sectors with the Approach of Green Communications</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارائه مدلی جهت ارزیابی عملکرد واحدهای فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات با رویکرد ارتباطات سبز</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>865</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>888</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">55357</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.55357</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mohammad</FirstName>
					<LastName>Fathian</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mahdi</FirstName>
					<LastName>Mehriar</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mohammad Reza</FirstName>
					<LastName>Gholamian</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Abstract: Performance evaluation models of information and communication technology (ICT) sectors have been already considered with many perspectives of ICT management. Since ICT has two distinct aspects of usefulness and harmfulness for the environment, therefore, this research with regard to the new dimension named environment, is going to present a new performance evaluation model with the approach of environment. To achieve such a model, the integration of criteria of the I.R.Iran ICT National Quality Award (ICTINQA), Green IT Balanced Scorecard, Iranian green management model, standards of the International Telecommunication Union (ITU) and other models are used. Afterwards, the most comprehensive suggested criteria are presented with redefinition under the title of fundamental concepts of green communications framework. &lt;br /&gt;For this purpose, by using the method of exploratory and confirmatory factor analysis, the final factors were determined and weighted using hierarchical analysis technique.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ICT Performance Evaluation</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Green Communications</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">environment</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Information and communication technology</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_55357_ddb3b03f72dafac3afb79a6096e19b75.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Review the Position of the Ethics paradigm in Code of Ethics by Meta-synthesis –Observed Case  (Association for Computing Machinery  )</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی جایگاه پارادایم ‏های اخلاق در منشورهای اخلاقی با بهره‎مندی از روش فراترکیب (مورد مطالعه: منشور اخلاقی انجمن کامپیوتر (ماشین‏های حسابگر))</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>889</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>908</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">55974</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.55974</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Amir</FirstName>
					<LastName>Manian</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Fateme</FirstName>
					<LastName>Abbasi</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>All researches and documents have a philosophical basis and since paradigm refers to the system of thinking, it can be basis for research patterns. Despite of the various discussions on information system paradigms and code of ethics , non of them deal with paradigm of code of ethics. Due to this gap the aim of this research is explaining the position of ethics paradigm in organizations code of ethics which work in information systems. In this research, features of ethics in paradigms is demonstrated in by using meta-synthesis. Extracted information shows organizational code of ethics which active in information system fields and totally specifies paradigms of each provision of Association for Computing Machinery (ACM). Totally our surveys shows that modern and post-modern are dominant paradigm of code of ethics which represent the dominance of applied ethics, ethical responsibility, Resistance oriented, critical training, domination struggles training and democratic training in ACM code of ethics.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Code of Ethics</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Meta-synthesis</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Ethics Paradigms</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">modern</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_55974_27862438a0fe28c1d8553330d1436101.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Social Network Analysis of the Co-authorship Network in the Scientific Articles of Information Systems</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل شبکۀ اجتماعی هم تألیفی مقالات علمی سیستم های اطلاعاتی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>909</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>930</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">55714</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.55714</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Amir Hossein</FirstName>
					<LastName>Mardani</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Elham</FirstName>
					<LastName>Mardani</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>24</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This research uses of Scientometric indicators and social network analysis to evaluate the performance of countries in the field of information systems in Web of Science during 2004 to 2013. The results show that co-authorship network has 166 vertices (countries) and 21518 links (co-authorships). In general, co-authorship network of information systems had a high density than some fields and Solidarity of the network is partially good. There are no isolated component in the network and more possible links in this network have emerged. According to micro-level metrics, countries like America and Britain are recognized as the most influential countries in co-authorship network and can control the flow of information between network. Using the findings, policy-makers and planners of university in Iran can provide facilities for the formation and strengthening of collaborative connections with the important and influential countries.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">information systems</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Social network analysis</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Scientometric</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Co-Authorship Network</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_55714_3effb2f832b09fbd2683786f27bea7b8.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Process Reengineering of Management In Iran Smart Schools With the emphasis on the role of information and communication technology</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بازمهندسی فرآیند مدیریت در مدارس هوشمند ایران با تأکید بر نقش فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>931</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>950</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">55975</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.55975</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mohammad Reza</FirstName>
					<LastName>Mardani</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Manijheh</FirstName>
					<LastName>Molaei</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In the areas that the introduction of information technology has fundamentally changed and is the field of education, has some shortcomings. The aim of this research sought to identify factors affecting the management of smart schools. In this paper simultaneously has been using field studies to collect data in the form of interviews and a questionnaire survey. The statistical community of this research has been the smart schools under the education of I.R.IRAN. Purposive sampling method is used and the data collection tool was a questionnaire consists of 36 questions that each question designates one of effective factors on the management of smart schools. Also each question consists of two parts. The first part designates the position of factor in the management process, which represents the domain&#039;s belonging to the management agent (planning, organizing, leading, controlling), According to the classification of Dabryn and in the second part the amount of affect of the factors on the process of managing the smart schools were examined. At the end the factors affecting the management of smart schools, recognized and prioritized, and were divided indabryn groups. According to this research subsets are extracted. The research conclusions show that the factors &quot;Internet Speed&quot;, &quot;The Introduction, facilities and smart equipment OF schools&quot;, &quot;Web and portal OF school, and solid sculpture systems&quot;, &quot; Promote academic ability and OF potential beneficiaries” ARE Effective ON the management process in the smart schools.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Re – engineering</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">The management process</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">The smart school</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Contributing factors</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_55975_8cb5f9e07089f9169b857db4b32d3cc9.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
