<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Individual Motivations on Knowledge Sharing Behavior Considering the Moderating Role of Values (The case of Ideshahr)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر انگیزه‌های فردی بر رفتار به اشتراک‌گذاری دانش با توجه به نقش تعدیل‎کنندگی ارزش‎ها (مطالعۀ موردی: ایده‎شهر)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>253</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>272</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">57366</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2016.57366</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Seyed Mohammadbagher</FirstName>
					<LastName>Jafari</LastName>
<Affiliation>1.	Assistant Prof., Faculty of Management and Accounting, College of Farabi, University of Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Masoud</FirstName>
					<LastName>Arianfar</LastName>
<Affiliation>MSc in Information Systems, Faculty of Management and Accounting, College of Farabi, University of Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Seyed Mahdi</FirstName>
					<LastName>Alvani</LastName>
<Affiliation>Prof., Faculty of Management and Accounting, Allameh Tabataba’i University, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Knowledge sharing is perceived as a fundamental process of knowledge management. Individual&#039;s values are among the factors affecting knowledge sharing behavior that have not been investigated before. The developed research model investigated the impacts of individual motivation (Altruism and Reputation) on knowledge sharing behavior considering the moderating role of user&#039;s values. In order to test the research model, Idea City (known as Ideshahr)  has been selected  as one of the prosperous samples of Iranian virtual community with real knowledge sharing behaviors. As a quantitative research, survey method has been used. Structural Equation Modeling was applied to test the model. Based on data from 217 active users in Ideshahr, results showed that altruism and reputation had positive effects on knowledge sharing behavior. Moreover, it has been indicated that values of users had not moderated the relation between altruism/reputation and quality/quantity of knowledge sharing behavior.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Values</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">reputation</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Knowledge Sharing Behavior</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">altruism</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_57366_4e7701f384d51767cc59f58c240e58dd.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
