<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Providing a Framework for E-readiness Assessment and Action for E-Commerce in Ramak Dairy Company in Shiraz</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارائۀ چارچوبی برای ارزیابی آمادگی الکترونیکی و اقدام برای تجارت الکترونیک در شرکت لبنیاتی رامک شیراز</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>811</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>832</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">59955</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2016.59955</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
					<LastName>Mohammadi</LastName>
<Affiliation>Prof., Faculty of Management, Shiraz University, Shiraz, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Farzaneh</FirstName>
					<LastName>Berahmand</LastName>
<Affiliation>MSc. in Industrial Management, Shiraz University, Shiraz, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Payam</FirstName>
					<LastName>Shojaei</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof., Faculty of Management, Shiraz University, Shiraz, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study aimed to provide a framework to assess the e-readiness of Ramak Company in Shiraz. To that end, after reviewing the related literature in the field of e-readiness and selecting the proper model, the model parameters were distributed among experts in the form of a questionnaire, and with the help of fuzzy screening, 49 indicators were finalized. Then, using the combination method of DEMATEL and Analysis of Network process, weight of the indicators was obtained. Finally, e-readiness of the indicators was investigated through proper statistical tests. The analysis indicated that the company had necessary preparation in the following indicators “market share of company” and “compliance with quality of ICT international standards”, “high bandwidth availability” and “diversity of communication channels available”, “quality of national wide ICT infrastructures” and “obstacles of trade investment” and any other observation. By doing the gap analysis, it was found that the dimensions of external environment readiness, the ICT readiness and external environment readiness, respectively had the highest priorities for enforcement action.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">E-commerce</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">e-readiness assessment</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Gap analysis</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Information Technology</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_59955_8295a99663b3bdee0b03dc9f22606608.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
