<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Model for the Acceptance of Cloud Computing Technology Using DEMATEL Technique and System Dynamics Approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارائۀ مدلی پویا برای پذیرش فناوری رایانش ابری با استفاده از تکنیک دیماتل و رویکرد پویایی‌ سیستم</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>93</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>116</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">62762</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2017.228091.1962</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Seyyed Mohammad</FirstName>
					<LastName>Zargar</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof. of Industrial Management, Semnan Branch, Islamic Azad University, Semnan, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Zahra</FirstName>
					<LastName>Shahriari</LastName>
<Affiliation>MSc. in Executive Management, Semnan Branch, Islamic Azad University, Semnan, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Cloud computing is a new method to provide computing resources and increase computing power in organizations. Despite the many benefits this method shares, it has not been universally used because of some obstacles including security issues and has become a concern for IT managers in organization. In this paper, the general definition of cloud computing is presented. In addition, having reviewed previous studies, the researchers identified effective variables on technology acceptance and, especially, cloud computing technology. Then, using DEMATEL technique, the effectiveness and permeability of the variable were determined. The researchers also designed a model to show the existing dynamics in cloud computing technology using system dynamics approach. The validity of the model was confirmed through evaluation methods in dynamics model by using VENSIM software. Finally, based on different conditions of the proposed model, a variety of scenarios were designed. Then, the implementation of these scenarios was simulated within the proposed model. The results showed that any increase in data security, government support and user training can lead to the increase in the adoption and use of cloud computing technology.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Cloud Computing</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">DEMATEL technique</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Information Technology</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">System Dynamics</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Technology Acceptance Model</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_62762_07bbf51b3f5a3dbac05975ac6decc5b7.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
