<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Proposing a Conceptual Framework to Utilize Storytelling Mechanism into Project Management Life Cycle</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارائه چارچوبی مفهومی برای بهره‌گیری از سازوکار داستان‌سرایی در مدیریت چرخه حیات پروژه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>83</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>104</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">36505</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2013.36505</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mahdi</FirstName>
					<LastName>Shami Zanjani</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof. in Information Technology Management, University of Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Narges</FirstName>
					<LastName>Farzaneh Kondori</LastName>
<Affiliation>M.Sc. in Information Technology Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>It is rather difficult to exploit knowledge in project organizations due to their unique characteristics and temporal behavior of activities. Therefore, development of knowledge management capability among projects is accounted for an important source to gain competitive advantage. This paper tries to provide a conceptual framework in order to introduce applications of storytelling as an effective and inexpensive mechanism for projects knowledge management. At first, a conceptual framework was designed including 58 story applications in activities of project life cycle by studying and analyzing the related literature. Then, validation of this conceptual framework was investigated and verified by relevant experts. Finally, application of storytelling was assessed within the projects of Sanam industrial and commercial company, using the framework designed. Analysis of data demonstrates that out of 58 applications introduced, this company benefit from just 28 applications. Research method in this section was survey. According to the available information, this paper is one of the first researches which have adopted to introduce applications of storytelling in the life cycle of project management by providing a conceptual framework. &lt;br /&gt; </Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Mechanism</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Knowledge Management</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">story</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">storytelling</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Project Management Life Cycle</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_36505_ff97121e5102745c7dc5750ccb518d7d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
