<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identifying Functions of Online Community of Practice</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی کارکردهای انجمن‌های خبرگی آنلاین</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>22</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">63293</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2017.236658.2079</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
					<LastName>Hamidizadeh</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof. in Public Administration, Farabi Campus University of Tehran, Qom, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Reza</FirstName>
					<LastName>Tahmasebi</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof. in Human Resources Management, Farabi Campus University of Tehran, Qom, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Atefeh</FirstName>
					<LastName>Zarean Shirvan Deh</LastName>
<Affiliation>MS.c. in Public Administration, Farabi Campus University of Tehran, Qom, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Nowadays, there is a growing trend in the constitution of community of practice (COP) through cell phone communication software. So, studies about COP and its functions seem necessary. In this research, the positive functions of COP have been identified through theme analysis, and then the identified functions have been categorized using exploratory factor analysis. This research has been done in two phases using mixed-method approach. In the qualitative phase, library resources and in the quantitative phase, researcher-made questionnaire were used. In addition, in the qualitative phase, the functions were identified through literature review. The statistical population of the quantitative phase includes employees of public organizations and private firms who are a member of any groups, consisting of their colleagues, on their cell phones using social communication software such as: Telegram, WhatsApp, and Viber. Purposive sampling was used to select the groups and the individuals. 446 individuals, within 19 groups, filled out the questionnaire. 38 main themes have been identified and divided into 6 categories of innovation and problem solving, information and knowledge exchange, collective identity, knowledge ability, continual development, gain and create value.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Communication Software</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Community of practice</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Exploratory Factor Analysis</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Knowledge Management</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Theme Analysis</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_63293_f3bd290c6668de9ad28422ef6221adc6.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Technical and Economic Factors in the Design Model Fuzzy Smart Priority Investment Projects for Industrial: Approach Fuzzy Expert System</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>نقش عوامل فنی و اقتصادی در طراحی مدل هوشمند فازی اولویت‎گذاری پروژه‎های صنعتی: رویکرد سیستم خبرۀ فازی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>23</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>46</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">63625</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2017.230908.1998</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
					<LastName>Rajabzadeh Ghatari</LastName>
<Affiliation>Associate Prof. in Management, Tarbiat Modarres University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Ahmadreza</FirstName>
					<LastName>Ghasemi</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof. of Industrial Management, Farabi Campus University of Tehran, Qom, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Adel</FirstName>
					<LastName>Azar</LastName>
<Affiliation>Prof. in Management, Tarbiat Modarres University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2123-7579</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Rohollah</FirstName>
					<LastName>Hosseini</LastName>
<Affiliation>Instructor of Management, Payame Noor University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This article aims at designing a Fuzzy Expert System that helps select the appropriate industrial investment and prioritize the projects based on credible criteria and international standards in fuzzy environment to reduce the risk of adverse selection where possible. The main objectives of the research issue are optimizing decisions, increasing productivity and reducing investment risk that can ultimately lead to development.This article describes how to design and use fuzzy expert system and indicated the role of technical and economic criteria in selection of industrial projects. In this study, MATLAB (fuzzy inference module system) software was used to analyze the data, fuzzy inputs and outputs, establishment of rules and, ultimately, expert system output and their defuzzification, and the graphical interface. The existence of such a model in addition to helping to improve decision-making will help the development of industry and IndustrialadvancementIn order to validate this study, a case study was done and the comparison of the output of the proposed system with the experts’ opinions   approved the validity of our system. The system helps to prioritize and select industrial projects and provides recommendations in more detailed.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">economic factors</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Fuzzy Expert System</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Fuzzy logic</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Knowledge base</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Technical Factors</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_63625_855f61fb9d7f7553239da065322f5e02.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Developing Modernization Strategy for CORE Banking Systems among Iran’s Commercial Banks (Case Study: One of the Commercial Banks of Iran)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تدوین استراتژی نوسازی سامانه‌های بانکداری متمرکز در بانک‌های تجاری کشور (مطالعۀ موردی: یکی از بانک‌های تجارتی کشور)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>47</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>68</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">62787</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2017.215356.1799</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
					<LastName>Rezaeian</LastName>
<Affiliation>Prof. in Public Administration, Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Sajad</FirstName>
					<LastName>Shokuhyar</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof. of IT Management, Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Seyed Jafar</FirstName>
					<LastName>Mortazavian Farsani</LastName>
<Affiliation>MSc. of IT Management, Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>15</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>After more than two decades of the emergence of CORE banking systems in Iran, their inefficiency and lack of accountability to the needs of the banks have become evident. Hence, modernization of CORE banking systems is one of the most serious concerns of the banks&#039; managers. All the customers of the banks can access the services of these systems through online and 7*24 channels such as ATMs, PoS and / or Internet. Even the slightest interruption in the provision of these services can because banks face serious crises; therefore, choosing the right strategy for modernization is of utmost importance. The researcher could identify internal and external factors affecting modernization by distributing a questionnaire among banks&#039; senior managers and experts. Afterwards, we used another questionnaire to identify internal and external factors affecting the target bank. Having formed the matrixes of IFE and EFE and completed the questionnaire, the related strengths, weaknesses, opportunities and threats were identified. Strategies were explained based on SWOT method, then the selected strategies were ranked by weighting of the indices with the help of AHP method using QSPM method. Finally, the strategy with the highest rank was determined as the most appropriate strategy for modernization in the target bank.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">AHP method</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">CORE banking</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">QSPM method</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Strategy planning</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">SWOT method</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_62787_5bea921765f908976f11069755754555.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Applying High-level Agreement Ensemble Classification Voting Techniques to Distinguish Inflammatory Bowel Disease</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>به‎‎کارگیری تکنیک‎های دسته‎بندی ترکیبی رأی‎گیری با توافق سطح بالا برای تفکیک بیماری التهاب روده</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>69</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>92</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">63208</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2017.233609.2043</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Nayere</FirstName>
					<LastName>Zaghari</LastName>
<Affiliation>Ph.D. Candidate, Department of Computer Engineering, Shahr-e-Qods Branch, Islamic Azad University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Rahil</FirstName>
					<LastName>Hosseini</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof, Department of Computer engineering, Shahr-e-Qods Branch, Islamic Azad University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Due to the complexity of medical decisions, there is a growing interest in the application of intelligence systems to support these decisions. In this paper, accordingly, the potential of several algorithms such as K Nearest Neighbor, Support Vector Machine, Random Forest, Naive Bayes, and Decision Tree was used to create an ensemble classification. Then, to obtain the voting result, high level agreement voting was used to evaluate the performance and make prediction. According to the involvement of body organs with this disease, the problem of diagnosing and differentiating various types of bowl inflammation was investigated. We should mention that higher prediction accuracy was obtained using the proposed model. The results and the comparisons of these methods showed that the proposed model indicates the highest prediction accuracy which is 98%. In the final step, the proposed model was evaluated applying the receiver operating characteristic curve model (ROC), and the area under the curve (AUC) was calculated.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Ensemble classification algorithms</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">High-level agreement voting algorithm</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Inflammatory bowel disease</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Noise detection</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ROC Curve</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_63208_e9adaea49c600dd42b1b289f79c1a2f9.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Model for the Acceptance of Cloud Computing Technology Using DEMATEL Technique and System Dynamics Approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارائۀ مدلی پویا برای پذیرش فناوری رایانش ابری با استفاده از تکنیک دیماتل و رویکرد پویایی‌ سیستم</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>93</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>116</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">62762</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2017.228091.1962</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Seyyed Mohammad</FirstName>
					<LastName>Zargar</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof. of Industrial Management, Semnan Branch, Islamic Azad University, Semnan, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Zahra</FirstName>
					<LastName>Shahriari</LastName>
<Affiliation>MSc. in Executive Management, Semnan Branch, Islamic Azad University, Semnan, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Cloud computing is a new method to provide computing resources and increase computing power in organizations. Despite the many benefits this method shares, it has not been universally used because of some obstacles including security issues and has become a concern for IT managers in organization. In this paper, the general definition of cloud computing is presented. In addition, having reviewed previous studies, the researchers identified effective variables on technology acceptance and, especially, cloud computing technology. Then, using DEMATEL technique, the effectiveness and permeability of the variable were determined. The researchers also designed a model to show the existing dynamics in cloud computing technology using system dynamics approach. The validity of the model was confirmed through evaluation methods in dynamics model by using VENSIM software. Finally, based on different conditions of the proposed model, a variety of scenarios were designed. Then, the implementation of these scenarios was simulated within the proposed model. The results showed that any increase in data security, government support and user training can lead to the increase in the adoption and use of cloud computing technology.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Cloud Computing</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">DEMATEL technique</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Information Technology</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">System Dynamics</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Technology Acceptance Model</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_62762_07bbf51b3f5a3dbac05975ac6decc5b7.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Deriving and Comparing Hierarchical Value Map for a Highly Involved Product in Virtual and Traditional Market</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>استخراج و مقایسۀ نقشۀ سلسله‎مراتبی ارزش برای یک محصول با درگیری بالا در فروشگاه‎های‌ مجازی و سنتی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>117</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>134</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">63626</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2017.239014.2120</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Shahriar</FirstName>
					<LastName>Azizi</LastName>
<Affiliation>Associate Prof. in Business Management, Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Seyed Milad</FirstName>
					<LastName>Hosseini</LastName>
<Affiliation>MSc. Student in Business Management, University of Shahid Beheshti, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study aims to outline the reasons behind the behavior of those customers buying laptop from virtual and traditional market, through deriving hierarchical value map (HVM) using means-end theory. Data was gathered from 40 students using laddering interview. Twenty students had online shopping experiences and had more trust to E-stores and twenty others had more trust and experience buying from traditional stores. Using content analysis, 6 attributes, 13 consequences, and 5 values for the online stores, and 7 attributes, 16 consequences and 5 values for the traditional store were derived. At the next step aggregated Hierarchical Value Map (HVM) was depicted for each market. Regarding the virtual store map, the following linkage “possibility of creating a personal profile- customization- unique offers- discount-being valuable” and regarding the traditional value map the following links “bargaining- influencing the price- economization- putting resources to other use- more comfort” have shown to have the most associations among the interviewees.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Hierarchical value map</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">High-involvement</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Laddering technique</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Means- end theory</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Virtual and traditional store</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_63626_d65ee8fe9bb7eb3995fd3fa930ca3008.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Presenting a Framework for Conceptualizing Knowledge Management Office</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارائۀ چارچوبی برای مفهوم‌سازی دفتر مدیریت دانش</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>135</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>158</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">63005</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2017.233451.2038</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Narges</FirstName>
					<LastName>Farzaneh</LastName>
<Affiliation>Ph.D. Candidate in IT Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mehdi</FirstName>
					<LastName>Shamizanjani</LastName>
<Affiliation>Associate Prof. in IT, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Amir</FirstName>
					<LastName>Manian</LastName>
<Affiliation>Prof. in IT, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Alireza</FirstName>
					<LastName>Hasanzadeh</LastName>
<Affiliation>Associate Prof. in IT, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Designing an effective structure for knowledge management is one of the critical factors for its success in the organization. Structuring to KM and identifying the experts of this field in the structure of the organization is necessary to achieve the sustained and continuous benefits of knowledge management. This paper deals with the conceptualizing of knowledge management office as the organizational structure for effective management of knowledge. For this purpose, Meta-synthesize methodology was adopted. From 198 sources founded, 12 articles were consistent with accepted standards. As a result of combining the findings, concept of knowledge management office was figured with 54 codes, 12 concepts in the four themes including purpose (Strategic and Functional), structure (Centralized and Decentralized and Mixed), function (Strategies, Processes and Mechanisms) and role (KM Committee, CKO, knowledge manager, Knowledge Representative). Organizations can use the results of this study to establish an appropriate structure of knowledge management. According to research, any article was not found by the researchers that have has this integrity and methodology. So, this paper has innovation.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Chief Knowledge Officer</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Conceptualization</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Knowledge Governance</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Knowledge Management Office</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Knowledge Management Structure</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_63005_e303a35cf87de7b3b88242f909bac5bb.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>How to Create Business Value through Information Technology (A Case Study on Automotive Production)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>چگونگی ایجاد ارزش کسب‎وکار از طریق فناوری اطلاعات (مطالعۀ موردی در تولید خودرو)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>159</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>184</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">63206</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2017.239098.2121</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Kamran</FirstName>
					<LastName>Feizi</LastName>
<Affiliation>Prof. in IT Management, Allameh Tabataba’I University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mahdi</FirstName>
					<LastName>Mahmoudsalehi</LastName>
<Affiliation>PhD. Candidate in IT Management, Allameh Tabataba’I University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mohammad Taghi</FirstName>
					<LastName>Taghavi Fard</LastName>
<Affiliation>Associate Prof. in IT Management, Allameh Tabataba’I University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Iman</FirstName>
					<LastName>Raeesi Vanani</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof. in IT Management, Allameh Tabataba’I University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study aimed at designing information technology business value model in order to explain the value of information technology in business and evaluate information technology contribution in organization function. For the purpose of a comprehensive analysis of the subject using qualitative data, the research method was set to be mixed method focusing on qualitative sequential design. The first stage of the research strategy was an exploratory single case study and for the second phase, the researchers used focus groups design. Saipa Corporation, one of the most famous firms in Iranian automotive industry, was selected as the case. The varied qualitative date were gathered through interview, document review and observation methods and were analyzed afterwards. Ultimately, the findings of the study highlighted the items and dimensions of information technology business value. This model is composed of the relationship between different dimensions of the theoretical models regarding and the share of information technology in building a business. In order to ensure research generalizability, the results of the research were compared with those in the literature review and the theoretic adequacy of the proposed framework was confirmed.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Business IT contribution</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">IT business value</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">IT contribution in automotive production</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">IT productivity</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">IT Value</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_63206_159be7e2f9e705912e83c1d5b312e6cc.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigating the Mediating Role of Knowledge Sharing in the Relationship between Intellectual Capital and Organizational Innovation (A Case Study of Iranian Software Companies)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی نقش میانجی تسهیم دانش در رابطۀ بین سرمایۀ فکری و نوآوری سازمانی (مطالعۀ موردی: شرکت‌های نرم‌افزاری ایران)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>185</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>208</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">62729</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2017.234557.2061</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Abdolhossein</FirstName>
					<LastName>Karampoor</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof., in Management, Shiraz University, Shiraz, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نازنین</FirstName>
					<LastName>مسعودی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه غیر انتفاعی زند</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Abolghasem</FirstName>
					<LastName>Ebrahimi</LastName>
<Affiliation>Associate Prof. in Management, Shiraz University, Shiraz, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;span&gt;This study is to evaluate the effect of intellectual capital and knowledge sharing on organizational innovation, based on structural equation modeling.30 software companies located in Tehran were selected by cluster sampling and the questionnaires were distributed among them. The reliability and validity of the questionnaire were confirmed using Cronbach&#039;s alpha and confirmatory factor analysis. Then, data analysis was conducted based on structural equation modeling using LISREL software. The findings suggested that intellectual capital has a positive and significant effect on knowledge sharing (0.27= β) and on organizational innovation (0.48 = β). In addition, the findings indicated that knowledge sharing has a positive impact on organizational innovation (p = 0.30). On the other hand, the findings suggested that knowledge sharing plays a mediating role in the relationship between intellectual capital and organizational innovation. Besides, intellectual capital not only has a direct impact on innovation through knowledge sharing, it also has an indirect influence on organizational innovation.&lt;/span&gt;</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Intellectual Capital</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">knowledge sharing</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Organizational Innovation</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">relational capital</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Structural Capital</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_62729_8296bcf7f61aeb787c83254eef370b6c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Impact of Business Intelligence (BI) Competence on Customer Relationship Management (CRM) Process: An Empirical Investigation of the Banking Industry</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر شایستگی‌ هوش تجاری بر فرایند مدیریت ارتباط با مشتری: مطالعۀ تجربی در صنعت بانکداری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>209</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>234</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">63084</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2017.237995.2105</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
					<LastName>Mortezaei</LastName>
<Affiliation>MSc. in Industrial Engineering, Fouman Faculty of Engineering Campus, University of Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mohamad Sadegh</FirstName>
					<LastName>Sangari</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof., Fouman Faculty of Engineering Campus, University of Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Salman</FirstName>
					<LastName>Nazari-Shirkouhi</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof., Fouman Faculty of Engineering Campus, University of Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Jafar</FirstName>
					<LastName>Razmi</LastName>
<Affiliation>School of Industrial and Systems Engineering, College of Engineering, University of Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Nowadays, establishing long-term and effective relationships with customers is a key factor in understanding customers’ needs and preferences and achieving competitive advantage. In addition, companies are facing with a growing need for information and analytical knowledge about their customers, market, competitors, organizational environment, and other factors affecting their business. Business intelligence has been considered as a response to this need. The purpose of this study is to investigate the role of business intelligence competence in improving customer relationship management process. Based on the literature review and the competence – capability relationship paradigm, a conceptual model was developed comprising of different dimensions of business intelligence competence and customer relationship management processes. The data were collected from the banking sector and partial least squares structural equation modelling was employed for data analysis. Empirical results showed that organizational business intelligence competence, comprising of managerial, technical, and cultural competence, has a significantly positive impact on enhancing capabilities of customer relationship management process including initiation, maintenance, and termination of the relationship.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Business Intelligence Competence</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Competence – Capability Relationship</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Customer relationship management</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Structural Equation Modeling</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_63084_8f5c1e0c4516b5dd66788e9df80bf5b1.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Factors Affecting the Success of a Professional-specialized Social Network Site: Findings of a Qualitative Study in Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>عوامل مؤثر بر موفقیت شبکۀ اجتماعی حرفه‌ای ـ ‌تخصصی: یافته‌های مطالعۀ کیفی در ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>235</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>258</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">63205</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2017.234259.2055</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Morteza</FirstName>
					<LastName>Nabi-Meybodi</LastName>
<Affiliation>Ph.D. Candidate in IT Management, Iranian Research Institute for Information Science and Technology (IranDoc), Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Sirous</FirstName>
					<LastName>Alidousti</LastName>
<Affiliation>Associate Prof. in IT Management, Iranian Research Institute for Information Science and Technology (IranDoc), Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Maryam</FirstName>
					<LastName>Nazari</LastName>
<Affiliation>Ph.D. in Educational Informatics, Consultant, Iranian Research Institute for Information Science and Technology (IranDoc), Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Professional-specialized social network sites are a form of emerging online communities hosting academic users and scientific contents. Indeed, the success of these social networks requires studies that would provide the stakeholders with constructive and practical knowledge on the factors that may affect the success of these social networks. Despite the importance of the issue, literature review shows that the factors affecting the success of these networks have not been studied much. Therefore, this case study aimed to identify and extract the main factors affecting the success of a professional-specialized social network site using a qualitative approach with a focus on the experience of ANJOMAN, a social network in Iran, policy makers and users. According to the findings, the policy makers classified the main factors affecting the success of a social network into the following six categories: the society readiness to accept this idea, owner&#039;s credit, management support, users&#039; motivation, website effectiveness, and management and control system efficiency. Moreover, the users believed that these effective factors can be placed into four categories: individual motivation, the establishment of efficient communication, content dynamism, and website attractiveness. These factors can lead to the implementation of more comprehensive policies and decisions. Accordingly, users will be more motivated to attend and participate in such social networks.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Policy maker</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Professional-specialized social network site</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Qualitative study</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Success factors</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">User</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_63205_5c09393112a60ed5f6ab8fafa7730936.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
