<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identifying and Ranking the Effective Factors on Successful Implementation of Social Commerce in Iran, Using AHP Fuzzy</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی و رتبه‌بندی عوامل موثر بر موفقیت پیاده‌سازی تجارت اجتماعی در ایران با استفاده از AHP فازی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>295</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>314</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">57231</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2016.57231</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Zahra</FirstName>
					<LastName>Rahimi</LastName>
<Affiliation>MSc. Student of Electronic Commerce, Faculty of Computer and Information Technology Engineering, Qazvin Islamic Azad University, Qazvin, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Neda</FirstName>
					<LastName>Abdolvand</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant IT Manager, Faculty of Social and Economics Sciences, Al-Zahra University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Social commerce has been introduced as a new approach to increase sales, number of customers and reduce marketing expenditures. This approach is a combination of business, communication between people, as well as communicative and informative technologies based on web 2.0 Its achievement originated from different factors relied on business, individuals, culture, and technology. These factors have been primarily identified on the basis of library researches and classified into six infrastructural groups including:  &lt;strong&gt;technical, economical and human resources, cultural, rules governing the countries, style of management&lt;/strong&gt;, and business. Then, it identified priority of the factors by using the fuzzy analytic hierarchy process (AHP). Innovation of this research was to extract a comprehensive list of factors and to prioritize them based on specific conditions in Iran.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">AHP Fuzzy</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">E-commerce</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Social commerce</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">social networks</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Success factors</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_57231_a25fe2af6687024b0c36f57279ae09a4.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
