<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigating the Relationship between Students’ Strategic Thinking Skills and Information Seeking Behavior among Undergraduate Students of Management in University of Tehran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی رابطۀ بین تفکر استراتژیک و رفتار جست‎وجوی اطلاعات دانشجویان مقطع کارشناسی دانشکدۀ مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>259</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>282</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">65660</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2018.248131.2262</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mohammad</FirstName>
					<LastName>Abooyee Ardakan</LastName>
<Affiliation>Associate Prof. in Public Administration, Faculty of Management, Tehran University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Fatemeh</FirstName>
					<LastName>Ghadyani</LastName>
<Affiliation>MA in Media Management, Faculty of Management, Tehran University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Tahereh</FirstName>
					<LastName>Alidadi</LastName>
<Affiliation>MA in Urban Management, Faculty of Management, Tehran University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study aims to consider the relationship between undergraduate management students’ strategic thinkingskills and their information seeking behaviors. The statistical population for this study was 400 undergraduate students of management faculty in University of Tehran and the sample size was calculated to be 201 students using Cookran formula. In this study, survey methodology was applied and the data were analyzed using structural equation modeling, Pearson correlation, and multiple regression tests. Based on Pisapia’s model of strategic thinking and ACRL model of information seeking behavior , the results indicated that in among the different dimensions of strategic thinking, reframing thinking  skill (leading to the formation of new values and  getting away from the old clichés) has caused the highest change unit in information seeking behavior.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Information seeking behavior</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Reflection thinking</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Reframing thinking</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Strategic thinking</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Systems thinking</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_65660_c60ba8ae50610a14ba3c7c5342668a04.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
