<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Classification of Internet banking customers using data mining algorithms</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طبقه‌بندی مشتریان اینترنت‌بانک با کمک الگوریتم‌های داده‌کاوی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>71</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>90</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">50051</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2014.50051</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Reza</FirstName>
					<LastName>Radfar</LastName>
<Affiliation>Associate Prof., Faculty of Management and Economics, Science and Research Branch Islamic Azad University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Navid</FirstName>
					<LastName>Nezafati</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof., Faculty of Management and Accounting, Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Saeid</FirstName>
					<LastName>Yousefi Asli</LastName>
<Affiliation>MSc. in Information Technology Management, Azad University, E Campus, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>26</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Classifying customers using data mining algorithms, enables banks to keep old customers loyality while attracting new ones. Using decision tree as a data mining technique, we can optimize customer classification provided that the appropriate decision tree is selected. In this article we have presented an appropriate model to classify customers who use internet banking service. The model is developed based on CRISP-DM standard and we have used real data of Sina bank’s Internet bank. In compare to other decision trees, ours is based on both optimization and accuracy factors that recognizes new potential internet banking customers using a three level classification, which is low/medium and high. This is a practical, documentary-based research. Mining customer rules enables managers to make policies based on found out patterns in order to have a better perception of what customers really desire.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Data Mining</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Decision Tree</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Classification</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">E-Banking</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_50051_267cbcc51cdf0588c44d046e3d143039.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
