<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Evaluation of E-Commerce Security using Shannon Entropy &amp; Dempster-Shafer (DS) theory</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی سطح امنیت در تجارت الکترونیک با استفاده از آنتروپی شانون و تئوری دمپستر.شافر</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>77</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>100</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">55715</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2016.55715</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Maryam</FirstName>
					<LastName>Hajmalek</LastName>
<Affiliation>MSc., In Business Administration International Marketing, Department of Economics and   Business Administration, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad (FUM), Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Ahmad</FirstName>
					<LastName>Tavakoli</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof., Faculty of Management Department, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study is to develop a method and a structure which enable us to evaluate security in e-commerce in different companies by various experts. In this study, Shannon entropy was placed along with Dempster- Shafer theory so that the ultimate level of security could be measured. Considering the fact that in the present study collecting data is based on the decision of a team of experts, data collection procedures were conducted in two phases; in the first phase, data related to determining the weight of measures were collected and in the second phase, the data about the security level of criteria were collected through interview and using a decision team in four commercial companies in Mashhad who were willing to cooperate. Then, the importance of security measures in relation to each other, security level of each measure and the overall level of security in this commercial company were determined. The final results showed that the overall level of security for the three companies is high and one is medium.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Dempster–Shafer</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">E-commerce</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">security</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Shannon-entropy</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_55715_e563b9e867511ee2531610b140a95628.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
