<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Prioritizing Intangible Assets in developing Competitive Advantage through the Process of Network Analysis: The Case of Information Technology Private Corporations</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اولویت‌بندی گزینه‌های سرمایۀ نامشهود در تدوین مزیت رقابتی از طریق فرایند تحلیل شبکه‌ای (مطالعۀ موردی: شرکت‌های خصوصی در حوزۀ فناوری اطلاعات)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>449</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>476</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">62018</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2017.62018</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Hamza</FirstName>
					<LastName>Khastar</LastName>
<Affiliation>Assistant Prof., Faculty of Management, Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mohammad Reza</FirstName>
					<LastName>Sheikhattar</LastName>
<Affiliation>MSc. In Information Technology Management, Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mohammad</FirstName>
					<LastName>Ghorbanifar</LastName>
<Affiliation>Ph.D. Candidate in Corporate Entrepreneurship, Islamic Azad University, Qazvin Branch, Qazvin, Iran</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The aim of this study is to identify and rank the most effective elements to create sustainable competitive advantage in information technology companies. In this study, with the help of a couple of experts from three information technology organizations, the most important intangible assets (intellectual capital, social capital and spiritual capital) were identified as alternatives to the ranking of competitive advantage. Having reviewed the related literature and developed a panel of expertise, 16 sub-options extracted for the intellectual, social and spiritual capital. Five criteria of price, support, design, image and quality were taken into account for competitive advantage and the ranking of alternatives based on these criteria was carried out through the process of network analysis. The results of the network analysis showed that compared to social and spiritual capital, intellectual capital can have a more important role in creating competitive advantage in IT companies. Besides, regarding rating of sub-options, human capital ranked the highest in gaining the competitive advantage. Interface element, vision-orientation/value- orientation ​​and relational/client capital were respectively the next ranks in making sustainable competitive advantage</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Competitiveness advantage</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Intellectual Capital</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">network analysis</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Social capital</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Spiritual Capital</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_62018_46f9e17b4c713188a97f2932ecb8c332.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
