<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>Journal of Information Technology Management</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5893</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identify factors affecting the development and use of electronic services in the tourism industry (studied Ardebil)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر گسترش و استفاده از خدمات الکترونیک در صنعت گردشگری (موردمطالعه: استان اردبیل)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>845</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>864</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">53829</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jitm.2015.53829</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Vahide</FirstName>
					<LastName>Alipour</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mohammad</FirstName>
					<LastName>Bashukouh</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>Mitra</FirstName>
					<LastName>Shekasteband</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>26</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present study aimed identifies factors affecting the development and use of electronic services in the tourism industry. Population of the study of those tourists who have traveled in April 2013 in the city of Ardabil. The population sample of 384 randomly selected. To gather data, researchers used a combination of questionnaires and questionnaire containing 51 questions was designed. The validity and reliability of the variables considered in the study as it was very good. Research questions investigated through descriptive and inferential statistics were performed using SPSS, Lisrel. The results of the analysis show that variable behavioral intention to make use of the technology has 84% rate, technology acceptance model it 79% of the impact, trust has 86 percent of the impact and the dissemination of innovation has a 67 percent impact on the plan to use the electronic services. In the meantime the trust of the organization and trust of the technology variables impact among other factors is more.</Abstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Tourism</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">e-tourism</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">electronic services</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">factor analysi</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jitm.ut.ac.ir/article_53829_12b0483aef4e13a55c2dcbec8907d878.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
