﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>61</Volume><Issue>1-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2018</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Business Performance Models based on Intellectual Capital Case Study: Companies Located in Zanjan Industrial Town</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>مدل عملکرد تجاری مبتنی بر سرمایه فکری(سرمایه انسانی، ساختاری و رابطه ای)  مطالعه موردی : شرکت های واقع درشهرک صنعتی زنجان</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>167</FirstPage><LastPage>180</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محمدرضا</FirstName><LastName>زاهدی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه مالک اشتر</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>پیمان</FirstName><LastName>اخوان</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه </Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></History><Abstract>The aim of this study is the effect of Intellectual Capital components(human capital, relation capital, structural capital) on each other and also the relationship of these components on Business Performance. The study population were located in the industrial city of Zanjan and the means of data collection was Bontis questionnairy which have been used first in Malaysia, Canada and Jordan. Data analysis was performed by a software called Visual PLC. The results showed that the structrual equation model which has been used, is a strong theoretical model for the effect of intellectual capital (human capital, structural capital and relational capital) on organization’s business performance. The results of study showed that by changing in human capital, the customer capital would be changed directly and improved, but would not be able to change structuaral capital.
The results of the analysis showed that all aspects of intellectual capital except human capital and structural capital have positive and significant relationship to each other and Finally, the structural capital has a significantly positive effect on the business performance. On the other hand, the results of this study showed that human capital has a positive and significant relationship with structural capital.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف اين مقاله بررسي تاثیر اجزای سرمایه فکری شامل سرمایه انسانی، سرمایه مشتری، سرمایه ساختاری بر هم و همچنین ارتباط این سه جزء با عملکرد تجاری مي باشد. جامعه آماری مورد مطالعه شرکت های واقع در شهرک صنعتی زنجان و ابزار جمع آوری اطلاعات، پرسشنامه بنتیس که ابتدا در کشورهای مالزی و کانادا و اردن استفاده شده است، می باشد. داده ها توسط نرم افزاری به نام ويژوال پي ال اس مورد تجزيه و تحليل قرار گرفت. نتايج نشان داد كه مدل معادلات ساختاري به كار گرفته شده، يك مدل نظري قوي براي تاثیر سرمایه فکری(سرمایه انسانی، ساختاری، رابطه ای) بر عملکرد تجاری سازمان مي باشد. نتایج تحقیق نشان داد که می توان از طریق تغییر در سرمایه انسانی، به طور مستقیم سرمایه مشتری را تغییر و بهبود داد. همچنین تغییردر سرمایه ساختاری از طریق سرمایه انسانی مقدور نبوده و نیز می توان بیان داشت که تغییر سرمایه ساختاری موجب تغییر در سرمایه مشتری می گردد. از سوی دیگر همه این تغییرات، موجبات تغییر و بهبود عملکرد تجاری را فراهم خواهد نمود. نتايج حاصل از تجزيه و تحليل نشان داد كه همه ابعاد سرمایه فکری به جز سرمایه انسانی و سرمایه ساختاری روابط معنادار و مثبتی با هم دارند و نهایتا سرمایه ساختاری نیز تاثیر مثبت و معناداری بر عملکرد تجاری اعمال نموده است. از سوي ديگر، نتايج اين تحقيق نشان داد كه سرمایه انسانی رابطه مثبت و معناداری با سرمایه ساختاری دارد. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سرمایه فکری، سرمایه انسانی، سرمایه ساختاری، سرمایه رابطه ای، عملکرد تجاری.</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13970711164717-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>