﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>57</Volume><Issue>3-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Critical Success Factors Analyses in Sustainable Supply Chain Implementation with ISM Approach (Case Study: Automotive Industry)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تحلیل عوامل کلیدی موفقیت در پیاده‌سازی زنجیره تأمین پایدار با رویکرد مدل‌سازی ساختاری تفسیری (مطالعه موردی در صنعت خودرو)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>171</FirstPage><LastPage>188</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>فرناز </FirstName><LastName>برزین پور</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>ناصر</FirstName><LastName>غقوری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>هادی</FirstName><LastName>صاحبی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day></History><Abstract>In recently years, the importance of environmental and social performances of industries beside their economic performance resulted in formation of a new concept and approach that is named sustainability. In today’s competitive world, different industries to achieve a competitive advantage and maintain their survival, needs to move towards achieving sustainability approach. The main problem is that, the implementation of this approach is simply not possible, and there are several barriers in this way. To deal with this, need to identify and understand the critical success factors. This study aimed to identify and analysis the critical success factors in implementation of sustainable supply chain management in the automotive industry. This paper proposes an interpretive structural modeling (ISM) approach to develop a structural model for evaluating the influential factors among recognized factors. After literature review, the 16 factors based on experts opinions have been selected. In presented research results, the factor of “top management commitment and support” is identified as the most effective and the factor of “Knowledge of competitive advantage” is identified as the most dependent critical success factor.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در طول سال‌های اخیر، اهمیت عملکردهای زیست محیطی و اجتماعی صنایع در کنار عملکرد اقتصادی آن‌ها باعث شکل‌گیری رویکرد و مفهوم جدیدی با عنوان  پایداری گردیده است. در دنیای رقابتی کنونی، صنایع مختلف، هر یک برای دستیابی به مزیت رقابتی و حفظ و بقای خود، نیازمند حرکت به‌سوی رویکرد پایداری هستند. مسأله اساسی این است که اجرای این رویکرد به‌سادگی امکان‌پذیر نبوده و در این راه موانع متعددی وجود دارد. بر این اساس، جهت رفع آن‌ها نیاز به شناسایی و آگاهی از عوامل کلیدی موفقیت در این زمینه است. هدف از این تحقیق شناسایی و تحلیل عوامل کلیدی موفقیت در پیاده‌سازی مدیریت زنجیره تأمین پایدار در صنعت خودرو است. تحقیق حاضر، رویکرد مدل‌سازی ساختاری تفسیری را جهت ایجاد مدلی ساختاری از عوامل کلیدی موفقیت، ارائه می‌دهد. پس از مرور ادبیات موضوع، تعداد 16 عامل کلیدی موفقیت بر اساس نظرات خبرگان و متخصصان تأیید نهایی گردیده‌اند. در میان این عوامل، در نتایج نهایی عامل«حمایت، تعهد و پشتیبانی مدیریت ارشد» به عنوان مهم‌ترین و تأثیرگذارترین و عامل«آگاهی از مزیت‌های رقابتی» به عنوان وابسته‌ترین عامل کلیدی موفقیت در پیاده‌سازی مدیریت زنجیره تأمین پایدار شناخته شده‌اند.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مدیریت زنجیره تأمین پایدار</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
عوامل کلیدی موفقیت</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدل‌سازی ساختاری تفسیری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
صنعت خودروسازی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/1396120218183480955-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>