﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>61</Volume><Issue>1-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2018</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Identify knowledge Intensive Business Services of Qom Water and Wastewater</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>شناسایی خدمات دانشی شرکت آب و فاضلاب استان قم </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>17</FirstPage><LastPage>34</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مریم</FirstName><LastName>قلی زاده</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد علی</FirstName><LastName>سرلک</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></History><Abstract>The purpose of this study was to identify knowledge Intensive Business Services of Qom Water and Wastewater Company. In this Delphi study, after reviewing previous research and examining the upstream documentation and infrastructure at ABFA, the areas of knowledge associated with a description of business services were identified. The results of data analysis showed that the areas of knowledge creation, upgrading and development of water and wastewater facilities, center of supervision, operation and maintenance of facilities, sales and customer service to be considered as a top priority and supply and support management, human resources management, management Financing, partner relationship management, developing management systems for review were the second priority. The processes and knowledge activities of each field were also identified and presented in separate business services.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">این پژوهش با هدف شناسایی خدمات دانشی شرکت آب و فاضلاب استان قم انجام شد. در این پژوهش که به روش دلفی انجام شد، پس از مرور پژوهش‌های پیشین‌ و بررسی اسناد بالادستی و زیرساخت‌های موجود در شرکت آبفا قم، حوزه‌های دانشی به همراه خدمات کسب و کار هر حوزه  شناسایی گردید .نتایج حاصل از تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها نشان داد که حوزه‌های دانشی ایجاد، بهسازی و توسعه تاسیسات آب و فاصلاب ، راهبری، بهره‌برداری و نگهداشت تاسیسات ، فروش و خدمات مشترکین  جهت بررسی به عنوان اولویت اول و مدیریت تامین و پشتیبانی، مدیریت منابع انسانی، مدیریت و تامین منابع مالی، مدیریت ارتباطات با ذی‌نفعان، توسعه سیستم‌های مدیریتی جهت بررسی در اولویت دوم قرار گرفت. همچنین فرایندها و فعالیت‌های دانشی هر حوزه به تفکیک خدمات کسب وکار شناسایی و ارائه شد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">خدمات کسب و کار،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 خدمات کسب و کار دانش‎بنیان(کیبس)،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 فرایند،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 فعالیت</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13980630192376-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>