﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>49</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Applied Science pathology training institutions skill Gilan province Tuesday ramifications approach and the Analytic Hierarchy Process( AHP)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>آسیب شناسی دوره های آموزشی موسسات جامع علمی کاربردی مهارت استان گیلان با رویکرد سه شاخگی و  به روش تحلیل  سلسله مراتبی AHP))</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName><LastName>المئی</LastName><Affiliation>دانش آموخته دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مهناز </FirstName><LastName>همتی نوعدوست گیلانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>رقیه </FirstName><LastName>یوسف نژاد لزرجانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد تهران واحد الکترونیکی</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></History><Abstract>In a society tailored to their circumstances, culture, growth and decline with a variety of diversions and problems facing a damaging effect on the development of the society. Understanding these factors can pave the path of society towards progress and interaction, so that in addition to understanding their function and prevent the continuation of the practice of offering solutions to the community health. In particular education and training leading to employment, such as science, alongside acts like the University of Applied Sciences is not exempt from this. In the meantime, effective training that leads to the target and output is beneficial to society, so we are going to achieve this important come the problems facing education. The research was conducted with the help of experts, a questionnaire was designed after consecutive sessions and then clinched the variables that affect its validity and reliability was determined. Cronbach's alpha coefficient is 0.831, which has demonstrated the reliability of Likert type and weight them using analytic hierarchy in paired comparison questionnaire (Questionnaire 2) and index vulnerable, to prioritize and to the manager to decide the was. Recommended to use this hybrid model for other teaching institutions</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در جامعه‌ای متناسب با شرایط خود ، فرهنگ، رشد و انحطاط خود با انواعی از انحرافات و مشکلات روبروست که تاثیرات مخربی روی فرآیند ترقی آن جامعه دارد. شناخت چنین عواملی می‌تواند مسیر حرکت جامعه را بسوی ترقی و تعامل هموار سازد، بطوری که علاوه بر درک عمل آنها و جلوگیری از تداوم آن عمل با ارائه راه حل هایی به سلامت جامعه کمک نماید. آموزش و بالاخص آموزش منجر به  اشتغال همانند علم در کنار عمل مانند دانشگاه علمی کاربردی از این امر مستثنی نیست. در این بین آموزشی موثر است که منجر به هدف  و بازده مفید برای جامعه گردد، لذا برآنیم تا با رفع مشکلات  پیش روی آموزش به این مهم نائل آییم. دراین پژوهش که به کمک خبرگان انجام شد، پس از جلسات متوالی پرسشنامه ای طراحی و پس از مسجل شدن روایی و پایایی آن  شاخص های موثر را مشخص شد. ضریب آلفای کرونباخ  نیز 0.831گردیده که نشان از پایایی پرسشنامه اول با طیف لیکرت دارد و وزن آنها را به کمک تحلیل سلسله مراتبی در پرسشنامه مقایسات زوجی (پرسشنامه شماره2) یافته و شاخص های آسیب پذیر، اولویت بندی و در اختیار مدیر برای تصمیم گیری قرار گرفت. پیشنهاد می گردد از این مدل ترکیبی برای سایر موسسات آموزشی استفاده گردد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">آسیب شناسی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
سه  شاخگی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تحلیل سلسله مراتبی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
جامع علمی کاربردی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139508262323223977-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>