﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>61</Volume><Issue>1-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2018</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Explaining the legal framework of the constitution and the law of civil services management decisions N.J.I.I</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تبیین ساختار حقوقی تصمیم گیری ن.ج.ا.ا در قانون اساسی و قانون مدیریت خدمات کشوری</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>73</FirstPage><LastPage>80</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>حمیدرضا</FirstName><LastName>قاسمی بنابری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>ابراهیم</FirstName><LastName>عزیزی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day></History><Abstract>One of the topics of the day in each period of the formation and implementation of decisions, or in other words the legal decisions are enforced. What is important at this time is the rest of the structure and the legal system decisions. As a director in the government know what decision-making authority and support his decisions or materials which legal principles. Legal principles in documents for the implementation of decisions is better because these decisions will find strong support law enforcement aspects better. One of the challenges facing government managers, particularly managers not familiar with the law and legal mechanisms. Therefore, this article examines the legal principles and legal structure of decision analysis methods are discussed. Constitution and management of the civil service laws that assessed and eventually decide on the model law has been proposed. </Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">یکی از مباحث روز در هر دوره زمانی شکل گیری تصمیمات و اجرایی شدن یا به تعبیر دیگر ضمانت اجرایی تصمیمات از نظر حقوقی است. آنچه که در این بین بیش از بقیه موارد مهم است ساختار و نظام حقوقی تصمیم گیری است. بطوریکه یک مدیر دولتی بداند در چه مواردی اختیار تصمیم گیری دارد و پشتیبانی کننده تصمیمات وی کدام اصول یا مواد قانونی است. اصول و مواد قانونی در اسناد بالادستی موجب اجرای هرچه بهتر تصمیمات می شود چرا که اینگونه تصمیمات با پشتوانه قوی قانونی بهتر جنبه اجرایی پیدا خواهند کرد. یکی از چالش های که مدیران بویژه مدیران دولتی با آن روبرو هستند آشنا نبودن با متن قانون و سازوکارهای قانونی است. لذا در این مقاله به بررسی اصول و مواد قانونی ساختار حقوقی تصمیم گیری با روش تحلیلی پرداخته شده است.  قانون اساسی و قانون مدیریت خدمات کشوری، قوانینی هستند که بررسی شده و در نهایت مدل تصمیم گیری در این دو قانون ارائه گردیده است.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">قانون</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 تصمیم گیری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 قانون اساسی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 قانون مدیریت خدمات کشوری </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13971014166667-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>