﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Factors Affecting Customer Participation in the New Product Development Process: Case study of food industry of Mazandaran province</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>عوامل موثر بر مشارکت مشتری در فرایند توسعه محصول جدید(مورد مطالعه صنایع غذایی استان مازندران)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>221</FirstPage><LastPage>232</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>خورشید</FirstName><LastName>فروغی نیا</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی اکبر</FirstName><LastName>جوکار</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد</FirstName><LastName>محمودی میمند</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>میرزا حسن</FirstName><LastName>حسینی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></History><Abstract>Constant changes in the business environment compel companies to think about new product development. In order to meet customer needs, active engagement with the customer and, more specifically, customer involvement in the process of developing new product is essential. The purpose of the present research is to identify the effective factors on customer involvement in the process of new product development in the food industry of Mazandaran province. Six effective variables include organizational strategy, new product features, external environment, organizational features, customer attributes, and relationships. The purpose of this research, in the form of applied research and in terms of the implementation of research, is descriptive-causal research. The statistical population of the research is the managers of different parts of the food industry of Mazandaran province, including production, product, marketing, brand, and other parts of the organization. The data gathering tool was a researcher-made questionnaire. In this research, structural equation modeling (SEM) has been used to analyze data and examine the hypothesis. The results showed that the organizational strategy variables, organizational characteristics, customer characteristics and relational factors have a positive and significant effect on customer involvement in the process of new product development. While the two variables of product and environment characteristics have no significant effect on customer involvement. Therefore, according to the results, food industry companies should pay particular attention to strengthening these factors in order to attract more customers to develop new products.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">چکیده
تغییرات مداوم محیط کسب¬وکار شرکت¬ها را وادار می¬کند تا به فکر توسعه محصول جدید باشند. برای ارضا نیازهای مشتری، تعامل فعال با مشتری و بصورت خاص¬تر؛ مشارکت مشتریان در فرایند توسعه محصول ضروری می¬باشد. هدف تحقیق حاضر شناسایی عوامل موثر بر مشارکت مشتریان در فرایند توسعه محصول جدید در صنایع غذایی استان مازندران می¬باشد. شش متغیر اثرگذار شامل؛ استراتژی سازمان، ویژگی های محصول جدید، محیط برون سازمانی، ویژگی¬های سازمان، ویژگی¬های مشتری و عوامل رابطه¬ای می¬باشند. جامعه آماری پژوهش مدیران بخش¬های مختلف شرکت¬های صنایع غذایی استان مازندران اعم از تولید، محصول، بازاریابی، برند می¬باشند. ابزار گردآوری داده¬ها، پرسشنامه محقق ساخته بوده که برای تحلیل داده¬ها و بررسی فرضیه از روش مدل¬سازی معادلات ساختاری (SEM) استفاده شده است. نتایج نشان داد که متغیرهای استراتژی سازمان، ویژگی¬های سازمان، ویژگی¬های مشتری و عوامل رابطه ای بر مشارکت مشتری در فرایند توسعه محصول جدید تاثیر گذارند. در حالی¬که دو متغیر ویژگی محصول و محیط اثر معناداری بر مشارکت مشتری ندارند. بنابراین با توجه به نتایج به دست آمده شرکت¬های صنایع غذایی می بایست جهت جلب مشارکت بیشتر مشتریان در توسعه محصولات جدید، به تقویت این عوامل توجه ویژه¬ای داشته باشند .
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مشارکت مشتری، فرایند توسعه محصولات جدید، صنایع غذایی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13971103167107-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>