﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>51</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Identification and analysis of the affecting factors on the success of technology road mapping by using interpretive structural modeling technique</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>شناسایی و تحلیل عوامل موثر بر موفقیت رهنگاری فناوری با استفاده از تکنیک  مدل¬سازی ساختاری تفسیری </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>افسانه</FirstName><LastName>احمدي</LastName><Affiliation>مركز تحقيقات سياست علمي كشور</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سيدسپهر</FirstName><LastName>قاضي نوري</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تربيت مدرس</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>فاطمه </FirstName><LastName>ثقفي</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></History><Abstract>With increasing cost, complexity and speed of technological changes and global competition, to ensure that technological investment is consistent and aligned to present and future needs of the organization, industry and country has become the most important challenges for policy makers and managers. So, technology management and innovation through a structured and flexible approach such as TRM is necessary. However Road mapping projects implementation and use of its advantages is impossible without identifying and prioritizing of success factors of technology road mapping. The aim of this work is using interpretive structural modeling technique to analyze the affecting factors on the success of technology road mapping. This helps improving technology road mapping process and identifying appropriate organizational policies. For this purpose, we firstly focus on literature review to extraction of technology road mapping success factors. Then, interpretive structural modeling technique is used for revealing the relation between those factors. For data gathering, 17 questionnaires are distributed among people with executive background or related working experience. The results show that the effective factors were classified in four levels. the most influencing factors are related to "commitment and support of management", "financial support" and "access to data, information and required knowledge", " appropriate participation of people ", "proper facilator" and " Accepting roadmapping ". The most influenced factors are "quality of roadmap" and "flexibility for reasonable changes by updating of roadmap"'. </Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">رشد سريع فناوري، افزایش هزینه، پیچیدگی و جهانی¬شدن رقابت، تطابق سرمایه¬گذاری‌های فناورانه با نیازهای سازمان را ضروي نموده است. لذا مديريت فناوري و نوآوری از طريق رويکردهاي ساختار¬يافته و انعطاف¬پذيری مانند رهنگاشت فناوري براي تصميم سازي براي سياستگذاران ضروری می نماید. استفاده از مزایای اجرای رهنگاری بدون شناسایی و اولویت¬بندی عوامل موثر بر آن غیر¬ممکن است. هدف از این مقاله بکارگیری روش مدل¬سازی ساختاری تفسیری برای تحلیل تعاملات و سطح بندی عوامل موثر بر موفقیت رهنگاری فناوری است بدین منظور ابتدا با مرور ادبیات عوامل مؤثر بر موفقیت رهنگاری فناوری شناسایی گردید سپس جهت سطح¬بندی این عوامل روش مدل¬سازی ساختاری تفسیری بکارگرفته شد. براي جمع¬آوري داده¬ها از پرسشنامه و توزيع آن در بين 17 نفر از خبرگان استفاده شد. با  تحليل يافته ها، عوامل مؤثر در چهار سطح و دو خوشه دسته¬بندی شدند. بیشترین تاثیرگذاری مربوط به عوامل"تامین منابع مالی"، "حمایت و تعهد مدیریت ارشد"، "پذیرش رهنگاری"، "مشارکت مناسب افراد"، " دسترسی به داده¬ها، اطلاعات و دانش مورد نیاز " و "وجود تسهیل¬گر و مشاور"، می¬باشند. بیشترین تاثیرپذیری را عامل " کیفیت سند رهنگاشت " و " انعطاف پذیری در برابر تغییرات لازم با بروز رسانی رهنگاشت " به خود اختصاص دادند.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">رهنگاری فناوری، مدل&amp;#172;سازی ساختاری تفسیری، عوامل موفقیت</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139511231121464961-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>