﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>55</Volume><Issue>2-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluating performance of IT department a fuzzy AHP and BSC approach</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ارزیابی عملکرد واحد های IT در صنعت با رویکرد ترکیبی تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی (FAHP) و کارت امتیازی متوازن (BSC) </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>0</FirstPage><LastPage>0</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محسن</FirstName><LastName>ناظم بکایی</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></History><Abstract>In this ever-changing world, information technology (IT) is a must for the survival of a company, and the functions of IT department is becoming increasingly important. The assessment of IT department is critical to understand how the department contributes to organizational and strategic goals. Because IT department performs many tasks that cannot simply be measured by monetary units, evaluation methods that solely rely on financial measures are not adequate. The objective of this study is to construct an approach based on the fuzzy analytic hierarchy process (FAHP) and balanced scorecard (BSC) for evaluating an IT department in the company studied. The BSC concept is applied to define the hierarchy with four major perspectives (i.e. financial, customer, internal business process, and learning and growth), and performance indicators are selected for each perspective. A fuzzy AHP (FAHP) approach is then proposed in order to tolerate vagueness and ambiguity of information. A FAHP information system is finally constructed to facilitate the solving process. The results provide guidance to IT departments in the Industry Case Study regarding strategies for improving department performance. The constructed information system is suggested to be a good tool for solving other multiple-criteria decision-making problems.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این دنیای در حال تغییر، تکنولوژی اطلاعات(IT) برای بقای شرکت ها، یک ضرورت است، و وظایف واحد IT روز به روز مهمتر می شود. ارزیابی واحد IT برای فهم اینکه چقدر این واحد در اهداف استراتژیک و سازمانی سهیم است، کار حیاتی است. از آنجایی که واحد IT وظایف بسیاری انجام می دهد که به سادگی با واحد های پولی قابل سنجش نمی باشد، روش هایی ارزیابی که به تنهایی بر معیار های مالی تکیه دارد مناسب نیستند. هدف این مطالعه ایجاد یک رویکرد بر اساس فرایند تحلیل سلسله مراتب(FAHP) و روش امتیازات متوازن(BSC) برای ارزشیابی واحد IT در یک شرکت مورد مطالعه می باشد. مفهوم روش امتیازات متوازن برای تعریف سلسله مراتب با چهار چشم انداز عمده یعنی امور مالی، مشتری، فرایندهای کسب و کار داخلی، یادگیری و رشد به کار می رود. برای هر چشم نداز، شاخص های عملکرد انتخاب می شود. سپس یک راه حل برای تحمل ابهام و عدم اطمینان در مورد اطلاعات پیشنهاد می شود. نهایتا یک » فرایند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی « رویکرد سیستم اطلاعاتی " FAHP" برای تسهیل فرایند حل مسئله ایجاد می شود. نتایج، یک راهنمای عمل در مورد استراتژی های بهیود عملکرد واحد، در اختیار واحدهای IT در صنعت مرود مطالعه قرار می دهد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">فرایند تحلیل سلسله مراتب فازی(FAHP) </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
روش امتیازات متوازن(BSC)</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
ارزشیابی عملکرد، تکنولوژی اطلاعات(IT) </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/1396112912432760926-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>