﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>51</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Motion Algorithm from EFQM toward BSC in order to prioritize improvement projects of self- assessment.</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>الگوریتم حرکت از EFQM به سمت BSC به‌منظور اولویت‌بندی پروژه¬های حاصل از خودارزیابی (مطالعه¬ی موردی: معاونت برنامه¬ریزی و توسعه¬ی شهرداری یزد) </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محمد صالح</FirstName><LastName>اولیا</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بیرمنگام- انگلستان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد حسین</FirstName><LastName>ابویی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی امیر کبیر</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>پرستو</FirstName><LastName>دمرچی</LastName><Affiliation>مهندسی صنایع</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></History><Abstract>EFQM excellence model with specifying the position of organization in the path of excellence is a practical tool in order to understand its deficiencies and shortcoming, so that with providing guidelines in the form of improvement projects helps organizations to advance the process of appropriate management systems .EFQM self- assessing model as a tool of Total Quality Management is facing with the problem of the lack of prioritizing improvement projects because of the lack of facilities and limits of resources in enterprises hence there are the necessity of strategic prioritizing of self-assessment projects in the organization. The aim of this study is to provide the steps of moving the EFQM model to BSC model as a strategic management tool by using FTOPSIS and   FANP techniques in order to strategic prioritize the improvement projects of the EFQM self-assessment. This study is functional in terms of the objective and in terms of method is a survey research and in terms of the   collection of information   is a field research. Statistical society consists of 7 persons of Yazd municipal managers in the form of excellence team and interview and questionnaire are tools used in the research. The result of prioritizing improvement projects led to determine importance of internal process perspective in the organization  in the organization and prioritize 21 improvement projects including “ provision and updating of educational electronic ID”,” personal relocation in occupational category according to given training”,” create documentation center in municipality”</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">مدل تعالی EFQM با تعیین جایگاه سازمان در مسیر تعالی، ابزاری عملی برای کمک به سازمان‌ها است که به درک کمبودها و نواقصشان کمک می‌نماید. این مدل با ارائه راهکارهایی در قالب پروژه‌های بهبود، به سازمان کمک می‌نماید که در مسیر سیستم‌های مدیریتی مناسب پیش رود. مدل خودارزیابی EFQM به‌عنوان ابزار مدیریت کیفیت فراگیر به علت کمبود امکانات و محدودیت منابع سازمان¬ها با مشکل عدم اولویت¬بندی پروژه¬های بهبود مواجه است ازاین‌رو ضرورت اولویت‌بندی استراتژیک پروژه¬های حاصل از خودارزیابی در سازمان¬ها وجود دارد. هدف از پژوهش حاضر ارائه¬ی گام¬های حرکت از مدل EFQM به سمت مدل BSC به‌عنوان ابزار مدیریت استراتژیک با استفاده تکنیک‌های FANP و FTOPSIS به‌منظور اولویت‌بندی استراتژیک است. این تحقیق ازنظر نوع هدف کاربردی و ازنظر روش پیمایشی و ازنظر گردآوری اطلاعات میدانی است. جامعه¬ی آماری متشکل از 7 نفر از مدیران شهرداری یزد در قالب تیم تعالی سازمان است به‌علاوه مصاحبه و پرسش¬نامه ابزار مورد استفاده در تحقیق است. نتایج اولویت¬بندی پروژه¬های بهبود منجر به تعیین اهمیت منظر فرآیندهای داخلی در سازمان و اولویت¬بندی 21 پروژه¬ی بهبود ازجمله «تهیه و به‌روزرسانی شناسنامه¬ی آموزشی الکترونیکی پرسنل»، «جابجایی کارکنان در دسته و رسته¬های شغلی برحسب آموزش¬های طی شده» و «ایجاد مرکز اسناد شهرداری» شده است.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مدل تعالی EFQM </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
اولویت‌بندی پروژه&amp;#172;های بهبود، </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
کارت امتیازی متوازن</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
FTOPSIS</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
FANP</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139508221620433925-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>