﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>2-ب</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effect of risk and resources on Firm's growth strategies in high tech industries </ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تاثیر منابع وریسک بر استراتژی رشد بنگاه‌ در صنایع هایتک</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>151</FirstPage><LastPage>160</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محسن</FirstName><LastName>پارساجم </LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد رضا</FirstName><LastName> حمیدی زاده</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>بهمن</FirstName><LastName>حاجی پور</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>اسماعیل </FirstName><LastName>فدایی نژاد</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی </Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day></History><Abstract>During the last decade there was a well known strategy to support startups and enterprenuers to stabilish firms in high tech industries. despite the position of high-tech industries has been weakened especially in export share. Growth strategies utilized by high-tech firms can improve the position. Growth strategies help firms to increase their market share and sale revenues. Hence, current study aims to designate and validate growth strategies of high-tech firms. Research model has been proposed based on the extended literature, the situation of high-tech industry, and experts' views. Data is gathered by a self-administrated questionnaire and would be analyzed by structural equation modeling using SPSS 18 and LISERL 8.54. Population is managers of high-tech firms in Iran. A convenience sampling approach is employed to collect estimated sample. Data achieved from 451 respondents was analyzed. Results indicated that: 1) growth strategies of high tech firms affect their outputs, 2) resources affect growth strategies of high-tech firms, 3) multiple risks affect the utilization of resources by the high tech firms, and 4) high tech firms provide the needed resources for their growth based on the outcomes in terms of profit and/or attractiveness</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">طی سالهای گذشته حمایت‌هایی از کارآفرینان و استارت‌آپ‌ها در صنایع هایتک انجام شده است. بنگاه‌های بسیاری بر مبنای نوآوری  فنی، فرصتهای بازار و حمایتهای موجود  ایجاد شده‌اند. تعداد کمی از آنها در طول زمان بقا پیدا کرده و توانسته‌اند رشد کنند. در حالیکه حمایت دولتی یا خلاء موقت در بازار ناشی از عدم ثبات می‌تواند کارآفرینان را به ایجاد بنگاه تحریک کند. اما اینکه بنگاههای نورسته بتواند رشد کرده و با رسیدن به مقیاس در گروه‌های استراتژیک صنعتی که در ان فعال هستند، قرار بگیرند و در ساختار رقابتی حضور یابند به الزامات بیشتری نیاز دارد.  استراتژی رشد بنگاه یکی از این  شرایط است. هدف از این پژوهش مطالعه استراتژیهای  رشد بنگاه در صنایع دارای فناوری بالا می باشد. در این پژوهش فرض شده است که اول داشتن استراتژی رشد، در رشد بنگاه موثر است به این معنی که فرآیند رشد تصادفی نیست. دوم، منابع در انتخاب استراتژی رشد موثر هستند و سوم، بنگاه براساس  ریسک  استراتژی رشد بر می گزیند. و چهارم آنکه حاصل رشد بنگاه در صنعت هایتک افزایش سود و جذابیت است که در تداوم چرخه رشد موثرند. جامعه اماری پژوهش شامل مدیران بنگاه‌ها در صنایع پیشرفته می‌باشد. با مصاحبه حضوری و پرسشنامه اطلاعات جامعه آماری اخذ و با استفاده از نرم افزار لیزرل تحلیل گردید. هر چهار فرضیه تحقیق مورد تایید قرار گرفت. حاصل این تحقیق می تواند در اتخاذ راهبردهای حمایت از بنگاهها مورد استفاده قرار بگیرد. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">استراتژی رشد</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 نفوذ در بازار</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 فناوری پیشرفته</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 رشد داخلی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 رشد خارجی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 کارآمدی بنگاه</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 ریسک مالی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 ریسک بانکی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 ریسک ارزی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
  ریسک مقررات گمرکی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13961226125226101341-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>