﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>57</Volume><Issue>3-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigating Effect of Technological Variables and Organizational Learning on Organizational Performance Through the Mediation of Organizational Innovation (Case Study: Iranian Industry Bank)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بررسی اثر متغیرهای فناورانه و یادگیری سازمانی بر روی عملکرد سازمانی با میانجیگری نوآوری سازمانی (مورد مطالعه: صنعت بانکداری ایران)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>261</FirstPage><LastPage>272</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مهدی </FirstName><LastName>جنیدی جعفری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام خمینی قزوین</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد </FirstName><LastName>اقدسی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day></History><Abstract>This paper examines the effects of technological variables, including top management support for technology, on the development of technological skills, technological distinctive competencies and organizational learning. It also examines the effects of technological distinctive competencies and organizational learning on organizational innovation. How these variables affect organizational performance. This study was conducted using a descriptive-survey research method with a sample of 30 banks approved by the Central Bank of Iran using a questionnaire and through structural equation method. The results of the research show that: (1) top management support has a positive impact on the development of technology skills, technological distinctive competencies, and organizational learning. (2) Technological distinctive competencies and organizational learning, directly or indirectly through organizational innovation, have a positive impact on organizational performance. It was also confirmed that innovation has a positive impact on organizational performance. Research also has recommendations for business professionals that the creation of merit is complex and a long-term process that should be pursued with the long-term strategy of the company. Therefore, the involvement of management through the design of an entrepreneurial strategy is also a major issue.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این مقاله به بررسی اثر متغیرهای فناورانه شامل حمایت مدیریت ارشد  از فناوری بر ایجاد مهارت های فناورانه، شایستگی های متمایز فناورانه  و یادگیری سازمانی  پرداخته شده است. همچنین تأثیرات شایستگی های متمایز فناورانه و یادگیری سازمانی را بر نوآوری سازمانی بررسی و مشاهده می شود این متغیرها چگونه بر عملکرد سازمانی تأثیر می گذارند.  اين پژوهش با استفاده از روش تحقيق «توصيفي-پيمايشي» با نمونه‌ای متشکل از 30 بانک مورد تأیید بانک مرکزی ایران با ابزار پرسشنامه و از طریق روش معادلات ساختاری مورد بررسي قرار گرفته‌اند. نتایج تحقیق نشان می دهد: (1) حمایت مدیریت ارشد تأثیر مثبتی بر ایجاد مهارت های فناوری، شایستگی های متمایز فناورانه و یادگیری سازمانی دارد. (2) شایستگی های متمایز فناورانه و یادگیری سازمانی، مستقیم یا غیر مستقیم از طریق نوآوری سازمانی، تأثیر مثبتی بر عملکرد سازمانی می گذارند. همچنین تأیید شد که نوآوری تأثیر مثبتی بر عملکرد سازمانی می‌گذارد. پژوهش توصیه‌هایی نیز برای متخصصان کسب‌وکار دارد، مبنی بر اینکه ایجاد شایستگی امری پیچیده بوده و یک فرایند طولانی مدت است که باید دست در دست راهبرد بلندمدت شرکت تحقق یابد. بنابراین، دخیل ساختن مدیریت از طریق طراحی راهبرد کارآفرینانه نیز موضوعی مهم و بنیادین است. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">حمایت مدیریت ارشد</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 شایستگی‌های متمایز فناورانه</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
یادگیری سازمانی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 عملکرد سازمانی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139606291124108150-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>