﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Portfolio strategies in industrial marketing   With the product life cycle approach</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>استراتژی های پورتفوی در بازاریابی صنعتی  با رویکرد چرخه عمر محصول</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>33</FirstPage><LastPage>46</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>هوشنگ</FirstName><LastName>نظامی وند چگینی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></History><Abstract>Determining the Portfolio Strategies Proper business-to-business placement in industrial marketing for parenting organizations or holdings is one of the most important tasks of planners. In this regard, there are many methods and techniques that many companies have outlined for developing their own portfolio strategy. The use of the life-cycle model helps companies active in modern technologies and organizations active in the industrial market to first consider their strategies for each of the products without considering their internal constraints. Determine. In this approach, by analyzing the status of the indicators associated with the market, the stage of product life cycle, and determined by the status of organizations in leadership or follow-up, specify attractive products.
This paper attempts to present the results of this approach to the Sina Electronic Development Company (holding ICT), one of the major companies active in the communications and information industry. The use of this approach and the results obtained demonstrate the effectiveness of this method For industries or fields of modern technology.
In this study, the strategic position analysis has also been used to improve the accuracy of the analysis, and the results are presented in the final section.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">تعیین استراتژی های پورتفوی کسب کار های مناسب در بازاریابی صنعتی برای سازمانهای مادر یا هلدینگ ها از مهمترین وظایف برنامه ریزان است.در این خصوص روش ها و تکنیک های زیادی معرفی شده است که بسیاری از شرکت ها از  این روش ها برای تدوین استراتژی پورتفوی خود استفاده می کنند.برای شرکت های فعال در فناوری های نوین و نیز سازمانهایی که بیشتر در بازار های صنعتی فعالند استفاده از مدل چرخه عمر کمک می کند تا ابتدا بدون در نظر گرفتن محدودیت های داخلی استراتژی های خود را برای هر یک از  محصولات مورد بررسی تعیین کنند . در این رویکرد و با تحلیل وضعیت شاخص های مرتبط با بازار مرحله عمر محصولات تعیین شده و بر حسب وضعیت سازمانها در رهبری یا پیرو بودن، محصولات جذاب را مشخص می کنند.
در این مقاله تلاش شده است تا نتیجه استفاده از این رویکرد درخصوص شرکت گسترش الکترونیک سینا (هلدینگ ICT) که یکی از شرکت های بزرگ فعال در صنعت ارتباطات و اطلاعات است ،ارائه شود.استفاده از این رویکرد و نتایج بدست آمده مبین کارآمدی این روش برای صنایع یا زمینه های با تکنولوژی نوین می باشد.
در این مطالعه از تحلیل موقعیت استراتژیک نیز برای بالابردن دقت تحلیل استفاده شده است که نتایج آن در بخش پایانی ارائه می شود.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مراحل چرخه عمر</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
موقعیت استراتژیک</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
استراتژي پورتفوی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13970828165661-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>