﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>54</Volume><Issue>1-ب</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>decision support system design by using data mining tools (CASE STUDY Cultural Assistance of University of Science and Technology)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>طراحی سامانه تصمیم یار با استفاده از ابزار داده کاوی(مطالعه موردی معاونت فرهنگی دانشگاه علم و صنعت)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>163</FirstPage><LastPage>176</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>روزبه</FirstName><LastName>قوسی</LastName><Affiliation>علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>عماد</FirstName><LastName>چیذری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>هانی</FirstName><LastName>وحدانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></History><Abstract>decision-making,is the most important duty of managers. In the new era , decision-making process has many difficulties and delicacies; so that decision-making without the use of new technologies and information analysis , the objectives will not be achieved as desired. Efficient management in addition to knowledge &amp; experience management, needs to know how to use information systems. decision support system(DSS) is one of these systems that support decision-making process for managers. In this paper , at first we review the literature of decision support systems; then data mining as a tool to extract information and knowledge from organizational raw data is introduced. This extracted knowledge, may contain concepts and informations that are neglected in organization up to now, so this knowledge can help managers in Decision-making process. Eventually, The findings of this study has been used to help managers and vicars in their decisions at Iran University of Science and Technology(IUST).</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">تصمیم‌گیری یکی از وظایف اصلی مدیران تلقی می‌شود؛ درعصر کنونی فرآیند تصمیم‌گیری با پیچیدگی‌ها و ظرافت‌های فراوانی همراه است به طوری که اخذ تصمیم بدون استفاده از فناوری‌های روز و تحلیل و بررسی اطلاعات، اهداف را به صورت مطلوب محقق نخواهد ساخت. مدیریت کارا علاوه بر دانش وتجربه مدیریت نیازمند به کارگیری صحیح سامانه‌های اطلاعاتی است؛ سیستم‌ پشتیبان تصمیم یکی از این سامانه‌های می‌باشد که پشتوانه‌ای برای فرآیند تصمیم‌گیری مدیران سازمانی می‌باشد. در این مقاله ابتدا ادبیات مربوط به سیستم پشتیبان تصمیم بررسی شده است؛ سپس داده‌کاوی به عنوان ابزاری برای استخراج دانش و اطلاعات کاربردی از داده‌های خام سازمانی معرفی شده است. این دانش به دست آمده حاوی مفاهیم و اطلاعاتی است که ممکن است پیش از این در سازمان مغفول مانده باشد لذا کمک شایانی به روند تصمیم گیری مدیران خواهد داشت. در نهایت یافته‌های این مطالعه در دانشگاه علم و صنعت به کار گرفته شده است تا راهنما و پشتیبان تصمیمات مدیران دانشگاهی باشد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سیستم پشتیبانی تصمیم</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 داده‌کاوی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 نظرسنجی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139512021919105070-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>