﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>58</Volume><Issue>دوم</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2015</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Proposing a model for low cost carriers market in Iran </ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>طراحی مدلی برای توسعه بازار سفرهای هوایی ارزان قیمت در ايران</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>69</FirstPage><LastPage>92</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محمدرضا</FirstName><LastName>محموديه</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران پرديس فارابي</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>اصف</FirstName><LastName>کريمي</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></History><Abstract>Low cost carriers are great revolutions in the air transportation industry in the last three decades. In fact, low cost  model in the airlines has been indicated as a successful and innovative model. Low cost model is a strategy, focusing on the primary needs of passengers and increaring productivity, that provides lowest prices in internal and international air transportation of passenger. In this study, it has been tried to propose a model of developing low cost carriers market. Population is experts in airline of Aseman, Iran Air Tour, and Kish Air. Samples were collected by targeted judgemental approach for qualitative interviews. Instrument was structured interviews. To analyze data, grounded theory was utilized. 33 interviews with experts of airlines help to gather the required data. Finally, 15 major concepts were extracted including liberalization and withdrawal from the state structure, internal and external tourismism, efficient human factor, security and timely order, regulatory interaction versus relation orientation, customer trust, structural modifications costs, infrastructure and airport management, reconciliation with aeronautical knowledge, customer service, optimal aircraft and flight network, governance mandate structure, optimal sales service management, lack of sanction pressure and society cultural development. Finally, these concepts shaped the paradigmatic pattern of the development of the market for low cost carriers.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">شرکت های هواپیمایی کم هزینه طی سه دهه‌ی گذشته تحول و انقلابی بزرگ در صنعت حمل و نقل هوایی محسوب می شوند. در واقع، مدل کم هزینه در شرکت¬های هواپیمایی مدلی موفق و نوآوری مسلم در صنعت هواپیمایی مطرح شده است. مدل تجاری كم هزینه، راهبردی است كه عموما در محور تامین نیازهای اساسی مسافران و افزایش بهره وری، ارزانترین نرخ های پروازی را در بازارهای داخلی و بین المللی حمل و نقل هوایی مسافر عرضه می نماید. در این تحقیق سعی شده که مدلی جهت توسعه بازار برای شرکت های هواپیمایی کم هزینه طراحی گردد. جامعه آماری پژوهش متخصصان و کارشناسان صنعت هواپیمایی کشور در شرکت های ایران ایر تور، کیش ایر و آسمان می باشد. نمونه های مورد نیاز برای مصاحبه کیفی از طریق نمونه گیری قضاوتی هدفمند گردآوری خواهند شد. ابزار گردآوری داده ها مصاحبه های ساختار یافته بود. به منظور تحلیل داده ها نیز از رویکرد تئوری داده بنیاد بهره گرفته شد. با مصاحبه از 33 متخصص صنعت هواپیمایی کشور، داده های مورد نیاز گردآوری و تحلیل گردید. در نهایت 15 مقوله اصلی شامل آزادسازی و خروج از ساختار دولتی، توریسم گرایی داخلی و خارجی، عامل انسانی کارا، امنیت و نظم زمانمند، تعامل ضابطه¬مند در مقابل رابطه گرایی، اعتماد آفرینی مشتریان، هزینه های اصلاحی ساختارمند، مدیریت زیرساختی و فرودگاهی، آشتی با دانش هوانوردی، مشتری پروری، هواپیمای بهینه و شبکه پروازی، ساختار تکلیفی حاکمیت، مدیریت خدمات فروش بهینه، نبود فشار تحریمی و توسعه فرهنگی جامعه، استخراج گردید و الگوی پارادایمی توسعه بازار سفرهای هوایی ارزان قیمت را شکل داد. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سفرهای ارزان قیمت</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
شرکت هواپیمایی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
سفرهای هوایی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
توسعه بازار</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13970619113610164287-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>