﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>49</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>A multi-period planning model for honey export network design considering quality requirements</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ارائه مدل برنامه‌ريزی چند دوره¬ای برای طراحی شبکه صادرات عسل با در نظر گرفتن الزامات کیفی محصول </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>عليرضا</FirstName><LastName>گريواني</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ايران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>میرسامان </FirstName><LastName>پیشوایی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day></History><Abstract>From the past, Honey has been known as a healthy product for human life. Iran has a suitable climate for beekeeping and is among the high-ranked countries in honey production. However, due to failure to comply with quality issues, export of honey from this country is associated with many problems. Honey quality also plays an important role in determination of honey sale price. According to this issue, in this study, the design of honey export network is taken into account. For this purpose a mixed integer programming mathematical model is developed which is able to consider the impact of honey sale price on demand quantity of importing countries. The numerical results show that the proposed model can efficiently determine the strategic network design decisions and help the managers in this regard.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">عسل محصولی است که از گذشته به داشتن فواید بسیار مشهور گشته است. کشور ایران دارای شرایط آب¬وهوایی مناسب برای پرورش زنبور عسل می¬باشد و در تولید عسل از جایگاه خوبی در میان کشورهای جهان برخوردار است. اما به دلیل رعایت نکردن مسائل مربوط به کیفیت، صادرات عسل از این کشور به سایر کشورهای جهان با مشکلات فراوانی همراه است. همچنین کیفیت عسل نقش مهمی در تعیین قیمت فروش آن دارد.  در این پژوهش، سعی شده است با توجه به این موضوع، شبکه صادرات عسل طراحی گردد. برای این منظور یک مدل ریاضی عدد صحیح مختلط چند دوره¬ای ارائه شده است که در آن الگوی تقاضا در کشورهای واردکننده عسل براساس سطح کیفیت عسل در نظر گرفته شده است. به کارگیری این مدل در واقعیت موجب ساماندهی به وضعیت صادرات عسل ایران خواهد شد، چنان که بر اساس نتایج حل مدل، صادرات عسل به هر کشور براساس تقاضای آن کشور در سطح کیفیت خاصی صورت می-پذیرد که الزامات آن در فرآوری عسل باید مد نظر قرار گیرد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">طراحی شبکه</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
زنجیره تامین بین المللی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
قیمت انتقالی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
نرخ ارز</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
صادرات عسل</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139506041042353220-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>49</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Identify factors affecting Internet Banking Service Quality Case Study: Mellat Bank customers</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>شناسایی عوامل موثر بر کیفیت خدمات بانکداری اینترنتی  مورد مطالعه: مشتریان بانک ملت  </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مریم </FirstName><LastName>اخوان </LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مجید</FirstName><LastName>باقری</LastName><Affiliation>مدیریت و حسابداری</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day></History><Abstract>Today, service quality, sustainable competitive advantage for the bank to bring it helps to create value and customer satisfaction. Therefore, improving the quality of customer service is vital for them. This study examined the factors affecting customers' perception of Internet banking through careful investigation of the main studies as well as different models provided for quality assessment of electronic services. Based on the findings, an optimal model for the quality assessment of Internet banking services provided by Mellat Bank was designed. The statistical population included customers of the Internet banking services provided by Mellat Bank in Isfahan. Data collection was done using a questionnaire whose validity was confirmed according to experts' opinions and the reliability of the test was assessed using Cronbach's alpha for the initial sample and for the main test performed on all subjects in the statistical population, showing a high reliability. The second-order factor analysis was used to test the research hypotheses and prioritize the factors affecting the quality of electronic banking services. The findings showed that website design, responsiveness, empathy, guarantee, efficiency, security/trust, and compensation for damage were the most effective factors (in the order of significance) in the quality of Mellat Bank on-line Internet banking services.

</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه کیفیت خدمات، مزیت رقابتی پایداری را برای بانک‌ها به همراه می‌آورد زیرا به ایجاد ارزش و رضایت مشتریان کمک می‌کند. ازاین‌رو بهبود کیفیت خدمت‌رسانی به مشتری برای آن‌ها اهمیتی حیاتی یافته است.در این پژوهش با بررسی دقیق مطالعات اصلی و مدل‌های مختلف ارائه‌شده در خصوص کیفیت خدمات الکترونیکی، عوامل مؤثر بر نگرش مشتریان در خصوص بانکداری اینترنتی موردبررسی قرارگرفته و مدل بهینه جهت سنجش کیفیت خدمات بانکداری اینترنتی بانک ملت طراحی گردیده است. جامعه آماري پژوهش شامل مشتریان خدمات بانکداری اینترنتی بانک ملت می باشد. جمع‌آوري‌ داده‌ها‌ در این پژوهش با ابزار ‌پرسشنامه انجام گردیده که روايي آن با استفاده از نظرات خبرگان تایید شده و روش آلفاي کرونباخ در نمونه اوليه و در کل جامعه آماری نشان از پايايي بالای آن داشته است. در پژوهش حاضر، از تحلیل عاملی مرتبه دو براي آزمون فرضيه¬هاي تحقيق و اولویت بندی عوامل موثر در کیفیت خدمات بانکداری الکترونیکی استفاده شده است. که در نهایت یافته‌های این پژوهش نشان می‌دهد که طراحی وبسایت، پاسخگویی، همدلی، تضمین، کارایی، امنیت/اعتماد، جبران خسارت به ترتیب به‌عنوان مهم‌ترین ابعاد موثر در کیفیت خدمات بانکداری آنلاین در بانک ملت می باشند. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">: کیفیت خدمات الکترونیکی،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 بانکداری اینترنتی،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 رضایت مشتری</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13950607188473248-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>49</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Functional Analysis of National Innovation System of IRAN</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تحلیل کارکردی نظام نوآوری ایران مبتنی بر مطالعات منتخب</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>جواد</FirstName><LastName>سلطان زاده</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>کاوس </FirstName><LastName>حیدری</LastName><Affiliation>هیأت علمی جهاد دانشگاهی تهران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>حمیده</FirstName><LastName>دباغی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>حمید</FirstName><LastName>امین اسماعیلی</LastName><Affiliation>عضو هیئت علمی جهاد دانشگاهی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>رضا</FirstName><LastName>انصاری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></History><Abstract>Performance of Innovation system is one of the most important segments of planning in every country which is needed for economic and social prosperity, security and welfare. But the lack of achievement to scientific purposes in Iran indicates that there are many challenges toward innovation system and its progress.  In the other word, it is necessary for improving national innovation system to be affected by consistent and clear policies. It means that a kind of policies is needed which can define the contribution of each players in the innovation system and the rate of their participation. Achieving to this goal, makes us to use a scale for measuring the policies and let us to evaluate and identify the pros and cones. Also, this approach toward the innovation system makes it better than the past and helps us to create more functional and strategic policies in the future. For this goal, we study a wide theoretic framework and 16 previous studies to suppose a functional scale consist of five levels named: Management and policy making, Knowledge creation and accumulation, Knowledge diffusion, Knowledge exploitation and Infrastructure. The results show that there are 159 weaknesses and shortcomings in innovation system according to the opinion of experts. In addition we supposed 43 indicators related to five levels scale for making functional policies of innovation in the future.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">عملکرد نظام نوآوری يكي از مهم‌ترین مؤلفه‌هاي برنامه‌ريزي براي شکوفایی اقتصادي، اجتماعي، تأمين امنيت و رفاه جامعه است. دستاوردهای اندک در حوزه‌های نوآوری و اقتصادی، و عدم دستیابی به اهداف علمی کشور، حکایت از وجود چالش‌هایی در نظام نوآوری ایران دارد. حال‌آنکه بهبود وضعیت نظام ملی نوآوری ایران، نیازمند سیاست‌گذاری یکپارچه، همسو و مشخص است. نوعی از سیاست‌گذاری که بتوان بر اساس آن به تعیین سهم و نرخ مشارکت هر یک از بازیگران این نظام، و راهبردهای کلی  پرداخت و بر بهره¬وری نظام ملی نوآوری افزود. اما حصول این امر مهم، جز در بستر سیاستی واحد، جامع و به‌دور از تشتت و تضاد سیاستی و فکری پشتیبان آن، ممکن نیست. در این راستا استفاده از معیارها و سنجه‌¬های تنظیم‌گر، تسهیل¬گر و مبتنی بر پذیرش اجتماع متخصصان این حوزه، حائز اهمیت است تا بتوان بر اساس آن به شناسایی کاستی‌های فعلی در نظام ملی نوآوری و همچنین ارزیابی سیاست‌های فعلی این نظام پرداخت و راه را برای سیاست‌های کاربردی و راهبردی در آینده نیز، بهبود بخشید. در مقاله حاضر با توجه به اهمیت مشخص نمودن سنجه‌ای معیار و کارکردی، ابتدا با استفاده از روش مطالعه کتابخانه‌ای به مروری بر ادبیات و مطالعات موجود پیرامون نظام ملی نوآوری پرداخته و پنج سطح کارکردی مبتنی بر رویکرد کارکردی تدوین شد. سپس با کاربست پنج سطح کارکردی به‌دست‌آمده که شامل سطوح مدیریت و سیاست‌گذاری، خلق و اخذ دانش، انتشار دانش، به‌کارگیری دانش و زیرساخت‌ها می‌باشد، به مروری بر کاستی‌ها و چالش‌های مطرح شده متخصصان حوزه نوآوری از خلال 16 مقاله داخلی پرداخته و برای هر سطح کارکردی هم از منظر نظری و هم کاربردی و کارکردی، مصادیقی ارائه شده¬است. نتایج مطالعه حاضر نشان می‌دهد که 159 ضعف و کاستی از منظر متخصصان داخلی در نظام ملی نوآوری ایران قابل‌بازشناسی است که در قالب 43 شاخص زیرمجموعه 5 سطح کارکردی فوق قرار می‌گیرد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">نظام ملی نوآوری، تحلیل متون سیاستی، کارکردهای نظام نوآوری.</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139602091139395807-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>49</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Choose the best suppliers with a decision support system based on self-organizing neural networks in Oil Projects</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>انتخاب بهترین تامین کننده با یک سیستم پشتیبان تصمیم مبتنی بر شبکه عصبی خودسازمانده در پروژه های نفتی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>میثم</FirstName><LastName>جعفری اسکندری</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName><LastName> یوسفی طزرجان</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه جامع علمی‌کاربردی</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></History><Abstract>One of the most essential activities to create the appropriate supply chain is supplier selection process. The system must be capable of providing buyer's requirements in terms of quality products, at affordable prices and at the appropriate time and volume.
The nature of these decisions is usually complex and unstructured. In this study, self-organizing neural networks for decision making for the supplier selection decision is provided in a decision support system environment.
Using self-organizing neural networks as a clustering techniques, suppliers clustered. new supplier standards compared with spikes winner and will decide on accepting or rejecting provider. The output of the model is supplier selection and evaluation by appropriate conditions for new suppliers.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">فرایند انتخاب تأمین کننده مناسبی که قادر به فراهم کردن نیاز خریدار از نظر محصولات با کیفیت، با قیمت مناسب و در زمان و حجم مناسب باشد یکی از ضروری ترین فعالیت ها برای ایجاد زنجیره تأمین مناسب است. ماهیت این تصمیمات معمولأ پیچیده و ساختار نیافته است. در این پژوهش تصمیم گیری با استفاده از شبکه عصبی خود سازمانده برای انتخاب تأمین کننده مناسب در یک محیط تصمیم گیری ارائه شده است. با استفاده از تکنیک شبکه عصبی خود سازمانده تامین‌کنندگان موجود خوشه‌بندی می‌شوند و با توجه به معیار مد نظر، خوشه برتر معرفی می‌گردد. با حضور تامین‌کننده جدید معیارهای وی با خوشه برنده مقایسه گردیده و در مورد رد یا پذیرش تامین‌کننده تصمیم‌گیری می‌شود. خروجی این مدل انتخاب تامین‌کنندگان مناسب و بررسی شرایط تامین‌کنندگان جدید می‌باشد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">شبکه عصبی خودسازمانده، انتخاب تأمین کننده، فرایند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی، سیستم پشتیبان تصمیم</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139602111210245838-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>49</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>An Integrated DEMATEL and Fuzzy ANP Techniques Based Assessment Model For Intrapreneurship with Approach EFQM</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ارایه یک مدل ارزیابی کارآفرینی سازمانی با رویکرد مدل تعالی سازمانی (EFQM)  با استفاده از تکنیک یکپارچه‌سازی دیمتل و فرآیند تحلیل شبکه‌ای فازی (F.D.ANP)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>کاظم </FirstName><LastName>نصیری کاشانی</LastName><Affiliation>واحد علوم و تحقیقات دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>فضل‌الله</FirstName><LastName>جمالو</LastName><Affiliation>واحد تهران جنوب دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>لیلا</FirstName><LastName>کیانی</LastName><Affiliation>واحد تهران جنوب دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></History><Abstract>In today's world, quick changes have varied the competition and also have faced organizational stakeholders with world’s challenges. In this turbulence environment, Intrapreneurship is functionality that can save today's systems as a new phenomenon in the economy at this critical period and play a more active role in economic development. Today, business excellence models also have an important role to deploy the key factors of organizational success and make performance improvements. These models provide the assessment criteria in both enablers and results and make guidelines for organizations to measure their progress and performance in the field of quality and organizational excellence. So it allows creating the needed infrastructure and capabilities for Intrapreneurship based on the EFQM Excellence Model. Therefore, after identifying the effective factors of implementation Intrapreneurship, these features are classified due to their nature at four main criteria include "leadership", "Policy and Strategy", "employees" and "partnerships, resources and processes" that all of them are the enablers of the EFQM model. This paper presents an analytical modeling method that makes practicable a qualitative relationship between the elements of Intrapreneurship. We used the integrated approach of fuzzy Dematel and fuzzy modeling network analysis to determine the relationship and weight relative importance of each element in model. The results indicated “leadership” at the main criteria level has the most highly effect and “employees” has the most important coefficient. Also "senior management support" has the highest importance coefficient and highly effect in the sub-criteria. In this study we presented individual entrepreneurs and Intrapreneurship assessment model that is a comprehensive model and can be used in different organizations and finally we evaluated this model in Iran Power Development Company.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">
تغییرات و تحولات پر شتاب دنیای کنونی، نحوه رقابت شرکت‌ها را دگرگون ساخته و ذینفعان سازمانی را در مواجهه با دنيايي پر از چالش قرار داده است. در این محیط پر از تلاطم، كارآفريني سازمانی قابليتي است كه به عنوان پديده‌اي نوين در اقتصاد، مي‌تواند نظام‌هاي امروزي را در اين برهه حساس، نجات داده و نقش موثرتری در توسعه و پيشرفت اقتصادي كشورها ايفا نماید. امروزه مدل‌های تعالی سازمانی نیز از نقش موثری در اشاعه عوامل کلیدی موفقیت سازمانی برخوردارند و بهبود عملکرد را به ارمغان می‌آورند. این مدل‌ها با ارایه معیارهای ارزیابي در دو بخش توانمندسازها و نتایج، خطوط راهنمایي برای سازمان‌ها ایجاد نموده اند تا آنها بتوانند پیشرفت و عملکردهای خود را در زمینه کیفیت و تعالي سازماني اندازه‌گیری نمایند. پس با اتکا بر توانمندسازهای مدل تعالی سازمانی EFQM  می‌توان زیرساخت‌ها و قابلیت‌های مورد نیاز کارآفرینی سازمانی را ایجاد نمود. لذا پس از شناسایی عوامل موثر بر پیاده‌سازی کارآفرینی سازمانی، این ویژگی‌ها با توجه به ماهیت‌شان در 4 معیار اصلی "رهبری"، "خط مشی و استراتژی"، "کارکنان" و "شراکت‌ها، منابع و فرآیندها" که همگی از ارکان توانمندساز مدل EFQM است، دسته‌بندی می‌شوند. این مقاله یک روش مدلسازی تحلیلی است که روابط بسیار کیفی میان عناصر کارآفرینی را عملیاتی می‌سازد. جهت تعیین روابط علی و معلولی و ضرایب وزنی اهمیت نسبی هر عنصر در مدل، از رویکرد یکپارچه‌سازی دیمتل‌فازی و مدل‌سازی فرآیند تحلیل شبکه‌ای فازی استفاده شده است. نتایج حاکی از آن است که در سطح معیارهای اصلی، "رهبری" دارای بیشترین شدت اثرگذاری و معیار "کارکنان" دارای بیشترین ضریب وزنی اهمیت نسبی است. همچنین در بخش زیرمعیارها "حمایت مدیریت ارشد" از لحاظ ضریب وزنی اهمیت نسبی و شدت اثرگذاری رتبه نخست را به خود اختصاص داده است. مدل ارزیابی کارآفرینی سازمانی ارائه شده در پژوهش مدلی جامع است که قابلیت بکارگیری در سازمان‌های مختلف را دارد. این مدل در سازمان توسعه برق ایران مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفته است.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">کارآفرینی سازمانی، مدل تعالی سازمانی EFQM، فرآیند تحلیل شبکه‌ای فازی، دیمتل فازی </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13951115225524863-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>49</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Proposing a superior model to localize technology in petrochemical industry by using of fuzzy multi-criteria decision-making method</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ارائه مدلی شاخص برای بومی‌سازی فناوری در صنعت پتروشیمی با استفاده از روش تصمیم‌گیری چند معیاره فازی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محمدعلي</FirstName><LastName>شفيعا</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName><LastName>علی احمدی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>بنیادی نائینی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>میر حمید</FirstName><LastName>تقوی</LastName><Affiliation>سیاستگذاری علم و فناوری-دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day></History><Abstract>The concept of indigenous technology and localization of technology, have been discussed in various circles, especially at the scientific and technological communities of developing countries. When these words are expressed, most minds are focused on the traditional industry. But in matters relating to technology transfer process and the need to consciously deal with imported technology, the concept of these words refer to the creation of structure and context for understanding and discovering of technical knowledge of imported technology and in fact, confirm the realization of a process that includes learning, absorption, reformation, compliance, internal development and big and small changes, and finally, the mastery of imported technology, innovation and its dissemination. While the mechanism of innovation in industrialized countries was well understood, but the process of localization and technology transfer that is considered as the main mechanisms of industrial development in developing countries, is still not clear.The statistical population of the study consisted of 40 managers, specialists and experts in the petrochemical industry, which has been selected by purposive sampling. In the current study, factors affecting localization of technology were extracted based on research literature and researchers studies in this field and successful experiences at academic center for education culture and research of Iran University of Science and Technology, Medical equipment manufacturing industry, Deffence industry, and Tajrobeh Nour Turbine Company as pertinent organizations involved in the issue. Methods used in deriving these factors are semi-structured interviews with experts in the petrochemical industry and validation method in the qualitative research. Quantitative techniques used in this research are: Fuzzy Analytical Network Process (FANP) to rank the criteria and sub-criteria, Fuzzy DEMATEL to determine the internal relationship between criteria and Fuzzy TOPSIS to prioritize models. The results show that there is a superior model to localize the technology in petrochemical industry.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">مفهوم فناوری بومی و بومی‌کردن فناوری سال‌هاست که موردبحث محافل گوناگون به‌ویژه مجامع علمی و فناوری کشورهای در حال رشد است. بابیان این واژه‌ها، اغلب ذهن‌ها به‌سوی صنعت سنتی متمرکز می‌شوند. اما در مباحث مربوط به فرآیند انتقال فناوری و لزوم برخورد آگاهانه با فناوری‌های وارداتی، مفهوم این واژه به ایجاد ساختار و زمینه‌ای برای درک و کشف دانش فنی فناوری وارداتی اشاره دارد و در واقع، مؤید تحقق فرآیندی است که شامل یادگیری، جذب و اصلاح و انطباق، توسعه داخلی و اعمال تغییرات کوچک و بزرگ و بالاخره، تسلط بر فناوری وارداتی، انجام نوآوری و اشاعه آن است. جامعه آماری این تحقیق، 40 نفر از مدیران، کارشناسان و خبرگان صنعت پتروشیمی می باشند که با روش نمونه گیری هدفمند انتخاب شدند. در این پژوهش، عوامل مؤثر بر بومی‌سازی فناوری با تکیه ‌بر ادبیات تحقیق و بررسی مطالعات پژوهشگران این حوزه و تجارب موفق بومی‌سازی فناوری در ایران با استفاده از روش مصاحبه نیمه ساخت‌یافته با خبرگان صنعت پتروشیمی و روش اعتباریابی در تحقیقات کیفی استخراج شدند. در بخش کمی تحقیق، روش تصمیم گیری چندمعیاره بکار برده شده است. برای رتبه‌بندی معیارها و زیرمعیارهای مؤثر بر هر مدل از فن تحلیل شبکه‌ای فازی، برای تعیین روابط درونی معیارها از فن دیمتل فازی و برای رتبه‌بندی مدل‌ها و انتخاب مدل برتر از تاپسیس فازی استفاده شده است. نتایج تحلیل نشان می‌دهند که مدلی برتر از بین مدل‌های موجود بومی‌سازی فناوری برای صنعت پتروشیمی وجود دارد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">بومی‌سازی فناوری،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
انتقال فناوری،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 تصمیم‌گیری چندمعیاره، </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
صنعت پتروشیمی،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 فازی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139602131444355871-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>49</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Design Evaluation System of Human Resources in the Social Security Fund of Semnan by using Fuzzy Data Envelopment Analysis</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>طراحی نظام ارزشیابی‌ نیروی انسانی در صندوق تأمین اجتماعي استان سمنان با استفاده از مدل تحليل پوششي داده‌هاي فازي</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>ابوالفضل </FirstName><LastName>دانایی</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سیده ناظره</FirstName><LastName>سیف هاشمی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد فیروزکوه</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day></History><Abstract>According to strategic importance of performance assessment, today a few limited numbers of organizations are going to guarantee the improvements of their personnel’s performance through an appropriate evaluation of their staff. For this purpose, the current research was done in social security fund of Semnan province. This research has followed a descriptive goal (based on a case study) with a comparative logic through a limited applicable process which is considered to be as the most crucial selected method in order to extract the information of documents and the organization. Receipt, tables and diagrams are referred to as the most important tools applied in this paper. The fuzzy data envelopment analysis was selected as the most appropriate method for analyzing the data based on the studies done. The results in this research indicate that the current traditional systems of assessment in the social security fund of Semnan province does not have enough efficiency and it does not have any effect on the increase of willingness and tendency of the staff. Therefore, a new system of assessment which was compiled on the basis of the fuzzy data envelopment analysis was represented to substitute the traditional system. This model had some strong points such as the personnel assessment without the manager`s verdict, having the ability to perform under the circumstance of uncertainly, the probable presence of an ideal virtual unit, and the evaluation of personnel based on the predetermined objects. There is a hope to see this part of the health services management to become more represented in the future by the conduction of the suggested assessment system in the research society.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">بر اساس اهميت استراتژيك ارزشيابي عملكرد، امروزه تعداد محدودي از سازمان‌ها به دنبال آن هستند كه از طريق ارزشيابي مناسب كاركنان خويش، بهسازي عملكرد كاركنان خود را تضمين نمايند. بر اين اساس در پژوهش حاضر اين موضوع در صندوق تامين‌اجتماعي استان سمنان دنبال شده است. اين تحقيق با منطق قياسي، هدفي توصيفي (مطالعه موردي) را با فرآيند اجرايي كمي دنبال كرده است كه مهم‌ترین روش انتخاب ‌شده جهت استخراج اطلاعات اسناد و اطلاعات سازماني است. از مهم‌ترین ابزار مورد كاربرد در اين تحقيق مي‌توان به فيش‌‌، جداول و نمودارها اشاره داشت. بر اساس مطالعات انجام‌شده مناسب‌ترين روش جهت تحليل اطلاعات، روش تحليل پوششي داده‌هاي فازي انتخاب شد. يافته‌هاي تحقيق حاكي است، سيستم ارزشيابي سنتي حاكم در صندوق تامين‌اجتماعي استان سمنان، از كارايي كافي برخوردار نبوده و در افزايش روحيه و تمايل كاركنان تأثیری ندارد. بر اين اساس، سيستم نوين ارزشيابي تدوين‌شده بر اساس مدل تحلیل پوششی داده¬های فازی، بر اساس نقاط قوتي چون استقلال از رأي مديران در ارزشيابي كاركنان، توان اجرايي در شرايط عدم اطمينان، امكان حضور واحد مجازي ايده‌آل و ارزشيابي كاركنان بر اساس اهداف از پيش تعیین‌شده، جهت جايگزيني براي سيستم سنتي ارائه شد. اميد است با اجراي سيستم ارزشيابي پيشنهادي در جامعه تحقيق، در آينده تجلي بیش‌ازپیش اين بخش از مديريت خدمات بهداشتي و درماني كشور ميسر گردد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value"> ارزشيابي كاركنان</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدل تحليل پوششي داده‌هاي فازي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
صندوق تامين‌اجتماعي استان سمنان</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139508181019373876-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>49</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>An Applicable Model for Diagnosing and Ranking the Key Success Factors of Project Risk Management (Case study: Research Institute of Petroleum Industry)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>یک مدل کاربردی در تشخیص و رتبه بندی فاکتورهای کلیدی موفقیت در پیاده سازی و اجرای نظام مديريت ريسك پروژه (موردکاوی: پژوهشگاه صنعت نفت)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محمدعلی</FirstName><LastName>هاتفی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعت نفت</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></History><Abstract>The purpose of project risk management is to improve project performance by systematically identifying and assessing risks, developing strategies to reduce threats and to maximize opportunities. According to our review, some key success factors have previously been identified in project risk management literature, but their importance relative to each other has yet been uncovered. This paper introduces an applicable model to diagnose and to rank the project risk management key success factors of an assumed project, using group decision-making. Surely, having the obtained rank may lead the project manager view toward focusing on critical points of project risk management. The proposed model could be used by the analysts of the other management fields. The paper ends with explaining a case study.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">مديريت ريسك پروژه عبارتست از فرايندي نظام مند براي شناسايي و ارزشيابي ريسك ها و توسعه پاسخ ها جهت كاهش تهديد ها و افزايش فرصت ها، در راستاي بهبود عملكرد پروژه. در ادبيات موضوع مديريت ريسك پروژه، برخی فاكتورها براي موفقيت مديريت ريسك، مطرح شده است اما تاکنون تلاشی برای رتبه بندی آنها صورت نگرفته است. مقاله حاضر، یک مدل کاربردی را ارائه می دهد که در آن با استفاده از نظرات خبرگان، فاکتورهای کلیدی موفقیت مدیریت ریسک یک پروژه مفروض، شناسایی شده و رتبه بندی می شوند. قطعا داشتن اطلاعات رتبه بندی این فاکتورها می تواند نگاه مد پروژه را برای تمرکز بر نقاط بحرانی مدیریت ریسک پروژه ه، هدایت نموده و از اتلاف منابع در این زمینه، جلوگیری نماید. مدل رتبه بندی ارائه شده در این مقاله می تواند برای تحلیلگران سایر حوزه های مدیریتی، علاوه بر مدیریت ریسک پروژه نیز سودمند واقع گردد. در انتهای مقاله، مطالعه موردی صورت گرفته با اعمال مدل پیشنهادی، ارائه شده است.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مديريت ريسك پروژه</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
فاكتورهاي كليدي موفقيت</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تصمیم گیری گروهی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13950822945553922-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>49</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effects of Cultural Intelligence and Transformational Leadership Style of Managers on Employee Resistance to Change</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بررسی تاثیرهوش فرهنگی و سبک رهبری تحول آفرین مدیران بر مقاومت کارکنان درمقابل تغییر</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>فخریه</FirstName><LastName>حمیدیان پور</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه خلیج فارس بوشهر</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مجید</FirstName><LastName>اسماعیل پور</LastName><Affiliation>ادبیات و علوم انسانی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>راضیه</FirstName><LastName>زارعی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه خلیج فارس بوشهر</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></History><Abstract>Abstract
Background: One of the most important challenges faced by organizations is the environmental factors’ change and increasing global competitions. In response to this challenge, it should be noted that change management is a difficult task. Most of organizational changes fail. Lack of personnel’s agreement with the change and their resistance are among the most important factors that cause the failure of organizational change.
Objective: The objective of this study was to evaluate the effect of two factors of cultural intelligence of managers and transformational leadership style on employees' resistance to change.
Methodology: The population of this research includes managers and employees of Jam Petrochemical Company (Iran). The sample consisted of 260 employees and 60 managers of various units of the company. Data were collected using the tool of questionnaire. To analyze the data SMART PLS structural equation modeling software was used.
Results: The findings of this study show that cultural intelligence of managers both directly and through transformational leadership style has a positive and significant impact on the resistance to change and also the transformational leadership style has a positive and significant impact on the resistance to change.

</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">چکیده 
زمینه: یکی از مهم‏ترین چالش‏هایی که سازمان‏ها با آنها مواجه‏اند، تغییر عوامل محیطی و رقابت فزاینده‏ی جهانی است. در پاسخ به این چالش، مديريت تغيير وظيفه بسيار دشواري است. غالب تغییرات سازمانی با شکست مواجه می‏شوند. عدم همراهی کارکنان با تغییر و مقاومت آنان در مقابل تغییر از جمله مهم‏ترین عوامل شکست تغییرات سازمانی می‏باشد. 
هدف: هدف این پژوهش، بررسی تاثیر دو عامل هوش فرهنگی  مدیران و سبک رهبری تحول‏آفرین  بر مقاومت در برابر تغییر  کارکنان است.
روش‏شناسی: تحقیق حاضر از نظر هدف، کاربردی و از نظر گردآوری داده ها از نوع توصیفی- پیمایشی و همبستگی می باشد. جامعه آماری این پژوهش را مدیران و کارکنان شرکت پتروشیمی‏جم(ایران) تشکیل می‏دهند. نمونه آماری این پژوهش شامل 260 نفر از کارکنان و 60 نفر از مدیران واحد‏های مختلف این شرکت می‏باشد. ابزار گردآوری داده‏ها پرسشنامه است. برای تجزیه و تحلیل داده‏ها از مدل یابی معادلات ساختاری به کمک نرم افزارSMART PLS استفاده شده است.
یافته‏ها: یافته‏های این پژوهش نشان می‏دهد که هوش فرهنگی مدیران هم به طور مستقیم و هم از طریق سبک رهبری تحول‏آفرین بر مقاومت در برابر تغییر تاثیر مثبت و معناداری دارد و همچنین سبک رهبری تحول‏آفرین بر مقاومت در برابر تغییر تاثیر مثبت و معناداری دارد. 
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سبک رهبری تحول‏آفرین، هوش فرهنگی مدیران، مقاومت در برابر تغییر</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13950825202793959-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>49</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Applied Science pathology training institutions skill Gilan province Tuesday ramifications approach and the Analytic Hierarchy Process( AHP)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>آسیب شناسی دوره های آموزشی موسسات جامع علمی کاربردی مهارت استان گیلان با رویکرد سه شاخگی و  به روش تحلیل  سلسله مراتبی AHP))</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName><LastName>المئی</LastName><Affiliation>دانش آموخته دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مهناز </FirstName><LastName>همتی نوعدوست گیلانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>رقیه </FirstName><LastName>یوسف نژاد لزرجانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد تهران واحد الکترونیکی</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></History><Abstract>In a society tailored to their circumstances, culture, growth and decline with a variety of diversions and problems facing a damaging effect on the development of the society. Understanding these factors can pave the path of society towards progress and interaction, so that in addition to understanding their function and prevent the continuation of the practice of offering solutions to the community health. In particular education and training leading to employment, such as science, alongside acts like the University of Applied Sciences is not exempt from this. In the meantime, effective training that leads to the target and output is beneficial to society, so we are going to achieve this important come the problems facing education. The research was conducted with the help of experts, a questionnaire was designed after consecutive sessions and then clinched the variables that affect its validity and reliability was determined. Cronbach's alpha coefficient is 0.831, which has demonstrated the reliability of Likert type and weight them using analytic hierarchy in paired comparison questionnaire (Questionnaire 2) and index vulnerable, to prioritize and to the manager to decide the was. Recommended to use this hybrid model for other teaching institutions</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در جامعه‌ای متناسب با شرایط خود ، فرهنگ، رشد و انحطاط خود با انواعی از انحرافات و مشکلات روبروست که تاثیرات مخربی روی فرآیند ترقی آن جامعه دارد. شناخت چنین عواملی می‌تواند مسیر حرکت جامعه را بسوی ترقی و تعامل هموار سازد، بطوری که علاوه بر درک عمل آنها و جلوگیری از تداوم آن عمل با ارائه راه حل هایی به سلامت جامعه کمک نماید. آموزش و بالاخص آموزش منجر به  اشتغال همانند علم در کنار عمل مانند دانشگاه علمی کاربردی از این امر مستثنی نیست. در این بین آموزشی موثر است که منجر به هدف  و بازده مفید برای جامعه گردد، لذا برآنیم تا با رفع مشکلات  پیش روی آموزش به این مهم نائل آییم. دراین پژوهش که به کمک خبرگان انجام شد، پس از جلسات متوالی پرسشنامه ای طراحی و پس از مسجل شدن روایی و پایایی آن  شاخص های موثر را مشخص شد. ضریب آلفای کرونباخ  نیز 0.831گردیده که نشان از پایایی پرسشنامه اول با طیف لیکرت دارد و وزن آنها را به کمک تحلیل سلسله مراتبی در پرسشنامه مقایسات زوجی (پرسشنامه شماره2) یافته و شاخص های آسیب پذیر، اولویت بندی و در اختیار مدیر برای تصمیم گیری قرار گرفت. پیشنهاد می گردد از این مدل ترکیبی برای سایر موسسات آموزشی استفاده گردد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">آسیب شناسی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
سه  شاخگی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تحلیل سلسله مراتبی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
جامع علمی کاربردی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139508262323223977-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>49</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Entrepreneurial approach, the dominant approach to creating strategies  In Iranian Successful companies</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>رویکرد کارآفرینی، رویکرد غالب خلق استراتژی در شرکت های موفق ایران</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>سید محمود</FirstName><LastName>حسینی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>بهمن</FirstName><LastName>حاجی پور</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>هوشنگ</FirstName><LastName>نظامی وند چگینی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></History><Abstract>Identifying pure and favorable strategies is one of the main concerns of managers and leaders in organizations and this managerial issue has become an important field for research. Many scholars in strategic management field have tried to provide multiple approaches or styles for strategy formation in the organizations. An effective way to identify strategy formation approach is to investigate how successful organizations are directed and lead. In this way, the reliable methods of strategy formation can be achieved by investigation of the organizations. 
This paper presents the result of a wide study on strategy formation approaches in Iranian organizations. Firstly, using taxonomical statistic method, five successful companies among 29 companies from various industries were selected as a result of their first ranking in their industrial groups during 2011-2013. To do this, six performance indices including asset returns, profit margin, human productivity, market share and sale rate, and profit growth rate were employed. Through the identification of the companies, their revolution trends were examined and the most important strategies leading to their success were determined. Finally, using a questionnaire and a sample of 150 top and middle managers of the surveyed organizations, their strategy formation approaches were identified. 
Entrepreneurial approach in strategy formation was more effective than formal approach or strategic planning, strategic venturing approach, and strategic learning approach. In some organizations, a combination of two approaches, namely strategic planning approach and entrepreneurial approach were utilized to formulate their strategies. Hence, it is obvious that among investigated companies, this is entrepreneurial approach that can be considered as reliable to formulate successful strategies. 
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">شناسایی استراتژی های ناب و مناسب از دغدغه های اصلی مدیران و رهبران سازمانها به شمار می رود و این موضوع در مدیریت نیز تبدیل به موضوعی مهم برای تحقیق و پژوهش شده است. بسیاری از اندیشمندان حوزه مدیریت استراتژیک تلاش کرده اند تا رویکردها یا سبک های متعددی برای خلق استراتژی در سازمانها ارائه کنند. یکی از شیوه های شناسایی رویکردهای خلق استراتژی بررسی نحوه هدایت و رهبری سازمانهای موفق است. بررسی این سازمانها می تواند روش های قابل اتکای خلق استراتژی را معرفی نماید.
این مقاله نتیجه یک مطالعه گسترده در خصوص رویکردهای خلق استراتژی در سازمانهای ایرانی را ارائه می کند. ابتدا با بکارگیری روش  آماری تاکسونومی تلاش شده است تا در بین 29 شرکت عضو گروه های مختلف صنعتی 5 شرکت موفق که در بیشتر سالهای 1380 تا 1392 رتبه های نخست گروه صنعتی خود را بدست آورده اند شناسایی شود. برای این منظور از 6 شاخص عملکرد بازده دارایی،حاشیه سود،بهره وری نیروی انسانی ،سهم بازار ، نرخ رشد فروش و نرخ رشد سودآوری استفاده شده است. پس از شناسایی این شرکت ها روند تحول آنها بررسی و مهمترین استراتژی هایی که موجب موفقیت آنها شده است تعیین شد. در نهایت با استفاده از مطالعه ای پرسشنامه ای و بهره گیری از مشارکت بیش از 150 مدیر ارشد و میانی این سازمانها رویکرد خلق استراتژی های آنها شناسایی شد.  
رویکرد کارآفرینی  در خلق استراتژی برای این سازمانها و در مقایسه با رویکردرسمی یا برنامه ریزی استراتژیک، رویکرد اقدام اکتشافانه و رویکرد  یادگیری استراتژیک کارآمد تر بوده است و در برخی از سازمانها نیز از تلفیقی از دو رویکرد رسمی یا برنامه ریزی استراتژیک و کارآفرینی است که منشاء استراتژی های آنها بوده است. بدین ترتیب پیداست که در مجموعه مورد بررسی این رویکرد کارآفرینی است که می تواند برای خلق استراتژی های موفق قابل اتکا باشد.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">رویکرد خلق استراتژی </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
کارآفرینی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
برنامه ریزی استراتژیک</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
یادگیری استراتژیک</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 اقدام اکتشافانه استراتژیک</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139509121842474093-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>49</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Relationship between quality of work life and organizational commitment:the role of moderators Employee empowerment</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>رابطه بین کیفیت زندگی کاری و تعهد سازمانی: نقش تعدیلگر توانمندسازی کارکنان</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>امیر </FirstName><LastName>غفوریان شاگردی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام رضا</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>امید</FirstName><LastName>بهبودی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد شاهرود</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></History><Abstract>The aim of the present research, the role of employee empowerment in the relationship between quality of work life and their organizational commitment. The present research  is of a descriptive- correlative type that is based on the Census; 80 questionnaires were distributed among  Staff Imam Hasan Mojtaba hospitals in Kalat. The data collection tools were 3 questionnaires: quality of work life questionnaire (1973), the organizational commitment questionnaire of Allen and Meyer (1990),  the Spreitzer’s empowerment questionnaire (1996). To determine the reliability coefficient of the questionnaires , Cronbach's alpha coefficient was used . Cronbach's alpha coefficients obtained for the three questionnaires, 85%, 78% and 92% respectively. To analyze the data, structural equation modeling and multiple regression was used. The findings show that the quality of work life and organizational commitment have a significant relationship.There is also a relationship between the quality of working life and employee empowerment (with the possibility of 99% have been identified. The results also show that employee empowerment have significant relationship with organizational commitment((with the possibility of 99% . In addition, research findings suggest an indirect impact the quality of working life on Organizational commitment this effect with the number 0.45 and is marked with 99% probability.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف این تحقیق بررسی نقش توانمندسازی کارکنان در رابطه بین کیفیت زندگی کاری و تعهدسازمانی آنان  است. تحقیق حاضر از نوع توصیفی – همبستگی بوده که به شیوه تمام شماری، تعداد 80 پرسشنامه بین پرسنل شاغل در بیمارستان امام حسن مجتبی (ع) شهرستان کلات توزیع شد. در این پژوهش ابزار جمع آوری اطلاعات  پرسشنامه¬ی، پرسشنامه  کیفیت زندگی کاری والتون (1973)، پرسشنامه تعهد سازمانی آلن و میر (1990)،و پرسشنامه  توانمندسازی کارکنان اسپریتزر (1996) است. برای تعیین ضریب پایایی پرسشنامه ها از ضریب آلفاکرونباخ استفاده شده که مقدار ضریب بدست آمده برای سه پرسشنامه مذکور به ترتیب  85% ، 78% و 92%  بود. برای تجزیه و تحلیل داده¬ها از آزمون رگرسیون چندگانه و مدلیابی معادلات ساختاری استفاده شد. یافتـه¬های پژوهش نشـان می¬دهـد که کیفیت زندگی¬کاری با تعهدسازمانی در ارتباط بوده و بر آن اثر گذار است ، همچنین وجود رابطه بین کیفیت زندگی کاری با توانمندسازی کارکنان  با احتمال 99 درصد شناسایی شده است . همچنین وجود رابطه معنادار بین توانمندسازی کارکنان و تعهد سازمانی  با احتمال 99 درصد شناسایی شده است .  علاوه بر این تاثیرات، یافته های تحقیق حاکی از تاثیر غیر مستقیم کیفیت زندگی کاری بر تعهدسازمانی است که این تاثیر با احتمال 99 درصد مشخص شده است. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">کیفیت زندگی کاری، تعهد سازمانی، توانمندسازی کارکنان</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13950930146434246-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>49</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>The impact of Lifestyle portal design on the change of lifestyle</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بررسی تاثیر طراحی پرتال سبک زندگی  بر تغییر سبک زندگی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محمد رضا </FirstName><LastName>تقوا</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>کامران </FirstName><LastName>فیضی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سید محمدعلی</FirstName><LastName>خاتمی فیروزآبادی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سمیرا</FirstName><LastName> قندچی </LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></History><Abstract>The emergence of information technology into human’s life, the lifestyle of human has gone through great changes and has influenced different dimensions of human life. In the meantime, as the portal is one of the most effective tools of information technology have been identified the research is going to investigating the influential of lifestyle portal design on the Human lifestyle changes. For this study, in the first Phase this research has looked into the literature of different dimensions of lifestyle and then been approved by the elite and experts of sociology science. After that, for extract of the effective variables of lifestyle portal, researcher used  deep interview and understanding and also Delphi method and then these variables have been extracted by the experts of information technology. The research method is survey. The population of the research: doctorate students of Allameh Tababaei IT management, Tehran University, Master students of Khaje Nasir toosi University in IT management section and the experts in IT in some parts of Tehran. A number of 100 subjects were selected using random sampling method and the data were collected using a researcher-constructed questionnaire.  The results showed that, the effect of the lifestyle portal on changing lifestyle with the certainty of 99% was approved.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">با توجه به گستردگی و پیچیدگی  جامعه انسانی و همچنین با ورود فناوری اطلاعات به زندگی بشر سبک و سیاق زندگی تغییر چشمگیری داشته است و توانسته است ابعاد مختلفی از زندگی انسان را تحت تاثیر قرار دهد. این پژوهش به بررسی تاثیر یکی از زمینه های فناوری اطلاعات تحت عنوان پرتال سبک زندگی و تاثیر آن بر تغییر سبک زندگی اختصاص دارد. هدف اصلی این تحقیق مشخص کردن تاثیرگذاری طراحی مدل پرتال سبک زندگی بر تغییر سبک زندگی می‌باشد. بدین منظور ابتدا از مرور ادبیات به استخراج ابعاد تاثیرگذار بر سبک زندگی پرداخته سپس توسط خبرگان جامعه شناسی این ابعاد مورد تایید قرار گرفته است. با مطالعه کتابخانه‌ای، مصاحبه عمیق و روش دلفی توسط خبرگان فناوری اطلاعات عوامل تاثیرگذار بر طراحی پرتال سبک زندگی استخراج شده است. روش پژوهش پیمایشی می‌باشد. جامعه آماری تحقیق: دانشجویان دکتری مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی ، دانشگاه تهران، تربیت مدرس و دانشجویان ارشد  مهندسی فناوری اطلاعات دانشگاه خواجه نصیرالدین طوسی و خبرگان فناوری اطلاعات در برخی از شرکت‌های انفورماتیک واقع در شهر تهران می‌باشند.از بین جامعه اماری 100 نفر با استفاده از روش نمونه گیری تصادفی نمونه گیری شده و اطلاعات مورد نیاز به کمک ابزار پرسشنامه جمع آوری شد. یافته های پژوهش تاثیر طراحی پرتال را برتغییر سبک زندگی و عوامل موثر بر طراحی پرتال را با اطمینان 99 درصد مورد تایید قرار داد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سبک زندگی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
فناوری‌ اطلاعات</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
فناوری ارتباطات</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
پرتال</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139511132336434844-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>49</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Strategic analysis of citizen satisfaction with service quality of Shiraz҆ urban parks by using multi criteria satisfaction analysis</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تحلیل استراتژیک رضایت شهروندان از کیفیت خدمات پارک¬های شهری شیراز با استفاده از مدل تجزیه و تحلیل چند معیاره رضایت</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>محمدی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>بنیادی نائینی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>کمیل</FirstName><LastName>فتاحی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مهین</FirstName><LastName>ثابت سروستانی</LastName><Affiliation>تربیت مدرس</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day></History><Abstract>The purpose of this research is to use of multi criteria satisfaction method for segment analysis citizen satisfaction with service quality of urban parks of Shiraz. The statistical population consists of all citizens that visiting urban parks of Shiraz and sample size is 384. Method of sampling is stratified random sampling method. The researcher-made questionnaire was used to measure the variables of study. The reliability of the questionnaire was determined using Cronbach’s alpha test (α=0.91).   The face validity and factor analysis was considered as validity of research. The result showed that dimension of citizen satisfaction with service quality of Shiraz҆ urban parks are Aesthetic and visual aspects, Park amenities, facilities and services, Physical health and safety of park, Social and psychological safety and Dynamic management of the park. Also the most satisfaction level in related to Jannat park and the least satisfaction level in related to Koohpayeh. In other hand, action diagrams indicated municipal of Shiraz almost in all of satisfaction criteria has low performance those requiring immediate improvement efforts for removing these weak points. </Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">احساس رضایت شهروندان از خدماتی که شهرداری ارائه می¬دهد، عامل مهمی در جهت ایجاد انگیزه درآن¬ها برای مشارکت در توسعه شهری و بهبود کیفیت محل سکونت آن¬ها است. در حال حاضر، در ایران شهرداری¬ به عنوان سازمانی نیمه دولتی، ارائه دهنده خدمات مرتبط با پارک¬ها و فضاهای سبز شهری است. درک ابعاد مهم رضایت از ارائه این خدمات و میزان رضایت شهروندان از آن¬ها می¬تواند به سازمان پارک¬ها و فضای سبز شهرداری در برنامه ریزی¬های آینده برای تخصیص بودجه محدود خود کمک کند، از این رو هدف این پژوهش مدلسازی و تحلیل بخشی  رضایت شهروندان ساکن شیراز از کیفیت خدمات پارک¬های شهری این شهر با روشی کمی مبتنی بر برنامه ریزی خطی به نام روش تجزیه و تحلیل چند معیاره رضایت (موسا) است. بنابراین پس از شناسایی ابعاد موثر بر رضایت شهروندان از پارک های شهری ساختار سلسله مراتبی آن ترسیم شد. سپس از این ساختار برای طراحی پرسشنامه رضایت سنجی استفاده شد در نهایت داده های حاصل از پرسشنامه نیز با روش تجزیه و تحلیل چند معیاره رضایت تحلیل شد. جامعه آماری پژوهش تمامی شهروندان ساکن شیراز است که از پارک¬های شهری این شهر استفاده می¬کنند. نمونه‌گیری به روش چندمرحله¬ای و ابزار گردآوری داده¬ها پرسش‌نامه است. نتایج پژوهش نشان داد، ابعاد موثر بر رضایت شهروندان از کیفیت خدمات پارک¬های شهری شامل زیبایی و جنبه¬های بصری، امکانات رفاهی، تسهیلات و خدمات، ایمنی بهداشتی و فیزیکی، ایمنی اجتماعی و روانی و مدیریت پویای پارک است، که با توجه به این ابعاد بیشترین سطح رضایت مربوط به پارک جنت و کمترین آن مربوط به پارک کوهپایه است. همچنین منحنی-های عملکرد نیز نشان دادند که شهرداری شیراز در اکثر شاخص¬های مورد بررسی عملکرد ضعیفی دارد که نیاز به برنامه ریزی صحیح برای رفع نقاط ضعف خود دارد. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">پارک شهری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 سنجش رضایت</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدل تجزیه و تحلیل چند معیاره رضایت</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
کیفیت خدمات</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
رضایت شهروندان  </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13950526114803137-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>49</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>An Investigation into the impact of Inter-university resource allocation mechanisms on educational and research performance of departments </ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر سازوکارهای تخصیص منابع مالی درون دانشگاهی بر عملکرد آموزشی و پژوهشی گروه‌های آموزشی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>97</FirstPage><LastPage>108</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>فرزانه</FirstName><LastName>قاسمی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>حمید</FirstName><LastName>فرهادی راد</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مسعود</FirstName><LastName>خداپناه</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد رضا</FirstName><LastName>آخوند</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day></History><Abstract>     The main purpose of this research was to investigate the effect of internal financial resource allocation mechanisms on the educational and research performance of departments. Present study could be classified as a theoretical-applied research in terms of objectives and descriptive-analytic as well as correlational in terms of methodology. Shahid Chamran University was selected as the statistical population and all the required data concerning faculties and departments was collected. In order to collect the required data in the time domain of 2010-2013, documents and records held by different units of the university were scrutinized and reviewed. For data analysis, descriptive statistics tables including average growth rates, means, standard deviations and correlation coefficients were developed while to determine the relationships between variables and fit regression models of interest, inferential statistics and multilevel modelling methods were used. The results show that: (1) values do not have the same structure and homogeneity and there is a dissonance between time units and departments. The calculated statistics for research performance (ρ=0.68) and academic performance (ρ=0.52) indicates the necessity of using multilevel modeling. 2) Managerial and educational performance of the departments per faculty member during the study period has encountered some fluctuations and the general trend of these indices has been increasing 3) each department has experienced an individual trend. 4) The mechanisms of financial resource allocation significantly affect educational and research performances of the departments.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف اصلی این پژوهش بررسی تأثیر سازوکار تخصیص منابع مالی درون دانشگاهی بر عملکرد آموزشی و پژوهشی گروه‌های آموزشی بود. پژوهش حاضر ازنظر هدف در گروه تحقیقات نظری- کاربردی بوده و ازنظر روش از نوع توصیفی- تحلیلی و روش همبستگي است.13 دانشکده و 53 گروه آموزشی  دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز به‌عنوان جامعه آماري انتخاب و داده‌هاي آماري در خصوص همه دانشکده‌ها و گروه‌های آموزشی دانشگاه گردآوری‌شده است. به‌منظور جمع‌آ‌وري داده‌هاي موردنیاز در قلمرو زماني 92-1389،  چک‌لیست‌های ساخته شده و با مطالعه اسناد، اطلاعات و مدارك موجود در واحدهای سازمانی دانشگاه استفاده، داده ها جمع آوری گردید. به‌منظور تعيين روابط بين متغيرها و برازش الگوهای رگرسیونی موردنظر از آمار استنباطي و روش آماري الگو‌سازي چند سطحي استفاده‌شده است. نتایج نشان می‌دهد که: 1- داده‌ها از ساختار يكسان و همگني برخوردار نبوده و بين واحدهاي زماني و بين گروه‌هاي آموزشي ناهمساني وجود دارد. ميزان آماره محاسبه‌شده برای عملکرد پژوهشی ( ) و عملکرد آموزشی( ) نشان‌دهنده ضرورت به‌کارگیری الگوسازي چند سطحی است.2- عملکرد پژوهشی و عملکرد آموزشی گروه‌های آموزشی به ازای هر عضو هیئت‌علمی در طول دوره موردبررسی با تغییراتی مواجه و روند کلی این شاخص‌ها افزایشی بوده است. 3- هر یک از گروه‌ها روند افزایش عملکردی متفاوتی را تجربه کرده است. 4- سازوکارهای تخصیص منابع مالی، عملکرد پژوهشی و عملکرد آموزشی گروه¬ها را به‌طور معنی‌داری تحت تأثیر قرار می‌دهد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سازوکارهای تخصیص، </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تخصیص منابع، </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
عملکرد آموزشی،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 عملکرد پژوهشی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13950917014484134-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>