﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>2-ب</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Measurement of Economic-Management Tourism Dimensions of Religious, Modern and Local Tourism in Iran</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بررسی ابعاد و زوایای اقتصادی-مدیریتی اکو توریسم، توریسم مذهبی-تاریخی و مدرن در ایران</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>97</FirstPage><LastPage>108</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>سمیرا</FirstName><LastName>متقی</LastName><Affiliation>اقتصاد</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>اصغر</FirstName><LastName>ابوالحسنی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></History><Abstract>Different dimensions of tourism and its relations with religious is an important issue in state management and religious stability planning. According to the important of recognizing correlation between different types of tourism with economy, the paper has studied the tendency of managers to modern, local and religious tourism. In fact, the paper is measured the quantity of managers tourism tendencies. A researcher-made questionnaire was used to collect information. The results showed that the relationship between all independent variables of research with the dimensions of collective tourism (religious, local/Eco-Tourism and modern) was significant. Among the variables, the value tendency system with a coefficient of 0.13 and religiosity with a regression coefficient of 0.255 are the most effective variables on religious tourism. The results also show that the variables of language and dialect with an effect level of 183/0, education with a coefficient of 142 religiosity with a coefficient of 0.41 are the most effective variables on local tourism. In the case of modern tourism, the variables of the value tendency system with the effect of 0.136, and religiosity with the coefficient of regression of -0.176 are the most effective variables on modern tourism.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">توریسم یکی از رهیافت¬های مدیریتی کارامد در افزایش بهره¬وری اقتصادی در دنیای امروز است. دولت¬ها برای افزایش درآمدهای خود، رغبت فزاینده¬ای به مدیریت کارامد توریسم و افزایش مزیت¬های اقتصادی آن نشان داده¬اند. در ایران نیز بررسی راهکارها و شیوه¬های بهره¬وری مناسب از ظرفیت¬های توریستی و مزیت¬های اقتصادی آن، از جمله ضروریات کشور به¬شمار می¬آید. با توجه به اهمیت شناخت رابطه میان ابعاد مختلف مدیریت توریسم یا ظرفیت¬های اقتصادی آن، پژوهش حاضر به بررسی این مسأله پرداخته است که مدیران و مسئولان ذیربط نسبت به ابعاد مختلف توریسم شامل توریسم مذهبی-تاریخی، محلی و مدرن چه اولویت¬هایی در نظر دارند و ترجیحات بهره¬ورانه (اقتصادی) آنها بیشتر متمایل به کدام نوع از توریسم است. بدین منظور این پژوهش با روش پیمایشی و با استفاده از پرسشنامه به بررسی ابعاد و زوایای اقتصادی-مدیریتی توریسم در ایران پرداخته است. نتایج نشان داد که رابطۀ تمام متغیرهای مستقل پژوهش با ابعاد اقتصاد توریسم (مذهبی-تاریخی، اکوتوریسم و مدرن) معنا‌دار بوده است. متغیرهای نظام تمایلات ارزشی با ضریب 130/0 و دین‌داری با ضریب 215/0 مؤثرترین متغیرها بر توریسم مذهبی-تاریخی هستند. متغیرهای فرهنگ و طبیعت با میزان تأثیر 183/0، مؤثرترین متغیرها بر اکوتوریسم هستند. در خصوص توریسم مدرن  نیز متغیرهای نظام تمایلات ارزشی با میزان تأثیر 136/0، و حقوق و آزادی گردشگران با ضریب 176/0- مؤثرترین متغیرها محسوب می¬شوند.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مدیریت توریسم، اقتصاد توریسم، توریسم مذهبی-تاریخی، توریسم مدرن، اکوتوریسم</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139607181315198464-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>