﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>1-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Structural Pattern of the Effects of Total Quality Management Components on Staff’s job Performance Along with Moderating Role of Organizational Factors in Teacher Training Universities</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>الگوي ساختاري اثر مؤلفههاي مديريت کيفيت جامع بر عملکرد شغلي کارکنان ستادي با نقش تعديل کننده عوامل سازماني در دانشگاههاي فرهنگيان</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>255</FirstPage><LastPage>268</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>اکبر</FirstName><LastName>کشاورزی</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day></History><Abstract>The main purpose of this research was to explore the effect of total quality management’ (TQM) components on the job performance of the employees considering the moderating effect of personal factors in teacher education universities of Iran. This study was conducted using correlational research method. Its statistical population consisted of all the staff employees working in the teacher education universities situated in 32 provinces of Iran (n=2553). Using Kerjesi-Morgan table and random cluster sampling method, a sample of 335 subjects was selected. Data collection was done using four questionnaires including TQM’s questionnaire developed by US Federal Quality Institute, Paterson’s (2000) job performance questionnaire and two self-designed questionnaires on the personal knowledge and skill factors which were checked and confirmed by the respective experts and practitioners in terms of their validity. Estimated using Cronbach’s alpha, the reliability of four questionnaires was found to be 0.97, 0.92, 0.95 and 0.74, respectively. As per the results, there was a statistically significant relationship between the components of customer focus, employee empowerment and teamwork, quality analysis, quality assurance and quality improvement and the job performance with the moderating effect of personal knowledge (P&lt;0.01). Furthermore, considering the skill as the moderator variable, a statistically significant relationship was observed between the top management support and leadership, strategic planning, customer focus, quality assurance and quality improvement and the job performance of the employees in question(P&lt;0.01). ). It is suggested that Teacher Training Universities apply Total Quality Management to improve job performance of their staff, where organizational culture and   organizational support play a key role.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        </Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف ازپژوهش حاضر بررسي الگوي ساختاري اثر مؤلفههاي مديريت کيفيت جامع بر عملکرد شغلي کارکنان ستادي با نقش تعديل کننده عوامل سازماني در دانشگاههاي فرهنگيان بود.روش پژوهش توصیفی- همبستگی و جامعه آماری شامل کارمندان ستادی32 دانشگاه در سال 1395و  به تعداد 2553 نفر بود. حجم نمونه  بر اساس  جدول  كرجسي  و مورگان 335 نفر  و روش نمونه گیری خوشه ای تصادفی بود. برای جمع آوری داده ها از پرسشنامه‌هاي مدیریت کیفیت فراگیر موسسه کیفیت فدرال آمریکا، عملکرد شغلي پاترسون (2000)، فرهنگ سازماني دنيسون و اسپريترز( 1991) و حمايت سازماني اينرنبرگر و همكاران ( 1986) استفاده شد. پایایی پرسشنامه ها بر اساس آلفای کرونباخ به ترتيب 97/0 -92/0 – 95 /0 و 74/0 برآورد گردید. داده‌ها با نرم افزار PLS وspss23 مورد تحلیل قرار گرفت. نتایج نشان داد مؤلفه‌هاي تمرکز بر مشتری، توانمندسازی کارکنان و کار تیمی، تجزیه و تحلیل کیفیت؛ تضمین کیفیت و بهبود کیفیت با نقش تعدیل گر فرهنگ سازمانی با عملکرد شغلی رابطه دارد (01/0 &gt; P ). هم چنین بین مؤلفه‌هاي حمایت و رهبری مدیریت عالی، برنامه ریزی استراتژیک، تمرکز بر مشتری؛ تضمین کیفیت و بهبود کیفیت با نقش تعدیل گرحمایت سازمانی با عملکرد شغلی رابطه دارد ( 01/0P&gt;).
پیشنهاد می شود در دانشگاه فرهنگیان از مدیریت کیفیت جامع برای بهبود عملکرد شغلی کارکنان استفاده شود و در این میان متغیرهای فرهنگ سازمانی و حمایت سازمانی نقش اساسی دارند. 
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مدیریت کیفیت فراگیر عملکرد شغلي فرهنگ سازماني حمايت سازماني دانشگاه فرهنگيان</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139603131921336340-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>