﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>55</Volume><Issue>2-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Identifying Evaluation Criteria for the Political Behaviors of Chief Administrative Officers at Bank Maskan Iran Using  DEMATEL - Fuzzy Delphi Technique</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>شناسایی معیارهای ارزیابی رفتار سیاسی مدیران ارشد بانک مسکن ایران با استفاده از تکنیک‌آزمایش وتحلیل‌تصمیم‌گیری(DEMATEL)- دلفی فازی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>137</FirstPage><LastPage>160</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>ناصر</FirstName><LastName>پورصادق</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه عالی دفاع ملی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>رشید </FirstName><LastName>ذوالفقاری زعفرانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد رودهن</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>امیر</FirstName><LastName>رضایی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد رودهن</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></History><Abstract>The role of effective and efficient management is becoming more important in today’s competitive world which is undoubtedly full of complexity, ambiguity, and uncertainty in challenging situations, competitions, and conflicts. People associate power with many advantages; therefore, they make many efforts to gain it in organizations. Battling for power raises the discussion of political behaviors in organizations. The aim of this study was to present a multi-index decision-making fuzzy hybrid model of qualitative analysis to identify the dimensions and indices of political behavior occurrence among CAOs at the branches of Bank Maskan in Tehran by using a fuzzy Delphi technique. Moreover, the decision-making trial and evaluation laboratory (DEMATEL) technique was employed to determine how influential and influenceable the indices were. The statistical population included 20 CAOs (Bank Maskan) with at least 10 years of executive and management experience. The research results indicated that Personal Characteristics became known as the most influential dimension with the highest value of (R-J) (1.244) among the evaluation criteria for political behaviors of CAOs at Bank Maskan. Moreover, Occupational Attitudes became identified as the most influenceable dimension according to the lowest value of (R-J) (1.358). Given the highest value of (R+J), Personal Characteristics interacted the most with other dimensions (1.244).</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA"> در دنيای امروز که بدون شک مملو از پيچيدگی، ابهام، عدم اطمينان و موقعيت‌های چالش‌برانگیز، رقابت‌ها و 
تعارض‌هاست، نقش مديريت اثربخش وکارآمد، اهميت بيشتری می‌يابد. قدرت برای افراد دارای مزايای زيادی است؛ لذا برای به دست‌آوردن آن در سازمان‌ها دست به تلاش می‌زنند. نزاع بر سر قدرت، بحث رفتارهای سياسی در سازمان را پديد می‌آورد. هدف‌ازانجام ‌پژوهش‌حاضر ارائه‌یک ‌مدل‌ترکیبی فازی تصمیم‌گیری چند شاخصه و تحلیل کیفی، جهت شناسایی ابعاد و شاخص‌های وقوع رفتارسیاسی مدیران ارشد بانک مسکن در شعب تهران، با استفاده از تکنیک دلفی فازی وتعیین شدت اثر‌گذاری و اثر‌پذیری شاخص‌ها با استفاده از تکنیک آزمایش‌و تحلیل‌تصمیم‌گیری(دیمتل) می‌باشد. جامعه آماری پژوهش حاضر را 20 نفر از مدیران ارشد سازمان‌های دولتی( بانک مسکن) که حداقل دارای 10 سال سابقه کار اجرایی و مدیریتی هستند، تشکیل می‌دهند. نتایج پژوهش حاضر نشان می‌دهد که بعد ویژگی‌های فردی، اثرگذارترین بعد، دارای بیش‌ترین مقدار (R-J)، بامقدار (244/1) و بدین ترتیب، با نفوذترین بعد در میان ابعاد مورد بررسی سنجش رفتار سیاسی مدیران ارشد بانک مسکن قرار می‌گیرد. همچنین بر اساس کمترین مقدار(R-J)، بعد نگرش های شغلی با مقدار(358/1)، اثرپذیرترین بعد می‌باشد. براساس بیشترین مقدار(R+J)، بعد ویژگی‌های فردی،  با مقدار(244/1)، بیشترین تعامل را با بقیه ابعاد داراست.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">رفتار سیاسی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 مدیران ارشد</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 بانک مسکن</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تکنیک آزمایش و تحلیل تصمیم‌گیری(دیمتل)</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تکنیک دلفی فازی.</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13960425557526997-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>