﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>1-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Identifying and ranking the effective factors on hospital teams' productivity using ANP-BWM approach (A case study: The Sadjad hospital in Tehran)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>شناسايي و رتبه‌بندی شاخص‌های بهره‌وری تیم‌های کاری بيمارستاني با استفاده از رويكرد ANP-BWM (مورد کاوی: بیمارستان سجاد تهران)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>111</FirstPage><LastPage>124</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مرضيه</FirstName><LastName>مظفري</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد الکترونیکی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>عبدالرضا</FirstName><LastName>کریمی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد الکترونیکی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>رامبد</FirstName><LastName> باران دوست</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد یادگار امام (ره)</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day></History><Abstract>Health care services are of the most important operations which are usually done inside teams. This paper aims at identifying and ranking the hospital teams' productivity indices. For this purpose, the effective factors that influence hospital teams' productivity have been identified through literature study as well as experts survey. These factors then have been reduced to 34 criteria using a screening approach and then categorized into 9 main groups. Internal relations among the factors have been examined using statistical tests. We proposed a new ANP-BWM approach combining the analytical network process (ANP) and best-worst method (BWM) to rank the factors. The proposed ranking approach can significantly reduce the number of pairwise comparisons in ANP method. Finally, in the case of Sadjad hospital, 12 nursing teams have been selected and investigated. Results show that “the quality of services” has the most and “the permanent employment” has the least impact on nursing teams’ productivity.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این مقاله که هدف آن شناسایی و اولویت بندی شاخص های بهره وري تیم های کاری بیمارستانی می باشد، عوامل موثر بر بهره وری تیم های کاری بيمارستاني از طریق بررسی ادبیات موضوعی و با استفاده از نظر كارشناسان شناسايي گرديد كه پس از غربالگري به تعداد 34 عامل مهم تقليل يافتند و در قالب 9 دسته طبقه بندي گرديدند. روابط داخلي اين عوامل بر اساس پرسشنامه ماتريس همبستگي مورد سنجش قرار گرفت و سپس شاخص ها با استفاده از رويكرد جديد تلفيقي بر پايه تجزيه و تحليل شبكه اي (ANP) و روش برداري بهترین-بدترین (BWM) رتبه بندی گردید. شایان ذکر است روش جديد پيشنهادي در این مقاله توانست تعداد مقايسات زوجي در تكنيك ANP را به طور قابل توجهي كاهش دهد. سپس در مطالعه موردی بیمارستان سجاد تهران، 12 تیم کاری بیمارستانی (در حوزه پرستاری) انتخاب و مدل پيشنهادي جهت کاووش و بررسی عوامل موثر بر بهره وری تیم های کاری بیمارستانی مورد اجرا قرار گرفت. نتایج حاصل از پژوهش انجام شده نشان می دهد، در میان 34 عامل در نظر گرفته شده، درصد رشد سالیانه کیفیت خدمات ارائه شده به بیماران موثر ترین عامل و درصد عضویت رسمی اعضا (نسبت به پیمانی) کم اثر ترین عوامل در سنجش بهره وری تیم های کاری بیمارستانی می باشند. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">بهره وری، تیم‌هاي کاری بيمارستاني ، رتبه‌بندی عوامل، تکنیک ANP-BWM</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13960516210377406-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>