﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>55</Volume><Issue>2-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Develop a business model with a focus on central enterprise in a collaboration network </ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>توسعه مدل کسب و کار با محوریت شرکت مرکزی در کسب و کارهای مبتنی بر شبکه‎های همکاری </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>ایمان </FirstName><LastName>صادق زاده</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></History><Abstract>The development of networked organizations usually done by a focal firm (the mother). For this purpose, the focal firm as the main center of network must implement her strategies with an action plan. Significance of business model in a network is important as many experts realize business model as an engine for network base strategy.
In the present study, we look at the subject of collaboration networks , to review, identify and prioritize the role of focal firm in the business model of collaboration networks. In this direction, by reviewing  existing literature on maternal advantage we extract the key functions of focal firm in her mothering strategy and business model.
Then the extracted factors in Delphi process was judged and developed by experts. After confirming the final factors  by experts to further validation and extract the Priority of factors  we design questionnaires that  given to Academic experts and managers who working in two network, the result of that questionnaires approved the applicability of the model</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">چکیده:
توسعه سازمان‏های شبکه‏ای معمولاً با تولیت یک بنگاه مرکزی (مادر) پی گرفته می‏شود، بدین منظور بنگاه مادر به عنوان مرکزیت اصلی شبکه باید استراتژی‎های خود را با راهکاری عملیاتی در سطح شبکه پیاده سازی کند اهمیت مدل کسب‌وکار در شبکه تا آنجا مهم است که بسیاری از صاحب‌نظران مدل کسب‌وکار را موتور استراتژی‌های مبتنی بر شبکه می‏دانند.
در پژوهش حاضر، با نگاه به موضوع شبکه‏های همکاری، به بررسی، شناسایی و اولویت بندی نقش سازمان مادر در مدل کسب و کاری شبکه‎های همکاری پرداخته شده است. در این راستا با مرور ادبیات مربوط به  مزیت مادری عملکردهای کلیدی شرکت مادر در بحث کسب و کاری شبکه‎ها استخراج گردید سپس با استفاده از روش دلفی و در سه دور به استحضار خبرگان فعال در حوزه شبکه‎های همکاری قرار گرفت و بهبود و توسعه یافت. پس از تائید فاکتورهای نهایی توسط خبرگان به‌منظور اعتبارسنجی و اولویت‎‎ بندی فاکتورها پرسشنامه‌ای تدوین و در اختیار خبرگان دانشگاهی و مدیران دو شبکه‏ همکاری قرار گرفت. که نتایج به کاربردی و عملیاتی بودن فاکتورها تدوین‌شده صحه می‏گذارد.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">شبکه، شرکت مرکزی، مزیت مادری، عملکرد شرکت مرکزی، همکاری‏های بلندمدت، استراتژی های مبتنی بر شبکه</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13950821112383919-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>