﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>2-ب</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigating the behavior of bank customers after the merger of branches with the development of a cluster analysis model; Case Study: Mellat Bank</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بررسی رفتار مشتریان بانک پس از ادغام شعب با توسعه‌ی یک مدل تحلیل خوشه‌ای؛  مطالعه موردی: بانک ملت</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>15</FirstPage><LastPage>26</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>رضا</FirstName><LastName>قسمتی</LastName><Affiliation>مهندسی صنایع و سیستم‌های مدیریت</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day></History><Abstract>The emergence and expansion of new service channels in banks, the large number of branches in the service network of banks, and the high cost of the branch, on the one hand, led the banks to reduce the number of branches and the integration of smaller branches in other branches, but factors such as the loss of customers , Brand coverage, social security deprivation, etc., have created considerations for banks in integrating branches. In this paper, a comprehensive overview of the literature on mergers of bank branches and similar issues was first discussed and influential variables were identified in the problem. Then, the behavior of customers influenced by the merger of branches as one of the key variables affecting the problem has been investigated. For this purpose, a five-step model has been developed in this paper, with its main core of cluster analysis techniques. Finally, in order to demonstrate the effectiveness and applicability of the developed model, a case study of Mellat branches has been used in the country.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">ظهور و گسترش کانال‌های خدمت‌دهی جدید در بانک‌ها ، تعداد زیاد شعب در شبکه‌ی خدمت‌رسانی بانک‌ها و هزینه‌های بالای شعبه از یک سو بانک‌ها را به سمت کاهش تعداد شعب خود و ادغام شعبه‌های کوچک‌تر در سایر شعب سوق داده است؛ اما عواملی از قبیل از دست دادن مشتریان، پوشش برند، محرومیت‌های مالی اجتماعی و... ملاحظاتی را برای بانک‌ها در ادغام شعب ایجاد کرده است. در این مقاله ابتدا به مرور جامعی از ادبیات ادغام شعب بانک‌ها و مسائل مشابه آن پرداخته شده و متغیرهای تأثیرگذار در مسئله شناسایی شده است. سپس به بررسی رفتار مشتریان متأثر از ادغام شعب به عنوان یکی از کلیدی‌ترین متغیرهای مؤثر در مسئله پرداخته شده است. بدین منظور یک مدل پنج مرحله‌ای در این مقاله توسعه یافته است که هسته‌ی اصلی آن را استفاده از تکنیک‌های تحلیل خوشه‌ای تشکیل داده است. در انتها به منظور نمایش اثربخشی و کاربردی بودن مدل توسعه یافته، از مطالعه‌ی موردی شعب بانک ملت در سطح کشور استفاده شده است.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">ادغام شعب</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
؛ ریزش مشتریان؛</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 تحلیل خوشه‌ای.</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13980117178483-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>