﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>46</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Performance Evaluation Model using the Balanced Scorecard and Fuzzy TOPSIS integrated approach BSC-FTOPSIS</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ارائه مدل ارزیابی عملکرد با استفاده از رویکرد تلفیقی تاپسیس  فازی و کارت امتیازی متوازن BSC-FTOPSIS</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محمد </FirstName><LastName>احسانی فر</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد اراک</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>کیومرث</FirstName><LastName>عباسی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد اراک</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></History><Abstract>ABSTRACT
The present paper aims at presenting an incorporative fuzzy approach towards evaluating of performance using Balanced Scorecard (BSC). To do so, first, based on the data collected from evaluating the components of strategic management, main objectives, key factors of success, and performance evaluation indices are identified. Next, using TOPSIS fuzzy method, the indices are prioritized and ranked so the indices with the highest impact on performance evaluation are identified and classified in the form of balanced scorecards. 29 people from among the elite, chiefs and key experts filled out a questionnaire, in order to achieve the goals of the study. The validity of the questionnaire was confirmed through the experts, and its reliability was defined using Cronbach's alpha (0.89%). At the end, the proposed model was executed in a branch of Saderat Bank in Tehran. The application of the improvisations resulted in the improvement in almost all defined indices, i.e., the Total Performance Index for the studied organization was 72.38% by April, 2015 (based on the last three months prior to that), which was raised to reach 79.16% three months after executing the model (the end of July, same year).    
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">اين پژوهش با هدف ارائه یک رویکرد تلفیقی فازی به منظور ارزیابی عملکرد با استفاده از کارت امتیازی متوازن انجام گرفت است. بدین منظور ابتدابا توجه به اطلاعات حاصل شده از تجزيه و تحليل اجزای مدیریت استراتژیک،اهداف کلان، عوامل کلیدی موفقیت و شاخص¬های ارزیابی عملکرد، شناسایی شدند، سپس این شاخص¬ها از طريق روش تاپسيس فازي اولويت¬بندي گردیده تا تاثیرگذارترین شاخص¬ها در ارزیابی عملکرداستخراج و در قالب کارت امتیازی متوازن دسته¬بندی شوند.جهت دستیابی به هدف پژوهش پرسشنامه در بین 29 نفر از خبرگان، روئسا و کارشناسان کلیدی تکمیل گشت. روایی پرسشنامه از طریق نظر اساتید و خبرگان و پایایی آنتوسط ضریب آلفای کرونباخ که مقدار آن برابر با 89/0  بدست آمد.در نهایت مدل ارائه شده در یکی از شعب بانک ملی تهران پیاده‌سازی شد.تقريباً در تمامي شاخص¬هاي تعريف شده با توجه به ابتکاراتی که اعمال شد، بهبود ایجاد شده است، به طوریکه شاخص كارآيي كل سازمان براي دوره برنامه¬ريزي شده در اول سال 94،  برگرفته از نتایج سه ماه پایانی سال 93، برابر با 72.38 % بود، كه پس از گذشتن سه ماه از پياده¬سازي و اجراي اين مدل اين رقم در انتهای سه ماهه اول 94، به 79.16 % افزايش يافته است.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">ارزیابی عملکرد، کارت امتیازی متوازن، تاپسیس فازی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139507121441233535-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>