﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>2-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2015</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>FINANCIAL STRUCTURE-ECONOMIC GROWTH NEXUS IN MENA COUNTRIES: EVIDENCE FROM PANEL DATA APPROACH  </ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>معماری نظام مالی: ارزیابی ساختار مالی کشورهای منا با استفاده از رهیافت پانل دیتا</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مهدی </FirstName><LastName>تقوی</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>تیمور </FirstName><LastName>محمدی</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>عباس  </FirstName><LastName>شاکری</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد </FirstName><LastName>نصر اصفهانی</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></History><Abstract>The financial structure is always considered as a major factor responsible for economic growth in a country. Based on various economic theories, there would be a positive relationship between the financial system and economic growth rate. In fact, a country with a better financial system can generate a larger Gross Domestic Product (GDP) which stands for a positive economic growth. However, it should be noted here that in the real world, there is not homogeneity in financial mechanism and economic growth, hence, we cannot completely set theory in the reality. According to this brief state of the problem, the main purpose of this research is exploring the financial structure (i.e. Financial development and financial architecture ) – economic growth nexus through the Panel Cointegraiton approach, FMOLS and Panel LS estimations over 19802011 for eight countries in the MENA region. The empirical findings report clear support for the long run relationship between financial development and economic growth, while do not provide any statistically significant relationship between financial architecture and economic growth. </Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">نظام مالی کشورها به عنوان بازوی محرک رشد اقتصادی یک کشور قابل مطرح است. براساس تئوری های اقتصادی رابطه مثبتی میان نظام مالی یک کشور و رشد اقتصادی آن می تواند وجود داشته باشد. به این صورت که یک کشور با نظام مالی قوی می تواند تولید ناخالص داخلی بیشتری در طول زمان ایجاد کند که خود به معنای رشد اقتصادی مثبت خواهد بود. هر چند این نکته حائز اهمیت است که در جهان واقعی همگنی در  مکانیزم نظام  مالی و رشد اقتصادی کشورها وجود ندارد و با قطعیت نمی توان قاعده تئوری را به جهان واقعی تسری بخشید. با توجه به این امر، در این پژوهش با استفاده از داده های تابلويي (پانل دیتا) در دوره 1980 الی 2011 میلادی و رهیافت هم انباشتگی پانل و تخمین از دو روش حداقل مربعات معمولی اصلاح شده کامل و حداقل مربعات پانلی ارتباط میان ساختار مالی (از طریق دو متغیر توسعه مالی و معماری مالی) و رشد اقتصادی 8 کشورمنتخب در منطقه منا (خاورمیانه و شمال افریقا) را بررسی نموده ایم. طبق نتایج بدست آمده در این تحقیق مشخص گردید که ضریب تاثیر توسعه مالی بر رشد اقتصادی معنادار و مثبت  بوده، در صورتی که ضریب تاثیر بلند مدت متغیر معماری مالی بر رشد اقتصادی از لحاظ آماری معنادار نمی باشد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">ساختار مالی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
رشد اقتصادی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 توسعه مالی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
معماری مالی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 پانل دیتا</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13941204233301187-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>