﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>54</Volume><Issue>1-ب</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Structural Modeling of strengthening purchase intention in the Instagram as a social network</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>مدلسازی ساختاری تقویت قصد خرید در شبکه اجتماعی اینستاگرام</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>177</FirstPage><LastPage>194</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>یاسر</FirstName><LastName>سبحانی فرد</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></History><Abstract>The effect of social networks on consumer behavior in cyberspace is growing. The popular social network Instagram as one of the networks are strengthening their role in purchasing intention. This article seeks to examine know how advertising on the social network Instagram and its role on the consumer`s shopping intention. In this regard, the study has tested effect of six advertising factors in Instagram on the shopping intention. Population of this study is Instagram users in the city of Qazvin. To generalize the results to the community infinite by random sampling, 384 samples were elected.  To answer hypotheses and test the study model, structural equation modeling was used.  The results confirm the study's model and majority of hypotheses.  Test results showed that the informativeness and advertising creativity, have a positive effect on attitudes toward empathy expression and and this will also affect the intention to express empathy and this reality have positive affect on Purchase intention.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">اثر شبکه های اجتماعی بر رفتار مصرف کنندگان در فضای مجازی رو به فزونی است .در این میان شبکه اجتماعی اینستاگرام به عنوان یکی از شبکه های پرمخاطب در حال پررنگ کردن نقش خود در شکل دهی قصد خرید کاربران می باشد. مقاله پیش رو به دنبال بررسی چگونگی تبلیغات در شبکه اجتماعی اینستاگرام و نقش آن بر قصد خرید مصرف کنندگان می باشد.جهت انجام این مهم اثر عوامل شش گانه تبلیغات در فضای اینستاگرام بر روی قصد خرید مورد آزمون قرار گرفت.جامعه آماری این تحقیق کاربران اینستاگرام در شهر آبیک قزوین بوده که برای تعمیم نتایج به این جامعه نامحدود، 384 نمونه به روش نمونه گیری تصادفی مورد انتخاب قرار گرفتند.برای پاسخ به فرضیات تحقیق و آزمون مدل از روش مدلسازی معادلات ساختاری استفاده شد. نتایج نشان از تایید مدل تحقیق و اکثر فرضیات داشت .نتایج آزمون های حاصل از الگوی پژوهش ، نشان دادند که اطلاع رسان بودن و خلاقیت تبلیغاتی ، اثر مثبتی بر نگرش افراد نسبت به اجماع گروهی داشته و این موضوع نیز از طریق اثر گذاری بر قصد همراهی افراد با اجماع موجب بهبود قصد خرید مصرف کنندگان می شود.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">شبکه های اجتماعی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
اینستاگرام</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 قصد خرید</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مصرف کننده</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/1396092912292119781-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>