﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>1-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Designing lay-off pattern of human resources in local organizations (Case study: Municipalities of Esfahan province)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>طراحی الگوی تعدیل منابع انسانی در سازمان های محلی  (مورد مطالعه: شهرداری های استان اصفهان)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>269</FirstPage><LastPage>282</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محسن </FirstName><LastName>صانعی</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day></History><Abstract>The purpose of this research is to present a pattern regarding lay-off in local organizations (a case study about municipalities of Esfahan province) and also to analyze the impact of structural, behavioral and individual factors on lay-off and its aspects. The method used to do this research is descriptive and correlative .The method used to collect information is mixed (qualitative and quantitative).In the first stage (qualitative approach), the subjects were 22 experts who had suitable information about the issue of lay-off. A lay-off pattern and the influential factors on lay-off were designed using the fuzzy Delphi method and also fuzzy logic. These two methods were used to have more correlation between the views of the experts. Then, in the quantitative part, a questionnaire was designed in order to evaluate the pattern and then after reviewing the validity of the questionnaire through Exploratory Factor Analysis, it was given to some managers who, based on Judgmental Sampling, had been chosen out of managers of branches and units of municipalities in Esfahan province.
The relationships between components of the model were reviewed using structural equation model. The findings demonstrated that the hypotheses were confirmed and the effect of individual, behavioral and structural factors on lay-off, the mutual effect of behavioral and structural factors and also the effect of individual factors on structural and behavioral factors are meaningful and direct.To this end, municipalities can take the right decisions, which are based on the views of experts, about the time of lay-off, the branch or the people who are going to be laid off and also the influential resources in lay-off.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر با هدف ارائه الگویی پیرامون تعدیل کارکنان در سازمان های محلی (نوعی مطالعه موردی در شهرداری های استان اصفهان) و بررسی تأثیر پذیری تعدیل کارکنان و ابعاد آن از عوامل ساختاری، رفتاری و فردی صورت پذیرفته است. روش انجام این تحقیق، توصیفی و از نوع همبستگی است روش گردآوری اطلاعات، به صورت آمیخته (کمی و کیفی) می باشد جامعه آماری پژوهش در مرحله اول (رویکرد کیفی) 22 نفر از صاحب نظران و خبرگان که دارای اطلاعات مناسبی پیرامون موضوع تعدیل کارکنان هستند، می باشد که با بکارگیری چند دور روش دلفی و استفاده از منطق فازی برای ایجاد همگرایی بالاتر میان نظرات کارشناسان، الگویی پیرامون تعدیل کارکنان و عوامل اثر گذار بر تعدیل، طراحی گردید. سپس در بخش کمی، جهت آزمون الگوی مذکور، پرسشنامه ای طراحی و پس از بررسی اعتبار پرسشنامه از طریق تحلیل عاملی اکتشافی و تأییدی، در اختیار تعدادی از مدیران که با استفاده از روش نمونه گیری غیر احتمالیِ قضاوتی از میان مدیران دوایر و واحدهای شهرداری های استان اصفهان انتخاب گردیده بودند، قرار گرفت.
با استفاده از مدل یابی معادلات ساختاری روابط بین عناصر مدل بررسی شد. یافته های پژوهش نشان داد که فرضیه ها مورد تأیید قرار گرفته و تأثیر عوامل فردی، رفتاری و ساختاری بر تعدیل، تأثیر متقابل عوامل رفتاری و ساختاری بر یکدیگر و همچنین تأثیر عوامل فردی بر عوامل ساختاری و رفتاری، مستقیم و معنادار می باشد. در این راستا شهرداری ها می¬توانند با در نظر گرفتن شاخص های ذکر شده برای ابعادِ سه عاملِ مطرح در این پژوهش، تصمیماتی منطقی و کارشناسی شده پیرامون زمان تعدیل، واحد و یا افراد تعدیل شونده و منابع مؤثر در تعدیل، اتخاذ نمایند.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">برنامه ریزی منابع انسانی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تعدیل کارکنان</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
عوامل رفتاری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
عوامل ساختاری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
عوامل فردی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
سیستم اطلاعات منابع انسانی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
پوشش حمایتی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
دلفی فازی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139605181157167425-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>