﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>55</Volume><Issue>2-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigation the effect of employee involvement on organizational citizenship behavior with moderating role of organizational identity</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بررسي تاثير درگيري شغلي کارکنان بر رفتار شهروندي سازماني با نقش تعديل-‏گري هويت سازماني</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>سید مرتضی</FirstName><LastName>غیور باغبانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام رضا(ع)</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>امید</FirstName><LastName>بهبودی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد شاهرود</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>پورنگ</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام رضا (ع)</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سید علی</FirstName><LastName>قادری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام رضا (ع)</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>الهام</FirstName><LastName>نصیری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد مشهد</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day></History><Abstract>Human resource is the most important resources in organization, which influences organizational direction and performance. Organizational citizenship behavior is a desired consequence that managers tend to increase it among human resources. The aim of this study is to investigate effects of job involvement on organizational citizenship behavior with moderating role of organizational identity. The population of study is Iran Insurance Company agencies (representatives) in Mashhad, with 300 agencies. Two-stage cluster sampling method was used with regard to the distribution of agencies in Mashhad. 167 agencies were determined for sampling size using Morgan table. Data collection tool were three questionnaires which their validity confirmed through construct validity and reliability were assessed using Cronbach's alpha. To ensure of returning adequate questionnaires, 170 questionnaires were distributed and 167 questionnaires were returned. Data analysis using structural equation modeling and partial least squares (PLS) was conducted. The results showed that job involvement has significant positive effect on organizational citizenship behavior. Also, organizational identity has moderating role in the relationship between job involvement and organizational citizenship behavior.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">مهمترين منبع هر سازمان كه تعيين‏¬كنندة جهت¬گيري و عملکرد آن مي¬باشد، منابع انساني است. رفتار شهروندي سازماني پيامد مطلوبي است که مديران درصدد افزايش بروز آن در بين منابع انساني هستند. هدف اين پژوهش بررسي اثر درگيري شغلي بر رفتار شهروندي سازماني با نقش تعديل‏¬گري هويت سازماني بوده است. جامعه آماري پژوهش، نمايندگي¬‏هاي شرکت بيمه ايران در شهر مشهد به تعداد 300 نمايندگي است. با توجه به پراكندگي نمايندگي¬هاي مذكور در سطح شهر، روش خوشه¬اي دو مرحله¬اي براي نمونه¬گيري استفاده شد. حجم نمونه با استفاده از جدول مورگان، 167 نمايندگي تعيين شد. ابزار جمع¬‏آوري داده¬‏ها، سه پرسشنامه است که روايي آن¬ها به روش سازه و پايايي با استفاده از آلفاي کرونباخ احراز گرديد. جهت اطمينان از بازگشت تعداد مكفي از پرسشنامه¬ها، 170 پرسشنامه توزيع و 167 پرسشنامه برگشت داده شد. داده‏¬هاي پژوهش با استفاده از مدل‏¬يابي معادلات ساختاري و روش حداقل مربعات جزئي (PLS) تجزيه و تحليل شدند. نتايج تحقيق نشان داد که درگيري شغلي بر رفتار شهروندي سازماني، اثر معني¬‏دار و مثبتي دارد. همچنين نقش تعديل¬‏گري هويت سازماني در رابطه بين درگيري شغلي و رفتار شهروندي سازماني نيز مورد تاييد قرار گرفت.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">درگيري شغلي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
رفتار شهروندي سازماني</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
هويت سازماني</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139604211451526881-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>