﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>61</Volume><Issue>1-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2018</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Futurology of Integrated Communication of Social Marketing at the Iranian National Tax Administration  (Based on Network Analysis Technique)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>آینده پژوهی ارتباطات یکپارچه بازاریابی اجتماعی سازمان امور مالیاتی کشور  (مبتنی بر تکنیک تحلیل شبکه)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>123</FirstPage><LastPage>136</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>سید اکبر</FirstName><LastName>منچگانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد شاهرود</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>امیر </FirstName><LastName>غفوریان شاگردی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام رضا</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>گلنار</FirstName><LastName>شجاعی باغینی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علوم و تحقیقات</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day></History><Abstract>The aim of this paper is to provide research results using descriptive-analytical research method and qualitative-quantitative data obtained from questionnaire. Some factors such as reaching effectiveness of tax system functions, establishing social justice, taxpayers dissatisfaction and especially the culture of tax fraud, motived us to investigate effective agents on attaining a favorite future in social relationships with taxpayers from organizational expert's point of view. 
Regarding limitation of the numbers of experts in Iranian National Tax Administration, available sample was used. Therefore, utilizing organizational documentation and experts, some components were recognized and extracted then they were prioritized by analytical Network Process .Afterwards, based on Dymtel Technique, the intensity of impression and being impressed as well as relationship network of relevant factors were examined by futurology method. Following assessment of these factors by experts, prioritizing of subordinate criterions was done as well. Results show that experts anticipated that individual oriented resources organization and social responsibilities as the most important priority in integration relationships in social marketing in Tax Affairs System, furthermore, motivation tendency, addressees' cooperation and economic needs were the most important priorities in subordinate criterions. 

The result of this research can be used to explain social marketing strategies and designing of integration relationship of social marketing model in Iranian National Tax Administration. 

</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این مقاله، سعی بر آن است با استفاده از روش تحقیق توصیفی- تحلیلی و داده های کمی- کیفی پیمایشی برگرفته از ابزار پرسشنامه نتایج تحقیقی را ایفاد نماییم. دلایلی نظیر دستیابی به اثربخشی کارکردهای نظام مالیاتی، برقراری عدالت اجتماعی، نارضایتی مودیان و بخصوص فرهنگ فرارمالیاتی مودیان، موجب گردید فاکتورهای تاثیر گذار بر دستیابی به آینده ای مطلوب در ارتباطات اجتماعی با مودیان در این حوزه، از دیدگاه خبرگان سازمانی را مورد بررسی قرار دهیم. نظر به محدودیت تعداد خبرگان سازمان مالیاتی کشور، از نمونه دردسترس استفاده شد. لذا در ابتدا مولفه هایی به کمک مستندات سازمانی و خبرگان شناسایی و استخراج و سپس با کمک روش تحلیل سلسله شبکه اولویت بندی شدند و سپس بر اساس تکنیک دیمتل به بررسی شدت تاثیرو تاثر و شبکه ارتباطات فاکتورهای مورد بررسی با رویکرد آینده پژوهی پرداخته شد. پس از ارزیابی این فاکتورها از دیدگاه خبرگان اولویتهای معیارهای فرعی نیز صورت پذیرفت.  نتایج این تحلیل، نشان داد خبرگان منابع مبتنی بر افراد و سازمان و مسئولیتهای اجتماعی سازمان را بعنوان مهمترین اولویتهای اصلی یکپارچه سازی ارتباطات بازاریابی اجتماعی در حوزه نظام مالیاتی کشور پیش بینی نمودند و از میان معیارهای فرعی نیز تمایل انگیزشی، همکاری مخاطبین و نیازهای اقتصادی بعنوان اولویت دار ترین فاکتورهای اثرگذار پیش بینی شدند. نتایج تحقیق حاضر را میتوان در تبیین استراتژیهای بازاریابی اجتماعی و طراحی مدل ارتباطات یکپارچه بازاریابی اجتماعی نظام مالیاتی کشور مورد استفاده قرار داد . </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">ارتباطات یکپارچه بازاریابی </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 بازاریابی اجتماعی </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 نظام مالیاتی </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 آینده پژوهی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13980203178877-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>