﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>58</Volume><Issue>دوم</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2015</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>An integrated model for a multi-product production-inventory-routing problem in a bi-echelon green supply chain</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>توسعه مدلي يکپارچه براي مسئله چندمحصولي توليد-مسيريابي-موجودي در زنجيره تأمين سبز دوسطحي</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>35</FirstPage><LastPage>50</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>میرسامان </FirstName><LastName>پیشوایی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>عادل</FirstName><LastName>اعظمی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>پاپی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day></History><Abstract>Manufacturing company’s decisions regarding the quantity of production and inventory is a production planning and inventory control problem. Decisions about transferring products are expressed as a transportation and routing problem. Considering these three problems together results in an integrated production-inventory-routing planning (PIRP) which is one of the important supply chain problems. Companies which solve their PIRP problems better can decrease the cost of their products and gain more competitive advantage compared to other competing companies. Based on today’s strict regulations, companies must take into account environmental considerations in addition to economical ones in all their processes, from production until supply. Thus, an appropriate transportation planning can prevent the excessive increase in costs and decrease environmental pollution. Therefore, this study integrates the problem of decreasing environmental pollution with PIRP and develops a green PIRP (GPIRP) problem which efficiently considers the economic and social dimensions of production and supply. This problem is modeled in an integrated manner using the MILP approach. In order to show the applicability of the developed model and its practicability of environmental aspect, a case study is conducted on Ahvaz Sugar Refinery, Iran. Finally, some managerial insights are derived from the computational results.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">تصميم گيري شرکت هاي توليدي پيرامون ميزان توليد و موجودي به عنوان يک مسئله برنامه ريزي توليد و کنترل موجودي است. تصميم گيري براي انتقال محصولات بصورت مسئله حمل ونقل و مسيريابي بيان مي شود. از ادغام سه مسئله مذکور، مسئله يکپارچه برنامه ريزي توليد-موجودي-مسيريابي (PIRP) حاصل مي شود که جزء مسائل مهمِ زنجيره تأمين است. شرکت هايي که بتوانند PIRP خود را بهتر حل نمايند؛ مي توانند هزينه نهايي محصولات خود را کاهش داده و مزيت رقابتي بيشتري نسبت به رقيب کسب کنند. بنابر سختگيري هاي کنوني، شرکت ها موظفند علاوه بر بعد اقتصادي فعاليت هايشان، ملاحظات زيستمحيطي را نيز در تمام فرايندهاي توليد تا عرضه رعايت کنند. لذا، برنامه ريزي مناسب حمل ونقل مي تواند همزمان با جلوگيري از افزايش بيش ازحد هزينه ها، آلودگي هاي زيستمحيطي را نيز کاهش دهد. بنابراين، مي توان مسئله کاهش آلودگي هاي زيستمحيطي را با PIRP ادغام و مسئله PIRP سبز (GPIRP) را توسعه داد که بطور همزمان دوبعد اقتصادي و اجتماعي توليد و عرضه را لحاظ مي کند. در اين پژوهش، اين مسئله پيچيده بصورت يکپارچه به کمک رويکرد MILP، مدل سازي شده است. به منظور نشان دادن کاربردپذيري مدل توسعه داده شده و نيز عملي بودن لحاظ جنبه زيستمحيطي، يک مطالعه موردي روي شرکت توليدي قند و تصفيه شکر اهواز انجام شده است. در نهايت، چند نتايج مديريتي از نتايج محاسباتي گرفته شده است. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">برنامه ريزي توليد-مسيريابي-موجودي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 مسيريابي وسايل نقليه</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 زنجيره تأمين سبز</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
ملاحظات زيست محيطي</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13970421154740143213-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>