﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>2-ب</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>A model for change governance structures for implementation theocracy  based velayat-e faqih</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>مدلی برای تغییر ساختارهای حاکمیتی برای اجرای حکومت دینی مبتنی بر ولایت ‏فقیه</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>207</FirstPage><LastPage>224</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>سید حاتم</FirstName><LastName>مهدوی نور</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد شهرری (یادگار امام خمینی)، گروه معارف اسلامی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></History><Abstract>The Iranian people, led by Imam Khomeini revolted for the establishment of Islamic rule.  Today the world's ‎dominant discourse is democracy and for this purpose, the nature of the government of Iran became Islamic Republic that ‎democracy is form and Islamic is terms of content of government. Due to the lack of experience of Islamic countries in ‎democratic, western systems of governance was accepted to implement democracy. For Islamization of the government, it ‎placed the Supreme Leader at the head and the Guardian Council supervisory of parliament. Now, after nearly four decades ‎is essential to be revised in the governance structures. If there is a fault in the system should be desgined a system based on ‎religious approch and according to the conditions implement that in the absence of Imam Islamic roles should be ‎implemented. ‎
The study based on religious principles, characteristics of Islamic government and conditions of our country a ‎model for implementing religious government is designed.  Content analysis method is used to obtain principle that should ‎be considered in the design of governance structures.  For finding religious (Islamic) government a questionnaire among 30 ‎people who were selected snowball was distributed and analyesd with AHP method. For the realization of these features ‎according to religious principles and features of Iranian people, a system was designed that accordind to the idea of ten of ‎experts was revised. ‎
Keywords: neighborhood management, theocracy, theocracy structure, urban managementthe supreme leader.‎
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">مردم ایران به رهبری حضرت امام خمینی (ره) برای برپایی حکومت اسلامی قیام کردند. امروز در دنیا گفتمان غالب ‏دموکراسی است و به این منظور ماهیت حکومت ایران، جمهوری اسلامی شد که از لحاظ شکلی دموکراسی و از لحاظ محتوا ‏اسلامی است. با توجه به بی‌تجربه بودن کشورهای اسلامی در دموکراسی نظام‌های حاکمیتی غربی برای اجرای دموکراسی ‏پذیرفته شد. برای اسلامی کردن آن ولی فقیه در رأس و شورای نگهبان ناظر بر مصوبات مجلس شورای اسلامی شد. حال بعد از ‏حدود چهار دهه ضروری است در ساختارهای حاکمیتی بازنگری شود و در صورت وجود ایراد نظامی مبتنی بر دین و متناسب با ‏شرایط مکان و زمان برای اجرای قوانین دینی که در رأس آن ولی فقیه در زمان غیبت قرار دارد طراحی شود.‏
در این پژوهش مبتنی بر مبانی دینی، ویژگی‌های مردم ایران و خصوصیات حکومت اسلامی مدلی برای اجرای حکومت دینی ‏مبتنی بر ولایت فقیه ارائه شده است. از روش تحلیل محتوا برای به دست آوردن مبانی‌ای که در طراحی ساختارهای حاکمیتی به ‏آن توجه شود استفاده شده است. روش پژوهش برای  به دست آوردن خصوصیات مردم ایران تحلیل ۱۰۰۰ ساعت فیلم از رفتار ‏مردم در حین رانندگی، از خیابان رد شدن و ... است که نگارنده از سال ۱۳۸۵ تا سال ۱۳۹۲ در موقعیت‌های مختلف ضبط کرده ‏است و برای یافتن ویژگی‌های حکومت دینی (اسلامی) پرسش‌نامه‌ای بین ۳۰ نفر از خبرگان مدیریتی و دینی که به صورت گلوله ‏برفی انتخاب شدند توزیع و با ستفاده از ای‌اچ‌پی تحلیل و رتبه‌بندی شد. برای تحقق این ویژگی‌ها با توجه به مبانی دینی و ‏ویژگی‌های مردم نظامی طراحی شد که با مصاحبه با ده از از خبرگان مدیریتی و دینی اصلاح شد.‏
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">حکومت دینی، ساختار حکومت دینی، مدیریت شهری، مدیریت محله، ولایت فقیه‏</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139602091758425813-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>