﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>1-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Explain the gap in entrepreneurship and technology commercialization in cooperation between industry and university</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تبيين شکاف کارآفريني و تجاري سازي فناوري در همکاري صنعت و دانشگاه </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>227</FirstPage><LastPage>234</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>یزدان</FirstName><LastName>مرادی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم وصنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سیامک</FirstName><LastName>نوری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم وصنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></History><Abstract>T
he present study aimed to evaluate the analysis of studies in the field of cooperation between industry and university Over the past three decades have done so through a gap in cooperation between them be explained. This study used a descriptive-analytic review of research methods. And previous studies have been done and then get the experts from Through in-depth interviews with experts from both university and industry organizations.Continued Interviews conducted on the basis of theoretical adequacy of the data was stopped on 18 interviews. Of these, 8 out of university professors and experts in the subject, 3 persons CEO industrial companies,4 people, government officials and three experts in the field of entrepreneurship and CEO of intermediary companies participated in interviews. The results show that although University-industry cooperation in education, research and Knowledge-based entrepreneurship &amp; technology commercialization is raised but over time the share of education and  too research reduced and a desire for cooperation of Knowledge-based entrepreneurship and technology commercialization has increased. Review current approaches in cooperation between industry and universities prefer to Ability of the private sector and companies of intermediate (hub), especially in knowledge-based entrepreneurship and technology commercialization. The results show that the role of local patterns and human resources entrepreneur who has Commitment and sense of responsibility towards the country, industry and university cooperation with industry and university was found in successful models.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA"> پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسي تحليلي مطالعات انجام شده در حوزه همکاري بين صنعت و دانشگاه طي سه دهه اخير انجام شده است تا از اين طريق شکاف موجود در همکاري‌هاي صنعت و دانشگاه تبيين گردد. اين پژوهش از نوع توصيفي بوده و با روش تحليل تحقيقات و مطالعات گذشته صورت گرفته است و سپس با دريافت نظرات خبرگان از طريق انجام مصاحبه‌هاي عميق با متخصصان هر دو نهاد دانشگاه و صنعت ادامه يافته است. انجام مصاحبه‌ها براساس کفايت نظري داده‌ها در 18 مصاحبه متوقف شد. از اين تعداد 8 نفر از اساتيد دانشگاه و صاحب‌نظر در موضوع، 3 نفر مدير عامل شرکت‌هاي صنعتي، 4 نفر از مسئولان دولتي و 3 نفر از کارشناسان و مديرعاملان شرکت‌هاي واسطه‌اي حوزه کارآفريني و تجاري‌سازي در مصاحبه ها شرکت داشتند. نتايج نشان مي دهد که اگرچه همکاري‌هاي دانشگاه و صنعت در زمينه هاي آموزشي، پژوهشي و تحقيقاتي، کارآفريني دانش بنيان و تجاري سازي فناوري مطرح مي باشد ولي به مرور زمان هر چه به زمان حال نزديک‌تر مي‌شويم سهم آموزش و در ادامه سهم پژوهش و تحقيقات کاهش يافته و تمايل براي همکاري‌هايي از نوع کارآفريني دانش بنيان و تجاري سازي فناوري بيشتر شده است. بررسي رويکردهاي فعلي در همکاري بين صنعت و دانشگاه،گرايش زياد به بهره‌برداري از توان بخش خصوصي وشرکت‌هاي واسطه‌اي(هاب) را خصوصاً در فعاليتعاي کارآفريني دانش بنيان و تجاري سازي فناوري نشان مي دهد. همچنين نقش موثر الگوهاي بومي و نيز نيروي انساني کارآفرين که داراي تعهد و حس مسئوليت نسبت به کشور، صنعت و دانشگاه مي‌باشد در مدلهاي موفق همکاري صنعت و دانشگاه مشخص شده است.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">دانشگاه کارآفرين، تجاري سازي فناوري، همکاري صنعت و دانشگاه</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139511141437334851-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>