﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>55</Volume><Issue>2-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Synergistic leadership, post-modern approach to human resource flexibility and voice behavior</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>رهبری تضایف¬گرانه، رویکردی فرا نوگرا در راستای انعطاف¬پذیری منابع انسانی و آوای کارکنان</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>17</FirstPage><LastPage>30</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>امیر </FirstName><LastName>غفوریان شاگردی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام رضا</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سعید</FirstName><LastName>آیباغی اصفهانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>رامین </FirstName><LastName>الهی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></History><Abstract>Nowadays, In developing countries the women's participation in senior sectors of the organizations is lower than men, thus glass ceilings and walls have limited horizontally and vertically movement of women in the organizations. The synergistic leadership theory is the post-modern approach to leadership that conceptualized the presence of women in leadership positions of the leadership of the organizations as the synergistic agent in the organizations. This study aims to evaluate the effect of synergistic leadership on flexibility of human resources, in this evaluation the effect of the voice behavior of employees is considered as a mediator variable. This study is a practical search in terms of aim and is a descriptive survey in terms of method. The realm of study is the offices of social security organizations which is located in Tehran. For doing this study for measuring synergistic leadership in organization is used through the questionnaire of synergistic leadership, Thus after validation testes, reliability and validity were approved. Data analysis is done by using regression test and structural equations through software Amos and the findings of the research show the positive effect of synergistic leadership on the flexibility of human resources and also confirmed the positive and significant effect of synergistic leadership on the voice behavior of employees.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه در کشورهای در حال توسعه مشارکت زنان در بخش¬های عالی سازمان¬ها نسبت به مردان کمتر بوده و سقف و دیوار شیشه¬ای حرکت افقی و عمودی زنان در سازمان¬ها را محدود کرده است. تئوری رهبری تضایف¬گرایانه رویکردی فرانوگرا به رهبری است که حضور زنان در جایگاه رهبری سازمان را به عنوان عامل هم¬افزایی در سازمان مفهوم¬سازی می¬کند. بر این اساس پژوهش حاضر بر آن است تا به بررسی نحوه تاثیرگذاری رهبری تضایفی بر انعطاف¬پذیری منابع انسانی بپردازد و در این راستا اثر رفتارهای آوایی کارکنان به عنوان متغیر میانجی مورد مطالعه قرار گرفته است. تحقيق حاضر از نظر هدف، كاربردي و از نظر روش پژوهش، توصيفي از نوع پيمايشي است. حوزه پژوهش حاضر، ادارات سازمان تامین اجتماعی واقع در شهر تهران می¬باشد. در راستای انجام این تحقیق برای سنجش و اندازه¬گیری رهبری تضایفی در سازمان پرسشنامه رهبری تضایف¬گرایانه طراحی گردید که پس از آزمون¬های اعتبارسنجی، پایایی و روایی آن مورد تایید قرار گرفت. تحليل داده¬ها با استفاده از آزمون رگرسيون و معادلات ساختاري از طریق نرم افزارAmos  صورت گرفته و نتايج به دست آمده حاکی از تاثیر مثبت رهبری تضایفی بر انعطاف¬پذیری منابع انسانی می¬باشد، همچنین اثر مثبت و معنادار رهبری تضایفی بر رفتارهای آوایی کارکنان و نقش میانجی گری رفتار آوایی تایید گردید. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">هم&amp;#172;افزایی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 رهبری تضایف&amp;#172;گرایانه</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
رفتار آوایی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
انعطاف&amp;#172;پذیری منابع انسانی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/1396101915241240157-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>