﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle></ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>طراحی شبکه زنجیره تأمین با در نظر گرفتن هماهنگی سطوح با استفاده از تبلیغات مشارکتی در بستر فروش اینترنتی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>99</FirstPage><LastPage>112</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>علی اصغر</FirstName><LastName>عمادآبادی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>ابراهیم</FirstName><LastName>تیموری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>میرسامان </FirstName><LastName>پیشوایی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></History><Abstract>The decisions about designing the supply chain network are considered as strategic decisions of supply chain management, which have long-term impacts on overall performances of the chain. However, one of the most important challenges of problems of designing the supply chain network is coordination of its parts that can lead to several restrictions in tactical and operational levels. One of the increasing approaches of the coordination in supply chain is using Collaborative Advertisements. In this article, using the collaborative advertisement in designing the multi-level supply chain, multi-period and multi-product, have been considered in order to make coordination. The chain is also looking forward to fulfill the requirements of establishing new facilities. Advertisements are provided in two sections; supplying advertisements and chain advertisements. The chain advertisements and the information resource of the chain that customers purchases and orders registration are registered within it, is an internet website, which gets some percent as website’s costs per purchase from the chain’s parts. The demand of each customer is considered dependent on price and advertisement function. In case study the plan of publication subscription has been specified that for all of the variances in the impact factor of the advertisement supplier, summation of supplier’s benefits in presented model are better than the present situations; however, this matter is not compatible with all of the suppliers and some of them would have less benefits. But by means of sharing benefits of this coordination, this problem would be satisfied</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">تصمیمات مربوط به طراحی شبکه زنجیره تأمین جزء تصمیمات راهبردی مدیریت زنجیره تأمین محسوب می‌شوند که تأثیرات بلندمدتی بر عملکرد کلی زنجیره خواهند داشت؛ اما یکی از مهم‌ترین چالش‌های مسئله‌ی طراحی شبکه زنجیره تأمین هماهنگی اعضای آن است که می‌تواند منجر به ایجاد محدودیت‌های متعدد در سطوح تاکتیکال و عملیاتی شود. یکی از راهکارهای افزایش هماهنگی در زنجیره تأمین استفاده از تبلیغات مشارکتی است.در این مقاله تأثیر استفاده از تبلیغات مشارکتی در طراحی شبکه زنجیره تأمین چهار سطحی، چند دوره‌ای، چند محصولی جهت ایجاد هماهنگی موردبررسی قرارگرفته است. زنجیره جهت برآورد نیاز به دنبال تأسیس تسهیلات جدید نیز است. تبلیغات در دو بخش تبلیغات تأمین‌کننده و تبلیغات زنجیره ارائه‌شده است. تبلیغات زنجیره و منبع اطلاعاتی زنجیره که ثبت سفارش و خرید مشتریان در آن ثبت می‌شود، یک سایت اینترنتی است که به ازای هر فروش درصدی را به‌عنوان هزینه سایت از اعضای زنجیره دریافت می‌نماید. تقاضای هر مشتری وابسته به قیمت و تابع تبلیغات در نظر گرفته‌شده است در مطالعه موردی طرح اشتراک نشریات مشخص گردید که به ازای تمامی تغییرات ضریب تأثیر تبلیغات تأمین‌کننده، مجموع سود تأمین‌کننده‌ها در مدل پیشنهادی از شرایط کنونی بهتر است اما این موضوع برای تمامی تأمین‌کننده‌ها مصداق نداشته و بعضی از تأمین‌کننده‌ها سود کمتری خواهند داشت اما با توجه به اشتراک‌گذاری سود حاصل از هماهنگی این مشکل رفع می‌شود.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">طراحی شبکه زنجیره تأمین</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 هماهنگی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 تبلیغات مشارکتی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
فروش اینترنتی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 طرح اشتراک نشریات کشور</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13971110167300-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>