﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>51</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Design and offering conceptual model of investigation impact of strategic entrepreneurship on strategic innovation  in knowledge-based firms of Bushehr provience</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle> ارائۀ مدل مفهومی جهت بررسی تاثیر کارآفرینی استراتژیک بر نوآوری استراتژیک در شرکتهای دانش بنیان شهرستان بوشهر</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>فخریه</FirstName><LastName>حمیدیان پور</LastName><Affiliation>دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محبوبه</FirstName><LastName>شفیعی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه خلیج فارس بوشهر</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مریم</FirstName><LastName>دهقانی</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></History><Abstract>Market's condition is changeable and this condition force businesses to adopt themselves with new situation, technology and value propositions. In the today competitive environment, organizations try to imitate innovation from competitors, so innovation and continuous improvement is necessary for success of organizations, therefore strategic innovation is an important issue.  Strategic innovation is about creation of new markets and leaps in customer value and reshaping the existing markets to achieve value improvements for customers. On the other hand, strategic entrepreneurship results from the integration of entrepreneurship and strategic management knowledge. Objective of strategic entrepreneurship is making continuous competitive advantages that lead to wealth creation. In this paper, first we introduce the concept of strategic innovation and strategic entrepreneurship, then explain the conceptual model of strategic entrepreneurship impact on strategic innovation. Statistical society of this research, is knowledge-based companies of Science and technology park of Boushehr. According to the results obtained from testing this model, the main hypothesis of this study confirm that the result shows a positive and significant relationship between strategic entrepreneurship and strategic innovation in the organization.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">شرایط بازار متغیر است و همین شرایط کسب و کارها را وادار می¬کند که با شرایط موجود انطباق یابند و کسب و کار خود را متناسب با فناوری¬های جدید و گزاره¬های ارزشی منحصر بفرد بازنویسی کنند. در محیط رقابتی امروزه، سازمان¬ها تلاش می¬کنند که نوآوری¬های رقبای خود را تقلید کنند در نتیجه نوآوری و بهبود مستمر برای موفقیت کسب و کار بسیار ضروری است و بنابراین برای حل این مسئله نوآوری استراتژیک در دستور کار سازمان¬ها قرار می¬گیرد. نوآوری استراتژیک، نوآوری ایجاد بازارهای جدید است و باعث ایجاد ارزش برای مشتری می¬شود و بازارهای موجود را به¬منظور ایجاد ارزش برای مشتری تغییر شکل می¬دهد. از طرفی دیگر کارآفرینی استراتژیک که نقشی مهم در محیط¬های بسیار آشفته دارد، فعالیت¬های استراتژیک را با فعالیت¬های کارآفرینی ادغام می¬کند. هدف از کارآفرینی استراتژیک ایجاد مزایای رقابتی مستمری است که منجر به حداکثر خلق ارزش می¬شود. در این مقاله ضمن معرفی مفهوم نوآوری استراتژیک و کارآفرینی استراتژیک و بررسی پیشینه¬ها و ادبیات موجود، مدل مفهومی تأثیر کارآفرینی استراتژیک بر نوآوری استراتژیک، طراحی و شرح داده شده که جامعۀ آماری این پژوهش شرکت¬های دانش بنیان فعال در پارک علم و فن¬آوری بوشهر می¬باشد. با توجه به نتایج به¬دست آمده از آزمون این مدل، فرضیۀ اصلی پژوهشی تأیید می¬شود که نشان می¬دهد کارآفرینی استراتژیک رابطۀ مثبت و معناداری با نوآوری استراتژیک در سازمان دارد. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">واژگان کلیدی: </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
کارآفرینی استراتژیک</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 نوآوری استراتژیک</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 فرهنگ</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
رهبری</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139508222027583927-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>