﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>57</Volume><Issue>3-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Providing the best two- or multi-faceted barter between the two companies in the holding company</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ارائه بهترین تهاتر دو یا چند جانبه در حسابهای فی‎مابین در مجموعه شرکت‎های هلدینگ</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>53</FirstPage><LastPage>66</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>سعید</FirstName><LastName>کریمی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سعید</FirstName><LastName>میرزا محمدی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day></History><Abstract>The existence of debt in the accounts between a set of companies causes the items to be flooded to the left and right of the corporate balance sheet. And have misleading financial ratios for corporate finance analysts and lead to misleading predictions about the company's future. This is the case in a set of companies under the umbrella of a holding due to interactions between them and on the other hand, if there is a solution, it can be tracked and reduced due to the upstream management of the holding. In this paper, using mathematical modeling and optimization, the best combination of the two or multiple possible channels between the holding companies is suggested. How to deal with this issue is one of the issues of day care and modeling and solving it in the form of math planning is the main innovation of this article. The proposed modeling is implemented in one of the IT field holdings and its results are reported in this paper.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">وجود بدهی‎ در حسابهای فی‎مابین در مجموعه‎ای از شرکتها باعث فربه شدن اقلام سمت راست و چپ ترازنامه‎ی شرکتها می‎شود. و نسبت‎های مالی گمراه کننده‎ای را برای تحلیل کنندگان وضعیت مالی شرکت‎ها بهمراه داشته و به پیش بینی های گمراه کننده ای درخصوص آینده شرکت منجر شود. این موضوع در مجموعه‎ای از شرکتها که ذیل یک هلدینگ اداره میشوند بدلیل مراودات فی‎مابین بیشتر بوده و از طرفی در صورت وجود راهکار، به دلیل وجود مدیریت بالادستی هلدینگ قابل پیگیری و کاهش است. در این مقاله با استفاده از مدل‎سازی ریاضی و بهینه سازی، بهترین ترکیب از تهاتر دو یا چند جانبه‎ی ممکن بین شرکت‎های هلدینگ پیشنهاد می‎گردد. نحوه‎ی مواجه با این مسئله که یکی از مسائل روز هلدینگ‎ها است و مدل‎سازی و حل آن در قالب برنامه‎ریزی ریاضی نوآوری اصلی این مقاله می باشد. مدلسازی ارائه شده، در یکی از هلدینگ‎های حوزه فناوری اطلاعات پیاده شده و نتایج آن در این مقاله گزارش شده است.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">هلدینگ</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 مدل سازی ریاضی </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مسیریابی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13980321190064-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>