﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>47</Volume><Issue>47</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2016</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effect of performance management, organizational structure and career-based promotion system on job offer considering the role of organizational based self-concept</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر مدیریت عملکرد، ساختار سازمان و نظام ارتقائی مبتنی بر کارراهه بر پذیرش شغل با توجه به نقش تعدیلی خودپنداره سازمانی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>هاجر</FirstName><LastName>براتی</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>حمیدرضا</FirstName><LastName>عریضی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></History><Abstract>Abstract
Job offer by an employee is based on factors related to job and organization. It seems that factors such as performance management, organizational structure and promotion system to be effective on these variables. This research is done by aim to investigate the effect of performance management, organizational structure and career-based promotion system on job offer considering the role of organizational based self-concept. The research sample was consisted 120 people that were selected by convenience sampling and were assigned in the experimental groups. To manipulate the effect of performance management, organizational structure and career-based promotion system, vignettes were used. Organizational self-concept and job offer were measured using self-report measures.  For analyzing data, multivariate analysis of covariance was used. The results showed that organizational self-concept play a moderating role in relationships between performance management, organizational structure and career-based promotion system with job offer. According to the results for increased job offer, organizations should intervene based on organizational self–concept in organizational variables namely performance management, organizational structure and career-based promotion system.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">پذیرش شغل از سوی کارمند مبتنی بر عوامل مربوط به سازمان و شغل است. به نظر می رسد عواملی مانند مدیریت عملکرد، ساختار سازمان و نظام ارتقائی بر این متغیر موثر باشند. این پژوهش با هدف بررسی تأثیر مدیریت عملکرد، ساختار سازمان و نظام ارتقائی مبتنی بر کارراهه بر پذیرش شغل با توجه به نقش تعدیلی خودپنداره سازمانی انجام شده است. نمونه پژوهش شامل 120 نفر بود که به روش در دسترس انتخاب شدند و در گروه های آزمایشی گمارده شدند. برای دستکاری تأثیر مدیریت عملکرد، ساختار سازمان و نظام ارتقائی مبتنی بر کارراهه از متن های کوتاه استفاده شد. خودپنداره سازمانی و پذیرش شغل با استفاده ازابزارهای خودگزارشی سنجیده شدند. برای تحلیل داده ها آزمون تحلیل کوواریانس چندمتغیره مورد استفاده قرار گرفت. نتایج نشان داد که خودپنداره سازمانی در رابطه مدیریت عملکرد، ساختار سازمان و نظام ارتقائی مبتنی بر کارراهه با پذیرش شغل نقش تعدیلی را ایفا می‌کنند. با توجه به نتایج برای افزایش پذیرش شغل، سازمان‌ها باید بر اساس خودپنداره سازمانی در متغیرهای سازمانی یعنی مدیریت عملکرد، ساختار سازمان و نظام  ارتقائی مبتنی بر کارراهه مداخله کنند.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">پذیرش شغل، خودپنداره سازمانی، مدیریت عملکرد، ساختار سازمان، نظام  ارتقائی مبتنی بر کارراهه</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13950712164293545-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>