﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>57</Volume><Issue>3-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ranking suppliers in sustainable supply chain, using data envelopment analysis (Case study: Region Six Water &amp; Wastewater Company of Tehran)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>رتبه¬بندی تأمین¬کنندگان در زنجیره تامین پایدار با استفاده از تکنیک تحلیل پوششی داده‌ها ‏(مطالعه موردی : شرکت آب و فاضلاب منطقه شش شهر تهران)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>33</FirstPage><LastPage>52</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>نعیمی صدیق</LastName><Affiliation>پژوهشگاه علوم و فناوری اطلاعات ایران (ایرانداک)</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>آرمان</FirstName><LastName>ساجدی نژاد</LastName><Affiliation>پژوهشگاه علوم و فناوری اطلاعات ایران (ایرانداک)</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></History><Abstract>    The supply chain management debate is one of the most important discussions in the organizations. But there are many social, economic, and environmental problems encouraging organizations to use sustainable supply chain management. Because the sustainable supply chain is to improve the long-term supply chain performance to address the social, economic, and environmental problems of the traditional supply chain. Given that supply chains have grown rapidly in recent years, only paying attention to economic performance for cost optimization cannot lead to sustainable development in the supply chain, therefore, the impact of various activities involved in the supply chain on social life and Environmental issues that lead to sustainable development should also be considered. In this research, the goal of evaluation and ranking of sustainable supply chain suppliers is using the data envelopment analysis method. First of all, using previous studies in this area, we first identify the important variables of choosing sustainable supply chain suppliers according to the economic, environmental and social measures for the District 6 water and sewage company. Subsequently, according to an interview with experts in this area, we reduced the indexes. Finally, DEA models were ranked by the suppliers of sustainable supply chain water and sewage companies in District 6 of Tehran as a statistical population.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">    بحث مدیریت زنجیره تأمین از مهمترین بحث¬های حاضر در سازمان¬ها می¬باشد. اما وجود مشکلات متعدد اجتماعی، اقتصادی و زیست محیطی سازمان¬ها را تشویق به استفاده از مدیریت زنجیره تامین پایدار هدایت نموده است. چون که زنجیره تامین پایدار عبارت است از بهبود عملکرد طولانی مدت زنجیره تامین جهت رفع مشکلات اجتماعی، اقتصادی و زیست محیطی در زنجیره تأمین سنتی می¬باشد. با توجه به اینکه زنجیره‌های تامین در سال های اخیر به سرعت رشد یافته¬اند و تنها توجه نمودن بر عملکرد اقتصادی برای بهینه سازی هزینه¬ها نمی¬تواند سبب توسعه پایدار در زنجیره تأمین شود لذا تاثیر فعالیت¬های گوناگون درگیر در زنجیره تأمین بر زندگی اجتماعی و مسایل زیست محیطی که منجر به توسعه پایدار می‌گردد را نیز باید در نظر گرفت. در این تحقیق هدف ارزیابی و رتبه¬بندی تامین¬کنندگان زنجیره تامین پایدار  با استفاده از  روش تحلیل پوششی داده ها می¬باشد. به اینصورت که  ابتدا با استفاده از مطالعات قبلی در این حوزه به شناسایی متغیر¬های مهم انتخاب تامین‌کنندگان زنجیره تامین پایدار با توجه به سنجه¬های اقتصادی، زیست محیطی و اجتماعی برای شرکت آب و فاضلاب منطقه 6 می پردازیم. بعد از آن با توجه به مصاحبه با خبرگان این حوزه شاخص¬ها را کاهش دادیم. در نهایت با استفاده از مدل¬های تحلیل پوششی داده¬ها (DEA) به رتبه بندی تامین‌کنندگان زنجیره تامین پایدار شرکت آب و فاضلاب منطقه 6 شهر تهران به¬عنوان جامعه آماری مورد مطالعه پرداختیم.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مدیریت زنجیره تامین، </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
پایداری، </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تحلیل پوششی داده‌ها، </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
شرکت آب و فاضلاب</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13970618193125164279-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>