﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>57</Volume><Issue>3-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>An Effective Communication Model Effectiveness of  In-service training in  Organizations</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>مدل ارتباطی موثر بر اثربخشی آموزش ضمن خدمت سازمان ها</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>145</FirstPage><LastPage>152</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>بهروز </FirstName><LastName>کاوه یی</LastName><Affiliation>سازمان سنجش اموزش کشور</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>افسانه </FirstName><LastName>مظفری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه ازاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>معصومه </FirstName><LastName>کبریایی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه ازاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات </Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></History><Abstract>In recent years, with the advances made in the field of communication, the provision of educational services in various dimensions worldwide has become more evident but what makes it more important for organizations is the existence of an optimal communication model to make it more tangible for organizational learning and helps organizations advance their goals.
This research is aimed at designing an effective communication model for learning in organizations' education, which has been done using qualitative methods and approach based on the grounded theory. Data collection tools were semi-structured interviews and interviews were conducted with 15 managers, teachers and staff members of Mellat Bank to collect information using a targeted sampling method.Data analysis was conducted in three stages: open coding, axial coding and selective coding, and based on this, a qualitative research model was designed.
 The results of this study indicate that the extraction of over 678 codes from interviews has 197 concepts and 27 categories that have been considered as a paradigmatic model including the effectiveness of organizational education as a pivotal phenomenon and causative conditions, interventional conditions, strategies and consequential factors.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در سال های اخیر و همگام با پیشرفت های صورت گرفته در حوزه ارتباطات، عرضه خدمات آموزشی در ابعاد و اشکال مختلف در سطح جهان بیش از پیش مشهود است لیکن آنچه اهمیت آن را برای سازمان ها دو چندان می کند، وجود مدل بهینه ارتباطی است تا بتواند اثرگذاری آموزش سازمانی را ملموس تر نموده و سازمان ها را در پیشبرد اهداف شان یاری نماید.
این پژوهش به دنبال طراحی مدل ارتباطی موثر بر یادگیری در آموزش سازمانهاست که با استفاده از روشهای کیفی و رویکرد مبتنی بر نظریه داده بنیاد انجام شده است. ابزار جمع آوری داده ها، مصاحبه های نیمه ساختار یافته بوده و بمنظور گردآوری اطلاعات، با بکارگیری روش نمونه گیری هدفمند با 15 نفر از مدیران، مدرسان و پرسنل بانک ملت مصاحبه انجام شد. تجزیه و تحلیل داده ها در سه مرحله کدگذاری باز، کدگذاری محوری و کدگذاری انتخابی انجام گرفته و بر اساس آن، مدل کیفی پژوهش طراحی شده است.
نتایج پژوهش حاضر، نشان دهنده استخراج بالغ بر 678 کد از مصاحبه ها 197 مفهوم و 27 مقوله است که در قالب مدل پارادایمی شامل اثربخشی آموزش سازمانی به عنوان پدیده محوری و شرایط علی، شرایط مداخله گر، راهبردها و عوامل پیامدی قرار گرفت.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مدل ارتباطی </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 اثربخشی آموزش سازمانی </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 یادگیری</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13970702164531-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>