﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>58</Volume><Issue>دوم</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2015</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>strengthening the participation of the nongovernmental sector in financing higher education</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تقویت مشارکت بخش غیردولتی در تأمین منابع مالی آموزش عالی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>123</FirstPage><LastPage>138</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>عطیه</FirstName><LastName>دادجوی توکلی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه مدیریت آموزشی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد علی </FirstName><LastName>حسینی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علوم بهزیستی و توانبخشی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مصطفی </FirstName><LastName>نیکنامی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد جواد </FirstName><LastName>صالحی</LastName><Affiliation>مؤسسه پژوهش و برنامه ریزی آموزش عالی</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day></History><Abstract>The purpose of study is to provide a model for the participation of the nongovernmental sector in higher education financing. By examining theoretical foundations and researches, a number of indicators and factors influencing the ways of financing higher education were identified and then during a semi-structured interview with 12 faculty members who had experience in financing ways, A total of 50 indicators were identified and then, by the content validity of the indicators adjusted and finally were approved by the experts for 11 factors influencing and based on the obtained indicators, a questionnaire with 41 items was formulated.
The questionnaire distributed and collected in a field study among 392 faculty members of the Humanities University of Tehran province, which were selected by available sampling method. The results showed that in state universities, the government had the largest share and the creation of a higher education bank had the lowest share in funding. While in private universities, students (tuition) have had the largest share of contributions and loans or loans from international institutions having had the smallest share in funding.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از انجام پژوهش ارائه مدلی برای مشارکت بخش غیردولتی در تأمین مالی آموزش عالی است. با بررسی مبانی نظری و پژوهش های انجام شده تعدادی از شاخص ها و عوامل تأثیر گذار بر راه های تأمین مالی آموزش عالی شناسایی شده و سپس در مصاحبه نیمه ساختار یافته با 12 نفر از اعضای هیأت علمی که در زمینه راه های تأمین مالی تجربه داشتند و به صورت نمونه گیری هدفمند انتخاب شدند، در مجموع 50 شاخص شناسایی شد و سپس از طریق روایی محتوایی شاخص ها تعدیل شده و در نهایت 41 شاخص برای 11عامل تأثیر گذار مورد تأیید خبر گان قرار گرفت و بر اساس شاخص های بدست آمده پرسشنامه با 41 گویه تدوین شد. پرسشنامه در یک مطالعه میدانی بین 392 نفر از اعضای هیأت علمی دانشگاه های علوم انسانی استان تهران که با روش نمونه گیری در دسترس انتخاب شده بودند، توزیع و گردآوری شد. نتایج حاصل نشان داد در دانشگاه های دولتی، دولت بیشترین سهم و ایجاد بانک آموزش عالی کمترین سهم را در تأمین منابع مالی داشته اند. در حالیکه در دانشگاه های خصوصی، دانشجو بیشترین سهم و کمک ها یا وام های مؤسسات بین المللی کمترین سهم را در تأمین منابع مالی داشته اند. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">کلید واژگان: مشارکت، بخش غیردولتی، تأمین منابع مالی، آموزش عالی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/1397062015527164315-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>