﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>46</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effect of the innovative behavior experts intuitive problem solving style   Moderator role of information technology and knowledge sharing</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle> بررسی تاثیر سبک حل مساله شهودی بر رفتار نوآورانه کارشناسان  فناوری اطلاعات با نقش تعدیلگر رفتار تسهیم دانش</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>سید مرتضی</FirstName><LastName>غیور</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام رضا</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>امیر </FirstName><LastName>غفوریان شاگردی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام رضا</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>یحیی</FirstName><LastName>کاتب</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد مشهد</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></History><Abstract>Abstract
Innovation in today’s competitive world and changing environment, is necessary not only for the growth of organization, but also for their survival. IT companies need continuous innovation more than other companies ,because of high speed of change in this area and if not innovative, they immediately exclude from competitive IT industry. The key of innovation is in innovative behavior of staff. There are various factors which have impact on the innovative behavior. This study examines the effect of intuitive problem solving style on the experts’ innovative behavior and the moderator role of knowledge sharing behavior. The statistical society of this research is IT experts of companies which are members of computer trade organization of KhorasanRazavi. Three scales of algebraic problem solving , Mora knowledge sharing behavior and Johnson innovative behavior, a 5-choice Likert range(total 26 question) have been used for measuring the research variables. Cluster sampling was performed and sampling included 290 IT experts of KhorasanRazavi province. Pearson‘s correlation and hierarchical regression style is used for data analysis. This research suggested that intuitive problem solving style to generate idea, promotion and implementation of idea (dimensions of innovative behavior) have a significant and positive impact and also the relationship between intuitive problem solving style  and innovative behavior moderates knowledge sharing behavior in three dimensions of generating idea, promoting idea and implementation of idea.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">    نوآوری در دنیای رقابتی و محیط متغیر امروز، نه تنها برای رشد سازمان‌ها، بلکه برای بقای آن‌ها نیز ضروری است. شرکت‌های فناوری اطلاعات، به دلیل سرعت بالای تغییرات در این حوزه، بیش از سایرین به نوآوری مستمر نیاز دارند و اگر نوآور نباشند، در صنعت پررقابت فناوری اطلاعات، به سرعت از گردونه خارج می‌شوند. کلید نوآوری نیز در رفتار نوآورانه کارکنان سازمان است. عوامل مختلفی بر رفتار نوآورانه تاثیر دارند. پژوهش حاضر به بررسی تاثیر سبک حل مساله شهودی بر رفتار نوآورانه و نقش تعدیلگر رفتار تسهیم دانش پرداخته است. جامعه آماری این پژوهش، کارشناسان و متخصصان فناوری اطلاعات شرکت‌های عضو سازمان نظام صنفی رایانه ای استان خراسان رضوی می‌باشند. برای سنجش متغیرهای پژوهش از سه مقیاس سبک حل مساله جبری، رفتار تسهیم دانش مورا و رفتار نوآورانه جانسن ، با طیف 5 گزینه ای لیکرت (جمعا شامل 26 سوال)، استفاده گردید. نمونه گیری به روش خوشه ای صورت پذیرفت و شامل 290 نفر از کارشناسان فناوری اطلاعات استان خراسان رضوی بوده است. برای تجزیه و تحلیل داده از روش همبستگی پیرسون و رگرسیون سلسله مراتبی استفاده شده است. این تحقیق نشان داد سبک حل مساله شهودی بر تولید ایده، ترویج ایده و پیاده سازی ایده (ابعاد رفتار نوآورانه)، دارای تاثیر مثبت و معنادار می‌باشد و نیز رفتار اشتراک دانش رابطه میان سبک حل مساله شهودی و رفتار نوآورانه را در سه بعد تولید ایده، ترویج ایده، پیاده سازی ایده تعدیل می‌کند</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سبک حل مساله شهودی، فناوری اطلاعات، رفتار نوآورانه،  رفتار تسهیم دانش</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139507121535423538-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>