﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Designing a sustainable supply chain network under sanction conditions</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>طراحی شبکه زنجیره تأمین پایدار در شرایط تحریم</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>77</FirstPage><LastPage>98</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محمدعلی</FirstName><LastName>زارع شوریجه</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران، دانشکده مدیریت</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>عزت‌اله</FirstName><LastName> اصغری‌زاده</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سید علی</FirstName><LastName>ترابی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>محقر</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day></History><Abstract>Nowadays, with the advent of the concepts of risk management and sustainability and increasing of social pressures to reduce the negative impacts of industries on the environment and society, it is almost impossible to make strategic decisions such as the supply chain network design (SCND) without considering these concerns. Accordingly, in this paper a general mixed-integer linear programming (MILP) was developed for designing a closed-loop supply chain network, under disruptions conditions and sustainability considerations (focusing on social aspects). This is a multi-echelon, multi-product and multi-modal supply chain network. The sanctions on raw materials (as disruption events) were considered in the mathematical model through planning some scenarios. The most important decision variables in this model are related to: supplier selection, quantity of each raw material, facilities location, products flow between different facilities and transportation modes. Finally, designing a closed-loop supply chain network in Iran's tire industry was taken as a real world case study to demonstrate the applicability and effectiveness of the proposed model. In addition, the sensitivity analysis on some of the important parameters was carried out.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه با ظهور مفاهیم مدیریت ریسک و پایداری و تشدید فشارهای اجتماعی برای کاهش تأثیرات منفی فعالیت صنایع بر محیط زیست و اجتماع، اتخاذ تصمیماتی مانند طراحی شبکه زنجیره تأمین (SCND) بدون توجه به این ملاحظات تقریباً ناممکن است. در این مقاله با ترکیب ملاحظات مدیریت ریسک اختلال و پایداری (با تمرکز بیشتر بر جنبه‌های‌‌ اجتماعی)، یک مدل کلی برنامه‌ریزی خطی عدد صحیح آمیخته (MILP) چندهدفه برای طراحی یک شبکه زنجیره تأمین حلقه بسته در شرایط اختلال تأمین مواد توسعه داده شد. شبکه زنجیره تأمین طراحی شده، زنجیره‌‌ای چندسطحی و چندمحصولی با حمل‌ونقل چندگانه است. رخداد تحریم به عنوان عامل اختلال تأمین مواد اولیه به صورت سناریوهای اختلال در مبادی تأمین مواد در مسأله در نظر گرفته شد. مهمترین متغیرهای تصمیم این مدل مربوط هستند به: انتخاب تأمین‌کنندگان، مقدار سفارش از هر ماده اولیه، استقرار انواع تسهیلات، جریان بین تسهیلات و نوع وسیله حمل‌ونقل. در نهایت برای سنجش اثربخشی و کاربردی بودن مدل پیشنهادی، به عنوان یک موردِ مطالعه‌ی دنیای واقعی، یک شبکه زنجیره تأمین حلقه بسته در صنعت تایر ایران طراحی گردید و روی برخی پارامترهای مهم مسأله تحلیل حساسیت صورت گرفت.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">طراحی شبکه زنجیره تأمین</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
پایداری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
اختلال</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تحریم</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدل‌ ریاضی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13980117178492-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>