﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>48</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2016</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Designing the Policy Intelligence Model for Implementing E-Government</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>طراحی مدل هوش خط¬مشی¬گذاری در راستای پیاده¬سازی دولت الکترونیک</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>حمزه </FirstName><LastName>خواستار</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بوعلی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی اصغر</FirstName><LastName>صارم</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بوعلی همدان</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></History><Abstract>Abstract:
This article presents the concept of Policy Intelligence and the way of designing it in order to implementing E-Government. Policy Intelligence is referred to a kind of information system which collects data and information from different social fields and after processing these materials, present them to policy makers in form of appropriate decision making packages. This article at first reviews E-Government and its place in our era. Then by pointing that implementing E-Government paradigm needs to using modern instruments and models, we will present Policy Intelligence model by considering the major fields of Iran's public administration. Finally, the implications of Policy Intelligence, which are monitoring and governance of society, will be articulated.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">مقاله حاضر به ارائه مفهوم هوش خط¬مشی¬گذاری و طراحی آن در راستای دستیابی به هدف پیاده¬سازی دولت الکترونیک می¬پردازد. هوش خط¬مشی¬گذاری به نوعي سیستم اطلاعاتی گفته می¬شود که اطلاعات و داده¬ها را از عرصه¬های مختلف اجتماعی گردآوری کرده و پس از پردازش، آنها را به صورت بسته¬های مناسب تصمیم¬گیری در اختیار خط¬مشی¬گذاران می¬گذارد. در ابتدای مقاله حاضر به بررسی دولت الکترونیک و جایگاه آن در دوره معاصر پرداخته می¬شود. سپس با اشاره به اینکه پیاده¬سازی پارادایم دولت الکترونیک نیازمند بهره¬گیری از مدلها و ابزارهای نوین است، مدل هوش خط¬مشی¬گذاری با در نظر گرفتن عرصه¬های اصلی در مدیریت دولتی ايران ارائه می¬شود. در انتهای مقاله نيز، کاربردهای اصلی هوش خط¬مشی¬گذاری که شامل پایش و اداره الکترونیک جامعه است، بررسی می¬شوند. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">هوش خط&amp;#172;مشی&amp;#172;گذاری، فناوری اطلاعات، دولت الکترونیک، برنامه&amp;#172;هاي توسعه</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/1395112016934916-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>