﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>57</Volume><Issue>3-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Promoting Brand Personality Based on Effective Variables on Brand </ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ارتقاء شخصیت برند براساس متغیرهای تأثیرگذار بر برند  </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>189</FirstPage><LastPage>202</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>سعید</FirstName><LastName>میر</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد کرمانشاه</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>رشیدپور</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه ازاد اسلامی واحد اصفهان(خوراسگان)</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day></History><Abstract>The current study was conducted to introduce promoting brand personality based on effective variables on the brand using ISM approach. This study is on the basis of the mixed method research, both qualitative and quantitative, in a deductive-inductive paradigm. Regarding its purpose, this is a practical and a descriptive-survey research in nature and procedure. Statistical population of the current study in qualitative and quantitative was 15 people selected from experts at the university who were investigated based on purposive sampling method. Also, they were asked questions to obtain as much information as required. In qualitative section of this research, data-collection instrument of the text information is based on content analysis technique. The instrument of data collection in quantitative section was the ISM Matrix Questionnaire which its validity and reliability was measured using content validity and retesting. In qualitative section, the acquired data were analyzed using content analysis technique and MATLAB Software was used for analysis of data in quantitative section. The results of the study consist of introducing eight effective aspects in promoting brand personality which is introduced as the final model of the research. These aspects are: brand personality, brand performance, marketing mix, brand design, technology and social networks, customer, culture and social responsibility.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر با هدف ارتقاء شخصيت برند بر اساس متغيرهاي تأثيرگذار بر برند با استفاده از رویکرد ISM انجام پذیرفت. اين پژوهش بر پایه پژوهش¬های آمیخته و به صورت کیفی و کمی در پارادایم قیاسی- استقرایی است که از نظر هدف، كاربردي و از حيث ماهيت و روش، توصيفي پيمايشي می باشد. جامعه آماری پژوهش در بخش کیفی و کمی، 15 نفر از خبرگان در دانشگاه هستند که بر اساس روش نمونه¬گیری هدفمند و تا سرحد اشباع اطلاعات مورد نیاز و کفایت نظری مورد بررسی قرار گرفتند. در بخش کیفی پژوهش ابزار گردآوري اطلاعات متون بر اساس تکنیک تحلیل محتوا است. ابزار گردآوری اطلاعات در بخش کمی نیز پرسشنامه ماتریس  ISMاست که روایی و پایایی آن با استفاده از روایی محتوا و آزمون مجدد مورد سنجش قرار گرفت. در بخش کیفی، داده¬های بدست آمده از تکنیک تحلیل محتوا و در بخش کمی پژوهش، داده¬ها با استفاده از نرم¬افزار Matlab تحلیل شد. نتایج پژوهش مشتمل بر معرفی ابعاد هشت گانه موثر در ارتقاء شخصیت برند است که در قالب مدل نهایی پژوهش معرفی گردید. این ابعاد عبارتند از: شخصیت برند، عملکرد برند، آمیخته بازاریابی، طراحی برند، فناوری و شبکه های اجتماعی، مشتری، فرهنگ و مسئولیت اجتماعی.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">برند  ارتقاء شخصیت برند شرکت های تولید کننده قطعات مدلسازی ساختاری تفسیری</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13970612112359164158-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>