﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>1-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Build, reliability and validation of Knowledge Management questionnaire based on the model of Nonaka and Take Uchi in Payam Noor University</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ساخت، اعتباریابی و رواسازی پرسشنامه مدیریت دانش بر اساس مدل نوناکا و تاکه اوچی در دانشگاه پیام نور</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>19</FirstPage><LastPage>32</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>عباس </FirstName><LastName>عباسپور</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد رضا</FirstName><LastName>نیلی احمد آبادی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>عصمت </FirstName><LastName>مومنی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>فرهاد</FirstName><LastName>کیانفر</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day></History><Abstract>The purpose of this study was to construct reliability and validity of Knowledge management questionnaire scale among faculty members of Payam Noor University. In this research, due to the wide extent of the statistical society of this university and the uniformity of the organizational and educational structure of this university in the country, the faculty members of the centers and units of Payam Noor University of Khuzestan province in the academic year of 2016-2017 were selected as the statistical population of this research. Was studied in this research, a scale has been prepared based on the Knowledge Management Model of Nonaka and Take uchi, which evaluates the status of knowledge levels and its conversion processes. This scale was distributed electronically and in a presence among 171 faculty members of 31 centers and Payam Noor University of Khuzestan province. Cronbach's alpha coefficients were used to measure the reliability of the scale and its value was 0.84 for the whole scale. The factual and content validity of the scale was confirmed by 5 experienced experts. In order to assess the construct validity, factor analysis was also performed using principal components along with Varimax rotation. The extent of the explanation of the variance of variables for the eight factors extracted is 66/77 of the total variable variance. Also, the other results of the study and the construction of the current questionnaire are that the questionnaire is prepared in such a way that it can identify the centers of knowledge production and how to distribute information and knowledge in the target society. In fact, questionnaire questions can set the ideal, purpose, and ideal of an organization in such a way that the organization can achieve its purpose according to their implementation.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">تحقیق حاضر با هدف ساخت و تعیین اعتبار و روایی مقیاس پرسشنامه مدیریت دانش دربین اعضای هیات علمی دانشگاه پیام نور انجام شده است. در این تحقیق به دلیل گستردگی جامعه آماری  این دانشگاه و نیز یکسان بودن ساختار سازمانی و آموزشی این دانشگاه در سطح کشور به صورت موردی کلیه اعضای هیأت علمی مراکز و واحدهای دانشگاه پیام نور استان خوزستان در سال تحصيلي 9613-1395 به عنوان جامعه آماري این پژوهش مورد مطالعه قرارگرفت. در این تحقیق بر مبناي مدل مدیریت دانش نوناکا و تاکه اوچی، مقیاسی آماده گردید، که وضعیت سطوح دانش و فرایندهای تبدیل آن را مورد ارزیابی قرار می دهد. این مقیاس با روش سرشماری بصورت الکترونیک و حضوری در بین 171 نفراز اعضای هیات علمی 31 مرکز و واحد دانشگاه پیام نور استان خوزستان توزیع شد. براي سنجش پایایی مقیاس از روش ضرایب فرمول آلفای کرونباخ استفاده شد که مقدار آن برای کل مقیاس 84/0 بدست آمد. روايي صوري و محتوایی مقیاس توسط 5 نفر ازاساتيد مجرب تاييد گردید و برای سنجش روایی سازه  نیز از تحلیل عاملی به روش مولفه های اصلی همراه با چرخش واریماکس استفاده شد. میزان تبیین واریانس مشترک بین متغیرها برای8 عامل استخراج شده بر روی هم برابر با 66/77 درصد کل واریانس متغیر می باشد. همچنین از دیگر نتایج مطالعه و ساخت پرسشنامه حاضر اين است که پرسشــنامه به گونه اى تهيه شده كه قادر است مراكز توليد دانش را شناسايى و نحوه توزيع اطلاعات و دانش را در جامعه هدف بررسي نمايد. درواقع سوالات پرسشنامه مى تواند آرمان، غايت و ايده آل يك سازمان رامشــخص كند به نحوى كه سازمان با توجه به اجراي آنها، ميتواند به مقصود خود برسد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">پرسشنامه مديريت دانش</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
اعتباریابی و رواسازی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدل نوناکا و تاکه اوچی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13960407234956722-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>