﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>52</Volume><Issue>4-ب</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigating the effect of information technology on the capital decentralization and optimal management of Tehran city</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تاثیرفناوری اطلاعات در تمرکززدایی از پایتخت و مدیریت بهینه شهر تهران</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>نعیمی صدیق</LastName><Affiliation>پژوهشگاه علوم و فناوری اطلاعات ایران (ایرانداک)</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>آرمان</FirstName><LastName>ساجدی نژاد</LastName><Affiliation>پژوهشگاه علوم و فناوری اطلاعات ایران (ایرانداک)</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>10</Day></History><Abstract>Decentralization with the concept of transferring or resigning the power and decisions authorities from power centers and associated organizations has political, economical, cultural, and social dimensions.  One of the most strategic approaches to decrease the problems of Tehran as a centralized capital city is decentralization. In fact, decentralization not only leads to progress, growth, and social development for other cities of the country, but also enhances the capital administration. In this research we discuss that information technology management can lead to decentralization of Tehran with the minimum challenges and costs. Also, it can help the capital administration. Hence, in this paper, with interdisciplinary approach we first investigate the attractions of Tehran, and then apply an analytical hierarchy process (AHP) method to rank the attractions. Finally, we highlight the factors which can reduce the number of visits to Tehran by developing information technology. In fact, we propose the use of information technology to provide these attractions available in the other cities. Pairwise comparisons of attribute preferences are determined by experts from public and private organizations. The research findings shows that information technology not only has a significant effect on traffic reduction and optimum administration of Tehran city but also cause a much fare assignment of Tehran facilities to the other cities in the country. </Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">تمرکززدایی با مفهوم انتقال و یا واگذاری قدرت و اختیارات تصمیم‌گیری از مراکز قدرت و نهادهای وابسته به‌آن دارای ابعاد سیاسی، اقتصادی، فرهنگی و اجتماعی می‌باشد. یکی از بهترین و راهبردی ترین راه در مورد کاهش مشکلات پایتخت متمرکز تهران بحث تمرکززدایی است. بنابراین تمرکززدایی نه‌تنها باعث پیشرفت، رشد و توسعه اجتماعی شهرها و مراکز کشور می‌گردد، بلکه باعث اداره بهتر پایتخت نیز می‌گردد. در این تحقیق به‌این موضوع پرداخته خواهد شد که مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات باعث می‌گردد که این مهم با کمترین چالش و هزینه انجام گیرد و چگونه باعث خواهد گردید که اداره شهر تهران راحت‌تر از گذشته گردد. بدین ترتیب در این مقاله با رویکرد میان‌رشته‌ای ابتدا جاذبه‌های شهر تهران مورد بررسی قرار می‌گیرد، سپس با استفاده از روش تجزیه و تحلیل سلسله‌مراتبی وزن هر یک از عوامل مشخص می‌شوند و رتبه‌بندی صورت می‌گیرد و در نهایت عواملی شناسایی خواهد شد که می‌توان با توسعه فناوری اطلاعات از میزان مراجعات به شهر تهران کاهید و به عبارت دیگر این جاذبه‌ها برای شهرهای دیگر کشور نیز در دسترس باشد. مقایسه‌های زوجی عوامل مختلف که کدامیک بر دیگری ترجیح دارند توسط افراد متخصص سازمان‌های دولتی و خصوصی صورت گرفته است و یافته‌های تحقیق نشان‌دهنده اینست که نه تنها فناوری اطلاعات تاثیر شگرفی در کاهش ترافیک و اداره بهینه شهر تهران دارد بلکه باعث تسهیم منابع و امکانات شهر تهران با شهرهای مختلف کشور می‌گردد.  </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">فناوری اطلاعات</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تمرکز زدایی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدیریت بهینه شهر</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تجزیه و تحلیل سلسله مراتبی گروهی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139601211251475587-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>