﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>57</Volume><Issue>3-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Identifying the key factors affecting construction project portfolios combination in iran</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>شناسایی عوامل کلیدی مؤثر بر ترکیب پروژه¬ها در پورتفولیوهای احداث ایران</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>83</FirstPage><LastPage>96</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مریم</FirstName><LastName>عاملی بصیری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>رضا</FirstName><LastName>فلسفی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه هنر تهران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>احسان اله</FirstName><LastName>اشتهاردیان</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></History><Abstract>The current competitive and turbulent construction situation in Iran, which has a low degree of stability, has made project-based organizations encounter with a variety of unforeseen which can occur during the life of project portfolios and disrupt their performance. However, researchers in the field of portfolio management have more focused on portfolio defining processes, including project selection, prioritization and balancing, and have less considered the uncertainties which affect the portfolio expected results, eliminate strategic alignment of the portfolio components and also portolio combination optimization. In this study, by using the literature review and qualitative content analysis method, at first  we explored these factors and prioritized them with the help of inferential statistics, and then identified the most important ones from the perspective of experts in this field Based on paretto analysis. According to the findings of the research, most important factors are: change in business strategy, change in the accessibility of portfolio capital and its financing, change in economic conditions, change in the profitability and financial value of the portfolio projects and change in political conditions.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">شرایط رقابتی و پر تلاطم کنونی احداث در ایران، که از ثبات اندکی برخوردار است، سازمان¬های پروژه¬محور را با انواع تغییرات و وقایع غیرقابل پیش¬بینی مواجه می¬سازد که می¬توانند در طول عمر پورتفولیوهای پروژه رخ داده و عملکرد آن را مختل سازند؛ با این وجود اکثر محققین حوزه مدیریت پورتفولیو، فرآیندهای تعریف کننده پورتفولیو شامل انتخاب، اولویت¬بندی و توازن پروژه¬ها را مورد توجه قرار داده و به تشریح و بررسی عدم¬قطعیت¬هایی که می¬توانند بر کسب نتایج مورد انتظار از پورتفولیو تأثیر گذاشته و هم¬راستایی راهبردی اجزاء پورتفولیو را از بین برده یا ترکیب آن را از حالت بهینه خارج نمایند، کم¬تر پرداخته شده است. در پژوهش حاضر با استفاده از مطالعه ادبیات موضوع و روش تحلیل محتوای کیفی ابتدا این عوامل را شناسایی و به کمک آمار استنباطی اولویت¬بندی نموده، سپس بر اساس تحلیل پارتو، مهم¬ترین آن¬ها را از دیدگاه خبرگان این حوزه مشخص نمودیم. به استناد یافته-های تحقیق می¬¬توان اذعان داشت، از جمله مهم¬ترین این عوامل تغییر راهبرد کسب و کار، تغییر امکان دسترسی و تأمین سرمایه لازم برای پورتفولیو، تغییر شرایط اقتصادی، تغییر میزان سودآوری و ارزش مالی حاصل از اجرای پروژه و تغییر شرایط سیاسی است.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مدیریت پورتفولیو</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 عدم قطعیت</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 احداث</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13970701164523-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>