﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>55</Volume><Issue>2-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prioritize Allocating Budget For Civil Project In Ministry of Sience, Research and Technology Using Fuzzy Anatical Hierarchy Process and Fuzzy Topsis</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>اولویت بندی پروژهها  و طرحهای عمرانی وزارت علوم، تحقیقات و فناوری برای تخصیص بودجه با استفاده از تحلیل سلسله مراتبی و تاپسیس فازی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>0</FirstPage><LastPage>0</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName><LastName>علی احمدی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محسنعلی</FirstName><LastName>شایانفر</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName><LastName>فرمانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></History><Abstract>Recently, decisions and debates related to it, such as the allocation of credits for planes and projects at the country level and at managerial levels, are a major issue in organizations, ministries and official institutions of the country. The proposed model for budget allocation is a tool for accelerating decision making by managers. In this research, which was conducted to prioritize development projects at Science Research and Technology ministry , in addition to the management decision making quicknessusing, it has been tried to answer the question ,which is the most appropriate choice among options available (projects) using  multi-index models? This method is based on decision-making and decision-making matrix basis. To this end, in this research, a multi-index model is used to answer what factors are to be allocated This research studies how to design aeffective model for allocating credit to development of the construction projects in the Ministry of Science, Research and Technology using multi-criteria techniques. The purpose of this research is to identify and rank effective indicators on credit allocation and Their grading (importance coefficient) and choosing the optimal option and preparing a credit allocation model. After initial refinement among the indicators and criteria, using the fuzzy hierarchical process method and the fuzzy topisation method, which are the multi-Criteria decision-making methods  and with the help of MATLAB software and other related software which is one of the most important tools for accelerating multi-criteria decision-making techniques, criteria and indicators are ranked and weighted.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">اخیرا تصمیم گیري و مباحث پیرامون آن مانند تخصیص اعتبار برای طرح ها و پروژه ها در سطح کشور و در سطوح مدیریتی به عنوان موضوع بسیار مهم در سازمان ها ، وزارت خانه ها و نهادهای رسمی کشور مطرح است . مدل پیشنهادي برای تخصیص بودجه، ابزاري براي تسریع در تصمیم گیري مدیران محسوب می گردد . این تحقیق که برای اولویت بندی طرح¬های عمرانی در وزارت علوم ، تحقیقات و فناوری انجام گرفته است، سعی شده که با استفاده از مدل هاي چند شاخصه علاوه بر سرعت در تصمیم گیري مدیریت به این سوال پاسخ داده شود که مناسب ترین انتخاب از بین گزینه هاي موجود (پروژه ها) کدام است . این روش بر اساس شاخص هاي تصمیم گیري و برپایه ي ماتریس تصمیم بنا گردیده است . بدین منظور در این تحقیق براي پاسخ به اینکه به چه عوامل، چه امتیازي باید تخصیص داد، از مدل چند شاخصه استفاده شده است. این پژوهش به چگونگی طراحی یک مدل کار آمد جهت تخصیص اعتبار به پروژه های عمرانی در اداره طرح های عمرانی وزارت علوم، تحقیقات و فناوری با استفاده از تکنیکهاي چند معیاره پرداخته و هدف از این تحقیق شناسایی و رتبه بندي شاخص هاي موثر بر تخصیص اعتبار و درجه بندي آنها ( ضریب اهمیت ) و انتخاب گزینه بهینه و تهیه مدل تخصیص اعتبار است که پس از پالایش اولیه در بین شاخصها و معیارها با استفاده روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی و روش تاپسیس فازی که از روشهاي تصمیم گیری چند معیاره می باشند و به کمک نرم افزار تصمیم گیري متلب وسایر نرم افزارهاي مرتبط که از مهم ترین ابزارهاي کمک درتسریع فنون تصمیم گیري چند معیاره هستند ، معیارها و شاخصهای رتبه بندي شده و وزن دهی می شوند و در نهایت پروژه¬ها رتبه بندی شوند</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مدل تصمیم یار</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
روش تاپسیس فازی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تخصیص اعتبار طرح های عمرانی </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13960820158359030-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>