﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>54</Volume><Issue>1-ب</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigating organizational characteristics during the go-go and adolescence stages using the PAEI framework and the system dynamics approach</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بررسی ویژگی‌های سازمان در طول دوره عمر آن در مراحل رشد سریع و بلوغ با استفاده از چارچوب PAEI و رویکرد پویایی‌شناسی سیستم</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>103</FirstPage><LastPage>124</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>یعقوب</FirstName><LastName>فرجامی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه قم</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>رامین</FirstName><LastName>مولاناپور</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه قم</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>فاطمه </FirstName><LastName>ثقفي</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day></History><Abstract>Understanding the characteristics of an organization during different stages of its lifecycle help us make appropriate decisions at each stage in order for solving any problem. Employing the PAEI framework proposed by Adizes, and the system dynamics approach, we have analyzed the characteristics and behavior of an organization during the go-go and adolescence stages of its lifecycle. Moreover, using the system dynamics analysis approach, we have plotted the causal feedback loops and stock-and-flow diagrams of each stage of the organizational lifecycle. Then, the output of the simulations of 100 months of the go-go and adolescence stages of the organizational lifecycle performed in the VENSIM software are obtained .Finally appropriate strategies have been proposed for tackling the problems that the organization may face in each stage of its lifecycle.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">شناخت ویژگی‌های سازمان در هر یک از  مراحل عمر آن باعث می‌شود تصمیمات درستی در هر یک از این مراحل، برای حل مشکلات سازمان اتخاذ کنیم. در این مقاله با استفاده از چارچوب پیشنهادی ایزاک آدیزس (PAEI) درباره دوره عمر سازمان و روش تحلیل پویایی‌های سیستم به تحلیل ویژگی‌ها و رفتار سازمان در دوره‌های رشد سریع و بلوغ عمر آن‌ها پرداخته می‌شود. ابتدا ویژگی‌های هر یک از این مراحل به صورت جداگانه تحلیل و بررسی می‌شوند و سپس با استفاده از روش تحلیل پویایی‌های سیستم، حلقه‌های بازخوردی علت و معلولی و نمودارهای حالت و جریان مربوط به این دو مرحله از دوره عمر سازمان رسم می‌شود. سپس خروجی مربوط به شبیه‌سازی مربوط به مراحل رشد سریع و بلوغ عمر سازمان در افق زمانی 100 ماهه با استفاده از نرم‌افزار Vensim به دست آمده است. سرانجام برای این دو مرحله از مراحل عمر سازمان، استراتژی‌های مناسب برای مقابله با مشکلات آن‌ها ارائه شده است.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">دوره عمر سازمان</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدل PAEI آدیزس</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
پویایی‌شناسی سیستم</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
شبیه‌سازی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدیریت استراتژیک</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139603271942316591-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>