﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>61</Volume><Issue>1-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2018</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>A framework for organizational social capital development based on the organizational emotional capital</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>توسعه چارچوبی برای توسعه سرمایه اجتماعی در سازمان¬های ایرانی برمبنای سرمایه عاطفی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>81</FirstPage><LastPage>92</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>سید محمد</FirstName><LastName>طغرا</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>حسن </FirstName><LastName>زارعی متین</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سید حسین</FirstName><LastName>اخوان علوی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>حمیدرضا</FirstName><LastName>یزدانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></History><Abstract>Social capital development is one of the most important challenges of the managers in the today organizations. Decrease of social capital index as level is in Iran proves the necessity of research in this field. Emotional behaviors is an important aspect of interpersonal communication. This research tries to develop a framework for social capital development based on the organizational emotional capital. This is a qualitative research and uses grounded theory method with emerging approach. Data collection in this research is done using a semi-structured interview. Interviewees where selected from managers in public sector and NGOs of Markazi and Qom provinces. Theoretical saturation after 16 interviews. Final framework of this research consists of two schemas, first one diagnosis social capital and the second one emotional based development of social capital. Under diagnosis schema there are three main categories causes of social capital weakness symptoms of emotional capital weakness and consequences of social capital weakness. And under the second schema there are four main categories reinforcing phenomenon, central phenomenon (emotional social capital), strategies and outcomes.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">توسعه سرمایه اجتماعی امروزه از دغدغه های مهم مدیران در سازمانها است. همچنین افت شاخصهای سرمایه اجتماعی در ایران بیانگر اهمیت بالای نیاز به تفکر و اقدام در راستای توسعه آن است. نکته مهم در مورد ارتباطات انسانها ابعاد هیجانی رفتار انسانی است.این پژوهش به دنبال تدوین چارچوبی برای توسعه سرمایه اجتماعی در سازمان ها بر مبنای سرمایه عاطفی سازمانی می باشد. این پژوهش از نوع کیفی بوده و با استفاده از روش نظریه داده بنیاد با رویکرد نوظهور به تدوین چارچوب توسعه سرمایه اجتماعی بر مبنای سرمایه عاطفی پرداخته است.داده برداری در این روش از طریق مصاحبه نیمه ساختاریافته با جمعی از مدیران و کارکنان سازمان های دولتی و مردم نهاد ایرانی در استان های قم و مرکزی انجام شد. طی مصاحبه با ۱۶ نفر اشباع نظری به دست آمد. چهارچوب نهایی این پژوهش شامل دو الگوی "تشخیص و تعیین افت سرمایه اجتماعی" و "توسعه عاطفی سرمایه اجتماعی" می‌باشد. در الگوی تشخیص 3 مقوله اصلی علل ضعف سرمایه اجتماعی ،نشانه های افت شاخصهای سرمایه اجتماعی و عواقب افت سرمایه اجتماعی دیده می‌شود. همچنین در الگوی توسعه عاطفی سرمایه اجتماعی 4 مقاله اصلی شامل ماهیت های تقویت کننده ،پدیده محوری( سرمایه اجتماعی عاطفی)، راهبردها و نتایج وجود دارند.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سرمایه اجتماعی عاطفی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 هوش هیجانی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
سرمایه عاطفی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
نظریه داده بنیاد</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
الگوی تشخیص</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
الگوی توسعه</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13970930166313-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>