﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>The sustainable design of the supply chain of bioethanol production of sugarcane </ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>طراحی پایدار زنجیره تأمین تولید اتانول زیستی از نیشکر</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>0</FirstPage><LastPage>0</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>هادی</FirstName><LastName>صاحبی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>هانی</FirstName><LastName>گیلانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم وصنعت</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></History><Abstract>High cost, the risk of ending fossil fuels and pollution severely threatens metropolitan areas today and therefore paying attention to renewable energies is inevitable. This paper presents a three-level supply chain of bioethanol production with the three objectives of maximizing profit, reducing environmental impacts and maximizing social impacts, using the Epsilon-constraint method for optimization. On the third level, there are several consumer markets that satisfy end-customer demand. The type of feedstock intended is sugarcane, which can be used to produce bioethanol. The planning horizon of the model is multi-period, and the relationship of chain levels to each other may be disrupted. Finally, a case study in the Southwest region of Iran demonstrates the function of the model.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">گراني و خطر پايان يافتن سوخت هاي فسيلي و شدت آلودگي هوا امروزه کلان شهرها را به شدت تهديد مي کند و از این رو توجه به انرژی های تجدید پذیر امری اجتناب ناپذیر است. در این مقاله یک زنجیره تأمین سه سطحی تولید اتانول زیستی با سه هدف ماکزیمم کردن سود، کاهش اثرات زیست محیطی و ماکزیمم کردن اثرات اجتماعی ارائه گردید است که برای حل آن از روش اپسیلون- محدودیت استفاده شده است. در سطح سوم چندین بازار مصرف وجود دارد که به ارضا کردن تقاضای مشتری نهایی می پردازند. نوع خوراک در نظر گرفته شده نیشکر است که می توان از آن ها برای تولید اتانول زیستی استفاده کرد. افق برنامه ریزی چند دوره ای با فرض این که ارتباط سطوح زنجیره با یکدیگر ممکن است دچار اختلال شوند. در نهایت با یک مطالعه موردی در منطقه جنوب شرقی ایران کارکرد مدل نشان داده شده است.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">زنجیره تأمین</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 زنجیره تأمین پایدار</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 اتانول زیستی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
برنامه ریزی سناریو محور</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
اختلال</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13981030214850-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>