﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2013</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigation and Ranking of Proper Inter-Organizational Theories in Supply Chain Management (SCM) with Fuzzy Analytical Hierarchy Process (FAHP)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ارزیابی و اولویت¬بندی تئوری¬های روابط ¬سازمانی مناسب در مدیریت زنجیره تأمین(SCM) با رویکرد تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی(FAHP)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>فاطمه </FirstName><LastName>شخصیان</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سید محمد صادق </FirstName><LastName>خاکسار</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه لترب، ملبورن، استرالیا </Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></History><Abstract>One of the key success factors of supply chain management (SCM) is inter-organizational relations controlling and coordination. Investigation on the literature shows that there is a gap in theoretical foundation for illustrating this kind of interactions. One of its solution is using of theories in other fields which are conformable in SCM. In this research four inter-organizational theories (Principal- Agent Theories, transaction cost analysis; the network theory; and the resource-based view) based on the literature are considered. The aim is determine their importance and preference upon proper theory evaluation criteria for development theoretical foundation of SCM according to this research. The research was descriptive-survey based on the experts’ viewpoint with the use of Fuzzy Analytical Hierarchy Process (FAHP). As a result, “reality” and “logical consistency” have the upset weight for the theories’ evaluation. In theories evaluation, “transaction cost analysis” and “the resource-based view “were more appropriate than two others.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">یکی از عوامل موفقیت در مدیریت زنجیره تأمین، کنترل و هماهنگی روابط میان سازمانی است. بررسی ادبیات حاکی از کمبود تئوری¬های پایه¬ای مناسب جهت تشریح تعاملات میان سازمانی است. یکی از راه¬حل¬های برطرف کردن این مشکل بکارگیری تئوری¬های مطرح در حوزه تعاملات بین سازمانی است. در این تحقیق چهار تئوری اصلی روابط سازمانی تحت عناوین«تئوری کارفرما- کارگزار»، «تئوری تحلیل هزینه مبادله»، «تئوری شبکه»، و «تئوری مبتنی بر منابع» بر اساس بررسی پیشینه موضوع انتخاب شده و میزان اهمیت و اولویت آنها بر پایه معیارهای ارزیابی تئوری مناسب جهت توسعه پایه¬های نظری مدیریت زنجیره تأمین از جنبه روابط میان سازمانی مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. تحقیق به روش توصیفی- پیمایشی با نظرخواهی از خبرگان و استفاده از روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی انجام شد. که در نتیجه معیارهای «واقعیت¬گرایی» و «سازگاری منطقی» دارای بالاترین اوزان برای تئوری¬های مورد بررسی شناخته شدند. طی ارزیابی تئوری¬ها دو تئوری تحلیل" هزینه مبادله " وتئوری مبتنی بر منابع" مرتبه بالاتری جهت بکارگیری برای ارتقای موفقیت مدیریت زنجیره تامین نسبت به دو تئوری دیگر کسب نمودند.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مدیریت زنجیره تأمین</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 تئوری&amp;#172;های روابط سازمانی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 معیارهای تئوری مناسب</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی.</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139412121411281355-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>