﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>31</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2014</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Model Designing of Total Softpower Policy  the Islamic Republic of Iran</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>طراحی الگوی جامع سیاستگذاری قدرت نرم جمهوری اسلامی ایران</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محمد تقی </FirstName><LastName>امینی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد </FirstName><LastName>محمودی میمند</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمدمهدی </FirstName><LastName>پرهیزگار</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد رضا </FirstName><LastName>مشایخ</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></History><Abstract>Policy making is a word which usually accompanies by government content. Government strategy in defending area and government plan for security is named security policy making.
The goal of policy making is to accelerate or decelerate a changing movement in a part, therefore; policy makings make changes inevitably which should be managed. 
The mission of the present research is to design a major policy making for soft power (soft warfare) to reach national soft security.
According to Joseph Nai, to face soft warfare holding soft power to obtain national soft security should consist of three main criteria; 1. Cultural attraction, 2. Internal political ideals, 3. Foreign policies of a state to own the capability of gaining “ideality” of internal system and foreign societies through attraction and not force or bribing. Vikers (2008) classifies the main elements of a soft power into; 1. Psychological, 2. Social, 3. Political, 4. Cultural, and 5. Scientific elements.
According to Imam Khomeini, as he mentioned in his spiritual -political last will, fundamental criteria of soft power are as follows: 1. Cultural, spiritual, social, 2. Science and industry, 3. Economic, 4. Political and military. These criteria in soft power frame, based on the opinions of Imam Khameneyee, are also determined in four groups: 1. Cultural, 2. Scientific-Technologic, 3. Unity and National Identity, political steadiness, 4. Economic and defending. Islamic Republic of Iran Constitution stresses on four powers of; 1. Cultural, 2. Social, 3. Political (domestic&amp; foreign), 4. Economic, to create a soft power and deems them as the main principle for the state development.
In the proposed four-dimensional model of this paper, the main criteria for structure of resource of soft power regarding to providing soft security and preventing soft war, includes: 
Cultural- Social, 2. Scientific-Technological, 3. Political (domestic &amp; foreign), 4. Economic.
The following actions have been performed to examine the proposed model:
Considering the four resources of soft power and their priority comparing with each other through Delphi and AHP methods
Considering the parameters of four resources of soft power and national soft security as well as their priority and abbreviating them through Delphi and AHP methods
Measuring the relation of evaluated parameters with indices of national soft security through AHP
The relation of permanence and validity and accuracy of answers by Pierson impetus indices 
Findings of the study reveal that:
1.	The main priority of soft power resources is cultural-social soft power, which gained the most marks.
2.	The second priority of soft power resources is scientific-technological soft power, which is deemed as the second resource to provide soft power.
3.	The third resource in the measurements is political (domestic &amp; foreign) resource.
4.	The weakest resource in soft power resources is economic resource.
Ideal Model:
3.	One-dimensional model “Cultural-Social”   
4.	The cultural-social resource is the one-dimensional producer of soft power for national soft security which can provide a short-term effect solely.
5.	Two-Dimensional model “Cultural-Social” &amp; “Scientific-Technologic”
6.	This model enjoys a more strength and effect on production of national soft security.
7.	Three-Dimensional model “Cultural-Social” &amp; “Scientific-Technologic”&amp; “Political (domestic &amp; foreign)”
1.	Four-Dimensional model “Cultural-Social” &amp; “Scientific-Technologic”&amp; “Political (domestic &amp; foreign)” &amp; “Economic”
2.	This model is complete and comprehensive for policy making of effective resources to remove threats and soft war and develops national soft power and makes use of the highest capacities of existing state soft power.

Finally, after conclusion, some proposals have been offered to organization, researchers, thinkers and scientists to continue the way.
 
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">سیاستگذاری واژه ای است که معمولا با مفهوم دولت همراه است . هدف سیاستگذاری، همواره شتاب بخشیدن یا کند کردن جریان تغییر در یک بخش است. سیاستگذاری حوزه قدرت نرم جمهوری‎اسلامی‎ایران مستلزم طراحی الگویی جامع، مانع و کامل است که محقق پس از بررسی 30 مدل سیاستگذاری، مدل فرایندی یا مرحله‎ای را به عنوان مناسبترین الگو جهت دستیابی به این هدف به کار گرفته است. 
نظر به اینکه هدف تحقیق مبنی بر طراحی الگوی سیاستگذاری جامع قدرت نرم جمهوری‎اسلامی‎ایران به منظور تأمین امنیت نرم نظام و دفع تهدید نرم است و جنگ نرم، محقق ضمن استخراج منابع قدرت نرم از دیدگاه تئوریستهای غربی و نظرات امام خمینی(ره) و امام خامنه‎ای (حفظه ا...) و قانون اساسی جمهوری اسلامی ایران، منابع چهارگانه قدرت نرم را به عنوان معیارهای اصلی در پانل دلفی به ترتیب:
1-	منبع قدرت نرم فرهنگی – اجتماعی  2- منبع قدرت نرم علم - فناوری 
3-	منبع قدرت نرم سیاسی (داخلی و خارجی) 4- منبع قدرت نرم اقتصادی
استخراج و زیر معیارهای هر کدام از معیارها را به طور مستقل پس از چهار مرحله دلفی، احصاء نموده و الویت آنان را نسبت به هم  با روش AHP تعیین گردید و در پایان نیز با روش ضریب  همبستگی پیرسون رابطه معیارها و زیرمعیارهای منابع را با معیارها و زیرمعیارهای امنیت نرم سنجیده شده است.
نتایج این تحقیق نشان میدهد که در فاز دو الگوی سیاستگذاری که مرحله شکل‎گیری و تنظیم سیاست است، الویت بندی معیارهای اصلی چهارگانه قدرت نرم به ترتیب فرهنگی- اجتماعی، علمی- فناوری، سیاسی (داخلی و خارجی) و اقتصادی می‎باشد که بایستی توسط سیاستگذاران و استراتژی پردازان قدرت نرم، مورد توجه قرار گیرد  تا سطوح سه گانه تاکتیکی، عملیاتی و استراتژیک سیاستگذاری نرم نظام تأمین گردد. 
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سیاستگذاری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 جنگ نرم</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 قدرت نرم</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 امنیت نرم</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 منبع قدرت فرهنگی- اجتماعی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
علمی- فناوری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 سیاسی (داخلی و خارجی) و اقتصادی.</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139412121654171365-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>