﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>1-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>(Proposing a Rapid Plant Assessment Hybrid method using Data Envelopment Analysis for Municipalities Performance Evaluation (Case Study: Isfahan Municipality</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ارائه روش تلفيقي ارزيابي سريع با تحليل پوششي داده¬ها جهت ارزيابي عملکرد شهرداري‌ها  (مورد مطالعه: در شهرداری اصفهان )</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>209</FirstPage><LastPage>226</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>روزبه</FirstName><LastName>قوسی</LastName><Affiliation>علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علي</FirstName><LastName>نداف پور</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></History><Abstract>Municipal is a public institution that independent, non-governmental, to the nature of the state and local performance that has the duty of the city and serve the citizens and tourists to be responsible, and as one of the principles of management, use of local resources to its task-focused.
Effective accountability and improve the efficient activities of a variety of municipal needs assessment. Evaluating the performance of the corporate sector is usually synonymous with the effectiveness of activities. One of the methods used to assess is fast evaluate. And other quantitative performance Assessment methods, data is envelopment analysis that relative to assessment of performance pay.
Given the importance of evaluating the performance of municipalities, this study provides a combination of performance assessment using data envelopment analysis and rapid assessment are discussed. For this purpose, in the first chapter the words of the issue has been discussed and explained the objectives and research questions. In the second chapter the research literature and research methods described in Chapter III.
In the fourth chapter the index has been developed for the rapid assessment to evaluate areas of the municipality. And by providing rapid assessment of tick box of municipalities was discussed. Which formed DEA model to evaluate the relative performance of municipalities and the number of performance in each region were determined. Then by sensitivity analysis on the model input data envelopment analysis to prioritize rapid assessment indicators, and then use the same method to determine the priority region of the municipality was the ideal option. After the above steps, in the rapid assessment survey regions 6, 11 and 12, respectively ranked first and the third &amp; in evaluating the performance of the municipal regions of the DEA BCC using the input, the number of functional regions, including six regions units 4, 5, 8, 13, 14 and 15 were identified  and in combination with problem solving method returns to scale the number of functional regions, including four units, the regions 4, 5, 8, 13, 14 and 15 were determined. After sensitivity analysis of the input variables in BCC, The effect of varying complexity and diversity management practices and continuous improvement and effective management also vary in SBM 's been more than others. The results of the rapid assessment approach by prioritizing organizational units similar to the ideal option indicated that the municipal zone 11 has a minimum distance with the ideal option and has earned first place and then in the region 6 won the second prize.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">میزان پاسخگویی اثربخش و بهبود کارآمد فعالیت های متنوع شهرداری، نیازمند ارزیابی است. از طرفی با توجه به کمبود منابع و امکانات در سازمان‌ها و بالاخص در شهرداری‌ها، استفاده مناسب و بهره‌ور از این منابع اهمیت بالایی پیدا می‌کند و بدین منظور مدیران جهت بررسی وضعیت واحدهاي سازماني بایستی بتوانند به ارزیابی دوره‌ای آن بپردازند. لذا محقق در این پژوهش به ارایه روش تلفیقی ارزیابی عملکرد با استفاده از روش تحلیل پوششی داده ها و ارزیابی سریع پرداخته است. بدين منظور در ابتدا با استفاده از نظرخواهي از خبرگان، به تعيين شاخص¬هاي ارزيابي سریع در شهرداري¬ها پرداخته و در ادامه با استفاده از مدل¬هاي تحليل پوششي داده¬ها به ارزيابي عملکرد آن-ها پرداخته شد، سپس با تحلیل حساسیت بر روی ورودی های مدل تحلیل پوششی داده ها ، به اولویت بندی شاخص های ارزیابی سریع و در انتها با استفاده از روش شباهت به گزینه ایده¬آل اولویت‌بندی مناطق شهرداری انجام گردید. در پایان براي بررسي قابليت اجرايي روش پيشنهادي در اين پژوهش، شهرداري اصفهان به عنوان مطالعه موردي انتخاب شد. پس از انجام مراحل فوق، در ارزیابی عملکرد مناطق شهرداری اصفهان با تحلیل پوششی داده ها به روش بی سی سی ورودی¬محور، تعداد مناطق کارا، شش منطقه‌ي 4، 5، 8، 13، 14 و 15 و در روش حل مسأله به روش ترکیبی با بازده به مقیاس متغیر تعداد مناطق کارا، چهار منطقه شامل 4، 5، 8، 13، 14 و 15 تعیین گردید و پس از تحلیل حساسیت در متغیرهای ورودی در روش بی سی سی، تاثیر متغیر مدیریت پیچیدگی و تنوع روشها و بهبود مستمر و در روش اس بی ام نیز متغیر مدیریت اثر بخش بیشتر از سایر موارد بوده است. نتایج حاصل از اولویت بندی واحدهای سازمانی با رویکرد ارزیابی سریع به روش شباهت به گزینه ایده‌آل نیز نشان داد که منطقه 11 رتبه اول را بدست آورد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">ارزيابي عملکرد</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
ارزيابي سريع</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تحليل پوششي داده ها</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 شباهت به گزینه ایده آل</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
شهرداري</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13951019104264544-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>