﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2014</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>An Investigation of Knowledge Management capability success factors in small Technology based enterprises in Technology Incubators</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تبیین عوامل موثر برپیاده سازی سامانه ی مدیریت دانش در شرکت های فناورکوچک مستقر در مراکز رشد فناوری</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName><LastName> کاظمی</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>غلامرضا </FirstName><LastName>ملک زاده</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد </Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></History><Abstract>Success Factors in Knowledge Management (KM) capability in small and medium enterprises (SMEs) have less been systematically investigated. Existing studies have derived their CSFs from large companies' perspectives and have not considered the needs of small businesses. In this article, existing studies on Knowledge Management capability success factors were reviewed and their limitations were identified. By integrating insights drawn from these studies, the authors proposed a set of 11 CSFs which is believed to be more suitable for SMEs. An empirical assessment was conducted to evaluate the extent of success of proposed propositions using experts’ opinions.  The overall results from the empirical assessment were positive, thus reflecting the appropriateness of the proposed success factors.  The set of success factors can act as a list of items for SMEs to address when adopting KM. However it can provide a common language for managers to discuss and study the factors crucial for the success of KM in SMEs. 
The results show that adequate and suitable leadership and management supports, use of Information Technology, bussiness strategies, motivation, resource availability, personnel education, human resource management, performance assessment measures, infrastructures and Knowledge Management processes can increase Knowledge Management capability in small firms. Organization culture, Leadership and management and leader supports and Information Technology were the most important factors</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش در رابطه با عوامل موثربر موفقیت در پیاده سازی مدیریت دانش در شرکت های کوچک و متوسط کمتر صورت گرفته است.مطالعات موجود عوامل موثر بر پیاده سازی  مدیریت دانش را از دیدگاه شرکت های بزرگ مورد بررسی قرار داده اند ولی به نیازهای شرکت های کوچک توجه چندانی نشده است . این مقاله در پی ایجاد پلی برروی این شکاف مطالعاتی است . با بررسی و مرورمطالعات انجام شده،یازده عامل که به نظر می رسد برای شرکت های کوچک مناسب باشند انتخاب گردید و یک ارزیابی عملی با بهره گیری ازنظرات یک گروه کارشناسانی و خبره،فرضیه های تحقیق مورد آزمون قرارگرفت. نتایج کلی رضایتبخش و مثبت بود وعوامل شناسائی شده مورد تأئیدگروه خبرگان قرار گرفت. این مجموعه از عوامل می تواند در هنگام اقدام برای پیاده سازی مدیریت دانش در شرکت های کوچک مورد استفاده قرار گیرد و به مدیران کمک کند زبانی مشترک به دست آورند.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">موفقیت </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 مدیریت دانش</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
شرکت های کوچک و متوسط</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
فرهنگ سازمانی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
راهبرد</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
رهبری </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139412121753521372-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>