﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2014</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reviewing the role of knowledge management tools in employee empowerment using Fuzzy AHP (Case study in knowledge-based companies located on science and technology parks)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>شکل‏گیری چارچوبی برای توسعه نظام های منطقه ای نوآوری مبتنی بر تجارب موفق سایر کشورها</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>میثم </FirstName><LastName>جعفری</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>حامد </FirstName><LastName>نوذری</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد ابراهیم </FirstName><LastName>صادقی</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سید سعید </FirstName><LastName>منجم زاده</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></History><Abstract>Employees are critical factors for organization survival Therefore, empowering of them can play an important role in increasing the competitiveness of organizations. Studies show that five dimensions are effective in empowering which includes: "work meaning", "competence", "self-determination", "impact" and "trust". Knowledge management is one of the issues connected to human resource management and employee empowerment and various tools are used in processes related to knowledge management in organizations. The aim of this study is evaluation of knowledge management tools in employee empowerment. Therefore, seven knowledge management tools were selected by asking experts’ point of views. The statistical population of this study was considered the Knowledge-based companies located in science and technology parks and ultimately 43 questionnaires were studied. In this study Fuzzy AHP were used in order to ranking of seven tools of knowledge management. Results shows that among of seven tools “by asking experts’ point of view” and “In-service training” have greatest effect on employee empowerment and “Job Rotation” and “impact” have minimal effect on employee empowerment</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">اهمیت توسعه منطقه ای و جایگاه مهم آن در ارتقاء توانمندی نوآوری و رقابتپذیری ملی، موجب توجه ویژه به توسعه نوآوری در سطح منطقه و شکلگیری مفهوم «نظام منطقه ای نوآوری» در سال های اخیر شده و در این زمینه مطالعات قابل توجهی توسط محققین و مراکز تحقیقاتی و سیاستگذاری در سطح جهان صورت پذیرفته است. با این حال این موضوع چندان که شایسته است در کشور ما مورد بررسی قرار نگرفته است. با توجه به خلأ مطالعاتی موجود و در عین حال نیاز کشور در این زمینه، در این مقاله تلاش نموده ایم تا با بررسی ادبیات مربوط به این حوزه و مطالعه تحقیقات کاربردی صورت گرفته، مولفه های اصلی شکلگیری و ارتقاء نظام های منطقه ای نوآوری را استخراج نماییم. به منظور تجزیه و تحلیل اطلاعات و ارائه نظریه نهایی، از روش رویش نظریه ها استفاده شده است. در مدل نهایی ارائه شده، شرایط علی، شرایط مداخله گر، شرایط زمینه ای، و تعاملات، فرایندها و استراتژیهای توسعه نظام های منطقه ای نوآوری و نیز پیامدهای آن تشریح و تبیین شده است. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">نظام منطقه ای نوآوری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 توسعه منطقه ای</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 رویش نظریه ها یا روش گراندد</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139412121842531378-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>