﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>49</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Identify factors affecting Internet Banking Service Quality Case Study: Mellat Bank customers</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>شناسایی عوامل موثر بر کیفیت خدمات بانکداری اینترنتی  مورد مطالعه: مشتریان بانک ملت  </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مریم </FirstName><LastName>اخوان </LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مجید</FirstName><LastName>باقری</LastName><Affiliation>مدیریت و حسابداری</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day></History><Abstract>Today, service quality, sustainable competitive advantage for the bank to bring it helps to create value and customer satisfaction. Therefore, improving the quality of customer service is vital for them. This study examined the factors affecting customers' perception of Internet banking through careful investigation of the main studies as well as different models provided for quality assessment of electronic services. Based on the findings, an optimal model for the quality assessment of Internet banking services provided by Mellat Bank was designed. The statistical population included customers of the Internet banking services provided by Mellat Bank in Isfahan. Data collection was done using a questionnaire whose validity was confirmed according to experts' opinions and the reliability of the test was assessed using Cronbach's alpha for the initial sample and for the main test performed on all subjects in the statistical population, showing a high reliability. The second-order factor analysis was used to test the research hypotheses and prioritize the factors affecting the quality of electronic banking services. The findings showed that website design, responsiveness, empathy, guarantee, efficiency, security/trust, and compensation for damage were the most effective factors (in the order of significance) in the quality of Mellat Bank on-line Internet banking services.

</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه کیفیت خدمات، مزیت رقابتی پایداری را برای بانک‌ها به همراه می‌آورد زیرا به ایجاد ارزش و رضایت مشتریان کمک می‌کند. ازاین‌رو بهبود کیفیت خدمت‌رسانی به مشتری برای آن‌ها اهمیتی حیاتی یافته است.در این پژوهش با بررسی دقیق مطالعات اصلی و مدل‌های مختلف ارائه‌شده در خصوص کیفیت خدمات الکترونیکی، عوامل مؤثر بر نگرش مشتریان در خصوص بانکداری اینترنتی موردبررسی قرارگرفته و مدل بهینه جهت سنجش کیفیت خدمات بانکداری اینترنتی بانک ملت طراحی گردیده است. جامعه آماري پژوهش شامل مشتریان خدمات بانکداری اینترنتی بانک ملت می باشد. جمع‌آوري‌ داده‌ها‌ در این پژوهش با ابزار ‌پرسشنامه انجام گردیده که روايي آن با استفاده از نظرات خبرگان تایید شده و روش آلفاي کرونباخ در نمونه اوليه و در کل جامعه آماری نشان از پايايي بالای آن داشته است. در پژوهش حاضر، از تحلیل عاملی مرتبه دو براي آزمون فرضيه¬هاي تحقيق و اولویت بندی عوامل موثر در کیفیت خدمات بانکداری الکترونیکی استفاده شده است. که در نهایت یافته‌های این پژوهش نشان می‌دهد که طراحی وبسایت، پاسخگویی، همدلی، تضمین، کارایی، امنیت/اعتماد، جبران خسارت به ترتیب به‌عنوان مهم‌ترین ابعاد موثر در کیفیت خدمات بانکداری آنلاین در بانک ملت می باشند. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">: کیفیت خدمات الکترونیکی،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 بانکداری اینترنتی،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 رضایت مشتری</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13950607188473248-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>