﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>48</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2016</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Studying the effect of Qualified Management on Environmental Management and Green Supply Chain and their impact on Green function  ( A Case study done by:Pars Khazar co.)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر مدیریت کیفیت بر مدیریت محیطی و زنجیره تأمین سبز و اثر آن ها بر عملکرد سبز ( مورد بررسی شرکت پارس خزر )</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>سید سجاد</FirstName><LastName>محتشم</LastName><Affiliation>موسسه آموزش عالی راهبرد شمال</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>رضا </FirstName><LastName>اسماعیل پور</LastName><Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت ،دانشگاه گیلان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد رحیم </FirstName><LastName> رمضانیان</LastName><Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت ،دانشگاه گیلان</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></History><Abstract>Nowadays, in the competitive market, for survival in the global and local competition, companies are required to improve the quality of their goods and do not limit the improvement of the quality of their products to a series of characteristics and features to attract the customers’ satisfaction. But, they consider the quality in the product’s design and process and believe that in order to achieve a developed production and improve the performance, they must include the environmental factor in the quality of their goods. Considering environmental factors and managing the green supply chain are effective in the quality of goods and lead to an improvement in the performance of companies in production.
This research is applied in terms of objective and scientific in terms of nature and research methodology, and its statistical population includes all managers, experts, consultants, engineers, employees, customers and some of expert activists in the sector of Pars Khazar manufacturing companies and their relating branches. For data analysis, the structural equations modeling, partial least squares, multivariate analysis and fitness model variables test were done using LISREL(8.5) and SPSS(21) softwares. 
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه در بازار رقابتی شرکت‌ها برای بقاء در عرصه رقابت جهانی و محلی بهبود در کیفیت کالاهای خود را امری ضروری دانسته و در جهت جلب رضایت مشتریان خود، بهبود در کیفیت محصول را تنها به یک سری از ویژگی‌ها و مشخصات محدود نمی‌کنند بلکه کیفیت در طراحی محصول و فرایند را نیز مورد نظر قرار داده و براین عقیده‌اند که برای رسیدن به تولید توسعه یافته و بهبود عملکرد، عامل زیست محیطی را نیز در کیفیت کالاهای خود لحاظ کنند. توجه به عوامل زیست محیطی و مدیریت زنجیره تأمین سبز در کیفیت کالاها مؤثر بوده و به بهبود عملکرد شرکت‌ها در تولیدات می‌انجامد. 
این پژوهش از لحاظ هدف کاربردی و به لحاظ ماهیت و روش تحقیقی علّی می‌باشد وجامعه آماری آن را کلیه مدیران، کارشناسان، مشاوران، مهندسان، کارکنان، مشتریان و برخی از فعالان خبره در بخش شرکت‌های تولیدی پارس خزر و شعبات مرتبط آن تشکیل می‌دهند، جهت تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها نیز از روش‌های معادلات ساختاری، حداقل مربعات جزیی، تجزیه تحلیل چند متغیره و آزمون متغیرهای مدل جهت برازش نیز با استفاده از نرم افزار LISREL(8.5) و SPSS(21) انجام شده است.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مدیریت کیفیت</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدیریت محیطی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 زنجیره تامین سبز </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 عملکرد سبز</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139511201614264918-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>