﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>2-ب</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Creating a systemic model for identifying the success factors of establishing a knowledge management system in aeronautical organizations and providing improvement solutions (case study: one of the Air Organizations)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ایجاد مدلی سیستمی برای شناسایی عوامل موفقیت استقرار نظام مدیریت دانش در سازمان‌های هوایی و ارائه راهکارهای بهبود (مورد مطالعاتی:یکی از سازمان‌های هوایی) </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>109</FirstPage><LastPage>122</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>سید حسین</FirstName><LastName>حسینی</LastName><Affiliation>عامل موسسه آموزشی-پژوهشی سیستم‌های مدیریتی الگو محور(سمام)</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day></History><Abstract>In today's world, many organizations with low profits, limited capital and intensive competition, and at the same time must meet the endorsements of shareholders, are successful organizations that can create better opportunities and create new opportunities. Given the importance of knowledge and its pivotal role in the knowledge age, organizations, especially knowledge-based organizations, whose knowledge is a strategic source and a key factor in acquiring and maintaining the core competence of the organization, is essential for establishing knowledge management and identifying obstacles. Thought ahead with implementation with a systematic approach to develop the capabilities that lead to the development of knowledge as a key source of enterprise. In order to achieve this goal, a knowledge-based knowledge-based airspace-based knowledge management organization was considered and a system model was mapped out. At first, various factors that can be effective were identified through questionnaires and interviews and literature reviews. Then, the causal and impulsive diagrams, which are one of the tools used in the dynamics dynamics methodology, were drawn and finally, these factors were prioritized using the fuzzy dematerial method and the effective and effective factors were identified. The rate of knowledge sharing, the number of human resources with a high level of knowledge and experience, the quality of individual work of the staff, the culture of sharing knowledge and the level of attention of senior executives to the IT infrastructure were the five most important and important factors. These factors were used as the basis for developing knowledge management strategies in the organization in order to achieve effective strategic strategies. In today's world, many organizations with low profits, limited capital and intensive competition, and at the same time must meet the endorsements of shareholders, are successful organizations that can create better opportunities and create new opportunities. Given the importance of knowledge and its pivotal role in the knowledge age, organizations, especially knowledge-based organizations, whose knowledge is a strategic source and a key factor in acquiring and maintaining the core competence of the organization, is essential for establishing knowledge management and identifying obstacles. Thought ahead with implementation with a systematic approach to develop the capabilities that lead to the development of knowledge as a key source of enterprise. In order to achieve this goal, a knowledge-based knowledge-based airspace-based knowledge management organization was considered and a system model was mapped out. At first, various factors that can be effective were identified through questionnaires and interviews and literature reviews. Then, the causal and impulsive diagrams, which are one of the tools used in the dynamics dynamics methodology, were drawn and finally, these factors were prioritized using the fuzzy dematerial method and the effective and effective factors were identified. The rate of knowledge sharing, the number of human resources with a high level of knowledge and experience, the quality of individual work of the staff, the culture of sharing knowledge and the level of attention of senior executives to the IT infrastructure were the five most important and important factors. These factors were used as the basis for developing knowledge management strategies in the organization in order to achieve effective strategic strategies.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در دنیای امروز که بسیاری از سازمان‌ها با سود کم، سرمایه محدود وتحت رقابت فشرده فعالیت می‌کنند و در عین حال باید انتطارات سهامداران را نیز برآورده نمایند، سازمان‌هایی موفق هستند که بتوانند موقعیت بهتر و فرصت‌های جدید ایجاد کنند. با توجه به اهمیت دانش و نقش محوری آن در عصر دانشی، ضرورت دارد سازمان‌ها بویژه سازمان‌های دانش محور که دانش در آنها به‌عنوان منبع استراتژیک و عامل کلیدی در کسب و ارائه و حفظ شایستگی اصلی سازمان محسوب میشود، تمهیداتی جهت استقرار مدیریت دانش و شناسایی موانع پیش روی پیاده‌سازی با یک رویکرد سیستمی اندیشیده و سنجیده شود تا قابلیت‌هایی را که منجر به تکامل دانش به‌عنوان یک منبع سازمانی کلیدی می‌گردد، توسعه دهد.
به منظور دستیابی به این هدف در این تحقیق، یک سازمان هوایی دانش محور که استقرار مدیریت دانش در آن با شکست همراه بود مورد بررسی قرار گرفت و یک مدل سیستمی برای آن ترسیم گردید. در ابتدا عوامل مختلفی که می‌توانند اثرگذار باشند از طریق پرسشنامه و مصاحبه و مرور ادبیات شناسایی شدند. سپس نمودار علی و معلولی که یکی از ابزارهای مورد استفاده در متدولوژی سیستم دینامیک می‌باشد ترسیم شد و در انتها با استفاده از روش دیماتل فازی این عوامل اولویت‌بندی شده و عوامل اثر گذار و اثر پذیر شناسایی شدند.
نرخ به اشتراک‌گذاری دانش، تعداد نیروی انسانی با سطح بالای دانش و تجربه، کیفیت کار فردی کارکنان، فرهنگ به اشتراک‌گذاری دانش و میزان توجه مدیران ارشد به زیرساخت‌های فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات، 5 عاملی بودند که بیشترین وزن و اهمیت را کسب کردند. این عوامل به عنوان مبنای تدوین استراتژی‌های مدیریت دانش در سازمان مورد استفاده قرار گرفتند تا بتوان به راهکارهای استراتژیک اثربخش دست یافت.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مدیریت دانش،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 استقرار مدیریت دانش، </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
رویکرد سیستمی، </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تکنیک دیماتل فازی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13980117178485-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>