﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>50</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Operational agility impact on organizational performance in service organizations (Iranian banks for instance)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تاثیر چابکی عملیاتی بر عملکرد سازمانی در سازمانهای خدماتی(بانک های ایران بعنوان نمونه)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مهدی</FirstName><LastName>ارجلو</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>کامران </FirstName><LastName>فیضی</LastName><Affiliation> دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>ابوالفضل </FirstName><LastName>کزازی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمدتقی</FirstName><LastName>تقوی فرد</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></History><Abstract>In recent years the concept of agility has been considered in many academic research that shows the importance of this concept in the current business world and is due to the emergence of powerful competitors, rapid technological change, changing expectations of customers, new social patterns and etc . ability of an   service organization in monitoring   and exploiting opportunities in the service sector while has many similarities with manufacturing sector ,but requaiers special finesse and   this study, developing  concept of agility to service sector want to test its effect on bank performance.The study population consisted of all 30 banks are active in Iran with at least five years experience in the industry .Due to the exploratory nature of this research, after reviewing the literature in the field of agility, providers and dimensions of service organizations operational   agility and operational agility via interview with Bank experts identified and to measure its  impact on organizational performance   PLS-SEM was used  .The findings show, operational agility has significant positive impact on organizational performance. Also among the factors affecting organizational performance by mediating variable operational agility, human resources, has the greatest impact.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">مفهوم چابکی در سالهای اخیر مورد توجه تحقیقات دانشگاهی بسیاری بوده که نشاندهنده اهمیت این مفهوم در فضای کسب کار فعلی دنیاست و ناشی از ظهور رقبای پرقدرت، تغییرات سریع تکنولوژیکی، تغییر انتظار مشتریان، الگوهای جدید اجتماعی و ... می باشد. قابلیت یک بنگاه خدماتی در رصد کردن و بهره برداری از فرصتها، در خدمات در عین حال که شباهتهای زیادی با بخشهای تولیدی دارد ظرافتهای خاصی را نیز طلب می کند که در این تحقیق برآنیم تا با توسعه مفهوم چابکی به بخش خدمات بانکداری تاثیر آنرا بر عملکرد بانک مورد توجه قرار دهیم. جامعه آماری این پژوهش تمامی 30 بانک فعال در ایران هستند که دارای حداقل سابقه فعالیت پنج سال در این صنعت باشند. با توجه به ماهیت اکتشافی این تحقیق، پس از مطالعه ادبیات موضوع در حوزه چابکی، عوامل و ابعاد چابکی عملیات در سازمانهای خدماتی با استفاده از مصاحبه با کارشناسان بانکی شناسایی شده و برای سنجش تاثیر چابکی عملیاتی بر عملکرد سازمانی، با توجه به محدودیتهای نمونه مورد مطالعه از مدلسازی معادلات ساختاری به روش PLS   استفاده شد. یافته ها نشان می دهد، چابکی عملیاتی بر عملکرد سازمانی تاثیر مثبت و معنا دار دارد. همچنین در میان عوامل تاثیر گذار بر عملکرد سازمانی با متغیر میانجی چابکی عملیاتی، منابع انسانی، بیشترین تاثیرگذاری را دارا می باشند.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">چابکی عملیاتی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
خدمات</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
ابعاد چابکی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
عوامل چابکی </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139510059804289-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>