﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>2-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2015</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Supplier selection with the approach of combining Fuzzy Delphi Analytic  Hierarchy Process (FDAHP) and Grey VIKOR methods</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>انتخاب تأمین کننده با رویکرد تلفیقی فرآیند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی دلفی فازی و روش  ویکور خاکستری </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محمد مهدی </FirstName><LastName>مظفری</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></History><Abstract>The supplier selection is one of the most important issues in supply chain management discipline and it is regarded as an effective factor for companies to survive in the competitive environment. Selecting the best supplier among various suppliers, considering a mixture of criteria that are sometimes in conflict, makes it a complicated multi-criteria decision making problem. On the other hand, supplier selection is highly dependent on the assessments of decision makers and according to the environmental dynamics and incomplete information available to decision makers, they are faced with some uncertainty in their assessments. The purpose of this paper is to present a model of multi-criteria decision making under uncertainty by using concepts of fuzzy and grey theories in order to select the optimal supplier.  In this research, first, the weights of supplier selection criteria are determined by using fuzzy Delphi and analytic hierarchy process, then suppliers are ranked by using Grey VIKOR which is a newly developed approach in the field of multi-criteria decision making under uncertainty</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">مسئله انتخاب تأمین کننده، یکی از موضوعات بسیار مهم در مدیریت زنجیره تأمین می باشد و از آن به عنوان عاملی مؤثر براي بقا در محیط رقابت یاد می شود. انتخاب بهترین تأمین کننده از میان تأمین کنندگان متعدد، با در نظر گرفتن معیارهای گوناگون و گاهاً در تضاد با یکدیگر، مقوله انتخاب تأمین کننده را به یک مسئله پیچیده تصمیم گیری چند معیاره تبدیل نموده است؛ از سوی دیگر انتخاب تأمین کننده بشدت وابسته به نظرات تصمیم  گیرندگان می باشد، که با توجه به پویایی های محیطی و ناکامل بودن اطلاعات در دسترس تصمیم گیرندگان با نوعی عدم قطعیت در بیان نظرات تصمیم گیرندگان روبرو هستیم.  هدف این مقاله، ارائه یک مدل مناسب تصمیم گیري چند معیاره در شرایط عدم قطعیت و با استفاده از مفاهیم تئوری فازی و خاکستری براي انتخاب بهینه تأمین کننده می باشد. در این مقاله ابتدا اوزان معیارهای انتخاب تأمین کننده با استفاده از روش فرآیند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی دلفی فازی(FDAHP ) تعیین و سپس با استفاده از روش ویکور خاکستری(Grey VIKOR) که یکی از رویکردهای جدید توسعه یافته  تصمیم گیری چند معیاره در شرایط عدم قطعیت، می باشد به رتبه بندی تأمین کنندگان پرداخته شده است</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">انتخاب تأمین کننده</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 تصمیم گیری چند معیاره</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 فرآیند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی دلفی فازی(FDAHP)</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
ویکور خاکستری(Grey VIKOR)</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 عدم قطعیت</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139412042314181184-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>