﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>62</Volume><Issue>1-ب</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2018</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Designing Strategic Pattern of Knowledge Management in Cultural and Educative Affairs</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>طراحی الگوی راهبردی مدیریت دانش در اداره امور فرهنگی  و تربیتی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>59</FirstPage><LastPage>72</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مهدی</FirstName><LastName>رحیمی</LastName><Affiliation>گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی،واحد تهران جنوب، تهران، ایران </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>هادی </FirstName><LastName>رزقی </LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی اکبر </FirstName><LastName>فرهنگی </LastName><Affiliation> دانشگاه تهران </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>نادر </FirstName><LastName>محقق </LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></History><Abstract>These days based on the feature and variety of cultural and educative organizations designing the knowledge management components in accordance with strategy are different and the main strategy of organization improves the synergy of organizational knowledge. Success of a cultural and educative organization relies on applying an appropriate pattern of knowledge management in ruling that organization. A variety of factors may affect designing the strategic pattern of knowledge management that noticing to them may be a key issue in designing successful pattern of knowledge management. The aim of this research is to identify the fundamental components of knowledge management in Tehran province’s prison organization that may have an effect on designing an appropriate strategic pattern of knowledge management in cultural and educative affairs.
For identifying and extracting the aimed components the qualitative method is chosen based on the explorative nature and complexity of different dimensions of research. For gathering information from the society of this research that include cultural bosses, employees and prisoners of cultural affairs the deep interview is used. The experts are chosen by using purposeful sampling method and theory. Data analysis shows that after 19 interviews the categories reached to a theoretical saturation.
Findings show that 20 components including explanation and dissemination of organizational culture, knowledge oriented strategy an policies, patterning, role of leadership, importance of human resource, appropriate infrastructure of technology and information, evaluation processes of role, organizational structure, experts’ network, assigning rewards and incentives, educational programs, cooperation and teamwork, difficulty in accessing knowledge, knowledge management architecture, reengineering, clarity, trust, systematic relationship with stakeholders, knowledge strategies, importance of recording  saving and documentation of knowledge are identified.
Conclusion: Designing strategic pattern of knowledge management in cultural and educative affairs of Tehran’s province prison organization may be successful in case the identified components find establishment and to be used in that organization concerned.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه با توجه به ویژگی و تنوع سازمان های فرهنگی و تربیتی، مؤلفه های مدیریت دانش این سازمان ها بر اساس استراتژی متفاوت است و استراتژی اصلی سازمان به هم افزایی دانش سازمانی کم می کند. توفیق راهبردی یک سازمان فرهنگی و تربیتی مستلزم بهره گیری از الگوی راهبری مناسب مدیریت دانش در اداره آن است.عوامل گوناگونی بر طراحی الگوی راهبردی مدیریت دانش در اداره امور فرهنگی و تربیتی تاثیرگذار هستند که توجه به این عوامل در طراحی موفق الگوی مدیریت دانش حیاتی است.هدف از انجام این پژوهش شناسایی عوامل اساسی مدیریت دانش در سازمان زندان های استان تهران بوده که بر طراحی مناسب الگوی راهبردی مدیریت دانش در اداره امور فرهنگی  و تربیتی اثر می گذارد.
جهت شناسایی و استخراج مولفه های مورد نظر،بنا بر ماهیت اکتشافی و نیز بدلیل پیچیدگی ابعاد مختلف پژوهش، روش کیفی انتخاب گردید. برای جمع آوری اطلاعات از جامعه مورد نظر این پژوهش شامل رؤسای فرهنگی و کارکنان ادارات فرهنگی از روش مصاحبه عمیق استفاده شد. از طریق روش نمونه گیری نظری خبرگان مورد نظر انتخاب شدند.تحلیل داده ها نشان داد که پس از نوزده مصاحبه مقولات شکل گرفته به اشباع نظری رسیده اند. 
یافته ها نشان داده است که 20 مؤلفه شامل تبیین و اشاعه فرهنگ سازمانی، استراتژی و سیاست های دانش محور، الگوبرداری، نقش رهبری، اهمیت منابع انسانی، زیرساخت مناسب فناوری و اطلاعات، فرآیندهای ارزیابی دانش، ساختار سازمانی، شبکه خبرگان، اختصاص پاداش و مشوق ها، برنامه های آموزشی، همکاری و کار تیمی، سهولت در دسترسی به دانش، معماری مدیریت دانش، مهندسی مجدد، شفافیت، اعتماد، ارتباط نظام مند با ذینفعان، راهبردهای دانش، اهمیت ثبت، ذخیره و مستند سازی دانش شناسایی شده است.
نتیجه گیری: طراحی الگوی راهبردی مدیریت دانش در اداره امور فرهنگی و تربیتی زندان های استان تهران در صورتی  موفقیت آمیز است که این مؤلفه ها شناسایی شده  در آن سازمان  استقرار و بکار گرفته شوند.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مدیریت دانش،راهبرد، تجارب کارکنان، یادگیری سازمانی، سازمان یادگیرنده </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13981023214695-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>