﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>59</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigating the relationship of corporate social responsibility disclosure and Intellectual capital with Considering the role of ownership status</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بررسی رابطه بین افشای مسئولیت اجتماعی شرکت و سرمایه فکری با نقش تعدیل گری ساختار مالکیت</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>201</FirstPage><LastPage>217</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>امیر </FirstName><LastName>غفوریان شاگردی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام رضا</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد سجاد</FirstName><LastName>غفوریان شاگردی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام رضا (ع)</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></History><Abstract>This study Investigating the relationship of corporate social responsibility disclosure and Intellectual capital with Considering the role of ownership status in companies listed on Tehran stock Exchange. this research is objectively, appliable and through the method of collecting and analyzing in the field of descriptive,correlational. The statistic sociaty population of this research,includes the firms listed in the Tehran Stock Exchange as 147 companies operating in various industries over the years 2011 to 2016 .  To measure corporate social responsibility through content analysis and information on the check list,coding them and intellectual capital, by (Pulic model-2000) is used. The test assumptions of this study are regular multiple regression with utilizing the method of ordinary least squares (OLS) and using the Eviews software .  According to the results of the mentioned test assumptions: there is a significant relationship between corporate social responsibility disclosure and intellectual capital. Also ownership status on the relationship between corporate social responsibility disclosure and intellectual capital had significant effect.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">تحقیق حاضر به بررسی رابطه بین افشای مسئولیت اجتماعی شرکت و سرمایه فکری با نقش تعدیل گری ساختار مالکیت در شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده بورس اوراق بهادار تهران می‌پردازد. این پژوهش از نظر هدف،  پژوهشی کاربردی و به لحاظ روش انجام پژوهش، توصیفی– همبستگی می‌باشد. جامعه آماری تحقیق شامل تمامی شرکت‌های پذیرفته در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران که پس از نمونه‌گیری، بالغ بر 147 شرکت و در یک دوره زمانی 6 ساله از سال 1390 الی 1395 است،  می‌باشد.  برای اندازه‌گیری مسئولیت اجتماعی شرکت از روش تحلیل محتوا مبتنی بر چک لیست اطلاعات و کدگذاری آن ها و سرمایه فکری از (مدل پالیک، 2000) استفاده شده است. روش آزمون فرضیات در مطالعه حاضر استفاده از رگرسیون معمولی چندگانه و با بهره‌گیری از روش حداقل مربعات معمولی می‌باشد و با استفاده از نرم‌افزار ایویوز بوده است. نتایج تحقیق نشان می‌دهد که بین افشای مسئولیت اجتماعی شرکت و سرمایه فکری رابطه معناداری وجود دارد، ساختار مالکیت شرکت‌ها نیز بر رابطه بین افشای مسئولیت اجتماعی شرکت و سرمایه فکری تاثیر معناداری دارد. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">افشای مسئولیت اجتماعی شرکت</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 سرمایه فکری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 ساختار مالکیت </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13971225178264-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>