﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>61</Volume><Issue>1-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2018</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Designing and compiling a behavioral decision making model for investors considering the role of financial marketing mix using structural equation modeling</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>طراحی و تدوین مدل تصمیم گیری رفتاری سرمایه گذاران با توجه نقش آمیخته بازاریابی مالی با استفاده از مدلسازی معادلات ساختاری</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>35</FirstPage><LastPage>62</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>حمید رضا</FirstName><LastName>شکری زاده</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه یزد</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>جمال</FirstName><LastName>برزگری خانقاه</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه یزد</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>ججت الله</FirstName><LastName>صادقی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه یزد</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day></History><Abstract>Capital markets play an important role in the economy, because the cash flow of people who can not use their funds leads to those who are capable of it. Naturally, the good performance of these markets will be a key factor in ensuring economic growth, so if capital markets are efficient, economic development will be realized. On the other hand, because of the irrational decision making of investors in the capital market, systematic errors have occurred and this leads to market failure. The present study seeks to examine the impact of the financial marketing mix(7p) on the relationship between behavioral bourgeois and investor decision making. The method of this research is applied to the purpose of the research and the method of collecting and collecting data is descriptive survey. The statistical population is real investors in Tehran Stock Exchange. 422 questionnaires were distributed. By eliminating incomplete questionnaires, 391 questionnaires were used for statistical analysis. The data was analyzed using SmartPLS and LISREL software. The results indicate that the financial marketing mix (7 p) affects the relationship between emotional and decision-making factors of investors more than cognitive biases. The two sides of the trained and promoted people have the most impact.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">بازارهاي سرمايه نقش مهمي در اقتصاد دارند، زيرا وجوه نقد افرادي كه توان استفاده از وجوه خود را ندارند، به كساني كه اين توانايي را دارند، هدايت مي كنند. طبيعتا عملكرد خوب اين بازارها عامل كليدي در تامين رشد اقتصادي خواهد بود، لذا اگر بازارهاي سرمايه كارآ باشند، توسعه اقتصادي تحقق مي‌يابد. از سوي ديگر بدليل تصميم گيري غيرمنطقي سرمایه‌گذاران در بازار سرمايه خطاهاي سيستماتيك رخ داده و همين مساله موجب عدم كارآيي بازار مي‌شود.تحقیق حاضر در صدد است تا تاثیر آمیخته بازاریابی مالی را بر رابطه بین تورشهای رفتاری و تصمیمگیری سرمایه گذاران را مورد بررسی قرار دهد. روش تحقیق حاضر از نظر هدف کاربردی و از حیث روش انجام و گردآوری داده‌ها توصیفی پیمایشی می باشد. جامعه آماری سرمايه‌گذاران حقیقی در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران می‌باشند که 422 پرسشنامه توزیع شد که با حذف پرسشنامه‌هاي ناقص در نهایت 391 پرسشنامه جهت تجزیه و تحلیل آماري استفاده گردید. داده های حاصل با نرم افزارهای SmartPLS و LISREL مورد تجزیه و تحلیل قرار گرفت. نتایج حاکی از آن است که عوامل آمیخته بازاریابی مالی(7p) بر رابطه بین تورشهای عاطفی و تصمیم گیری سرمایه گذاران بیشتر از تورشهای شناختی تاثیر گذارند.و دوعامل افراد آموزش دیده و ترفیع بیشترین تاثیر را دارند.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">تصمیم‌گیری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
آمیخه بازاریابی مالی(7p)</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 تورش عاطفی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 رفتار سرمایه‌گذاران</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تورش شناختی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13980117178472-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>