﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Identify the critical factors for sustainable banking success with a mixed approach</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>شناسایی عوامل حیاتی موفقیت بانکداری پایدار با رویکرد آمیخته</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>19</FirstPage><LastPage>32</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>میر حمید</FirstName><LastName>تقوی</LastName><Affiliation>سیاستگذاری علم و فناوری-دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName><LastName>علی احمدی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>بنیادی نائینی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></History><Abstract>A new concept in the area of achieving sustainable development goals is sustainable banking which is of particular importance in developing countries. To succeed in achieving sustainable banking goals, it is necessary to identify and conceptualize the underlying factors. This paper aims to identify the critical factors for sustainable banking success. This paper is an applied research in terms of purpose and has been done with a cross-sectional survey approach. Semi-structured interviews and expert questionnaire were used for data collection. The statistical population of the study consists of managers and experts of the central bank selected by purposeful sampling from among these experts.
The research methodology is a mixed (qualitative-quantitative) approach. In the qualitative phase, the thematic analysis method is used to identify the critical factors for sustainable banking success. Then, at the quantitative stage, the identified factors are screened and prioritized based on the Fuzzy Delphi and SWARA method. The results show that the critical success factors of sustainable banking can be categorized into three factors: input factors, process factors and output factors. Support entrepreneurs, marketing management, clear regulation and process evaluation are of the utmost importance in the field of sustainable banking.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">یک مفهوم جدید در حوزه دستیابی به اهداف توسعه پایدار، بانکداری پایدار می‌باشد که بویژه در کشورهای درحال توسعه از اهمیت بسیار بالایی برخوردار است. برای موفقیت در نیل به اهداف بانکداری پایدار لازم است تا عوامل زیربنایی آن شناسایی و مفهوم‌سازی شوند. این مقاله با هدف شناسایی عوامل حیاتی موفقیت بانکداری پایدار انجام شده است. مقاله حاضر از نظر هدف یک تحقیق کاربردی است و با رویکردی پیمایشی- مقطعی انجام شده است. برای گردآوری داده‌ها از مصاحبه نیم‌ساختار یافته و پرسشنامه خبرگانی استفاده شده است. جامعه آماری تحقیق شامل مدیران و کارشناسان بانک مرکزی می‌باشد که به روش هدفمند، نمونه‌ای از میان این خبرگان انتخاب شده است.
روش شناسی تحقیق بر مبنای رویکرد آمیخته (کیفی-کمی) است. در مرحله کیفی، از روش تحلیل مضامین (تِم) برای شناخت عوامل حیاتی موفقیت بانکداری پایدار استفاده شده است. سپس در مرحله کمی، عوامل شناسایی شده براساس روش دلفی فازی و سوارا غربالگری و تعیین اولویت شده است. نتایج نشان داده است عوامل حیاتی موفقیت بانکداری پایدار در سه محور عوامل درون‌داد، عوامل فرآیندی و عوامل برون‌داد قابل دسته‌بندی می‌باشند. از میان عوامل، پشتیبانی از کارآفرینان، مدیریت بازاریابی، وضع مقررات روشن و ارزیابی فرآیندها از بیشترین اهمیت در حوزه بانکداری پایدار برخوردار هستند. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">بانکداری پایدار، </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
توسعه پایدار،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 بازاریابی تامین مالی، </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
رویکرد آمیخته</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
عوامل حیاتی موفقیت</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13980905193668-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>