﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>62</Volume><Issue>1-ب</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2018</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Analysis of the effect of production and investment types in selected Organisation of Islamic Cooperation countries</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تحلیل اثرتولیدوانواع سرمایه گذاری درمنتخبی ازکشورهای سازمان همکاری اسلامی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>3</FirstPage><LastPage>18</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>الهام</FirstName><LastName>نیک نژاد</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزادواحداصفهان(خوراسگان)</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>همایون</FirstName><LastName>رنجبر</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>حسین</FirstName><LastName>شریفی رنانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزادواحداصفهان</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></History><Abstract>Investment is one of the important components of the production function of the most economical country, and this is one of the main reasons for the economic development of each country. In the general case, the investment is divided into internal and external divisions, which domestic investment include public investment and private investment. Considering the role and place of trade, growth and investment, the nonlinear relationship between public and private investment is expanded in this research, and then the interaction between public investment, private investment and foreign direct investment in 45 OIC countries is analyzed. Therefore, the factors influencing the country's economic growth including public investment, private investment, foreign direct investment, and the degree of trade openness have been reviewed during the period (1997-1997). The method used in this research is the static panel data method in the form of Generalized method of moments (GMM).The results indicate that public investment, private investment, foreign direct investment, the degree of trade openness, and the  population growth have been effective and meaningful in improving the country's economic growth, and is estimated at a level of 0.507%.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">سرمایه گذاری به عنوان یکی ازاجزاء مهم تابع تولیددراقتصادهرکشوری مطرح می باشدوازهمین رو است که یکی ازضروریات اساسی درپیشرفت اقتصادی هرکشورمحسوب می شود.درحالت کلی سرمایه گذاری به دودسته داخلی وخارجی تقسیم می گرددکه سرمایه گذاری داخلی شامل سرمایه گذاری دولتی وسرمایه گذاری خصوصی می باشد.باتوجه به نقش وجایگاه تجارت،رشداقتصادی و سرمایه گذاری،در این تحقیق رابطه غیرخطی بین سرمایه گذاری دولتی ورشداقتصادی بسط داده می شود،سپس تعامل میان سرمایه گذاری دولتی،سرمایه گذاری خصوصی،سرمایه گذاری مستقیم خارجی،درجه بازبودن تجاری ورشدجمعیت در45کشورعضو سازمان همکاری اسلامی(OIC)تحلیل می گردد.بنابراین عوامل موثربرسرمایه گذاری ورشداقتصادی کشورهاازجمله سرمایه گذاری دولتی،سرمایه گذاری خصوصی،سرمایه گذاری مستقیم خارجی،درجه بازبودن تجاری ورشدجمعیت طی دوره زمانی(2014-1997)موردبررسی قرارگرفته است.روش مورداستفاده دراین تحقیق،روش داده های تابلویی بااثرات ثابت به صورت پویاونیزروش گشتاورهای تعمیم یافته(GMM) می باشد.نتایج حاکی از آن است که سرمایه گذاری دولتی،سرمایه گذاری خصوصی،سرمایه گذاری مستقیم خارجی،درجه بازبودن تجاری ورشدجمعیت اثرمثیت ومعنی داری بررشداقتصادی کشورهاداشته است وحداکثرسطح رشدسرمایه گذاری دولتی0.507%برآوردگردیده است که ازسطح میانگین آن بسیارپایین ترمی باشد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سرمایه گذاری دولتی </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
سرمایه گذاری خصوصی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
سرمایه گذاری مستقیم خارجی </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
رشداقتصادی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13970906165833-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>