﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>51</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring Content of Nurses’ Emotional Labour Dimensions and Investigating the Impact of Human Resource Management Practices on it in Mashhad’s Public Hospitals</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle> کشف محتواي ابعاد نيروي کار احساسي پرستاران و بررسي تاثير اقدامات مديريت منابع انساني بر آن  در بيمارستان‌هاي دولتي مشهد</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>187</FirstPage><LastPage>112</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>سیده منصوره</FirstName><LastName>حسینی رباط</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>فریبرز </FirstName><LastName>رحیم نیا </LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName><LastName>کاظمی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سعید </FirstName><LastName>مرتضوی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></History><Abstract>Emotional labor as the management of emotions is the vital aspect of nursing profession that must be observed in order to express the organization’s intended emotions. Despite the emphasis made over the importance of this topic, it has not been much within the spot light of experts inside the country; as the result there is no accurate cognition over the phenomenon. The current study, due to the existing knowledge gap and its important application in the domain being studied, explores contents of emotional labor dimensions in nurses; since a special goal out of HRM practices must be developed to create and preserve desired organization’s emotions, the second aim for this paper is studying the impact of HRM practices on contents of these dimensions.
In the qualitative, all exemplar nurses of Mashhad’s public hospitals were interviewed by purposeful sampling; and the analysis was conducted through Colaizzi method. In quantitative, a questionnaire was distributed among 130 experienced nurses; and the analysis was conducted through confirmatory factor analysis (CFA) and AMOS software.
Finally, in qualitative, in surface acting, 5 subcategories in 2 categories “emotional mask and emotional deal”; and in deep acting, 15 subcategories in 5 categories “emotional withdrawal, emotional empathy, emotional arousal, emotional sharing, and emotional reflection” emerged. In quantitative, the result for confirmatory factor analysis confirmed all categories and subcategories obtained in nurses’ emotional labor; also, HRM practices affected contents of emotional labor dimensions.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">نيروي کار احساسي به عنوان مفهوم مديريت احساسات به منظور ابراز احساسات مورد انتظار سازمان، جنبه حياتي حرفه پرستاري است که پرستاران ملزم به رعايت آن مي‌باشند، اما علي رغم اهميت، اين بحث چندان مورد توجه پژوهشگران داخل کشور نبوده است و لذا شناخت دقيقي از اين پديده وجود ندارد. پژوهش حاضر، با توجه به شکاف دانشي موجود و اهميت کاربردي آن با توجه به حوزه مورد مطالعه خود، به دنبال کشف محتواي ابعاد نيروي کار احساسي پرستاران است و از آنجا که براي ايجاد و حفظ احساسات مناسب سازماني، بايستي هدف خاصي از اقدامات مديريت منابع انساني توسعه داده ‌شود، هدف دوم پژوهش، بررسي تاثير اقدامات مديريت منابع انساني بر محتواي اين ابعاد مي‌باشد. بر اين اساس، در بخش کيفي، کليه پرستاران برگزيده کشوري بيمارستان‌هاي دولتي مشهد با نمونه‌گيري هدفمند مورد مصاحبه قرار گرفتند و تجزيه و تحليل آن با رويکرد کلايزي انجام شد و در بخش کمي نيز، پرسشنامه‌اي بين 130 نفر از پرستاران با سابقه توزيع شد که تجزيه‌ و تحليل آن با تحليل عاملي تاييدي و نرم‌افزار آموس صورت گرفت. بر مبناي نتايج حاصل از تجزيه‌و تحليل مصاحبه‌ها، در بعد بازيگري ظاهري، 5 زيرمولفه در 2 مولفه «نقاب احساسي، مقابله احساسي» و در بعد بازيگري عميق، 15 زيرمولفه در 5 مولفه «عقب‌نشيني احساسي، همدلي احساسي، برانگيختگي احساسي، اشتراک‌گذاري احساسي، انعکاس احساسي» پديدار شدند و نتايج تحليل عاملي تاييدي تمامي اين مولفه‌ها و زيرمولفه‌هاي احصا شده نيروي کار احساسي پرستاران را تاييد نمود و همچنين مشخص شد، اقدامات مديريت منابع انساني بر محتواي ابعاد نيروي کار احساسي تاثير دارد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">نيروي کار احساسي، بازيگري ظاهري، بازيگري عميق، اقدامات مديريت منابع انساني</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13950817184043869-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>