﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>1-ب</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2014</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>How to deal with “  Management of Mind Change” under the  Modernisationsparadigm in the Globalizationsspace</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>چگونگی مواجهه با"مدیریت تغییر ذهنیت"  تحت  پارادایم  مدرنیته در فضای جهانی سازی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محمد رضا </FirstName><LastName>مشایخ</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day></History><Abstract>Background and objective: The result of “global paradigm shift” is birth of new minds and naturally the emersion of a newly global human world – Class  society. Paradigm shifts originate from the change of 9 fold paradigm components (Theology, ontology, anthropology, epistemology, axiology, methodology, deontology, practicism, eventualism). Paradigm shifts are among the most important methods of making fundamental changes in the society. These changes take place in “Background”, “Contents”, and “structure” of the mind. Thus by subtilization and manipulation of " Management of Mind Change “ and using soft tools and soft technology, it is possible to humanize, socialize, civilize, systemize, globalize and lead mankind and societies to desired objectives. In other words, the world is constantly giving birth to new mentalities and interactions; confrontations and dispute of conceptual models in the concrete world.
Research methodology and Findings: In this study with the presentation of globalization in modernism and a comparative study of postmodern and divine globalization, the portrait of a postmodern and divine man is extracted in humanist and divine paradigms and it is contemplated and judged by scholars. The type of qualitative research is based on analytical-descriptive study with using comparative text examination and post analysis of collected data libraries. The final result of the study is that mental imperialism attempts to change the constituents of the paradigm overwhelming the mentalities of the target societyin Kurt Lewin’s three step transformation process “Unfreezing-transition-freezing” and comparing it with Dusterandobill’s model (1997) in which the beginning chain of this processis triggering stream of consciousness in minds of scientists, strategists, professors and intellectuals of the subject society
Conclusion: According to Imam Ali (AS) in sermon 27 of the noble NahjulBalagahe “No one will be degraded and despicable unless one who has fought against the foe in his homeland” and also based on Imam Khomeini’s order regarding the exportion 
of “spirituality &amp; revolution” instead of mere defense in homeland, the necessity of soft invasion, adaption of the universal doctrine for soft war in mental peculiarities in enemy’s land in order to prepare the global atmosphere for the emersion of the world’s savior (Aj) has appeared so as to prevent the intrusion of “humanist anti-values” in the public mentality of divine societies and to stop the gradual transition of mental, cultural, values, identity, philosophical, behavioral, and structural models of the Islamic societies in order for the free people of the world such as Muslims and Islamic society not to be compromised by the cultural invasion of the hegemonic system.
.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">زمینه و هدف:نتیجه ی"پارادایم شیفت جهانی" تولد اذهان جدید و بالتبع ظهور جامعه انسانی نو پدید طراز جهانی است. تغییرات پارادایمی از تغییرات اجزاءپارادایمهای نه گانه(خداشناسی، هستی شناسی، انسان شناسی، معرفت شناسی، ارزش شناسی، روش شناسی، تکلیف شناسی، عمل شناسی و عاقبت شناسی) نشأت می گیرد.تغییرات پارادایمی در زمره مهمترین روشها برای ایجاد تغییر و تحول اساسی در جامعه محسوب می شود.جایگاه این تغییرات در" زمینه"،" محتوا" و" ساختار"  ذهن می باشد، بنابراین با نرم سازی، دستکاری و "مدیریت برای تغییر  اذهان " می توان به انسان سازی، جامعه سازی، تمدن سازی، نظام سازی وجهانی سازی توسط فناوری ها و ابزارهای نرم پرداخت و انسانها و جوامع را به سمت اهداف مورد نظر سوق داد. به سخن دیگر جهان دائماً در حال زایش ذهنیت جدید وتعامل، تقابل وجنگ مدلهای ذهنی، برای تغییر در عرصه های عینی است.
روش تحقیق و یافته ها:در این تحقیق ضمن معرفی جهانی سازی در فضای مدرنیته و مطالعه تطبیقی جهانی انگاری پسامدرنیسم و جهان مداری الهی، تصویر انسان فرامدرن با انسان الهی در پارادایمهای اومانیستی و الهی استخراج و در مدل تطبیقی در معرض نظر و قضاوت اندیشمندان قرار گرفته است.نوع تحقیق کیفی، متکی برروش پژوهش تحلیلی- توصیفی به کمک  متن کاوی تطبیقی و فرا تحلیل اطلاعات جمع آوری شده کتابخانه ای است. نتیجه نهایی حاصل از تحقیق اینکه امپریالیسم ذهنی در پی ایجاد تغییردر اجزاء پارادایم حاکم بر اذهان جامعه هدف، طی فرایند تغییرات  سه مرحله ای "خروج از انجماد"، "تغییر"و"انجماد مجدد"، کرت لوین و مقایسه آن با مدل داستراندوبیل (1997) می باشد که آغاز زنجیره این فرایند، راه اندازی جریان سیال ذهنی در اذهان اندیشمندان، راهبردپردازان، اساتیدو فضلاء در جامعه سوژه است.
نتیجه گیری:عطف به فرمایش امام علی (ع) در خطبه 27 کتاب شریف نهج البلاغه مبنی براینکه "خوار و ذلیل نشد مگر کسی که با دشمن در خانه خود جنگید" و همچنین نظر به دستور امام راحل (ره ) در خصوص صدور"معنویت و انقلاب" بجای دفاع محض در سرزمینهای خودی؛ ضرورت هجوم نرم،وفق دکترین جامع جنگ نرم درمختصات ذهنی درخانه دشمن برای آمادگی فضای جهانی جهت  ظهور منجی عالم (عج) نمایان گردیده تا از نفوذ ورسوخ "ضد ارزشهای اومانیستی" در اذهان مردم جوامع الهی جلوگیری بعمل آورده و مانع تغییرات تدریجی مدلهای ذهنی، فرهنگی، ارزشی، اندیشه ای، رفتاری وساختاری جوامع اسلامی گردیم تا در نهایت خدشه ای در اثر تهاجم فرهنگی نظام سلطه، متوجه انسانهای آزاده جهان واز جمله مسلمان و جامعه اسلامی نگردد. انشا.... 
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مدیریت تغییر ذهنیت</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 پارادایم مدرنیته</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
فضای جهانی سازی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 تهاجم فرهنگی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
قدرت نرم</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13941228202221454-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>