﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>57</Volume><Issue>3-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Presentation of  interpretive structural model for claim management in the construction projects </ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ارائه مدل ساختاری تفسیری جهت مدیریت ادعا در پروژه های عمرانی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>153</FirstPage><LastPage>170</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>سید ابوالفضل</FirstName><LastName>موسوی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت . دانشکده مهندسی صنایع</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مرتضی</FirstName><LastName>باقرپور</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></History><Abstract>Claim management is one of the most important and challenging issue in projects in the world, and many of stakeholders of projects belive that the claims are one of the most destroyer in constraction industry.
Growth of claims in construction projects has an inverse correlation with triangular goals of project management (time, cost and quality), so increasing claims cause extension of time and cost and decrease in project quality.
Claims are natural trait in construction industry. However we can’t remove contingency of this claims but we can, by identify main causes of claims and relation between them, prevent from contingency them in future projects.In this research, research data have been collected by literature review studies and interview with expert  was conducted to identify the 34 causes of claims in construction projects.Then these causes by questionnaire in cluding frequency and intensity of impactwere distributed among experts.Then according to the result of this questionnairesthe most important causes of claim in construction projects are determined that they are contained 10 causes.a model for relationship between causes of claim in construction projects has designed byInterpretive structural modeling.At the end some suggestions has been presented to prevent the claim or to manage them. These corrective solutions have been presented base on model in 4 stage in procedure of project.
research results show that between claims causes, these causes: selecting contractor on base low price without notice to qualification and technical ability, ambiguities in contract documents and clauses, unexpected change in exchange and interest and low price of contract due to high competition, have a significant effect and impressment on other causes, so they play important roles in preventing or decreasing claims. 
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">مدیریت ادعا از جمله مهمترین مباحث و چالش های پروژه ها در دنیاست که بسیاری از ذینفعان پروژه ها، آن را از مخرب ترین اتفاقات در صنعت ساخت می دانند. افزایش ادعاها در صنعت ساخت با حصول اهداف اصلی سه گانه مدیریت پروژه (زمان، هزینه و کیفیت) رابطه معکوس دارد به طوری که افزایش ادعاها، سبب افزایش زمان و هزینه ها و کاهش کیفیت پروژه ها می گردد.
ادعاها به ویژگی‌های ذاتی در صنعت ساخت تبدیل شده‌اند. اگرچه در هیچ پروژه‌ای نمی‌توان احتمال بروز ادعاها را از میان برد، اما می‌توان با شناسایی علل اصلی ایجاد ادعاها و رابطه میان آنها، تا حد زیادی از وقوع آنها در پروژه‌های آتی جلوگیری کرد. در همین راستا با استفاده از مطالعات کتابخانه ای و مصاحبه با خبرگان ، تعداد 34 علت ایجاد ادعا در پروژه های عمرانی به دست آمده است که به وسیله پرسشنامه ای شامل احتمال وقوع و شدت تاثیر، میان عوامل پروژه شامل کارفرما، مشاور و پیمانکاران پروژه های عمرانی که شرایط خبرگی را دارند، توزیع گردید و با بررسی نتایج جمع آوری شده، رتبه بندی علل و مهم ترین علل ایجاد ادعا شامل 10 علت اصلی، بر اساس شاخص اهمیت تعیین شده است. سپس با استفاده از رویکرد مدلسازی ساختاری تفسیری، مدل روابط میان علل ایجاد ادعا در پروژه های عمرانی ترسیم گردید. درانتها نیز راهکارهایی جهت پیشگیری و مدیریت ادعاها بر اساس مدل به دست آمده در 4 مرحله از فرایند پروژه ارائه می گردد.
یافته های پژوهش نشان می دهد4 علت"انتخاب پیمانکار بر مبنای قیمت پایین تر و بدون در نظر گرفتن صلاحیت و توانایی فنی"،" قیمت پایین قرارداد به دلیل رقابت بالا"،"ابهام و تناقض در اسناد یا مفاد قرارداد"،" تغییرات شدید و غیر منتظره در نرخ ارز و بهره بانکی"، از بالاترین قدرت نفوذ و اثرگذاری بر دیگر علل برخوردارند و در نتیجه دارای بالاترین اهمیت در کاهش و پیشگیری از بروز ادعاها می باشند.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مدیریت ادعا</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
علل ایجاد ادعا</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
پروژه های عمرانی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدلسازی ساختاری تفسیری</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139508221819503926-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>