﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>55</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>شناسایی فرآیندهای کسب‌وکار (مطالعه موردی: شرکت ساماندهی صنایع و مشاغل شهر تهران)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>شناسایی فرآیندهای کسب‌وکار (مطالعه موردی: شرکت ساماندهی صنایع و مشاغل شهر تهران)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مهرداد</FirstName><LastName>آقا محمد علی کرمانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم‌ و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>حیدر</FirstName><LastName>بیرانوند</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>عطیه</FirstName><LastName>بزرگی پور</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day></History><Abstract>مدیریت فرآیندهای کسب‌وکار یک روش‌شناسی نظام‌مند به‌منظور شناسایی، طراحی/ بازطراحی، ایجاد، مستندسازی، اندازه‌گیری، پایش و کنترل فرآیندهای کسب‌وکار، به‌منظور ایجاد ارزش برای مشتریان سازمان با چابکی بالاتر است. پژوهش حاضر با توجه به اهمیت بسیار بالای شناسایی فرآیندها به عنوان سنگ بنای طراحی و بهبود مستمر فرآیندهای کسب‌وکار، به ارائه یک رویکرد جدید و بسیار کارا جهت شناسایی فرآیندهای سازمان پرداخته است.  معماری فرآیندهای سازمانی عنوان این رویکرد می‌باشد. در ادامه، شرکت ساماندهی صنایع و مشاغل شهر تهران به عنوان مطالعه موردی مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است و سه مورد از فرآیندهای اصلی آن شناسایی‌شده‌اند. نتایج نشان می‌دهد که با استفاده از این روش، امر شناسایی و کشف فرآیندهای سازمان با دقت و کارایی فوق‌العاده بالایی صورت پذیرفته و در قالبی کاملاً استاندارد ارائه می‌گردد.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">مدیریت فرآیندهای کسب‌وکار یک روش‌شناسی نظام‌مند به‌منظور شناسایی، طراحی/ بازطراحی، ایجاد، مستندسازی، اندازه‌گیری، پایش و کنترل فرآیندهای کسب‌وکار، به‌منظور ایجاد ارزش برای مشتریان سازمان با چابکی بالاتر است. پژوهش حاضر با توجه به اهمیت بسیار بالای شناسایی فرآیندها به عنوان سنگ بنای طراحی و بهبود مستمر فرآیندهای کسب‌وکار، به ارائه یک رویکرد جدید و بسیار کارا جهت شناسایی فرآیندهای سازمان پرداخته است.  معماری فرآیندهای سازمانی عنوان این رویکرد می‌باشد. در ادامه، شرکت ساماندهی صنایع و مشاغل شهر تهران به عنوان مطالعه موردی مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است و سه مورد از فرآیندهای اصلی آن شناسایی‌شده‌اند. نتایج نشان می‌دهد که با استفاده از این روش، امر شناسایی و کشف فرآیندهای سازمان با دقت و کارایی فوق‌العاده بالایی صورت پذیرفته و در قالبی کاملاً استاندارد ارائه می‌گردد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">شناسایی فرآیند، مدیریت فرآیند، معماری فرآیندی، شرکت ساماندهی صنایع و مشاغل</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13960126044345630-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>55</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prioritize Allocating Budget For Civil Project In Ministry of Sience, Research and Technology Using Fuzzy Anatical Hierarchy Process and Fuzzy Topsis</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>اولویت بندی پروژهها  و طرحهای عمرانی وزارت علوم، تحقیقات و فناوری برای تخصیص بودجه با استفاده از تحلیل سلسله مراتبی و تاپسیس فازی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>0</FirstPage><LastPage>0</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName><LastName>علی احمدی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محسنعلی</FirstName><LastName>شایانفر</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName><LastName>فرمانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></History><Abstract>Recently, decisions and debates related to it, such as the allocation of credits for planes and projects at the country level and at managerial levels, are a major issue in organizations, ministries and official institutions of the country. The proposed model for budget allocation is a tool for accelerating decision making by managers. In this research, which was conducted to prioritize development projects at Science Research and Technology ministry , in addition to the management decision making quicknessusing, it has been tried to answer the question ,which is the most appropriate choice among options available (projects) using  multi-index models? This method is based on decision-making and decision-making matrix basis. To this end, in this research, a multi-index model is used to answer what factors are to be allocated This research studies how to design aeffective model for allocating credit to development of the construction projects in the Ministry of Science, Research and Technology using multi-criteria techniques. The purpose of this research is to identify and rank effective indicators on credit allocation and Their grading (importance coefficient) and choosing the optimal option and preparing a credit allocation model. After initial refinement among the indicators and criteria, using the fuzzy hierarchical process method and the fuzzy topisation method, which are the multi-Criteria decision-making methods  and with the help of MATLAB software and other related software which is one of the most important tools for accelerating multi-criteria decision-making techniques, criteria and indicators are ranked and weighted.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">اخیرا تصمیم گیري و مباحث پیرامون آن مانند تخصیص اعتبار برای طرح ها و پروژه ها در سطح کشور و در سطوح مدیریتی به عنوان موضوع بسیار مهم در سازمان ها ، وزارت خانه ها و نهادهای رسمی کشور مطرح است . مدل پیشنهادي برای تخصیص بودجه، ابزاري براي تسریع در تصمیم گیري مدیران محسوب می گردد . این تحقیق که برای اولویت بندی طرح¬های عمرانی در وزارت علوم ، تحقیقات و فناوری انجام گرفته است، سعی شده که با استفاده از مدل هاي چند شاخصه علاوه بر سرعت در تصمیم گیري مدیریت به این سوال پاسخ داده شود که مناسب ترین انتخاب از بین گزینه هاي موجود (پروژه ها) کدام است . این روش بر اساس شاخص هاي تصمیم گیري و برپایه ي ماتریس تصمیم بنا گردیده است . بدین منظور در این تحقیق براي پاسخ به اینکه به چه عوامل، چه امتیازي باید تخصیص داد، از مدل چند شاخصه استفاده شده است. این پژوهش به چگونگی طراحی یک مدل کار آمد جهت تخصیص اعتبار به پروژه های عمرانی در اداره طرح های عمرانی وزارت علوم، تحقیقات و فناوری با استفاده از تکنیکهاي چند معیاره پرداخته و هدف از این تحقیق شناسایی و رتبه بندي شاخص هاي موثر بر تخصیص اعتبار و درجه بندي آنها ( ضریب اهمیت ) و انتخاب گزینه بهینه و تهیه مدل تخصیص اعتبار است که پس از پالایش اولیه در بین شاخصها و معیارها با استفاده روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی و روش تاپسیس فازی که از روشهاي تصمیم گیری چند معیاره می باشند و به کمک نرم افزار تصمیم گیري متلب وسایر نرم افزارهاي مرتبط که از مهم ترین ابزارهاي کمک درتسریع فنون تصمیم گیري چند معیاره هستند ، معیارها و شاخصهای رتبه بندي شده و وزن دهی می شوند و در نهایت پروژه¬ها رتبه بندی شوند</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مدل تصمیم یار</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
روش تاپسیس فازی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تخصیص اعتبار طرح های عمرانی </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13960820158359030-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>55</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Develop a business model with a focus on central enterprise in a collaboration network </ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>توسعه مدل کسب و کار با محوریت شرکت مرکزی در کسب و کارهای مبتنی بر شبکه‎های همکاری </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>ایمان </FirstName><LastName>صادق زاده</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></History><Abstract>The development of networked organizations usually done by a focal firm (the mother). For this purpose, the focal firm as the main center of network must implement her strategies with an action plan. Significance of business model in a network is important as many experts realize business model as an engine for network base strategy.
In the present study, we look at the subject of collaboration networks , to review, identify and prioritize the role of focal firm in the business model of collaboration networks. In this direction, by reviewing  existing literature on maternal advantage we extract the key functions of focal firm in her mothering strategy and business model.
Then the extracted factors in Delphi process was judged and developed by experts. After confirming the final factors  by experts to further validation and extract the Priority of factors  we design questionnaires that  given to Academic experts and managers who working in two network, the result of that questionnaires approved the applicability of the model</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">چکیده:
توسعه سازمان‏های شبکه‏ای معمولاً با تولیت یک بنگاه مرکزی (مادر) پی گرفته می‏شود، بدین منظور بنگاه مادر به عنوان مرکزیت اصلی شبکه باید استراتژی‎های خود را با راهکاری عملیاتی در سطح شبکه پیاده سازی کند اهمیت مدل کسب‌وکار در شبکه تا آنجا مهم است که بسیاری از صاحب‌نظران مدل کسب‌وکار را موتور استراتژی‌های مبتنی بر شبکه می‏دانند.
در پژوهش حاضر، با نگاه به موضوع شبکه‏های همکاری، به بررسی، شناسایی و اولویت بندی نقش سازمان مادر در مدل کسب و کاری شبکه‎های همکاری پرداخته شده است. در این راستا با مرور ادبیات مربوط به  مزیت مادری عملکردهای کلیدی شرکت مادر در بحث کسب و کاری شبکه‎ها استخراج گردید سپس با استفاده از روش دلفی و در سه دور به استحضار خبرگان فعال در حوزه شبکه‎های همکاری قرار گرفت و بهبود و توسعه یافت. پس از تائید فاکتورهای نهایی توسط خبرگان به‌منظور اعتبارسنجی و اولویت‎‎ بندی فاکتورها پرسشنامه‌ای تدوین و در اختیار خبرگان دانشگاهی و مدیران دو شبکه‏ همکاری قرار گرفت. که نتایج به کاربردی و عملیاتی بودن فاکتورها تدوین‌شده صحه می‏گذارد.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">شبکه، شرکت مرکزی، مزیت مادری، عملکرد شرکت مرکزی، همکاری‏های بلندمدت، استراتژی های مبتنی بر شبکه</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13950821112383919-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>55</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Synergistic leadership, post-modern approach to human resource flexibility and voice behavior</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>رهبری تضایف¬گرانه، رویکردی فرا نوگرا در راستای انعطاف¬پذیری منابع انسانی و آوای کارکنان</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>17</FirstPage><LastPage>30</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>امیر </FirstName><LastName>غفوریان شاگردی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام رضا</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سعید</FirstName><LastName>آیباغی اصفهانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>رامین </FirstName><LastName>الهی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></History><Abstract>Nowadays, In developing countries the women's participation in senior sectors of the organizations is lower than men, thus glass ceilings and walls have limited horizontally and vertically movement of women in the organizations. The synergistic leadership theory is the post-modern approach to leadership that conceptualized the presence of women in leadership positions of the leadership of the organizations as the synergistic agent in the organizations. This study aims to evaluate the effect of synergistic leadership on flexibility of human resources, in this evaluation the effect of the voice behavior of employees is considered as a mediator variable. This study is a practical search in terms of aim and is a descriptive survey in terms of method. The realm of study is the offices of social security organizations which is located in Tehran. For doing this study for measuring synergistic leadership in organization is used through the questionnaire of synergistic leadership, Thus after validation testes, reliability and validity were approved. Data analysis is done by using regression test and structural equations through software Amos and the findings of the research show the positive effect of synergistic leadership on the flexibility of human resources and also confirmed the positive and significant effect of synergistic leadership on the voice behavior of employees.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه در کشورهای در حال توسعه مشارکت زنان در بخش¬های عالی سازمان¬ها نسبت به مردان کمتر بوده و سقف و دیوار شیشه¬ای حرکت افقی و عمودی زنان در سازمان¬ها را محدود کرده است. تئوری رهبری تضایف¬گرایانه رویکردی فرانوگرا به رهبری است که حضور زنان در جایگاه رهبری سازمان را به عنوان عامل هم¬افزایی در سازمان مفهوم¬سازی می¬کند. بر این اساس پژوهش حاضر بر آن است تا به بررسی نحوه تاثیرگذاری رهبری تضایفی بر انعطاف¬پذیری منابع انسانی بپردازد و در این راستا اثر رفتارهای آوایی کارکنان به عنوان متغیر میانجی مورد مطالعه قرار گرفته است. تحقيق حاضر از نظر هدف، كاربردي و از نظر روش پژوهش، توصيفي از نوع پيمايشي است. حوزه پژوهش حاضر، ادارات سازمان تامین اجتماعی واقع در شهر تهران می¬باشد. در راستای انجام این تحقیق برای سنجش و اندازه¬گیری رهبری تضایفی در سازمان پرسشنامه رهبری تضایف¬گرایانه طراحی گردید که پس از آزمون¬های اعتبارسنجی، پایایی و روایی آن مورد تایید قرار گرفت. تحليل داده¬ها با استفاده از آزمون رگرسيون و معادلات ساختاري از طریق نرم افزارAmos  صورت گرفته و نتايج به دست آمده حاکی از تاثیر مثبت رهبری تضایفی بر انعطاف¬پذیری منابع انسانی می¬باشد، همچنین اثر مثبت و معنادار رهبری تضایفی بر رفتارهای آوایی کارکنان و نقش میانجی گری رفتار آوایی تایید گردید. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">هم&amp;#172;افزایی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 رهبری تضایف&amp;#172;گرایانه</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
رفتار آوایی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
انعطاف&amp;#172;پذیری منابع انسانی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/1396101915241240157-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>55</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effect of service brand dimensions on brand loyalty with the mediating role of customer satisfaction and brand attitude: A case study of Keshavarzi Bank branches in Torbat-e Heydarieh</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بررسی تاثیر ابعاد برند خدمات بر وفاداری به برند با نقش واسط رضایت و نگرش نسبت به برند  (مورد مطالعه مشتریان شعب بانک کشاورزی تربت حیدریه)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>0</FirstPage><LastPage>0</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>وجیهه </FirstName><LastName>هوشیار</LastName><Affiliation>مدیریت</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد</FirstName><LastName>رستم پور</LastName><Affiliation>موسسه آموزش عالی عطار</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></History><Abstract>Today, research on brand has acquired a special position in business, because the issue, through its impact on customer satisfaction and loyalty, can be very influential in the survival and life of a service entity. Accordingly, the purpose of this research is to investigate the effect of service brand dimensions on customer loyalty to a brand. The study was conducted in the population of customers of Keshavarzi Bank branches in Torbat-e Heydarieh. We tested the effect of brand dimensions (brand evidence, brand hearsay) on customer satisfaction and brand attitude as well as the effect of brand attitude on customer loyalty through seven hypotheses. For this purpose, we used structural equation modeling and LISREL software. Hypothesis testing was conducted on a sample of 322 subjects that were selected by random sampling method. Confirmatory factor analysis was used to assess the validity of research instrument (questionnaire), and the results showed an acceptable validity for each variable in the questionnaire (test statistic for all variables was higher than 4%). The reliability of the questionnaire was measured using Cronbach’s alpha test and the test statistic for all variable was higher than 7%, which indicates that the questionnaire has a good reliability. Moreover, all the seven hypotheses of the study were confirmed.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه، پژوهش در خصوص برند، جایگاه ویژه‌ای در حوزه کسب و کار یافته است. این مساله از طریق تاثیری که بر رضایت و وفاداری مشتریان دارد، می‌تواند در بقا و حیات یک نهاد خدماتی تاثیر به سزایی داشته باشد. در همین راستا تحقیق حاضر با هدف بررسی اثر ابعاد برند خدمات بر وفاداری مشتریان به یک برند؛ قصد صحه گذاری بر این موضوع را دارد. جامعه آماری این تحقیق مشتریان شعب بانک‌ کشاورزی شهر تربت حیدریه هستند، که تعداد 322 نفر از آنان به شیوه نمونه گیری تصادفی، به عنوان نمونه انتخاب شدند. برای جمع آوری داده ها از پرسشنامه استاندارد استفاده شده است و جهت بررسی روایی از تحلیل عاملی تاییدی استفاده گردید و روایی تمام متغیرها مورد تایید واقع شد. جهت سنجش پایایی نیز از آلفای کرونباخ استفاده شد و آلفای کرونباخ تمامی متغیرها در سطح قابل قبول به دست آمد. به منظور تجزیه و تحلیل داده ها و آزمون فرضیه ها  از روش معادلات ساختاری استفاده شد. نتایج نشان داد شواهد برند، گفته ها و شنیده های برند و رضایت مشتریان بانک کشاورزی بر نگرش نسبت به برند و نگرش نسبت به برند نیز بر روی وفاداری مشتریان بانک کشاورزی تاثیرگذار می باشد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">وفاداری به برند، شواهد برند، رضایت، نگرش به برند، گفته ها و شنیده های برند</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/1396110319262850418-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>55</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Identifying Evaluation Criteria for the Political Behaviors of Chief Administrative Officers at Bank Maskan Iran Using  DEMATEL - Fuzzy Delphi Technique</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>شناسایی معیارهای ارزیابی رفتار سیاسی مدیران ارشد بانک مسکن ایران با استفاده از تکنیک‌آزمایش وتحلیل‌تصمیم‌گیری(DEMATEL)- دلفی فازی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>137</FirstPage><LastPage>160</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>ناصر</FirstName><LastName>پورصادق</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه عالی دفاع ملی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>رشید </FirstName><LastName>ذوالفقاری زعفرانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد رودهن</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>امیر</FirstName><LastName>رضایی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد رودهن</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></History><Abstract>The role of effective and efficient management is becoming more important in today’s competitive world which is undoubtedly full of complexity, ambiguity, and uncertainty in challenging situations, competitions, and conflicts. People associate power with many advantages; therefore, they make many efforts to gain it in organizations. Battling for power raises the discussion of political behaviors in organizations. The aim of this study was to present a multi-index decision-making fuzzy hybrid model of qualitative analysis to identify the dimensions and indices of political behavior occurrence among CAOs at the branches of Bank Maskan in Tehran by using a fuzzy Delphi technique. Moreover, the decision-making trial and evaluation laboratory (DEMATEL) technique was employed to determine how influential and influenceable the indices were. The statistical population included 20 CAOs (Bank Maskan) with at least 10 years of executive and management experience. The research results indicated that Personal Characteristics became known as the most influential dimension with the highest value of (R-J) (1.244) among the evaluation criteria for political behaviors of CAOs at Bank Maskan. Moreover, Occupational Attitudes became identified as the most influenceable dimension according to the lowest value of (R-J) (1.358). Given the highest value of (R+J), Personal Characteristics interacted the most with other dimensions (1.244).</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA"> در دنيای امروز که بدون شک مملو از پيچيدگی، ابهام، عدم اطمينان و موقعيت‌های چالش‌برانگیز، رقابت‌ها و 
تعارض‌هاست، نقش مديريت اثربخش وکارآمد، اهميت بيشتری می‌يابد. قدرت برای افراد دارای مزايای زيادی است؛ لذا برای به دست‌آوردن آن در سازمان‌ها دست به تلاش می‌زنند. نزاع بر سر قدرت، بحث رفتارهای سياسی در سازمان را پديد می‌آورد. هدف‌ازانجام ‌پژوهش‌حاضر ارائه‌یک ‌مدل‌ترکیبی فازی تصمیم‌گیری چند شاخصه و تحلیل کیفی، جهت شناسایی ابعاد و شاخص‌های وقوع رفتارسیاسی مدیران ارشد بانک مسکن در شعب تهران، با استفاده از تکنیک دلفی فازی وتعیین شدت اثر‌گذاری و اثر‌پذیری شاخص‌ها با استفاده از تکنیک آزمایش‌و تحلیل‌تصمیم‌گیری(دیمتل) می‌باشد. جامعه آماری پژوهش حاضر را 20 نفر از مدیران ارشد سازمان‌های دولتی( بانک مسکن) که حداقل دارای 10 سال سابقه کار اجرایی و مدیریتی هستند، تشکیل می‌دهند. نتایج پژوهش حاضر نشان می‌دهد که بعد ویژگی‌های فردی، اثرگذارترین بعد، دارای بیش‌ترین مقدار (R-J)، بامقدار (244/1) و بدین ترتیب، با نفوذترین بعد در میان ابعاد مورد بررسی سنجش رفتار سیاسی مدیران ارشد بانک مسکن قرار می‌گیرد. همچنین بر اساس کمترین مقدار(R-J)، بعد نگرش های شغلی با مقدار(358/1)، اثرپذیرترین بعد می‌باشد. براساس بیشترین مقدار(R+J)، بعد ویژگی‌های فردی،  با مقدار(244/1)، بیشترین تعامل را با بقیه ابعاد داراست.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">رفتار سیاسی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 مدیران ارشد</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 بانک مسکن</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تکنیک آزمایش و تحلیل تصمیم‌گیری(دیمتل)</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تکنیک دلفی فازی.</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13960425557526997-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>55</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigation the effect of employee involvement on organizational citizenship behavior with moderating role of organizational identity</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بررسي تاثير درگيري شغلي کارکنان بر رفتار شهروندي سازماني با نقش تعديل-‏گري هويت سازماني</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>سید مرتضی</FirstName><LastName>غیور باغبانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام رضا(ع)</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>امید</FirstName><LastName>بهبودی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد شاهرود</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>پورنگ</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام رضا (ع)</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سید علی</FirstName><LastName>قادری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام رضا (ع)</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>الهام</FirstName><LastName>نصیری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد مشهد</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day></History><Abstract>Human resource is the most important resources in organization, which influences organizational direction and performance. Organizational citizenship behavior is a desired consequence that managers tend to increase it among human resources. The aim of this study is to investigate effects of job involvement on organizational citizenship behavior with moderating role of organizational identity. The population of study is Iran Insurance Company agencies (representatives) in Mashhad, with 300 agencies. Two-stage cluster sampling method was used with regard to the distribution of agencies in Mashhad. 167 agencies were determined for sampling size using Morgan table. Data collection tool were three questionnaires which their validity confirmed through construct validity and reliability were assessed using Cronbach's alpha. To ensure of returning adequate questionnaires, 170 questionnaires were distributed and 167 questionnaires were returned. Data analysis using structural equation modeling and partial least squares (PLS) was conducted. The results showed that job involvement has significant positive effect on organizational citizenship behavior. Also, organizational identity has moderating role in the relationship between job involvement and organizational citizenship behavior.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">مهمترين منبع هر سازمان كه تعيين‏¬كنندة جهت¬گيري و عملکرد آن مي¬باشد، منابع انساني است. رفتار شهروندي سازماني پيامد مطلوبي است که مديران درصدد افزايش بروز آن در بين منابع انساني هستند. هدف اين پژوهش بررسي اثر درگيري شغلي بر رفتار شهروندي سازماني با نقش تعديل‏¬گري هويت سازماني بوده است. جامعه آماري پژوهش، نمايندگي¬‏هاي شرکت بيمه ايران در شهر مشهد به تعداد 300 نمايندگي است. با توجه به پراكندگي نمايندگي¬هاي مذكور در سطح شهر، روش خوشه¬اي دو مرحله¬اي براي نمونه¬گيري استفاده شد. حجم نمونه با استفاده از جدول مورگان، 167 نمايندگي تعيين شد. ابزار جمع¬‏آوري داده¬‏ها، سه پرسشنامه است که روايي آن¬ها به روش سازه و پايايي با استفاده از آلفاي کرونباخ احراز گرديد. جهت اطمينان از بازگشت تعداد مكفي از پرسشنامه¬ها، 170 پرسشنامه توزيع و 167 پرسشنامه برگشت داده شد. داده‏¬هاي پژوهش با استفاده از مدل‏¬يابي معادلات ساختاري و روش حداقل مربعات جزئي (PLS) تجزيه و تحليل شدند. نتايج تحقيق نشان داد که درگيري شغلي بر رفتار شهروندي سازماني، اثر معني¬‏دار و مثبتي دارد. همچنين نقش تعديل¬‏گري هويت سازماني در رابطه بين درگيري شغلي و رفتار شهروندي سازماني نيز مورد تاييد قرار گرفت.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">درگيري شغلي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
رفتار شهروندي سازماني</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
هويت سازماني</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139604211451526881-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>55</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Identifying factors affecting bancassurance desks efficiency, Case study: Bank MELLAT and MA Insurance</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>شناسایی عوامل موثر بر کارایی میزهای بانک ـ بیمه؛ مطالعه موردی: بانک ملت و بیمه ما</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>حمیدرضا</FirstName><LastName>نورعلیزاده</LastName><Affiliation>مهندسی پیشرفت</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی </FirstName><LastName>بنیادی نایینی</LastName><Affiliation>مهندسی پیشرفت</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محسن</FirstName><LastName>صادقی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></History><Abstract>A majority of studies around efficiency assessment just estimate it. Indeed, they don’t address the roots of inefficiency of DMUs. These shortcomings could be resulted from silo approaches conducted by researchers. Our research aims address this gap. We propose a two-stage procedure in which first, the efficiency of bancassurance desks are estimated by DEA (Data Envelopment Analysis) and then, roots of inefficiency are identified by a survey designed based on enabler section of European Foundation for Quality Management model (EFQM) and conducted among bancassurance desks employees. This study is applied in terms of purpose, and mathematical as well as statistical in terms of data analysis. The population of this study consisted of all bancassurance desks of BANK MELLAT in 2015. After efficient and inefficient branches of bancassurance have been estimated and ranked, in order to identify factors affecting efficiency, a questionnaire designed according with criteria of EFQM. Reliability of questionnaire was tested by Cronbach's alpha coefficient, and normal distribution of data was tested by using the Kolmogorov-Smirnov test. The effects of variables (factors) on efficiency were evaluated via regression analysis, then obtained answers were tested for research questions. The results of ranking the impact of factors on the efficiency of bancassurance desks showed that employees, partnerships and resources, products and services, strategy, and leadership are the efficient factors, respectively.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">بسیاری از مطالعات مرتبط با سنجش کارایی، به محاسبه آن و نهایتا تحلیل ورودی‌ها و خروجی‌های می‌پردازد. این مطالعات هرچند که در برآورد و رتبه‌بندی واحدهای مورد مطالعه دست‌آوردهای درخوری داشته‌اند اما از تبیین ریشه‌های کارآمدی و ناکارآمدی غافل مانده‌اند. امری که به نظر می‌رسد ریشه آن در رویکردهای نسبتا مجزای مورد نیاز برای پژوهش در این دو بخش نهفته باشد. بر این اساس مطالعه پیش‌رو، پژوهشی دو مرحله‌ای را برای شناسایی عوامل موثر بر کارایی شعب بانک‌بیمه پیشنهاد می‌دهد که در مرحله نخست با استفاده از ادبیات کارایی و مشخصا روش تحلیل پوششی داده‌ها DEA، کارایی آنها برآورد شده و سپس با استفاده از ادبیات مدل‌های تعالی و مشخصا بخش توانمندساز مدل بنیاد اروپایی مدیریت کیفیت EFQM به شناسایی عوامل تبیین‌کننده کارایی شعب بانک‌بیمه با استفاده از رگرسیون چندگانه یک متغیره میپردازد. این پژوهش از نظر هدف کاربردی و از نظر روش بدست آوردن داده‌ها تحلیلی– ریاضی می‌باشد. جامعه‌ی آماری این تحقیق جهت برآورد و تبیین عوامل موثر بر کارایی، شعب بانک‌بیمهی بانک ملت در سال 94 بوده است. در اين پژوهش ابتدا، کارایی میز بانک‌بیمهی بانک ملت و بیمه ما، با استفاده از روش تحليل پوششي داده‌ها (DEA)، برآورد و رتبه‌بندی شده‌اند و سپس با استفاده از چک لیست ارزیابی مبتنی بر EFQM، تاثیر عوامل توانمندساز مدل EFQM بر کارایی شعب، توسط تحلیل رگرسیون چندگانه یک‌متغیره مورد تحقیق قرار گرفته است. بر این اساس، عوامل موثر بر کارایی میزهای بانک‌بیمهی بانک ملت و بیمه ما به ترتیب اثرگذاری: کارکنان، شراکت و منابع، فرآیند محصولات و خدمات، استراتژی و رهبری میباشد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">کارائی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
بانک‌بیمه</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
میز بیمه</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تحلیل پوششی داده‌ها</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
رویه دو مرحله ای</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
رگرسیون</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدل تعالی سازمانی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
بانک ملت</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
بیمه ما</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13960529178287624-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>55</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>The evolution of incumbents’ role during new nanotechnology based firms’ collaboration within new product development</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تکامل نقش شرکت صنعتی در طی همکاری با بنگاه جدید فناوری نانو در فرایند توسعه محصول جدید</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>0</FirstPage><LastPage>0</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محمد علی</FirstName><LastName>بحرینی زارج</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علي </FirstName><LastName>مبيني دهكردي</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>نیما</FirstName><LastName>حیرتی</LastName><Affiliation>Newcastle business school</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمدرضا </FirstName><LastName>ميگون پوری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></History><Abstract>How incumbents benefit from advanced technologies has played an important role in the management literature. Industrial companies, in spite of certain advantages in the resources, experience and market knowledge, need to use advanced technology to increase their competitive advantages. Yet very little research has explained how incumbents collaborate with new nanotechnology based firms in order to develop new nano products. The study focuses on longitudinal six-year case studies of five collaborations between incumbents and new nanotechnology based firms. The contribution of this research is available in three parts. First, the benefit of incumbents from the nanotechnology requires a long-term extensive and interactive process, based on the synergy of technological capabilities of the new nanotechnology firms and the incumbents’ resources and capabilities. Second, the incumbents must have flexibility in their structures and collaboration’s strategies. Third, the role of the incumbents changes from a "technology taker" at the start of the collaboration to "new product development mentor" and then becomes a high-tech product / service buyer after clarifying the dimensions of technology and product innovation. This study provides a worthy illustration of these collaborations for researchers, managers and policymakers.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">چگونگی بهره‌مندی شرکت‌های صنعتی از فناوری‌های پیشرفته نقش مهمی در ادبیات مدیریت پیدا کرده است. شرکت‌های صنعتی علیرغم مزایای مشخص در منابع، تجربه و دانش بازار، لازم است برای افزایش مزیت‌های رقابتی خود از فناوری پیشرفته استفاده نمایند. به این منظور چگونگی همکاری شرکت صنعتی با بنگاه جدید فناوری نانو به‌منظور توسعه محصول جدید و تغییرات نقش آن در فرایند همکاری مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. این تحقیق به مطالعه موردی طولانی‌مدت شش‌ساله پنج همکاری بین شرکت‌های صنعتی با بنگاه‌های جدید فناور نانو که منجر به تولید محصول جدید نانو شده؛ پرداخته است. سهم این تحقیق در سه بخش قابل‌ارائه است. اول اینکه بهره‌مندی شرکت‌های صنعتی از فناوری پیشرفته بنگاه‌های جدید فناوری نانو، نیازمند یک فرایند تعاملی طولانی‌مدت است تا مبتنی بر هم‌افزایی قابلیت‌های فناورانه بنگاه ازیک‌طرف و همچنین منابع و قابلیت‌های شرکت صنعتی از طرف دیگر، فرایند توسعه محصول جدید طی گردد. دوم اینکه لازمه بهره‌مندی شرکت‌های صنعتی از فناوری‌های پیشرفته، انعطاف‌پذیری آن‌ها در ساختارها و راهبردهای همکاری است. سوم اینکه نقش شرکت صنعتی از یک «درخواست کننده فناوری» در ابتدای همکاری به‌مرورزمان تبدیل به یک «راهبر فرایند توسعه محصول جدید» شده و سپس بعد از شفاف شدن ابعاد فناوری و تولید محصول جدید، به یک خریدار محصول/خدمات فناوری پیشرفته تبدیل می‌شود. این مطالعه تصویر مناسبی از همکاری شرکت‌های صنعتی با بنگاه جدید فناوری نانو برای محققین، مدیران شرکت‌های صنعتی و سیاست‌گذاران ارائه می‌کند.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">نقش شرکت‌ صنعتی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
بنگاه جدید</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
فناوری نانو</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
همکاری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
توسعه محصول جدید</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139611221846360760-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>55</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluating performance of IT department a fuzzy AHP and BSC approach</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ارزیابی عملکرد واحد های IT در صنعت با رویکرد ترکیبی تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی (FAHP) و کارت امتیازی متوازن (BSC) </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>0</FirstPage><LastPage>0</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محسن</FirstName><LastName>ناظم بکایی</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></History><Abstract>In this ever-changing world, information technology (IT) is a must for the survival of a company, and the functions of IT department is becoming increasingly important. The assessment of IT department is critical to understand how the department contributes to organizational and strategic goals. Because IT department performs many tasks that cannot simply be measured by monetary units, evaluation methods that solely rely on financial measures are not adequate. The objective of this study is to construct an approach based on the fuzzy analytic hierarchy process (FAHP) and balanced scorecard (BSC) for evaluating an IT department in the company studied. The BSC concept is applied to define the hierarchy with four major perspectives (i.e. financial, customer, internal business process, and learning and growth), and performance indicators are selected for each perspective. A fuzzy AHP (FAHP) approach is then proposed in order to tolerate vagueness and ambiguity of information. A FAHP information system is finally constructed to facilitate the solving process. The results provide guidance to IT departments in the Industry Case Study regarding strategies for improving department performance. The constructed information system is suggested to be a good tool for solving other multiple-criteria decision-making problems.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این دنیای در حال تغییر، تکنولوژی اطلاعات(IT) برای بقای شرکت ها، یک ضرورت است، و وظایف واحد IT روز به روز مهمتر می شود. ارزیابی واحد IT برای فهم اینکه چقدر این واحد در اهداف استراتژیک و سازمانی سهیم است، کار حیاتی است. از آنجایی که واحد IT وظایف بسیاری انجام می دهد که به سادگی با واحد های پولی قابل سنجش نمی باشد، روش هایی ارزیابی که به تنهایی بر معیار های مالی تکیه دارد مناسب نیستند. هدف این مطالعه ایجاد یک رویکرد بر اساس فرایند تحلیل سلسله مراتب(FAHP) و روش امتیازات متوازن(BSC) برای ارزشیابی واحد IT در یک شرکت مورد مطالعه می باشد. مفهوم روش امتیازات متوازن برای تعریف سلسله مراتب با چهار چشم انداز عمده یعنی امور مالی، مشتری، فرایندهای کسب و کار داخلی، یادگیری و رشد به کار می رود. برای هر چشم نداز، شاخص های عملکرد انتخاب می شود. سپس یک راه حل برای تحمل ابهام و عدم اطمینان در مورد اطلاعات پیشنهاد می شود. نهایتا یک » فرایند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی « رویکرد سیستم اطلاعاتی " FAHP" برای تسهیل فرایند حل مسئله ایجاد می شود. نتایج، یک راهنمای عمل در مورد استراتژی های بهیود عملکرد واحد، در اختیار واحدهای IT در صنعت مرود مطالعه قرار می دهد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">فرایند تحلیل سلسله مراتب فازی(FAHP) </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
روش امتیازات متوازن(BSC)</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
ارزشیابی عملکرد، تکنولوژی اطلاعات(IT) </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/1396112912432760926-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>55</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigating the Impact of Sustainable Supply Chain on Organization Performance using Balanced Score Card Approach (Case of: Fajr Jam Gas Refinery)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر زنجیره¬تأمین پایدار بر عملکرد سازمان با رویکرد کارت امتیازی متوازن (مورد مطالعه: پالایشگاه گاز فجر جم)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>5</FirstPage><LastPage>16</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>عباس</FirstName><LastName>شول</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه ولی عصر(عج) رفسنجان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سعید </FirstName><LastName>صادقی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>لاله</FirstName><LastName> عباسلو</LastName><Affiliation>علوم تحقیقات</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></History><Abstract>The concept of sustainable supply chain management (SSCM) has been considered as an important organizational philosophy to achieve more profits by reducing environmental and social risk. In fact, the environmental management with an emphasis on environmental protection is one of the most important issues of customers, stakeholders, governments, employees and competitors. The main aim of this research is to assess impact of sustainable supply chain management on performance of Fajr Jam Gas Refinery using balanced scorecard approach. The data for this research collected through the questionnaires that sent to 80 managers and expert of Fajr Jam Gas Refinery. To analyze the data, partial least squares (PLS) method and smart PLS-Graph software version 3 was used. The results reveals that sustainable supply chain management has a significant positive effect on performance of Fajr Jam Gas Refinery. Finally, some practical offers and strategies for managers and some suggestions for future research of researchers are provided.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">مفهوم مدیریت زنجیره¬تأمین پایدار (SSCM) به عنوان یک فلسفه مهم سازمانی به¬منظور دستیابی به منافع بیشتر از طریق کاهش مخاطرات زیست¬محیطی و اجتماعی در نظر گرفته می¬شود. در واقع مدیریت زنجیره¬تأمین پایدار  با تأکید بر حفاظت از محیط‌ زیست و مسئولیت اجتماعی، یکی از مهم¬ترین مسائل مشتریان، سهام¬داران، دولت¬ها، کارکنان و رقبا است. هدف از پژوهش حاضر، بررسي تأثير مدیریت زنجیره¬تأمین پایدار  بر عملکرد پالایشگاه گاز فجر جم با رویکرد کارت امتیازی متوازن است. داده¬هاي اين پژوهش، از طريق پرسشنامه ارسالي به 80 نفر از مديران و کارشناسان پالایشگاه گاز فجر جم جمع¬آوری شده¬است. به¬منظور تجزيه و تحليل داده¬ها از روش حداقل مربعات جزئي و نرم¬افزارSmartPLS-Graph  نسخه 3 استفاده شده¬¬است. نتايج نشان مي¬دهد كه زنجیره¬تأمین پایدار تأثیر مثبت و معناداری بر عملکرد پالایشگاه گاز فجر جم دارد. در پایان برخی پیشنهادها و استراتژی¬های کاربردی برای مدیران و برخی پیشنهادات برای پژوهش-های آتی پژوهشگران ارائه شده¬است.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">زنجیره&amp;#172;تأمین پایدار</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
عملکرد</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 کارت امتیازی متوازن</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
پالایشگاه گاز فجر جم</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/1396111511591450635-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>55</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effect of oil shocks on the relationship between income - government expenditure in Iran And challenges of management and impulse control</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بررسی اثر تکانه‌های نفتی بر رابطه درآمد- مخارج دولت ایران و چالش‌های مدیریت و کنترل آن</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>جابر</FirstName><LastName>اکبری</LastName><Affiliation>علوم انسانی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>صادق</FirstName><LastName>بختیاری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مرتضی</FirstName><LastName>صامتی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>همایون</FirstName><LastName>رنجبر</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد اصفهان</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day></History><Abstract>
Abstract
Unexpected changes in oil prices on international unstable markets, impact on economic development (Due to budget dependence on oil and the high proportion of government in the economy). Financial management and economic planning in applying a policy, always consider other conditions constant but in action, macro-economic variables such as income and government expenditure are affected by unexpected internal and external shocks and this factor impairs economic development and the effectiveness of the policies intended are disrupted. Therefore, Iran's official policy has always been faced with the challenge of managing the oil income shocks. Considering the importance, in this study, by using models of TVP and TVPFAVAR, using software econometric MATLAB and EViews and using quarterly data over the period 1367 to 1394 has been paid to the effects of the oil shock on the relationship of income - expenditure the Iranian government. Considering that, the exchange rate is a channel for oil income to the economy, the effect of exchange rate shocks is estimated this relationship. Based on the results, oil income shocks increase the relationship of income - government spending. This means that oil shocks increase government expenditure in each period. However, the effects of increasing it during, is decreasing. Also, government spending relative to negative income shocks, was inflexible. Thus, the dependence of the budget oil revenue, through time, has not diminished. As a result, it is proposed that: managers and government policy makers, to improve the relationship between income and expenses, Avoid from policies of discretionary and temporary treatment and take action to prevent and systematic policies. Also, exchange rate shocks have caused the relationship between income and expenditure, reduced. In other words, the increase in the exchange rate through time is not a revenue source for the government to finance its expenditure.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">چکیده
تغییرات پیش‌بینی‌نشده قیمت نفت در بازارهای بی‌ثبات بین‌المللی همواره برنامه‌ریزی‌های اقتصادی را (به سبب وابستگی بودجه به نفت و سهم بالای دولت در اقتصاد) تحت تأثیر خود قرار داده است. مدیران مالی و برنامه‌ریزان اقتصادی در به‌کارگیری یک سیاست همواره سایر شرایط را ثابت در نظر می‌گیرند ولی در عمل، متغیر‌های کلان اقتصادی از جمله درآمد و مخارج دولت از تکانه‌های پیش‌بینی ‌نشده داخلی و خارجی متأثر بوده‌اند و این عامل برنامه‌ریزی‌های اقتصادی را مختل کرده و اثربخشی سیاست‌های اعمالی را دچار وقفه می‌کنند. از این رو مقامات سیاستگذاری ایران همواره با چالش مدیریت تکانه‌های درآمدی نفت مواجه بوده‌اند. نظر به اهمیت موضوع در تحقیق حاضر با به کارگیری الگوهای TVP و TVPFAVAR در نرم‌افزارهای اقتصادسنجی MATLAB و EViews، با استفاده از داده‌های فصلی طی دوره 1367 تا 1393 به بررسی اثر ورود تکانه نفتی بر رابطه درآمد - مخارج در کشور ایران پرداخته است. با توجه به اینکه درآمدهای نفتی از کانال ترخ ارز وارد اقتصاد می‌شود اثر تکانه‌های نرخ ارز بر رابطه مذکور نیز برآورد گردیده است. براساس نتایج تغییرات در تکانه‌های درآمدهای نفتی موجب افزایش رابطه درآمد-مخارج دولت شده است. بدین معنی که میزان بیشتری از درآمد حاصله صرف مخارج دولت شده است و مخارج دولت نسبت به تکانه‌های منفی درآمدی انعطاف‌ناپذیر بوده است، بر اساس نتایج کاهش وابستگی بودجه به درآمدهای نفتی در طی زمان مشاهده نمی‌گردد. همچنین تکانه‌های نرخ ارز موثر سبب کاهش رابطه درامد-مخارج شده است. به عبارتی افزایش نرخ ارز در طی زمان نتوانسته است منبع درآمدی برای دولت، جهت تأمین مخارج خود باشد. در نتیجه پیشنهاد می‌گردد مدیران و سیاست‌گذاران دولتی جهت بهبود وضعیت رابطه درآمد- مخارج از سیاست‌های صلاحدیدی و درمانی موقت خودداری نموده و اقدام به اجرای سیاست‌های پیشگیری و نظامند نمایند. 
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">تکانه‌ نفتی،  رابطه درآمد - مخارج دولت، TVP-FAVAR </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13950917117344140-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>55</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Designing the solutions to the existing damage guild system law adopted in 1392 in Islamic Parliament of Iran to enhance its effectiveness</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>طراحی راهکارهای برون رفت از آسیبهای موجود  قانون نظام صنفی مصوب سال 1392 مجلس شورای اسلامی به منظور ارتقاء اثربخشی آن</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>0</FirstPage><LastPage>0</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محسن</FirstName><LastName>صرامی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>ابراهیم</FirstName><LastName>عزیزی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></History><Abstract>In this paper, the guild system law adopted in 1392 in Islamic Parliament of Iran discussed And difficulties in the way of its implementation and the lack of some legal provisions conflicts with other laws of the country were investigated. In this paper .Guild system law is pervasive And all people in the community have been directly and indirectly involved with it in their lives and Provides private sector services in an easily and regular manner. If this law has problems, it will harm people and cause harm and disorder in society. Therefore, the review and promotion of this law are indispensable. The research method of this paper is a combination of quantitative and qualitative methods and used of questionnaire and Delphi techniques in this paper. This paper examines 16 of the most important legal issues that have error and  Has provided some suggestions for improving this provision. </Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این مقاله قانون نظام صنفی مصوب سال 1392 مجلس شورای اسلامی مورد بررسی قرار گرفته و مشکلاتی که در راه اجرای آن و همچنین کمبودها و تعارضات قانونی بعضی از مواد آن با سایر قوانین جاری کشور مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. قانون نظام صنفی قانونی فراگیر است و تمام افراد جامعه به نوعی با آن در زندگی خود به صورت مستقیم و غیرمستقیم درگیر بوده و خدمتگزاری بخش خصوصی را به صورت آسان و منظم سامان می دهد. حال چنانچه این قانون خود دارای مشکلاتی باشد به خدمت رسانی به مردم لطمه وارد کرده و موجب زیان و بی نظمی در جامعه می‏گردد. بنابراین بررسی و ارتقای این قانون جزء مواردی ضروری می باشد. روش تحقیق این مقاله ترکیبی کمی و کیفی بوده و در انجام آن از پیمایش و فنون دلفی و روشهای جمع آوری داده کیفی نظیر مصاحبه و مشاهده استفاده گردیده است. این مقاله 16 مورد از مهمترین مفاد قانونی که دارای اشکال است را مورد بررسی قرار داده و مواردی را برای بهتر شدن این مفاد ارائه نموده است.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">قانون نظام صنفی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
آسیب شناسی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/1396122022328101241-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>55</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Designing and the Explanation of the Innovation Model in Production of the Food Products through a Study in the JAMM and ROZE TALAEE Food Products Industries Group</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ارائه الگوی سطح بندی و استقرار متغیرهای مدل نوآوری تولید محصولات گروه صنایع غذایی جم و رز طلایی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>0</FirstPage><LastPage>0</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>رمضان</FirstName><LastName>غلامی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></History><Abstract>Nowadays, everything is changing and transforming, and the competitors are seeking for increasing in their own market share through reaching to the competitive advantage. The considering of the innovation, as one of the alternatives for increasing in competitive advantage within commercial dynamic environments and contexts, is an essential matter. On the other hand, there are various factors which are influential on the innovation. These factors, therefore, must be studied. Indeed, the purpose of the present research is designing and explanation of the innovation model in the production of food products. The methodology of the present study, in term of purpose, is an applied one, and in term of nature and method, is a descriptive-analytical study. Statistical population of the study includes the experts and managers of the JAMM and ROZE TALAEE Production and Packaging Industries Group. In the present research, after reviewing the literature, influential factors on the innovation process recognized and organized in three dimensions (behavioral factors, structural factors, and environmental factors). Research dada have been gathered and analyzed by using the questionnaire and Fuzzy Delphi Techniques and Interpretive Structural Modeling (ISM). The results of ranking of the research variables using Interpretive Structural Modeling (ISM) test, after identification of the main variables, showed that the innovation performance, commerce, productivity, research and development (R&amp;D), and venturing on the knowledge components as the most impressionable variables ranked in the upmost level, and the world economic streams and innovation policies components as the most influential variables ranked in the lowest level.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه همه چیز در حال تغییر و تحول است و رقبا بدنبال افزایش سهم بازار خود از طریق کسب مزیت رقابتی هستند، توجه به نوآوری که یکی از راه¬کارهای افزایش مزیت رقابتی در محیط¬های پویای تجارت است، امری ضروری است. از سویی دیگر، عوامل متعددی بر فرایند نوآوری تأثیرگذارند که باید مطالعه و شناسایی شوند. در واقع هدف از پژوهش حاضر، طراحی و تبیین الگوی نوآوری در تولید محصولات غذایی می¬باشد. روش این پژوهش به لحاظ هدف از نوع کاربردی و از لحاظ ماهیت و روش توصیفی- تحلیلی می¬باشد. جامعه آماری تحقیق شامل خبرگان و مدیران گروه صنایع تولیدی و بسته¬بندی مواد غذایی جمع و رزطلایی می-باشند. در پژوهش حاضر پس از مطالعه ادبیات تحقیق، عوامل مؤثر بر فرآیند نوآوری شناسایی و در سه بُعد (عوامل رفتاری، عوامل ساختاری و عوامل محیطی) سازماندهی شدند. داده‌های پژوهش نیز با استفاده از پرسشنامه‌ و تکنیک¬های دلفی فازی و مدل-سازی ساختاری تفسیری (ISM) مورد تجزیه و تحلیل قرار گرفتند. پس از شناسایی متغیرهای اصلی، نتایج سطح‌بندی متغیرهای تحقیق با استفاده از آزمون مدل سازی ساختاری تفسیری (ISM) نشان داده است که در بالاترين سطح، مؤلفه¬های عملکرد نوآوری، تجارت و بهره‌وری، تحقیق و توسعه، ¬و¬ سرمایه¬گذاری در دانش قرارگرفته¬اند که اثرپذیرترین متغیرها هستند و و در پايين-ترين سطح، مؤلفه جریان‌های اقتصادی جهانی و سیاست‌های نوآوری قرار دارند که اثرگذارترین متغیرها هستند.


</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">نوآوری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 محصولات غذایی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
دلفی فازی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدل&amp;#172;سازی ساختاری تفسیری (ISM)</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/1396122112149101252-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>