﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Providing a model for superior value proposition with emphasis on developing a unique marketing strategy for the company using of Grounded theory </ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ارائه مدل خلق ارزش پیشنهادی برتر با تاکید بر تدوین استراتژی بازاریابی منحصر به فرد شرکت با استفاده از نظریه داده بنیاد </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>175</FirstPage><LastPage>194</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>ابوالفضل </FirstName><LastName>دانایی</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></History><Abstract>The purpose of the present study is to provide a model for creating the superior value proposition through strategic focus on designing a unique marketing strategy for the company. In this regard, the qualitative method of data theory of the foundation has been used. The statistical population of the present study is marketing professors and marketing activists of packaged food products. The interview method has been used to collect the required information. The results of qualitative data analysis with MAXQDA software show that functional value, value, interactional value and emotional value as the proposed company value, value of use and exchange value as dimensions of perceived customer value, customer satisfaction and loyalty The customer has been identified as the dimensions of the marketing outcomes and ultimately the volume of sales, market share, net profit and return on investment as aspects of the financial implications of the proposed firm's value. In addition, the outputs indicate that the company's proposed value in the number of code count and in terms of generalization and learning in the majority of respondents is a priority, which indicates the importance of this category. Afterwards, the financial, marketing, and perceived value of customers are ranked next. This suggests that in our country, the strategic perspective (value from the perspective of the company) among the food industry managers and marketing professors is more general than the marketing perspective.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف پژوهش حاضر ارائه مدل خلق ارزش پیشنهادی برتر از طریق تمرکز استراتژیک بر طراحی استراتژی بازاریابی منحصر بفرد شرکت می باشد. در این راستا از روش کیفی نظریه داده بنیاد استفاده گردیده است. جامعه آماری تحقیق حاضر را اساتید بازاریابی و فعالان بازاریابی حوزه محصولات غذایی بسته بندی شده تشکیل می دهند و جهت گردآوری اطلاعات مورد نیاز از روش مصاحبه استفاده گردیده است. نتایج حاصل از تحلیل داده های کیفی با نرم افزار MAXQDA نشان می دهد که ارزش کارکردی، ارزش قیمتی، ارزش تعاملی و ارزش عاطفی به عنوان ابعاد ارزش پیشنهادی شرکت، ارزش استفاده و ارزش مبادله به عنوان ابعاد ارزش ادراک شده مشتری ، رضایت مشتری و وفاداری مشتری بعنوان ابعاد پیامدهای بازاریابی و در نهایت حجم فروش، سهم بازار، سود خالص و نرخ بازگشت سرمایه به عنوان ابعاد پیامدهای مالی ارزش پیشنهادی شرکت شناسایی و مستخرج گردیده اند. همچنین خروجی ها نشان می دهند متغیر ارزش پیشنهادی شرکت در تعداد شمارش کدها و هم از نظر عمومیت و فراگیری در اکثریت پاسخگویان، در اولویت است که نشان از اهمیت این مقوله می باشد. پس از آن پیامدهای مالی، بازاریابی و ارزش ادراک شده مشتریان در رتبه های بعدی قرار گرفته اند. این امر بیانگر آن است که در کشور ما کماکان دیدگاه استراتژیک (ارزش از منظر شرکت) در میان مدیران صنعت محصولات غذایی و اساتید حوزه بازاریابی عمومیت بیشتری نسبت به دیدگاه بازاریابی دارد. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">ارزش پیشنهادی برتر</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
ارزش ادراک شده</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 پیامدهای بازاریابی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
پیامدهای مالی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
محصولات غذایی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13970704164586-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>