﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>46</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>The business model designed for a network of partner organizations (collaborative network organization</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>طراحی مدل کسب و کار برای شبکه‏ای از سازمان‏های همکار</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>ایمان </FirstName><LastName>صادق زاده</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName><LastName>علی احمدی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></History><Abstract>Abstract
The development of networked organizations usually done by a focal firm (the mother). For this purpose focal firm in addition to defining the strategy of the partner firms and the nature and mechanisms of the network must develop a business model strategy to be implemented at the network. Significance of business model in a network is important as many experts as Zott and Amit realize business model as an engine for network base strategy.
In the present study, we look at the issue of collaboration networks business model designed , to reach the goal of this study we consider focal firm as a symbol of collaborative network then we design a business model for focal firm.
In this regard, after the literature review, the model presented by Osterwalder (2004) (BMO) was chosen as the Meta model, after that we adding several factors extracted from the literature on design requirements and the formation of networks.
Then the model in Delphi process was judged and developed by experts. After confirming the final model  by experts to further validate we design questionnaires that  given to Academic experts and managers who working in two network, the result of that questionnaires approved the applicability of the model
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">توسعه سازمان‏های شبکه‏ای معمولاً با تولیت یک بنگاه مرکزی (مادر) پی گرفته می‏شود، بدین منظور بنگاه مادر علاوه بر تعریف راهبرد، ماهیت و سازوکارهای شبکه باید با تبیین یک مدل کسب‌وکاری استراتژی‌های خود را در سطح شبکه به اجرا درآورد اهمیت مدل کسب‌وکار در شبکه تا آنجا مهم است که بسیاری از صاحب‌نظران نظیر زوت و آمیت مدل کسب‌وکار را موتور استراتژی‌های مبتنی بر شبکه می‏دانند.
در پژوهش حاضر، با نگاه به موضوع شبکه‏های همکاری، اقدام به طراحی مدل کسب‌وکار سازمان مادر در شبکه‏های همکاری به‌عنوان نماد شبکه شده است. در این راستا با بررسی ادبیات موضوع، مدل ارائه‌شده توسط استروالدر (2004) به‌عنوان مدل پایه انتخاب گردید و پس از افزودن چندین فاکتور مستخرج از ادبیات در بخش الزامات طراحی و شکل‌گیری شبکه‏ها، مدل کسب و کار شبکه‏ای در سه لایه تحت عنوان‏های «لایه اول-ستون‏های اصلی مدل کسب و کار شبکه‏ای»، «لایه دوم- بخش بندی ستون‏های اصلی» و «لایه سوم-  مصادیق»  طراحی و طی روش دلفی و در سه دور  مورد قضاوت خبرگان قرار گرفت. پس از تائید مدل نهایی توسط خبرگان به‌منظور اعتبارسنجی مدل پرسشنامه‌ای جهت سنجش مدل طراحی‌شده در اختیار خبرگان دانشگاهی و مدیران دو شبکه‏ همکاری قرار گرفت. که نتایج به کاربردی و عملیاتی بودن مدل تدوین‌شده صحه می‏گذارد.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">شبکه</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدل کسب و کار</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 اقتصاد مقاومتی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 مدل کسب و کار شبکه‏ای</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 سازمان‏های شبکه‏ای</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
همکاری‏های بلندمدت.</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139507121412443530-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>