﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prediction of Growth of Small and Medium Enterprises with the Combination of Artificial Neural Networks and Meta-Heuristic Algorithm</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>پیش¬بینی رشد شرکت¬های کوچک و متوسط با ترکیب شبکه عصبی مصنوعی و الگوریتم¬های فراابتکاری</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>205</FirstPage><LastPage>220</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName><LastName>کاظمی</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>حامد</FirstName><LastName>ابراهیم خانی</LastName><Affiliation>علوم اداری و اقتصاد</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علیرضا </FirstName><LastName>پویا</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>امیر محمد </FirstName><LastName>فکور ثقیه</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></History><Abstract>The growth of a company is considered to be an important economic goal. Given that many small and medium enterprises do not grow into growth and fail in the early years of their operations, a predictive system of corporate growth can be offset by the huge costs Starting businesses, entrepreneurs and companies to pay. Accordingly, the purpose of this study was to predict the growth of small and medium enterprises with the combination of neural network and meta-heuristic algorithms. The purpose of this research was applied and based on the method of doing descriptive-modeling work. Statistical population of this research was all small and medium enterprises of Zanjan province. Statistical sample size According to the growth of companies, 158 companies has been designated. In order to collect data in this study, interviews, questionnaires and documents of companies have been used. Validity and reliability of the questionnaire were verified and and using Cronbach's alpha coefficient. In order to analyze the research data using confirmatory factor analysis methods, the neural network of multilayer perceptron, neural network combined with genetic algorithm and neural network combined with particle swarm algorithm have been used. The results show that all three methods are able to predict the growth of the company. Among these three methods, the best predictive method for growth of the company is the neural network combined with the particle swarm algorithm with the least error rate compared to the other two methods. </Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">رشد یک شرکت برای دستیابی به اهداف اقتصادی مهم تلقی می¬شود. با توجه به اینکه بسیاری از کسب و کارهای کوچک و متوسط به فرایند رشد نمی¬رسند و در سال¬های اولیه فعالیت خود شکست می¬خورند، یک سیستم پیش¬بینی رشد شرکت¬ها می¬تواند از هزینه¬های هنگفتی که در شروع کسب و کارها، کارآفرینان و شرکت¬ها پرداخت می¬کنند، جلوگیری نماید. بر همین اساس هدف این تحقیق، پیش¬بینی رشد شرکت¬های کوچک و متوسط با ترکیب شبکه عصبی و الگوریتم¬های فراابتکاری بوده است. هدف این تحقیق کاربردی و بر اساس روش انجام کار توصیفی- مدل¬سازی بوده است. جامعه آماری این تحقیق کلیه شرکت¬های کوچک و متوسط استان زنجان بوده است. حجم نمونه آماری با توجه به رشد شرکت¬ها، 158 شرکت تعیین شده است. به منظور جمع¬آوری داده¬ها در این تحقیق از مصاحبه، پرسشنامه و اسناد و مدارک شرکت¬ها استفاده شده است. روایی و پایایی پرسشنامه به ترتیب به صورت روایی صوری و پایایی آن با استفاده از ضریب آلفای کرونباخ مورد بررسی و تأیید قرار گرفته است. به منظور تجزیه و تحلیل داده¬های تحقیق از روش¬های تحلیل عاملی تأییدی، شبکه عصبی پرسپترون چند لایه، شبکه عصبی ترکیب شده با الگوریتم ژنتیک و شبکه عصبی ترکیب شده با الگوریتم ازدحام ذرات استفاده شده است. نتایج نشان می¬دهد که هر سه روش قادر به پیش¬بینی رشد شرکت بوده و در بین این سه روش بهترین روش پیش¬بینی رشد شرکت، شبکه عصبی ترکیب شده با الگوریتم ازدحام ذرات با کمترین مقدار خطا نسبت به دو روش دیگر می¬باشد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">رشد شرکت</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
شبکه عصبی مصنوعی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
الگوریتم&amp;#172;های فراابتکاری</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/1397061915526164283-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>