﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle> Evaluating attractiveness and capability of Iranian Native Operating System Based on the Functions of the Technological Innovation System</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ارزيابي جذابيت و توانمندي فناوري سیستم عامل بومی ايران از منظر كاركردهاي نظام نوآوري فناورانه</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>131</FirstPage><LastPage>146</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>فاطمه </FirstName><LastName>ثقفي</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>امیرعلی</FirstName><LastName>سیف الدین اصل</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>احسان</FirstName><LastName>نورزاد مقدم</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ايران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day></History><Abstract>The high-tech operating system, is the most important software infrastructure in the exchange of secure electronic information for a country. Hence the availability of indigenous operating system technology in the country can increase economic stability, employment and information security. Some countries, such as Turkey, China, Canada and the United States, have operating system experience. In this paper, the evaluation of the attractiveness and capability of the native operating system technology of Iran will be evaluate from the perspective of the functions of the innovative technology system in its implementation experience. First, the status of the native operating system is reviewed. The criteria's for determining the attractiveness and capabilities of the native operating system are extracted from the literature review and measured by the questionnaire tool and the opinion of the experts. Then, the effect of the functions of the native operating system technology innovation system on the attractiveness and capability created by the Delphi method is investigated. The results showed that the native operating system has a moderate appetite, but has below average capability. In addition, these results are the result of the effects of knowledge dissemination functions, knowledge development and search guidance. The policy of the authorities and the lack of attention to this area has slowed the development of this technology and reduced capacity in this area.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">سیستم عامل، به عنوان یک فناوری برتر، کلیدی ترین زیرساخت نرم افزاری در تبادل اطلاعات الکترونیکی امن برای یک کشور محسوب می شود. از این رو در اختیار داشتن فناوری یک سیستم عامل بومی در کشور می تواند افزایش ثبات اقتصادی، اشتغال و امنیت اطلاعات را به همراه داشته باشد. برخی کشورها مانند ترکیه، چین ، کانادا و امریکا تجربه تولید سیستم عامل را دارند. در این مقاله ارزيابي جذابيت و توانمندي فناوري سیستم عامل بومی ايران از منظر كاركردهاي نظام نواوري فناورانه در تجربه پیاده سازی آن مد نظر قرار گرفته است. ابتدا وضعيت سيستم عامل بومي مرور مي شود. شاخصهاي تعيين جذابيت و توانمندي سيستم عامل بومي از مرور ادبيات استخراج و با ابزار پرسشنامه و با نظر خبرگان اندازه گيري مي شود. سپس اثر کارکردهاي نظام نوآوري فناورانه سيستم عامل بومي بر جذابيت و توانمندي ايجاد شده  با روش دلفي بررسي مي شود. نتایج نشان داد سيستم عامل بومي در حال حاضر جذابيت متوسطي دارد ولي از توانمندي زير حد متوسط برخوردار است. ضمنا اين نتايج نيز حاصل از اثر كاركردهاي انتشار دانش، توسعه دانش و هدايت جستجو بوده است.  سیاست‌های مسئولین و کم توجهی به این حوزه باعث کند شدن توسعه این فناوری و كاهش توانمندي در اين زمينه شده است.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">نظام نوآوری فناورانه </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
کارکرد</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 جذابيت</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 توانمندي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
سیستم عامل بومی </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13980120178566-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>