﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>51</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Explaining the Patterns of Excellence in Excellence for Activist Organizations</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تبیین الگوهای برتری در سرآمدی برای سازمان‌های تلاشگر</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مریم</FirstName><LastName>قلی زاده</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان ‍پژوهشگاه</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد رضا</FirstName><LastName> حمیدی زاده</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></History><Abstract>Despite the vast application of excellence models in modern organizations, it is not clear that which one is more appropriate. This paper is aimed to choose the most proper Excellence patterns to be employed to realize the excellence goals in progressive organizations. For this study, not only we studied the literature of research, but also we employed Fuzzy Delphi technique to filter and select superior excellence patterns. The conducted idea analysis was filtered during two steps using Cheng &amp; Lin approach.
    The study population was comprised of 30 industry experts and university faculties. In order to study and analyze, 12 excellence patterns were selected from different fields including human resources, training, ethics, and knowledge management from which 5 excellence models were chosen after filtering experts' opinions. It is considered that through this process, the excellence path for organizations will be defined and will make them capable to take actions in order to realize the excellence goals in much shorter period of time
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">با وجود كاربرد گسترده مدل‌هاي تعالي در سازمان‌هاي امروزي هنوز به روشني مشخص نشده است، که کدامیک از الگوهای سرآمدی موجود،  مناسب‌تراند. هدف اين مقاله انتخاب الگوهای سرآمدی مناسب جهت تحقق هر چه سریع‌تر سرآمدی در سازمان‌های تلاشگر می‌باشد. 
    براي انجام اين پژوهش علاوه بر مطالعه ادبیات پژوهش  از فن دلفي فازي جهت پالايش و انتخاب الگوهای برتری سرآمدی بهره گرفته شده است، ایده‌سنجي بعمل آمده در دو مرحله و با استفاده از رویکرد چنگ و ‌لين مورد پالايش قرار گرفته است. جامعه پژوهش را 30 نفر از خبرگان صنعت و دانشگاه تشکیل دادند.
     جهت بررسی و تحلیل در ابتدا 12 الگوی سرآمدی در حوزه‌های منابع انسانی، آموزش، اخلاق و مدیریت دانش انتخاب گردید، که پس از پالایش نظرات خبرگان دانشگاه و صنعت، 5 مدل تایید و 7 مدل سرآمدی دیگر حذف گردید. تا بدينوسيله مسیر سرآمدی برای سازمان‌ها روشن گردد و بتوانند هر چه سریع‌تر به تحقق سرآمدی در سازمان اقدام نمایند.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">تعالی سازمانی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
جایزه جهانی MAKE</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدل تعالی آموزش و توسعه</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدل شهاب</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدل تعالی اخلاقی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدل منابع انسانی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدل تعالی EFQM</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/1395110784484764-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>