﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>52</Volume><Issue>4-ب</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>(Recognition the components of organizational culture and its effect on the empowerment of human resources (Case Study: Mashhad Municipality</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>شناخت مؤلفه های فرهنگ سازمانی و اثر آن بر ابعاد توانمند سازی منابع انسانی (مورد مطالعه: شهرداری مشهد)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>269</FirstPage><LastPage>276</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>یوسف</FirstName><LastName>رمضانی</LastName><Affiliation>موسسه آموزش عالی عطار</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>فریبرز</FirstName><LastName>رحیم نیا</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سعید </FirstName><LastName>مرتضوی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>غلامرضا</FirstName><LastName>ملک زاده</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></History><Abstract>The importance of culture in the use of the ability of people in the organization is undeniable. This research is trying to true in the context of the organization in Iran, Mashhad Municipality to identify the components of organizational culture and its effect on the human resources dimension empowering human resources 
In this study, ethnographic is research method. In this study, by entering a local organization and means of observation and interviews was to understand the organizational culture and the analysis of 11 components, including: respect for the beliefs and religious values,adherence to accountability, formal behavior, organizational identity, physical symbols, personalized, banner honoring customers, revenue, emphasis on corporate law, resistance against foreign managers and language, in five levels artifacts (language), artifacts (symbols), artifacts (Meme), values and basic assumptions and beliefs respectively. To verify the integrity of the data in this study, the reliability, quality, reliability, functionality and portability dependence was used. In the quantitative as well as to assess the validity of the content validity and construct validity were used two methods to assess the reliability of the questionnaire was Krvnbaj alpha (organizational culture questionnaire 0/701, 0/857 empowerment questionnaire). The results indicate that a significant effect of organizational culture on human resources shows the dimensions of empowerment.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">اهمیت فرهنگ در بکارگیری توانائیهای افراد در سازمان غیر قابل انکار است. این تحقیق در تلاش است تا در بستر حقیقی سازمان در جامعه ایرانی، مولفه¬های فرهنگ سازمانی حاکم بر  شهرداری مشهد را شناسایی و اثر آن را بر ابعاد توانمند¬سازی منابع انسانی بررسی نماید. روش تحقیق در این مطالعه قوم نگاری است. در این تحقیق با ورود به یک سازمان محلی و استفاده از ابزارهای مشاهده و مصاحبه به شناخت فرهنگ سازمانی آن پرداخته شد و از تحلیل اطلاعات 11 مولفه شامل؛احترام به شعائر و ارزشهاي مذهبي،تبعیت پذیری،رفتارهاي رسمي، هويت سازماني، نمادهاي فيزيکي، فرد محوری، شعار تکريم ارباب رجوع، درآمدزايي، تاکید بر قوانين سازمانی، مقاومت در برابر مدیران بیگانه وزبان،در پنچ سطح مصنوعات (زبان) مصنوعات (نمادها) مصنوعات (الگوهای رفتاری)، ارزشها و مفروضات و باورهای اساسی بدست آمد. جهت تأیید استحکام داده‌ها در بخش کیفی این پژوهش از قابلیت اعتبار، قابلیت اعتماد، قابلیت وابستگی و قابلیت انتقال استفاده شد. در بخش کمی نیز جهت سنجش روایی پرسشنامه‌ها از دو روش روایی محتوا و روایی سازه بهره گرفته شد و جهت سنجش پایایی پرسشنامه‌ها نیز از آلفای کرونباج استفاده شد(پرسشنامه فرهنگ سازماني  701/0، پرسشنامه توانمند سازي 857/0). همچنین نتایج، اثر معنادار فرهنگ سازمانی بر ابعاد توانمند سازی منابع انسانی را نشان می¬دهد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">فرهنگ</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
فرهنگ سازمانی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
قوم نگاری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
توانمند سازی منابع انسانی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
شهرداری مشهد.</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13950813184933828-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>