﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>1-ب</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2014</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>The relation between organizational learning culture and customer satisfaction: The mediating role of job satisfaction</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>رابطه بین فرهنگ یادگیری سازمانی و رضایت مشتری: نقش میانجی¬گری رضایت شغلی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مهدی </FirstName><LastName>حقیقی کفاش</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>زهره </FirstName><LastName>دهدشتی شاهرخ</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName> حسن </FirstName><LastName>غریبی </LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day></History><Abstract>The purpose of this research is an experimental study in servicing sector (Parsian bank) for investigating the relation between organizational learning culture and job satisfaction and their relation with customer satisfaction which is used from Pantuakiz and Borenta (2013) model. In this model the relation between organizational learning culture and customer satisfaction with considering job satisfaction mediating role is investigated. For research investigation a sample size containing 234 people, working in Parsian bank branches in Tehran is taken in cluster random of sampling type. Collecting data of standard questionnaire with 21 questions which its validity and reliability is confirmed is done by distributing it among statistical population. Analyzing of data is done by descriptive statistics and statistical inference. In descriptive statistics section indexes including frequency index and percentage of frequency index and in statistical inference section, indexes including correlation methods and structural equation model are used respectively for path analysis. In this regard SPSS and LISREL software are used. The results of analysis shows the relation among organizational learning culture and customer satisfaction and job satisfaction. Generally, Parsian bank ability directly or indirectly to satisfy its customers is linked through its employees' effective and continuous effort and their job satisfaction. (p&lt;0.05)</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف تحقیق حاضر، انجام یک مطالعه تجربی در بخش خدمات(بانک پارسیان) به منظور بررسی روابط بین فرهنگ یادگیری سازمانی و رضایت شغلی و رابطه آنها با رضایت مشتری است که از مدل پانتواکیز و بورنتا(2013) استفاده شده است. در این مدل رابطه بین فرهنگ یادگیری سازمانی و رضایت مشتری با توجه به نقش میانجی رضایت شغلی بررسی می¬شود. برای بررسی تحقیق نمونه¬ای شامل 234 نفر  به  صورت خوشه¬ای تصادفی از کارکنان شعب بانک پارسیان در شهر تهران انتخاب شد. ابزار گردآوری داده پرسش‏نامه استاندارد با ۲1 سوال که روایی و پایایی آن تایید و بین جامعه آماری توزیع شد. تجزیه و تحلیل داده¬ها با استفاده از آمار توصیفی و آمار استنباطی انجام گرفت. در سطح آمار توصیفی از شاخص¬هایی چون فراوانی و درصد فراوانی؛ در سطح آمار استنباطی از روشهای همبستگی، مدل معادلات ساختاری، تحلیل مسیر انجام شده است؛ که برای این منظور از نرم افزارهای spss و lisrel  استفاده شد. نتایج تجزیه و تحلیل از وجود ارتباط بین فرهنگ یادگیری سازمانی و رضایت مشتری و رضایت شغلی حکایت دارد. به طور کلی، توانایی بانک پارسیان برای راضی کردن مشتریان خود به طور مستقیم و غیر مستقیم، از طریق توانایی مستمر موثر و کارآمد کارکنان بانک و رضایت شغلی کارکنان در ارتباط است (05/0&gt;p).</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">فرهنگ یادگیری سازمانی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 رضایت مشتری و رضایت شغلی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139412281946401452-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>