﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>51</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Developing the Roadmap of Succession Planning in the Organization (Case study: Iranian Gas Transmission Company, district 3)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تدوین ره‌نگاشت جانشین‌پروری در سطح سازمان (مطالعه موردی: شرکت انتقال گاز- منطقه 3 عملیات انتقال گاز)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>علی اکبر</FirstName><LastName>حسنی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مصطفی </FirstName><LastName>نجفی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>شرف الدین</FirstName><LastName>محمد عرازی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day></History><Abstract>Developing a roadmap for an organization creates a clear path to a series of goals and visions for the future. Organizations use roadmap as a tool for variety of strategic objectives and the reason of this, is the diversity of approaches and techniques in this field. Roadmap helps companies, industries and organizations to map what they need to do to succeed in the future. Planning for supply appropriate human resources for the organization's future is one of the key and strategic decisions making for the organizations. In general, the purpose of succession planning is the preparation of talented individuals within the organization, to fill key, delicate and strategic jobs. Therefore, planning to build an integrated model to replace the old forces in any organization is inevitable. Therefore, in this paper we have tried to draw a comprehensive roadmap for the implementation of the succession planning as a roadmap for the survival of the organization, as well. A case study in this paper is the Iranian Gas Transmission Company, district 3 and with respect to the company's strategic importance to the country from different aspects affecting the sustainable growth, the development of roadmap for the future of this organization has been on the agenda. Data collection based on experts' comments and by using the Delphi process was conducted. The findings show that the roadmap developed according to the validation conducted by experts, has been well managed the visible and invisible Gas company needs to provide succession of forces according to the goals.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">تدوین ره‌نگاشت برای سازمان، زمینه‌ساز مسیری روشن به سمت زنجیره‌ای از اهداف و چشم‌اندازها در آینده است. سازمان‌ها از ابزار ره‌نگاشت برای اهداف استراتژیک مختلفی بهره می‏گیرند و دلیل این موضوع تنوع رویکردها و تکنیک‌های موجود در این بحث است. ره‌نگاشت به شرکت‌ها، صنایع، سازمان‌ها کمک می‌کند تا نقشه آنچه را که لازم است انجام دهند تا در محیط آینده موفق شوند، به‌خوبی ترسیم کنند. ازجمله تصمیمات کلیدی و استراتژیک سازمان‌ها، برنامه‌ریزی برای تأمین نیروی انسانی مناسب برای آینده سازمان است. به‌طورکلی، هدف از برنامه جانشینپروری، آماده‌سازی نیروهای مستعد داخل سازمان برای تصدی مشاغل کلیدی، حساس و راهبردی است. پس در هر سازمانی لزوم برنامه‌ریزی برای ایجاد یک مدل یکپارچه جهت جایگزینی نیروهای قدیمی اجتناب‌ناپذیر است. ازاین‌رو در مقاله حاضر سعی شده است که به ترسیم یک ره‌نگاشت جامع برای اجرای برنامه جانشین‌پروری که به‌مثابه نقشه راه برای ادامه حیات سازمان است، پرداخته شود. مطالعه موردی در این مقاله شرکت ملی انتقال گاز، منطقه سه عملیات انتقال است و با توجه به اهمیت استراتژیک این شرکت برای کشور از منظرهای مختلف تأثیرگذار بر رشد پایدار، تدوین ره‌نگاشت برای نیروهای آینده این سازمان برای نخستین‌بار در دستور کار قرارگرفته است. جمع‌آوری داده‌ها مبتنی بر نظرات خبرگان و با استفاده از فرایند دلفی انجام‌شده است. یافته‌های تحقیق نشان می‌دهد که ره‌نگاشت تدوین‌شده با توجه به اعتبارسنجی انجام‌شده توسط خبرگان، به‌خوبی توانسته است نیازهای آشکار و پنهان شرکت گاز ایران را برای جانشین‌پروری نیروها با توجه به اهداف مدنظر سازمان تأمین نماید.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">تدوین ره‌نگاشت</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدیریت منابع انسانی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
جانشین‌پروری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مشاغل کلیدی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/1395060712153241-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>