﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>58</Volume><Issue>دوم</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2015</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Impact of Organization's capabilitis on Product Performance in the high-tech Defense Industry (Case study: Defense Electronics Industry</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تاثیر قابلیت های سازمان بر عملکرد محصول در صنعت دفاعی مبتنی بر فناوری برتر (مورد مطالعه: صنعت الکترونیک دفاعی)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>51</FirstPage><LastPage>68</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>سمیه</FirstName><LastName>محرابی گوروان</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه مالک اشتر</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>ابراهیم</FirstName><LastName>محمودزاده</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه مالک اشتر</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName><LastName>بوشهری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه مالک اشتر</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مجید</FirstName><LastName>رمضان</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day></History><Abstract>High-tech defense organizations, due to specific features such as: dependence on innovation, strategic goals, reliance on applied knowledge and dynamic nature, require more attention to Capabilities that are appropriate to circumstances, including innovation capability.Therefore, in this research, the effect of technological, product and process innovation and ambidexterity capability on the performance of defense products has been investigated. The research methodology is applied in terms of achievemen, exploratory and descriptive in terms of purpose. In order to localize the literature of the subject with the high-tech defense organizations in Iran, the Focus Group method was used. The required data in the form of a questionnaire from 58 defense organizations of the field of electronics (as a high-tech industry) Collected. Analysis of the data with the help of structural equation model (PLS SEM) has shown that the capabilities of product innovation, process innovation, ambidexterity and technology influence product performance. The research findings lead the managers of defense electronic industry to empower the organization in the field of product and process innovation, technological and ambidexterity capabilities.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">سازمان¬های دفاعیِ مبتنی بر فناوری برتر به دلیل ویژگی¬های خاص مانند: وابستگی به نوآوری، اهداف راهبردی، اتکا به دانش کاربردی و ماهیت پویا، نیازمند توجه بیشتر به قابلیت¬های متناسب با شرایط خود، از جمله قابلیت نوآوری می¬باشند. به همین دلیل در این پژوهش به بررسی اثر قابلیت نوآوری محصول و فرایند، قابلیت فناورانه و دوسوتوانی بر عملکرد محصول دفاعی پرداخته شده است. روش تحقیق از منظر هدف، اکتشافی و توصیفی و از منظر دستاورد، کاربردی است. در راستای بومی¬سازی متغیرهای ادبیات موضوع با سازمان¬های دفاعی مبتنی بر فناوری برتر در ایران، از روش گروه کانونی استفاده و داده¬های موردنیاز، در قالب پرسشنامه از 58 سازمان دفاعی حوزه الکترونیک (به عنوان یک صنعت مبتنی بر فناوری برتر) جمع¬آوری شد. تحلیل داده های حاصل با کمک مدلسازی معادلات ساختاری مبتنی بر حداقل مربعات جزئی نشان داد که قابلیت¬های: نوآوری محصول، نوآوری فرایند، دوسوتوانی و فناورانه، عملکرد محصول را تحت تاثیر قرار می دهند. یافته¬های تحقیق، مدیران صنعت الکترونیک دفاعی را به سمت توانمندسازی سازمان در حوزه نوآوری محصول و فرایند و ارتقای قابلیت فناورانه و قابلیت دوسوتوانی هدایت می نماید.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">قابلیت نوآوری محصول، قابلیت نوآوری فرایند، قابلیت فناورانه، قابلیت دوسوتوانی، عملکرد محصول</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13970416205015133138-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>