﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2013</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Explaining Positioning Strategies for Firms</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تبیین استراتژی های موقعیت‌یابی بنگاه‌های اقتصادی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محمد رضا</FirstName><LastName> حمیدی زاده</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>فرید </FirstName><LastName>ترهنده</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></History><Abstract>The aim's paper is to recognition and explanation of firms' position. Thus, this study presents a evaluating model based on two cores for the strategic positioning of firms. The research method is based on descriptive with especial focused on survey and case study one; therefore, its model has two dimensions as: Porter's generic strategies and positioning. This model directs seven research hypotheses. Thus, the population for study is electrical equipments industry; therefore, the sample size is 67 staffs. Questionnaires were distributed among 130 employees and vendors of “Part Bargh Iranian” company and at last 56 questionnaires were collected. Questionnaires were distributed among people with internal and external recognition about company. Finally research hypotheses: significant relationship between the Porter's generic strategy model and strategic positioning model, and secondary hypotheses: relationship between the cost leadership and  strategic positioning model (Product and firm) , relationship between the differentiation strategy and  strategic positioning model (Product and firm), relationship between the focus strategy and  strategic positioning model (Product and firm) , all confirmed.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف این تحقیق شناخت و تبیین استراتژی های موقعیت بنگاه ها و نیز ارایه ی مدل ارزیابی موقعیت یابی استراتژیک بنگاه های اقتصادی است.این تحقیق از نوع توصیفی پیمایشی است که مدلی دو بعدی را در ابعاد استراتژی عمومی و موقعیت‌یابی طراحی و ارزیابی می کند. نمونه تحقیق 67 نفری از جامعه آماری 130 نفر از کارکنان و فروشندگان شرکت پارت برق ایرانیان انتخاب گردید و در نهایت 56 پرسشنامه تکمیل و جمع آوری گردید. پرسشنامه میان افراد آگاه از مسایل درون و بیرونی سازمان توزیع گردید. در نهایت فرضیه اصلی تحقیق یعنی وجود رابطه ی معنادار میان مدل استراتژی های عمومی پورتر با مدل موقعیت یابی استراتژیک و فرضیات فرعی شامل رابطه ی معنادار میان رهبری هزینه با موقعیت یابی استراتژیک محصول و بنگاه ، رابطه ی معنادار میان رهبری تمایز و موقعیت یابی استراتژیک محصول و بنگاه ، رابطه ی معنادار میان تمرکز و موقعیت یابی استراتژیک محصول و بنگاه ، مورد تایید قرار گرفتند .</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">موقعیت یابی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 رهبری هزینه</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 استراتژی تمایز</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 استراتژی تمرکز</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139412121444281361-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>