﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>52</Volume><Issue>4-ب</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Selection a strategic process for applying the Lean Six Sigma methodology to improve performance by using a hybrid approach, BSC &amp; DEA</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle> انتخاب فرآیند استراتژیک  بمنظور بکارگیری در متدولوژی شش سیگمای ناب در راستای بهبود عملکرد   با استفاده از رویکرد ترکیبی  BSC&amp;DEA</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>اردشیر </FirstName><LastName>بذرکار</LastName><Affiliation>مدیریت</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سلیمان</FirstName><LastName>ایرانزاده</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تبریز</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></History><Abstract>Most organizations to increase productivity and ultimately achieve sustainable competitive advantage for survival in the global business arena, focusing much of their attention to fix the problems, difficulties and weaknesses in their own systems and processes. Organizations spend a lot of time and resources to plan and develop their own strategies, but most of them fail in the implementation of the strategy.Organizations are looking for a breakthrough performance through integrated processes and technology to respond to the needs of our customers. The use of Lean Six Sigma methodology for organizations that operate in a competitive world is very functional. The importance of implementing Lean Six Sigma in an organization that is in issue or to be discovered process properly investigated and the selection process to the strategic objectives of the organization so that the organization can be targeted to improve process performance and take steps towards continuous improvement. The purpose of this research is a strategic process through the accounting department processes to improve performance through the application of Six Sigma methodology Ghavamin Bank was pure. Therefore, in this study, the criteria for the selection process to select a strategic process through six main measure Balanced Scorecard and by experts Ghavamin Bank, were identified. Then processes information related to the accounting department of the bank through a database of Ghavamin as well as interviews with experts were collected Bank. The final step using cross efficiency DEA model to assess the efficiency of the process was done, the results showed that the process was No. 18 in the first place. And as the bank's strategic process to make continuous improvement in the Lean Six Sigma methodology was introduced.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">اغلب سازمان ها بمنظور افزايش بهره وري و نهايتا دستيابي به مزيت رقابتي جهت ماندگاري پايدار در عرصه تجارت جهاني ، بخش وسيعي از تمركز و توجه خود را به رفع مسائل ، مشكلات و نقاط ضعف موجود در سيستم ها و فرايندهاي خود مي نمايند . سازمان ها منابع و زمان زيادي را صرف تدوين و توسعه استراتژي هاي خود مي نمايند اما اغلب آنها در مرحله اجراي اسـتراتژي بـا شكست مواجه مي شوند. .سازمان ها به دنبال دستیابی  به موفقیت از طریق عملکرد یکپارچه فرآیندها و فن آوری هستند تا بتوانند نیازهای مشتریان خود را پاسخ دهند. امروزه استفاده ازمتدولوژی شش سیگمای ناب برای سازمانهایی که در دنیای رقابتی فعالیت می کنند بسیار کاربردی است. اهمیت اجرا و پیاده سازی شش سیگمای ناب در یک سازمان در این است که مسله و یا فرآیند مورد بررسی به درستی کشف شود و انتخاب فرآیند در جهت اهداف استراتژیک سازمان باشد تا از این طریق سازمان با بهبود عملکرد فرآیند بتواند هدفمند و در راستای بهبود مستمر گام بردارد.  هدف از این پژوهش انتخاب یک فرآیند استراتژیک از میان فرآیندهای گروه حسابداری بانک قوامین بمنظور بهبود عملکرد از طریق بکارگیری متدولوژی شش سیگمای ناب بود.به همین منظور در این پژوهش برای انتخاب فرآیند استراتژیک ابتدا معیارهای انتخاب فرآیند از طریق شش سنجه اصلی کارت امتیاز متوازن و با نظر خبرگان بانک قوامین ، شناسایی شدند و سپس اطلاعات مربوط به فرآیندهای گروه حسابداری ازطریق بانک اطلاعاتی واحدهای مختلف بانک قوامین و همچنین مصاحبه با خبرگان بانک جمع آوری شد.در نهایت با استفاده از مدل کارایی متقاطع در تحلیل پوششی داده ها ، سنجش کارایی فرآیندها صورت گرفت ، نتایج نشان داد که فرآیند شماره 18 در رتبه نخست قرار گرفت و به عنوان فرآیند استراتژیک بانک جهت ایجاد بهبود مستمر در متدولوژی شش سیگمای ناب ، معرفی شد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">فرآیند ،کارت امتیاز متوازن، تحلیل پوششی داده ها ، کارایی متقاطع، برنامه ریزی آرمانی، شش سیگمای ناب </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139509111515454090-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>