﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>2-ب</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring of Opportunity Identification Process in Corporate of Converging Technologies   </ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>واکاوی فرایند شناسایی فرصت در شرکت های فعال درحوزه فناوری های همگرا</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>123</FirstPage><LastPage>136</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محمد</FirstName><LastName>هاشمی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علي </FirstName><LastName>مبيني دهكردي</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمدرضا </FirstName><LastName>ميگون پوری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>کمال</FirstName><LastName>سخدری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></History><Abstract>In the present era, technological innovation is a key factor in the development and advancement of societies, and technological entrepreneurship is recognized as the main source of disruptive innovation through identifying and effectively exploiting technological opportunities. Given the emerging concept of "convergence" in high technologies and novel opportunities resulting from that, it is necessary to recognize the various dimensions of this phenomenon, especially the process of identifying opportunities, as the first and most fundamental step of the technological entrepreneurship process. This research is based on the epistemology of "interpretiveism" and it is exploratory and based on literature on Entrepreneurial opportunities, technological corporate entrepreneurship, interdisciplinary studies and convergent technologies. In this research, the unit of analysis, is the "opportunity identification process" and the level of analysis, is "organization" and the concept of "convergence" as the dominant approach to research has been considered. Also, the research method is qualitative and research strategy, is a multiple case study. The collection of research data has been done through a semi-structured interview and observation of archival documents. The results of the research indicate the great importance of factors such as interdisciplinary understanding, interdisciplinary absorptive capacity, and the type of human capital in the process of identifying opportunities in active companies in the field of converging technologies</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در عصر حاضر، نوآوری های فناورانه، عامل کلیدی توسعه و پیشرفت  جوامع بوده و کارآفرینی فناورانه، از طریق شناسایی و بهره برداری موثر از فرصت های فناوری، به عنوان منشا اصلی ایجاد نوآوری های تحول زا، شناخته می شود. با توجه به نوظهوري مفهوم "همگرايي" در فناوري‌های پيشرفته  و فرصت‌هاي بدیع ناشي از آن، لازم است ابعاد مختلف این پدیده، خصوصاً فرایند شناسایی فرصت، به عنوان اولین و بنیادی ترین گام از فرایند کارآفرینی فناورانه  شناخته شود. اين پژوهش بر مبنای معرفت شناسی "تفسیر گرایی" و از نوع اکتشافی بوده و بر روی ادبیات فرصت کارآفرینانه، کارآفرینی سازمانی فناورانه، مطالعات میان رشته ای و فناوریهای همگرا، استوار می باشد. در اين پژوهش، واحد تحليل، " فرایند شناسایی فرصت" و سطح تحليل، "سازمان" بوده و مفهوم " همگرایی"  به عنوان رویکرد حاكم بر پژوهش، مورد توجه قرار گرفته است. همچنین، روش تحقیق مورد استفاده، کیفی و استراتژی تحقیق، مطالعه چندموردی می باشد. گردآوری داده های مورد نیاز پژوهش، از طریق مصاحبه  نیمه ساختار یافته و مشاهده مستندات آرشیوی انجام گرفته است. نتایج پژوهش، بیانگر اهمیت فوق العاده عواملی همچون، فهم میان رشته ای، ظرفیت جذب میان رشته ای و نوع سرمایه انسانی، در فرایند شناسایی فرصت در شرکت های فعال حوزه فناوریهای همگرا می باشد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">فرصت کارآفرینانه</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
شناسایی فرصت</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
کارآفرینی سازمانی فناورانه</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
فناوری های همگرا </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مطالعات میان رشته ای</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139611302353370947-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>