﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>51</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Stuyding the relationship between assertiveness and empathy of faculty members who have managerial positions  (case study:Valiasr university of Rafsanjan)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بررسی رابطه بین قاطعیت و همدلی اعضای هیأت علمی دارای پست های مدیریتی (مطالعه موردی:دانشگاه ولی عصر (عج) رفسنجان)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>147</FirstPage><LastPage>156</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مرضیه</FirstName><LastName>کهنوجی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه ولی عصر (عج) رفسنجان</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day></History><Abstract>Objective: the main goal of the present research is to study the relationship between assertiveness and empathy of faculty members who have managerial positions. Method: this is a correlative-applied research. statistical population of the research includes all faculty members with managerial positions in academic year 2015-2016 in Valiasr University of Rafsanjan. The number of them is 61 persons. The statistical population has been studied as the sample. Data were gathered by standard questionnaires of assertiveness (Gambrel &amp; Richy) and empathy (Davis). Data were analyzed by descriptive and infrential statistics.Findings: results of data analysis suggest that there is no significant relationship between managers’ assertiveness and viewpoint and between amount of imagination and empathetic attention and there is relationship between managers’ assertiveness and personal distress.Conclusion: results of the research suggest that there is no relationship between assertiveness of faculty members with managerial positions and dimensions of empathy. Therefore, it is necessary to pay attention strictly to these dimensions in behaviors of managers. It is recommended that managers are chosen more accurately by holding educational periods, related workshops and more scientific selections.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف: هدف اصلی این تحقیق بررسی رابطه بین قاطعیت و همدلی اعضای هیأت علمی دارای پُستهای مدیریتی بوده است.روش:پژوهش حاضر تحقیق همبستگی از نوع تحقیقات کاربردی می باشد.جامعه آماری پژوهش شامل کلیه اعضای هیأت علمی دارای پُست مدیریتی در سال تحصیلی 95-1394 در دانشگاه ولی عصر (عج) رفسنجان می باشندکه تعدادآنها 61 نفر بودند و کلیه جامعه آماری به عنوان نمونه مورد بررسی قرار گرفتند. جمع آوری داده ها از طریق پرسشنامه های استاندارد قاطعیت(گمبریل و ریکی ) وهمدلی(دیویس )انجام شد. تجزیه و تحلیل داده ها در سطح توصیفی و استنباطی انجام گرفته استیافته ها:  از نتایج تحلیل داده ها چنین دریافت می شود که بین قاطعیت مدیران و اتخاذ دیدگاه، میزان تخیل وتوجه همدلانه رابطه معناداری مشاهده نمی شود و بین قاطعیت مدیران و پریشانی شخصی رابطه وجود دارد.نتیجه گیری: نتایج کلی پژوهش حاکی از آن است که بین میزان قاطعیت اعضای هیأت علمی دارای پُستهای مدیریتی با ابعاد همدلی رابطه ای وجود ندارد .این رهیافت لزوم توجه جدی به تقویت توام این ابعاد در رفتار مدیران را ضروری می نمایاند.لذا توصیه می گرددبا برگزاری دوره های آموزشی ، کارگاههای مرتبط  و انجام گزینش های علمی تر در انتخاب مدیران دقت بیشتری به عمل آید.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">قاطعیت، همدلی، اعضای هیأت علمی، مدیران.</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139601301033355696-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>