﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>1-الف</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Compilation Crisis Management Indicators with the Approach of Removing the Quran from Forgetfulness (Case Study: Calf Worship Crisis People of Moses)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تدوین شاخص های مدیریت بحران با رویکرد خارج سازی قرآن از مهجوریت (مورد مطالعه:بحران گوساله پرستی قوم حضرت موسی(ع)) </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>55</FirstPage><LastPage>72</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>علی   </FirstName><LastName>نجاتبخش اصفهانی</LastName><Affiliation>-</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>عزت الله </FirstName><LastName>مولایی نیا</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه قم</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></History><Abstract>Social, political, cultural and ideological crises on the one hand and the need to guide and lead the human society on the other hand necessitate the need to use an original thought in divine sovereignty. Since the philosophy of verses of revelation is not specific to a particular society at a certain time, the safest way to guide the society can be extracted from the teachings of the Quran and its operationalization can be facilitated in the current era. In this research, enjoying the Quranic verses, the researcher has studied the life and tradition of Moses in the form of indices before, during and after the crisis along with providing a conceptual model developed by the researcher and validated by university and seminary professors. The research method is the seminary traditional deductive method. This means that the needed information is collected by analyzing the content of the verses Result: crisis management in his tradition According to the Quran, Moses had special features which made him a significant comprehensiveness. In fact, the most useful way to guide human beings and save them from the yoke of captivity, corruption, etc. is the adherence to the teachings of the divine, on the other hand the great event of prophetic movement of Imam Khomeini, the need to analyze issues related to management and leadership has become inevitable from the perspective of Islam. Therefore, by knowing Moses tradition and principles of crisis management on issues concerning the today's society and relying on the achievements of this research, the problems and crises can be faced simply.  It is better to use these teachings in the face of crises to help the great leader in dispelling the management concerns, especially the demands of the spiritual leader of the Muslim world. </Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">بروز بحرانهای اجتماعی، سیاسی، فرهنگی ،عقیدتی از سویی و لزوم هدایت و رهبری جامعه انسانی از سوی دیگر ضرورت استفاده از  یک تفکر اصیل را در حاکمیت الهی ایجاب می نماید . از آنجا که فلسفه نزول آیات وحی براي جامعه¬ای خاص  و  در زمانی معین نمی باشد، می توان سالم ترین راه هدایت جامعه را از آموزه¬هاي قرآنی استخراج و در راستاي عملیاتی سازی آن در عصر کنونی زمینه سازی کرد. در این پژوهش محقق با بهره گیري از آیات قرآن زندگی حضرت موسی(ع) و سیره ی آن بزرگوار را در قالب شاخصهاي قبل، حین و پس از بحران همراه با با ارائه مدل مفهومی محقق ساخته و با اعتبارسنجی آن توسط اساتید حوزه و دانشگاه،مورد مطالعه قرار داده است. روش پژوهش "روش اجتهادی معهود حوزوی" است. بدین معنا که  اطلاعات مورد نیاز با تحلیل محتواي آیات قرآن جمع آوري شده است. نتیجه: مدیریت بحران در سیره حضرت موسی(ع) از دیدگاه قرآن از ویژگیهای خاص برخوردار بوده که به آن جامعیتی معنادار بخشیده است. در واقع سود مندترین راه برای هدایت و رهایی انسانها  از یوغ اسارت،فساد، و ... تمسک به آموزه های الهی است. از طرفی نهضت پیامبر گونه حضرت امام خمینی (ره) ضرورت واکاوی مسائل مربوط به مدیریت و رهبری را از منظر اسلام اجتناب ناپذیر کرده است. از این رو با شناخت سیره و اصول مدیریت بحران حضرت موسی(ع) در مسائل  مبتلابه امروز جامعه و با تکیه بر دستاوردهای این تحقیق می توان استفاده لازم در مشکلات و رویارویی با بحران ها را به عمل اورد. و به جاست از این آموزه ها استفاده نمائیم تا نسبت به برطرف کردن دغدغه های مدیریتی به ویژه مطالبات ولی امر مسلمین در این زمینه با هوشیاری یار و مددکار معظم له باشیم.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">قرآن</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 رهبري و مدیریت حضرت موسی(ع)</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
رهبری پیامبران</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
اصول مدیریت بحران</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
سیره</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/13960721197358500-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>