﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مدیریت فردا</PublisherName><JournalTitle>مدیریت فردا</JournalTitle><ISSN>2228-6047</ISSN><Volume>51</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Identifying and evaluation the effective factor on successfully implementation of ERP in Small and Medium-sized Enterprises with emphasis on the life cycle of this system (Case Study: Enterprises located in the industrial town of Rasht Sefidroud)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>شناسایی و ارزیابی عوامل موثر بر موفقیت پیاده‌سازی سیستم ERP در شرکت‌های کوچک و متوسط با تأکید بر چرخه حیات این سیستم</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مرضیه </FirstName><LastName>باباییان پور</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName><LastName>نیک پور</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور تهران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سید محمد حسن</FirstName><LastName>حسینی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشکده مهندسی صنایع و مدیریت</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></History><Abstract>ERP system implementation can affect all the functions of the areas in organization and lead to increased efficiency and total productivity in the organization. But usually the organizations face with important problems and barriers such as restrictions on capital, resources, poor management and so on during the process of ERP implementation. One of the priorities of economic development in many of the developed countries is small and medium firms. What is important in these companies is ERP system implementation, so in this research we provide a model for successful ERP implementation by using its critical success factors in ERP life cycle. Therefore, study population in this research is small and medium companies based in the industrial city of Rasht Sefidrud taken into account that the number of respondents included 166 patients and for analysing the results by using structural equation modeling (SEM). The results obtained confirm the factors to company's strategy (transparent goals), accuracy of information and knowledge management, organizational structure (organizational readiness), experience, knowledge and expertise of the members of the project team and the support and participation of senior managers in step pre implementation, and approve all contributing factors is in during ERP implementation. As well as factors of change management, system acceptance / resistance ERP, collaboration and communication between departments, participation of stakeholders (end users, shareholders, etc.) and the Steering Committee also approved sample was in ERP post implementation step.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">اجرای موفق سیستم ERP در یک سازمان، تمام فرایندهای آن سازمان را تحت تأثیر قرار داده و منجر به افزایش راندمان و بهره‌وری کلی در سازمان می شود. اما سازمان‌ها در طول فرایند طراحی و پیاده‌سازی ERP  با مشکلات و موانعی مواجه هستند که آنها را از رسیدن به اهداف مطلوب این سیستم باز می دارد. در تحقیق حاضر به شناسایی و رتبه بندی موانع پیاده‌سازی موفق ERP با درنظر گرفتن چرخه حیات این سیستم پرداخته می شود. از آنجا که بنگاه‌های كوچك و متوسط یكی از اولویت‌های اساسی در برنامه‌های توسعه اقتصادی کشور می باشد لذا در این تحقیق بر صنایع کوچک و متوسط متمرکز شده و به منظور جمع آوری داده های مورد نیاز، شرکت‌های کوچک و متوسط مستقر در شهرک صنعتی سفیدرود رشت به عنوان جامعه آماری درنظر گرفته ‌شده است. اندازه نمونه مورد نیاز طبق فرمول کوکران تعداد 166 نفر پاسخ‌دهنده بوده و برای تحلیل و بررسی نتایج از مدل معادلات ساختاری (SEM) استفاده شده است. نتایج به دست آمده گویای تأیید عوامل استراتژی شرکت، مدیریت دانش و دقت اطلاعات، ساختار سازمانی، تجربه، دانش و تخصص اعضای تیم پروژه، و پشتیبانی و مشارکت مدیران عالی‌رتبه در مرحله قبل از پیاده‌سازی، و تأیید تمامی عوامل مؤثر در حین پیاده‌سازیERP می باشد. همچنین عوامل مدیریت تغییر، سیستم پذیرش/ مقاومت ERP، همکاری و ارتباط بین بخش‌ها، مشارکت ذینفعان (کاربران نهایی، سهامداران و...)، و استفاده از یک کمیته راهبری نیز مورد تأیید نمونه‌ی آماری در مرحله بعد از پیاده‌سازی ERP قرار گرفت.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">پیاده‌سازی ERP </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
چرخه حیات</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
شرکت‌های کوچک و متوسط </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
عوامل موفقیت</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://modiriyatfarda.ir/WebUsers/modiryatfarda/UploadFiles/OK/139511171847134887-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>