<add><doc><field name="journal_id">10014</field><field name="abstract">Today, organizations are paying particular attention to the ways and methods of teaching. If that is often not the result of poor training objectives training process, ways, methods and training techniques. Therefore, methods that can be used in training while working problems, to prepare them for activities and responsibilities, and the overall is over effectiveness of the training.
The present study was carried out to survey the methods of training with the carried periods on in the Esfahan refined Oil Company in 2012.The statistical population of the study included all the employees working at Isfahan oil Refinery Company from whom 285 were selected to take part in the study through Cohen, Manion &amp; Morrison (2000( Stratified random sampling. 285 questionnaires were distributed and 211 were returned. The research instrument of the current study was the researcher-made questionnaire and the construct validity of the questionnaires was confirmed through exploratory factor analysis and so did its reliability via Spearman Brown and Gattman's Cronbach Alpha coefficient (0.96). The data from research questions were analyzed at two descriptive and inferential statistics. The results of Mono-variable t-test indicated that each four lecturing, seminar, on the job training and out of organization teaching methods have affected on the degree of learning more than the average level and the results of Friedman test stated that on the job training method has had the highest fitness and lecturing method has had the lowest fitness according to the employees' viewpoint. Further, based on the results of this test, in lecturing, seminar, on the job training, out of organization institutions methods, the constituents of teacher, content and the place of sessions implementation, sequentially, have had the highest effectiveness on the employees' learning. The results Ki-2 test showed that there is a significant difference between teaching methods rank According to the demographic features (p≤0.05).
 </field></doc></add>