<add><doc><field name="journal_id">10014</field><field name="abstract">One of the approaches that is currently being addressed not only in Iran but in the world is the problem of creating a perspective and strategy formulation. In this regard, the role of strategists in the organization is very important. So, the main goal of this qualitative research was «developing a strategic training model at the national Iranian oil company» , based on grounded theory approach, and secondary aims included identifying dimensions (main categories) , causal conditions, confounding factors (adversary and deterrent) , strategies and implications for the development of strategists in national Iranian oil company; Although, identifying the most important components of the main category, which is strategic thinking. This research is in the category of applied research in terms of purpose, in the category of exploratory research in term of level and methodologically located in the category of qualitative research with grounded theory and systematic approach. The research data were collected through semi-structured interviews (۲۴ experts from industry and university) from study sample, then by coding, we have identified the dimensions, the main categories and the subcategories and concepts associated with each of the codes obtained. After the axial and selective coding table was obtained, the paradigm model was realized and the type of relationship between dimensions and components of strategist development was achieved. The findings of the research showed ۱۱ main categories and ۲۴ sub categories and ۹۸ concepts, which are in the form of a paradigmatic model including: causal conditions (individual factors, organizational factors and discourse) , the central category of strategic thinking (systemic vision, conceptual thinking, prospective and philosophical attitude) , Interventive factors (external and internal environment) , background factors (cultural context, learning context, psychological factors and organizational independence, strategies of talent identification and absorption and maintenance) and consequences (development of strategic thinking and establishment of monitoring system) in national oil company and showed the relationship between its various dimensions. The findings of this study led to the exploration of a model for development of strategists at the National Iranian Oil Company.</field></doc></add>