<add><doc><field name="journal_id">10014</field><field name="abstract">Today, many demographic and sociological changes such as increasing the number of women, working couples, long working hours, and the complexity of technology in the workplace have been occurred, which National Iranian Gas Company (NIGC) is also influenced by them and seeks to find out the work-life balance and ways to improve it. Therefore, explaining and surveying the model of antecedents and consequences of work-life balance in Iranian Gas National Company has been considered as the goal of this research. The research method was descriptive – correlation. Statistical population was employees of NIGC including ۲۱۷۲ individuals. Among them ۳۲۷ people were selected by stratified random sampling method. Data was gathered through standard questionnaires and analyzed by using structural equation modeling and SPSS and LISREL software. The results indicated that job characteristics, core self-evaluations and the protean career orientation have a significant positive effect on work-life balance, and work-life balance also has a significant positive effect on job satisfaction, family satisfaction and organizational pride of employees. Also, organizational pride has a significant positive effect on job satisfactioToday, many demographic and sociological changes such as increasing the number of women, working couples, long working hours, and the complexity of technology in the workplace have been occurred, which National Iranian Gas Company (NIGC) is also influenced by them and seeks to find out the work-life balance and ways to improve it. Therefore, explaining and surveying the model of antecedents and consequences of work-life balance in Iranian Gas National Company has been considered as the goal of this research. The research method was descriptive – correlation. Statistical population was employees of NIGC including ۲۱۷۲ individuals. Among them ۳۲۷ people were selected by stratified random sampling method. Data was gathered through standard questionnaires and analyzed by using structural equation modeling and SPSS and LISREL software. The results indicated that job characteristics, core self-evaluations and the protean career orientation have a significant positive effect on work-life balance, and work-life balance also has a significant positive effect on job satisfaction, family satisfaction and organizational pride of employees. Also, organizational pride has a significant positive effect on job satisfaction. 
n.</field></doc></add>