<add><doc><field name="journal_id">10014</field><field name="abstract">Nowadays, factors such as economic globalization and creation of global markets, rapid changes of technologies, become-knowledgeable organizations, expansion of e-commerce, rapid and easy access of the consumer to goods and services, and change of their social requirements have caused a severe competition among businesses followed by a stress on these organizations` personnel. Thus, aside the organizations` social responsibility for their personnel physical and mental health, one of the pioneer organizations` strategies in the economic competition is to reduce the personnel stress in order to eliminate negative consequences such as the loss of efficiency .consequently, since optimum time management controls and regulates the stresses and daily influx of tasks as well as reducing the individuals` anxiety and finally their stress in addition to have a n effective role in improving their efficiency.
Three hypotheses were proposed and a significance level was considered for them. The method of this study is a correlation one and Olmsted's time management, Parker and DeCurtis ` job stress and Patterson `s job efficiency self-evaluation questionnaires were used for data collection. statistical society of this study is all personnel of National Iranian South Oilfields company`s supply and goods Affairs Department (477 ones) of which 250 ones were selected using the stratified random sampling .228 ones filled and returned the distributed questionnaires. Descriptive statistical methods (tables of frequency, percent, average, and etc.) were used to extract the results of questionnaires and inferential statistical methods (Pearson correlation coefficients (were used test the hypotheses and data analysis. Using the statistical methods above and SPSS software, all data were analyzed. Results indicated that there is a significant relationship between time management and job stress of male and female employees; there is a significant relationship between time management and efficiency of male and female employees; and there is a significant relationship between job stress and efficiency of male and female employees. Finally, suggestions were presented to improve the time management and efficiency and reduce the job stress of the personnel. </field></doc></add>