<add><doc><field name="journal_id">10014</field><field name="abstract"> The main purpose of this study was to provide a model for the expectations and priorities of human resources in National Iranian Oil Company by QFD for quality engineering of welfare system. The research method was qualitative and quantitative. At first, welfare indices were extracted from Delphi method and interviews with experts (n = ۱۵) and then these indices were matched with the needs of human resources (n = ۲۰۸) as a questionnaire. In the present study, the statistical sample in the qualitative section were the experts of the Oil Company's welfare department whose issues, such as time, availability of the interviewees, and the extent of their cooperation were considered. ۱۵ people. After preparing the final questionnaire of expert indices in the quantitative part the number of questionnaires was obtained by Cochran formula. Reliability was confirmed using Cronbach's alpha of greater than ۰٫۷ and validity test was performed by examining factor loadings and AVE scores. To ensure the quality of the home matrix (HOQ) , technical requirements were created and the welfare service quality plans were processed to build the quality home matrix. In the final model it was found that the usability of internet services (GPS, virtual pages, online content, online information, etc.) is one of the key human resource expectations that influences other expectations. Also, the ۱۸ components, depending on the type of relationship in their respective categories, have a positive or negative (strong and medium) impact on human resource expectations. , have a positive or negative (strong and medium) impact on human resource expectations. The main purpose of this study was to provide a model for the expectations and priorities of human resources in National Iranian Oil Company by QFD for quality engineering of welfare system. The research method was qualitative and quantitative. At first, welfare indices were extracted from Delphi method and interviews with experts (n = ۱۵) and then these indices were matched with the needs of human resources (n = ۲۰۸) as a questionnaire. In the present study, the statistical sample in the qualitative section were the experts of the Oil Company's welfare department whose issues, such as time, availability of the interviewees, and the extent of their cooperation were considered. ۱۵ people. After preparing the final questionnaire of expert indices in the quantitative part the number of questionnaires was obtained by Cochran formula. Reliability was confirmed using Cronbach's alpha of greater than ۰٫۷ and validity test was performed by examining factor loadings and AVE scores. To ensure the quality of the home matrix (HOQ) , technical requirements were created and the welfare service quality plans were processed to build the quality home matrix. In the final model it was found that the usability of internet services (GPS, virtual pages, online content, online information, etc.) is one of the key human resource expectations that influences other expectations. Also, the ۱۸ components, depending on the type of relationship in their respective categories, have a positive or negative (strong and medium) impact on human resource expectations. , have a positive or negative (strong and medium) impact on human resource expectations.</field></doc></add>