<add><doc><field name="journal_id">10042</field><field name="abstract">Nowadays, small cities take an important role in population distribution, identical and fair distribution of social and economic activities, reducing regional inequalities, and finally, regional equilibrium, and equality in urban-regional system. The current research aims at analyzing the role of small-sized cities in regional equilibrium of urban network of East Azerbaijan Province. The research type is applied-developmental and the population was all the cities of the province. The required data was collected from the population and housing census from 1956-2011, Iran Statistics Center, Governorship, Statistical and Census Annals, and different bureaus and organizations. Moreover, to determine the extent of systemic equilibrium of the region such quantitative models as Rank-Size, Entropy Coefficient, Primate City Index, Elasticity Coefficient, Shift Share, and Location Quotient were made use of. In 2011, East Azerbaijan Province included five small-sized cities with population of 25000-50000, constituting 0.075 population of urban network of the region. The results indicated that, upon Rank-Size model, from 1986-2011, lack of equilibrium in urban hierarchy of East Azerbaijan Province was readily observable. Besides, investigating main agricultural, industrial, and service activities in small-sized cities indicated that such cities, in service section, import their demands and the only exceptions are the cities of Sarab and Azarshahr, agriculture-wise. The cities of Ajabshir and Sardroud import all their demands in all aspects and have failed to take a proper role in regional system equilibrium. Therefore, injecting capital and facilities into small cities may be a proper solution for reducing regional inequality, population concentration, and industry in the metropolis of Tabriz and finally it can bring about relative equilibrium in the regional system of East Azerbaijan Province. </field></doc></add>