<add><doc><field name="journal_id">10042</field><field name="abstract">In recent decades, cities are seeking for new ways to promote themselves and economic growth; hence, in order to attract capital and enter to competition arena, city managers increasingly pay attention to optimal use of urban assets. In these competitive conditions, governments have focused on strengthening marketing activities and city branding for improving competitiveness. In this regard, this research tries to investigate the concepts and views on city branding, competitiveness and urban economic growth to extract the indicators of each, and then, by prioritizing extracted indices, will present a conceptual model of urban branding in line with competitiveness and the growth of urban economy. The research method based on purpose is applied and based on data collection is a library- survey research. Data collection instrument is questionnaire. In order to data analysis, F'ANP model is used in order to use the inherent advantages of the factor analysis method, the subject first analyze the dimensions of the constituent and then using the ANP method, these dimensions, elements and the relationship between the elements and the cluster to be investigated. The statistical sample consisted of professors and Ph.D. students of urbanization of Islamic Azad University, Science and Research and Shahr Qods branches, and simple random sampling was used. Factor analysis was performed using 21 indicators and using SPSS software. The results of the research indicated the importance and necessity of considering the principles of urban branding, such as creating urban attractions, creating distinct advantages of the place, increasing participation and productivity, connecting and communicating cities, improving the location, developing creativity, preserving and developing urban assets in the field of improving competitiveness and as a result the growth of the urban economy. Finally, strategies and suggestions for branding of cities are also being proposed to promote competitiveness and urban economic growth. </field></doc></add>