<add><doc><field name="journal_id">10042</field><field name="abstract">Considering the current problems in the field of transportation in Tehran, this paper attempts to develop a sustainable technology assessment model in Tehran’s urban transport sector. The research was carried out in a mixed method. In the qualitative phase, using the principles of the data theory of the foundation, identifying the important components in the technology evaluation and compiling the paradigm model, was performed and in the quantitative phase, using the confirmatory factor analysis, the developed model was tested. The results of the study indicated that the topic of assessment of sustainable technology in the urban transport sector of Tehran is related to the use of urban transportation technologies. Due to population growth and consequently the increasing demand for urban travel, the expansion of marginalization and migration around Tehran and limited natural and ecological resources, and energy resources are created. Strategies such as strategic and prospective planning in the urban transport sector of Tehran, capacity of transportation in proportion to the demand for urban travel, assessment of compliance with requirements, national and international regulations, assessment of the economic justification of sustainable technology in the field of transportation and the possibility of creating the necessary investment with the resistance economy approach, evaluation of qualitative and technical functional considerations in the field of urban transport, assessment and monitoring of environmental impacts and life cycle analysis of transportation technologies, the use of clean and low carbon energy in transportation equipment, and so on are suggested. The strategies are influenced by the values and culture of society, the level of knowledge and public understanding of society from the risks of unsustainable technologies in the field of transportation, urbanization culture and observance of laws and regulations in the field of transportation by people and characteristics of Tehran in terms of climatic, demographic, geographical, political, infrastructure, and engineering aspects. It is expected that the implementation of the mentioned strategies could lead to events and consequences such as promoting the status of Iran in international rankings, promoting physical and mental health, vitality and welfare of the society, and labor force productivity, optimal utilization of urban infrastructure and facilities, promoting the level of knowledge and attitudes towards the use of sustainable technologies in transport, sustainable economic growth, entrepreneurship and employment, efficiency and positive performance in the field of urban transport and the environmentally sound and productive urban environment. </field></doc></add>