<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title> Journal of Urban Economics and Management </title>
<link>http://www.iueam.ir</link>
<description>Journal of Urban Economics and Management - Journal articles for year 2016, Volume 4, Number 13</description>
<generator>Yektaweb Collection - https://yektaweb.com</generator>
<language>en</language>
<pubDate>2016/3/11</pubDate>

					<item>
						<title>Economic Pricing of Recreational Services and Determining Visitors’ Willingness to Pay Costs for Visiting Urban Tourist Places  (Case Study: Garden of Flowers in Isfahan)</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=312&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;Cities have many tourism attractions and they always absorb many tourists to themselves; therefore, development of urban tourism and its wise management require planning. Considering the importance of tourism in urban economy and job creation, economic pricing of urban tourism services enjoys a special place in urban management. Garden of flowers is one of the most important tourism areas in the city of Isfahan. Thus, its recreational pricing can be effective in predicting needs and tourism development in Isfahan. The purpose of this research is estimating recreational value of Isfahan&amp;rsquo;s garden of flowers and determining the rate of visitors&amp;rsquo; willingness to pay for it with contingent valuation method. Data were collected by interview questionnaire with 110 people. Logit model was used to measure people&amp;rsquo;s WTP and the parameters were estimated based on maximum likelihood method. Dual two-dimensional method has been used to extract bids. According to the estimated coefficients, revenue and age variables had positive and negative effects respectively on WTP, and women&amp;rsquo;s WTP is more than men. The average of people&amp;rsquo;s WTP is 4752.49 Rials for recreational use of garden of flowers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
						<author>Mostafa  Baniasadi</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Assessing the Effectiveness of Specialized Courses for Financial and Urban Economic Experts of Tehran Municipality Based on Patrick Model</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=313&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;Training is a convenient tool for investing in human resources. Tehran Municipality, as an institution that its mission is servicing to the public, is responsible for important mission of staff&amp;rsquo;s training and development that they should attempt in line with servicing to citizens. This is much more delicate in areas involving in financial and economic issues. The remarkable point is that training is not profitable by itself, unless presented training to be evaluated and specified whether they have had necessary effectiveness or not. This research is applied in terms of purpose, and it is descriptive-survey considering method. The effectiveness of seven specialized courses of financial and urban economy experts of Tehran Municipality held in 2014 has been assessed. Statistical population is all financial and urban economy experts of Tehran Municipality who they were 227 people. 143 of them were selected as available sample attended in these courses by using simple random method. 36 people were direct managers. Data collection tool is research-made questionnaire based on Kirkpatrick Model. Its validity was verified by professors and experts in the field of training and assessment and its reliability has been verified using Cronbach&amp;rsquo;s alpha coefficient. One sample t test was used for the first, third, and fourth levels (reaction, behavior change and results), and paired samples t test was used for the second level (learning). The results indicate that specialized training courses have had appropriate efficacy at all four assessment levels of Patrick model special for financial and urban economy experts of Tehran Municipality held in 2014 including employees&amp;rsquo; reaction to training courses, learning gained from training courses, behavioral changes in employees, and changes in organizational performance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
						<author>Seyyed Mohsen Tabatabaei mozdabadi</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>A Study of Spatial Compliance Rate of Socio-Economic Inequalities in Eight Areas of Yazd City</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=314&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;urbanization process has been faced with servicing inequalities, population distribution, and unbalanced urban growth in developing countries. Instability caused by the unbalanced growth has been represented in the form of lack of spatial-social balances with manifestations of urban poverty, informal housing and employment, and environmental pollution. This research studies existing social and spatial inequalities in different areas and districts of Yazd City and their relationship with each other. Research methodology is descriptive-analytical and necessary data have been collected through library method and mostly using the information of Yazd detailed plan in 2009. Ranking Yazd areas and districts regarding social development using 15 indexes and TOPSIS and Taxonomy method showed that district 3, areas 2-2 are in the first rank, and area 1-2 is in the last place. Choosing the average of land price as a criterion for assessing economic inequality among different areas of the city and comparing this index using ANOVA test indicate that there is a difference among different areas of Yazd so that area 2-3 has the highest value and area 1-1 has the least. Correlation test among the rate of social development of areas and land price in them done with Pearson&amp;rsquo;s correlation coefficient indicates significant and positive relationship between these two variables. Thus, we consider increase in land price in line with social development rise in different areas of Yazd city.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
						<author>Samaneh Iraji</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>The Impact of Construction Projects in the Last Four Years in the Development of Urban Economy Management and Citizens’ Satisfaction (Case Study: Qazvin’s Citizens)</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=315&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;Today, urban public spaces play a fundamental role in urban development plans. This indicates the importance of the spaces in improving cultural-social aspect of cities. In other words, a culture creates behavioral patterns that determine and reflect how people to use the spaces. Therefore, it is natural that the use of the public spaces varies in different cultures. The nature and manner of activities that take place in urban areas can be related to two basic factors; culture and environment (spatial-local features). Statistical society is all Qazvin&amp;rsquo;s citizens who have taken advantage of the projects in last few years. Sample has obtained by report and interview with 425 Qazvin&amp;rsquo;s citizens. In terms of purpose, this research is applied-developmental and it is descriptive-analytical and survey one regarding method. The method of data analysis has been accomplished by using qualitative methods, particularly criteria and sub-criteria of citizens&amp;rsquo; satisfaction. The purpose of the research is the study of construction projects in last four years and its impact on management and development of urban economy and citizens&amp;rsquo; satisfaction. The results have indicated that macro policies, citizens&amp;rsquo; satisfaction, and giving the cities identity are three basic variables in constructing development projects.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
						<author>Rashed Safavi</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Determining the Poverty Line of Urban Households in East Azerbaijan Province by Using Linear Expenditure System</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=316&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;Measuring poverty can make the process of poverty evolutions understandable in every society and present an image of these developments during the time. Government can target and adopt appropriate decisions to do necessary measures as a result. In this regard, statistical study of poverty and its analysis at the level of province can be a guide for planners to reduce penury. The poverty line of urban areas in east Azerbaijan was estimated by using dynamic linear expenditure system (DLES) method assuming the formation of habits and using seemingly unrelated regression (SUR) model during 2001 to 2011. Components of eight commodity groups including food, clothing, housing, appliances and furniture, healthcare, transport and communication, recreation and education, and a group for other issues were used as well as their price index published by statistical center of Iran. The results obtaining from estimations by using STATA and Eviews soft wares indicate that poverty of urban areas in east Azerbaijan has ascending trend with an average growth rate of 23% during the period under review. The percentage of urban households below the poverty line of the Province is 50 percent on average, and poverty gap and severity of poverty indices have been reduced with average values of 42% and 23% respectively at the end of the period. Thus, according to the results for indicators of poverty, it can be said that although poverty eradication policies during the ten-year period of this research have improved the welfare of the poor people partially, the number of people below the poverty line has increased considerably during this period. The process of escalating prices can be one of the main reasons for this increase that can be solved by the government with curbing inflation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
						<author>Hossein  Mirzaei</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>A Measurement of Economic Factors of the City on Satisfaction and Residential Displacement of Family (Case Study: Narmak Neighborhood-Tehran)</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=317&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;Satisfaction achievement in residential areas is formed by different factors; one of them is economic factor of city. Economic indicators are effective along with physical, cultural, social, cultural and other components on the amount of maintenance and absorption of population in urban context, in the assessment of residents from their home environments. It is raised as one of the effective factor on family&amp;rsquo;s motivation for residential displacement. The goal of this article is assessing economic factors on residential satisfaction and its impact on family&amp;rsquo;s displacement in Narmak neighborhood according to its background in Tehran. Descriptive-analytic method has been used for data collection in this paper, and 375 questionnaires have been prepared, due to the sample size. Data analysis has been done by SPSS method and CSM indicator. The results of this research show consent of access, transport and security in that area and low discontent of residents from residential unit, services and facilities. These issues caused 59.2% willingness to movement and 40.8% unwillingness to residential displacement despite current problems.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
						<author>Laala Jahanshahlou</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Viability Index in Urban Environments  (Case Study: The Central Part of Holy City of Qom)</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=318&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;Improvement of living conditions in urban environments not only increases their attractiveness, but it also prepares an appropriate context for achieving to major goals of sustainable development. However, rapid growth of urbanization and other related issues with urban development have caused the problems of these habitants be increased. The situation is well understood in many Iran&amp;rsquo;s cities suffering from the consequences of rapid growth of urbanization and lack of adequate financial and human resources in the process of management. Thus, this research tries to identify the characteristics of viable urban societies, assess the viability of central part of Qom city, and find the situation of the city regarding viability indexes. Research method is descriptive-analytical as well as documentary, survey, and field studies such as adopted techniques and measures in this research. According to the research findings, policies for decentralization of activities, change in development policy based on automobile, attempt to stabilize old residents of the region (renovation, improve the quality of neighborhood services), and such issues should be adopted in order to improve the quality of life in this part of the city.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
						<author>Ali Asghar Isaloo</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Identification and Determination of Dimensions of Tourism Management Model in Tehran</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=319&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;Tourism, as a modern phenomenon, has an economic nature. It is of great importance for countries having this capacity. The purpose of this research is identification and determination of dimensions of tourism management model in Tehran based on managers and experts&amp;rsquo; opinions in tourism field by using the ramification pattern of the tertiary branches for designing and developing urban tourism management model in accordance with economic, socio-cultural, political and environmental conditions of Tehran. This research has quantitative entity. It is applied in terms of purpose done in descriptive-survey method. To collect primary data, the assessment tool in the form of closed questionnaire included 55 items in five options Likert scale was designed after studying theoretical foundations and literature tourism subject. Face and content validity were used for questionnaire. To assess reliability, Cronbach's alpha coefficient was used and the value of 0.94 was estimated. Statistical sample were 400 academic experts and managers in the field of tourism in Tehran. 371 valid questionnaires were collected from them.&amp;nbsp; In this research, three hypotheses were proposed, and for data analysis, factor analysis and structural equation modeling were used as well. The results of the data analysis show that factors affecting the management of urban tourism in Tehran are in three dimensions including structural, environmental, and content. Designing three-dimensional model of urban tourism management based on the pattern of three ramifications can be a base for tourism policy and planning in Tehran.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
						<author>Mahmood Ziyaei</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>A Comparison of Influential Indexes in Classification of Urban Projects of Tehran Municipality with other Selected Cities</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=320&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;Undoubtedly, the manner of financing for intended projects depends on the features of each project in any level of existing organizations; therefore, defined and applied indexes and standards should be fitted and overlapped with characteristics of each project. In fact, each project is categorized based on its qualities and appropriate financial instruments are determined according to this criterion. Urban projects have been classified and effective factors on the categorization in urban projects have been identified in this article. Tehran Municipality is compared with some large cities, in this respect. In order to study the issue, equality of external financing of urban projects with transport missions, urban services, and other missions have been examined by using ANOVA analysis, according to the separation of municipal projects to different missions. Better financing can be obtained by better identification and emphasis on the qualities of urban projects of Tehran Municipality and its comparison with other selected cities in the world including Seoul, Shanghai, Kuala Lumpur, New York, London, and Istanbul. According to the results, the hypothesis of equivalent amount of external financing municipal projects with municipal service mission in Tehran and other intended cities is not rejected.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
						<author>Shokrollah Banar</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Systematic Approach to the Budgeting of Municipalities in Terms of Applying Adjustment Policies of Energy Prices</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=321&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;Implementation of targeted subsidies law has influenced the revenue and costs of these organizations directly or indirectly. In this regard, studying the impacts of mentioned plan on revenue resources and municipalities&amp;rsquo; costs of the country is of great importance with systematic approach in municipalities&amp;rsquo; budgeting. The impacts of adjustment policies of energy prices on municipalities&amp;rsquo; revenue and costs can be evaluated systematically based on input-output models. What complicates the issue is the adjustment of municipalities&amp;rsquo; costs issues.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;Rise in the price of energy carriers may directly lead to increase in revenue from value added tax act for municipalities through increasing revenues from duties related to fuel and electricity. In order to estimate the impact of the implementation of the first stage of law on the income item, Consumption and price of energy carriers were used in the years before and after of the law. Having information about price and consumption after targeting, this makes it possible to calculate the increase of Rial value of use of different energy carriers in the year and calculate the rate of increase in duties of each fuel for all municipalities and rural municipalities in the country by using obtained figure and applying toll collection rates related to municipalities, specified in VAT act, as well. The impact of adjustment of energy prices on the inflation of different products can be stimulated by using price model based on input-output table. Increase in the costs of municipalities can be calculated according to obtained inflation in goods and services of the total economy. This type of stimulation will be based on systematic approach and all direct and indirect effects are considered in it. Budgeting of municipalities based on mentioned approach will result in balanced budget.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
						<author>Mahdi Sadeghi Shahdani</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
	</channel>
</rss>
