<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>2016</YEAR>
<VOL>4</VOL>
<NO>14</NO>
<MOSALSAL>0</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>157</PAGE_NO>


<ARTICLES>

	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>اولویت‎بندی شاخص‌های مدیریت مواد زاید جامد شهری در راستای توسعه پایدار (مطالعه موردی: شهر بوکان)</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Prioritization of Management Indexes of Municipal Solid Waste in Line with Sustainable Development (Case Study: City of Bokan)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>مدیریت غیراصولی مواد زاید جامد شهری، زمینه را برای ایجاد مشکلات زیست&#8204;محیطی و انسانی در درازمدت فراهم می&#8204;کند؛ بنابراین استراتژی مدیریت پایدار و مؤثر زباله&#8206;های شهری، نیاز به تعادل برای توسعه، کیفیت زندگی انسان و محیط&#8204;زیست دارد. این مقاله با هدف ارزیابی شاخص&#8204;های مدیریت مواد زاید جامد شهری در راستای توسعه پایدار با استفاده از تکنیک TOPSIS در شهر بوکان، تدوین شده است. روش تحقیق، پیمایشی و روش تجزیه&#8204;و&#8204;تحلیل داده&#8204;ها، توصیفی- تحلیلی می&#8204;باشد. جامعه آماری، جمعیت 171773 نفری شهر بوکان بود که نمونه آماری آن، 384 نفر به&#8206;دست آمد. با توجه به محدودیت&#8204;های تحقیق، نمونه&#8204;ها به&#8204; 330 نفر کاهش یافت. یافته&#8204;های تحقیق نشان می&#8204;دهند که در شهر بوکان به طور متوسط روزانه 150 تن زباله تولید شده و سرانه زباله 0/740 کیلوگرم در روز بوده است. بیشترین مقدار زباله&#8204;های تولیدی، مربوط به مواد آلی با 75/82&#160;درصد و کمترین مقدار، مربوط به چوب (0/65 درصد) می&#8204;باشد. رتبه&#8204;بندی نهایی به&#8204;دست آمده از ارزیابی میزان رضایت&#8204;مندی از شاخص&#8204;های توسعه پایدار مدیریت مواد زاید جامد به روش TOPSIS نشان داد که عنصر درخواست انعام، در رتبه اول و عنصر جذابیت تبلیغات، رتبه بیست را کسب کرده که کم&#8204;اهمیت&#8206;ترین عنصر می&#8204;باشد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Non-systematic management of municipal solid waste prepares the ground for the creation of human and environmental problems in long run. Therefore, sustainable and effective municipal waste management strategy is needed to balance the development, quality of life and environment. This paper has been developed to evaluate the management indicators of municipal solid waste in accordance with sustainable development in Bukan by using TOPIS technique. Research method is survy (questionnaire and field study) and describtive- analytical data analysis was used. The statistical population was the city&#8217;s population of 171,773 people with the sample of 384 people. It was reduced to 330 due to the limitations of the study. Findings show that 150 tons of waste are produced daily on average in the city of Bukan and the waste per capita is 0.740 kg per day. The most amount of produced solid waste is related to organic materials with 75.82 and the least amount is related to wood with 0.65 percent. The final obtained ranking of satisfaction rate of sustainable development indexes of solid waste management by TOPSIS method has indicated that the factor of tip request was in the first rank and the factor of advertisement attractiveness was in the 20th rank that is the least important one.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>17</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمدحسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>سرایی</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad Hossein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Saraei</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>University of Yazd, Yazd, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>زهرا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>جمشیدی</Family>
				<NameE>Zahra</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Jamshidi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>University of Yazd, Yazd, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>نوید</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>آهنگری</Family>
				<NameE>Navid</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ahangari</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Municipal solid waste management</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>sustainable development</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>TOPSIS technique</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>city of Bukan</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدیریت مواد زاید جامد شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>توسعه پایدار</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تکنیک TOPSIS</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شهر بوکان</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##پوراحمد، احمد. (1388). قلمرو و فلسفه جغرافیا، تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه تهران.##رفیعی، رضا؛ سلمان ماهینی، عبدالرسول؛ خراسانی، نعمت‌اله. (1388). ارزیابی محیط‎زیستی چرخه حیات سامانه مدیریت پسماند شهری (مطالعه موردی: شهر مشهد)، فصلنامه علوم کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی، جلد شانزدهم، ویژه‎نامه 2، 220-208.##رقیمی، مصطفی. (1380). ضرورت استانداردسازی سیستم مدیریت مواد زاید جامد شهری، مجموعه مقالات نخستین کنفرانس توسعه و ترویج استاندارد، تهران: انتشارات مرکز آموزش و تحقیقات صنعتی ایران.##سعیدنیا، احمد. (1383). مواد زاید جامد شهری، کتاب سبز شهرداری، جلد هفتم، چاپ اول، تهران: انتشارات سازمان شهرداری‌ها و دهیاری‎های کشور.##شنبه‎زاده، سعید؛ مجلسی، منیره. (1391). بررسی وضعیت مدیریت مواد زاید شهری در مسجد سلیمان در ارتباط با سلامت محیط، مجله تحقیقات نظام سلامت، 8 (3)، 406-397.##طرح جامع مدیریت پسماند شهرستان بوکان. (1392). مهندسین مشاور پنگان‌آوران، شهرداری بوکان.##عبدلی، محمدعلی. (1387). بازیافت مواد زاید جامد شهری (کاهش، استفاده مجدد و بازچرخش)، چاپ سوم، تهران: مؤسسه انتشارات و چاپ دانشگاه تهران.##عمرانی، قاسم‌علی؛ علوی نخجوانی، نغمه. (1388). مواد زاید جامد (بازیافت)، جلد دوم، چاپ اول، تهران: انتشارات اندیشه رفیع.##فرج‌کرده، خدر. (1386). عوامل و متغیرهای مؤثر در تبیین بخش مرکزی شهرهای میانی (مورد مطالعه شهر بوکان)، پایان‎نامه دوره کارشناسی ارشد جغرافیا و برنامه‎ریزی شهری، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران.##لولوئی، کیوان. (1380). بررسی عامل محیط‌زیست در توسعه، مجموعه مقالات نخستین کنفرانس توسعه و ترویج استاندارد. انتشارات مرکز آموزش و تحقیقات صنعتی ایران، تهران.##مجلسی، منیره؛ عمرانی، قاسمعلی؛ الهی، پریسا. (1389). بررسی مدیریت مواد زاید جامد هتل‌ها در منطقه 6 شهر تهران، فصلنامه علوم و تکنولوژی محیط‌زیست، 1 2(1)، 96-89.##Antonopoulos, I. S., Perkoulidis, G., Logothetis, D., Karkanias, C. (2014). Ranking municipal solid waste treatment alternatives considering sustainability criteria using the analytical hierarchical process tool. Resources, Conservation and Recycling, 86, 149-159. ##Antonopoulos, I. S., Perkoulidis, G., Logothetis, D., Karkanias, C. (2014). Ranking municipal solid waste treatment alternatives considering sustainability criteria using the analytical hierarchical process tool. Resources, Conservation and Recycling, 86, 149-159. ##Burnley, S. J. (2007). A review of municipal solid waste composition in the United Kingdom. Waste Management, 27(10), 1274-1285.##Cheng, S., Chan, C. W., Huang, G. H. (2003). An integrated multi-criteria decision analysis and inexact mixed integer linear programming approach for solid waste management. Engineering Applications of Artificial Intelligence, 16(5), 543-554.##Cherubini, F., Bargigli, S., Ulgiati, S. (2009). Life cycle assessment (LCA) of waste management strategies: Landfilling, sorting plant and incineration. Energy, 34(12), 2116-2123.##Cohen, B. (2004). Urban growth in developing countries: a review of current trends and a caution regarding existing forecasts. World development, 32(1), 23-51.##Elwan, A., Arief, Y. Z., Adzis, Z., Saad, M. H. I. (2013). The viability of generating electricity by harnessing household garbage solid waste using life cycle assessment. Procedia Technology, 11, 134-140.##Ezeah, C., Roberts, C. L. (2012). Analysis of barriers and success factors affecting the adoption of sustainable management of municipal solid waste in Nigeria. Journal of environmental management, 103, 9-14.##Farrell, M., Jones, D.L. (2009). Critical evaluation of municipal solid waste composting and potential compost markets. Bioresource technology, 100(19), 4301-4310.##Fodor, Z., Klemeš, J. J. (2012). Waste as alternative fuel–Minimising emissions and effluents by advanced design. Process safety and environmental protection, 90(3), 263-284.##Getahun, T., Mengistie, E., Haddis, A., Wasie, F., Alemayehu, E., Dadi, D., ... &amp; Van der Bruggen, B. (2012). Municipal solid waste generation in growing urban areas in Africa: current practices and relation to socioeconomic factors in Jimma, Ethiopia. Environmental monitoring and assessment, 184(10), 6337-6345.##Guerrero, L. A., Maas, G., Hogland, W. (2013). Solid waste management challenges for cities in developing countries. Waste management, 33(1), 220-232.##Haghi, A. K. (2010). Waste Management: Research Advances to Convert Waste to Wealth. Nova Science Publishers, Inc.##Henry, R. K., Yongsheng, Z., Jun, D. (2006). Municipal solid waste management challenges in developing countries–Kenyan case study. Waste management, 26(1), 92-100. ##Herva, M., Neto, B., Roca, E. (2014). Environmental assessment of the integrated municipal solid waste management system in Porto (Portugal). Journal of Cleaner Production, 70, 183-193.##Ichinose, D., Yamamoto, M., Yoshida, Y. (2013). Productive efficiency of public and private solid waste logistics and its implications for waste management policy. IATSS Research, 36(2), 98-105.##Jahanshahloo, G. R., Lotfi, F. H., Davoodi, A. R. (2009). Extension of TOPSIS for decision-making problems with interval data: Interval efficiency. Mathematical and Computer Modelling, 49(5), 1137-1142.##Louis, G. E. (2004). A historical context of municipal solid waste management in the United States. Waste management &amp; research, 22(4), 306-322.##Menikpura, S. N. M., Sang-Arun, J., Bengtsson, M. (2013). Integrated solid waste management: an approach for enhancing climate co-benefits through resource recovery. Journal of Cleaner Production, 58, 34-42.##Meylan, G., Seidl, R., Spoerri, A. (2013). Transitions of municipal solid waste management. Part I: Scenarios of Swiss waste glass-packaging disposal. Resources, Conservation and Recycling, 74, 8-19.##Minghua, Z., Xiumin, F., Rovetta, A., Qichang, H., Vicentini, F., Bingkai, L., ... &amp; Yi, L. (2009). Municipal solid waste management in Pudong New Area, China. Waste management, 29(3), 1227-1233.##Nemerow, N. L. (2009). Environmental engineering: environmental health and safety for municipal infrastructure, land use and planning, and industry (Vol. 3). John Wiley &amp; Sons.##Olson, D. L. (2004). Comparison of weights in TOPSIS models. Mathematical and Computer Modelling, 40(7), 721-727.##Pandyaswargo, A. H., Onoda, H., Nagata, K. (2012). Energy recovery potential and life cycle impact assessment of municipal solid waste management technologies in Asian countries using ELP model. International Journal of Energy and Environmental Engineering, 3(1), 1-11.##Rada, E. C., Ragazzi, M., Ionescu, G., Merler, G., Moedinger, F., Raboni, M., Torretta, V. (2014). Municipal Solid Waste treatment by integrated solutions: Energy and environmental balances. Energy Procedia, 50, 1037-1044.##Ragazzi, M., Girelli, E., Rada, E. C. (2012). MSW selective collection in a tourist area: an Italian case-study. Proceedings SIDISA2012, Milan, June, 26-29.##Sahoo, R. C., Sahoo, D., Sahoo, J., Pradhan, S. C. (2013). Trends And Problems Of Municipal Solid Waste Management In The District Of Balasore, Odisha And Prospects For A Sustainable Development. International Journal of Innovative Research and Development, 2(5).##Santibañez-Aguilar, J. E., Ponce-Ortega, J. M., González-Campos, J. B., Serna-González, M., El-Halwagi, M. M. (2013). Optimal planning for the sustainable utilization of municipal solid waste. Waste management, 33(12), 2607-2622.##Seadon, J. K. (2006). Integrated waste management–Looking beyond the solid waste horizon. Waste management, 26(12), 1327-1336.##Shih, H. S., Shyur, H. J., Lee, E. S. (2007). An extension of TOPSIS for group decision making. Mathematical and Computer Modelling, 45(7), 801-813.##Su, J. P., Chiueh, P. T., Hung, M. L., Ma, H. W. (2007). Analyzing policy impact potential for municipal solid waste management decision-making: A case study of Taiwan. Resources, Conservation and Recycling, 51(2), 418-434.##Sujauddin, M., Huda, S. M. S., Hoque, A. R. (2008). Household solid waste characteristics and management in Chittagong, Bangladesh. Waste Management, 28(9), 1688-1695.##Tan, S. T., Lee, C. T., Hashim, H., Ho, W. S., Lim, J. S. (2014). Optimal process network for municipal solid waste management in Iskandar Malaysia. Journal of Cleaner Production, 71, 48-58.##Tchobanoglous, G., Kreith, F., (2002). Handbook of Solid Waste Management, second ed. McGraw-Hill, New York, USA.##Vego, G., Kučar-Dragičević, S., Koprivanac, N. (2008). Application of multi-criteria decision-making on strategic municipal solid waste management in Dalmatia, Croatia. Waste management, 28(11), 2192-2201.##Victor, D., Agamuthu, P. (2013). Strategic environmental assessment policy integration model for solid waste management in Malaysia. Environmental Science &amp; Policy, 33, 233-245.##Wani, M., Ahmad, S. (2013). Challenges, issues of solid waste management in Himalayas: a case study of Srinagar City. Afr J Basic Appl Sci, 5(1), 25-29.##Wilson, D. C. (2007). Development drivers for waste management. Waste Management &amp; Research, 25(3), 198-207.##Worrell, W., Vesilind, P. (2011). Solid Waste Engineering, SI Version. Cengage Learning. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر تحولات بازار زمین و مسکن شهری (مطالعه موردی: شهر شاندیز در سال‌های 1393-1388)</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Factors Affecting Land and Housing Market Changes (Case Study: Padideh Tourism Compony-Shandiz City in 2009-2014)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>در این مقاله، تأثیر حضور و فعالیت شرکت گردشگری پدیده شاندیز، بر تحولات بازار زمین و مسکن در شهر شاندیز، در فاصله سال&#8204;های 93-1388 از دیدگاه شهروندان، بررسی شده است. این مطالعه، از نظر هدف، کاربردی و روش گردآوری اطلاعات، کتابخانه&#8204;ای و میدانی (پرسشنامه) و روش تجزیه&#8204;وتحلیل اطلاعات، به صورت آمار توصیفی (میانگین و انحراف معیار) و استنباطی (رگرسیون و آزمون تی تک&#8204;نمونه&#8204;ای) می&#8204;باشد. جامعه آماری تحقیق، شامل خانوارهای ساکن در شهر شاندیز است که بر پایه سرشماری سال 1390، دارای 3056 خانوار و 10428 نفر جمعیت می&#8204;باشد و براساس فرمول کوکران، تعداد نمونه لازم 160 خانوار به دست آمد. یافته&#8204;های پژوهش نشان می&#8204;دهند که آثار مستقیم ناشی از حضور و فعالیت شرکت گردشگری پدیده در شهر شاندیز در فاصله زمانی مورد مطالعه، با آماره 43/6 درصد، بیشترین تأثیر را بر تغییرات بازار زمین و مسکن در این شهر داشته&#8204;اند. هم&#8204;چنین بر پایه آزمون تی تک&#8204;نمونه&#8204;ای، اختلاف معناداری بین میانگین عوامل مؤثر بر تحولات قیمت زمین و مسکن و میانه نظری 3 در شهر شاندیز از دیدگاه شهروندان وجود دارد که بیانگر تأثیر قابل ملاحظه این عوامل، بر تغییرات بازار زمین و مسکن است. با توجه به یافته&#8204;ها، راهکارهایی مانند: توجه مدیران شهری به تحولات بازار زمین و مسکن در آینده، توجه به مساکن اقشار کم&#8204;درآمد و بومی، جلوگیری از پیدایش تعارضات اجتماعی، فراهم نمودن زیرساخت&#8204;ها و غیره، پیشنهاد شده است.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>When the large urban projects (Mega Project) to be loaded on a national scale in a small town, you can see dramatic changes in the market for land and housing in urban settlements. This paper attempts to study the impact of presence and activity of Padideh Shandiz Tourism Company on land and housing market changes examined in 2009 to 2014 from the perspective of citizens. Regarding purpose, this research is applied. Data were collected via library, field study (questionnaire), and descriptive method was used for data analysis (mean, standard deviation) and inferential statistics (factor analysis and one-sample t-test) were performed. The statistical population community, including families living in Shandiz City on the basis of the 2011 census, with a 10,428 population of 3056 households and is required sample size of 160 households was based on Cochran formula. The findings indicate that the direct effects caused by the presence and activities of Padideh Shandiz Tourism Company in the time interval studied, the statistic 43.6% of the biggest impacts on the land and housing market changes have had on the town. Also based on one sample t-test showed a significant difference between the mean and median of the theoretical (3) Shandiz City from the perspective of citizens that are substantially influence of these factors on land and housing market changes. According to the findings, strategies including attention to urban managements of land and housing market changes in the future, due to the low-income indigenous housing, prevention of social conflicts, provision of infrastructure, etc. have been proposed.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>19</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>38</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>زهرا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>عنابستانی</Family>
				<NameE>Zahra</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Anabestani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Islamic Azad university, Science and Research Branch, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>رحیم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>سرور</Family>
				<NameE>Rahim</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Sarvar</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Islamic Azad university, Science and Research Branch, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مسعود</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>مهدوی حاجیلوئی</Family>
				<NameE>Masoud</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Mahdavi Hajilouei</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Islamic Azad university, Science and Research Branch, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Padideh Tourism Company</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>environmental factors</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>urban management</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>urban housing</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Shandiz City</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر تحولات بازار زمین و مسکن شهری  (مطالعه موردی: شرکت گردشگری پدیده شهر شاندیز در سال‌های 1393-1388)</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##احمدی، سید وحید. (1387). آسیب‌شناسی بازار مسکن در ایران، تهران: انتشارات سازمان مسکن و شهرسازی.##استانداری خراسان رضوی. (1393). آخرین تقسیمات کشوری شهرستان بینالود، مشهد: استانداری خراسان رضوی.##اکبری، نعمت‌الله؛ عمادزاده، مصطفی؛ رضوی، سیدعلی. (1383). بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر قیمت مسکن در شهر مشهد. مجله پژوهش‌های اقتصادی، شماره 11 و 12، 117-97.##ایزدی، حسن؛ برزه‌گر، سپیده؛ پاکشیر، عبدالرضا؛ حاجی‌پور، خلیل. (1393). سنجش ارزش‏های محیطی اثرگذار بر رضایتمندی از محل سکونت، موردشناسی: محدوده معالی‏آباد شیراز. مجله جغرافیا و آمایش شهری و منطقه‌ای، 4(11)، 66-49.##پورمحمدی، محمدرضا؛ خوب‌آیند، سعید. (1380). بررسی و ارزیابی سیاست‌های تأمین مسکن برای گروه‌های کم‌درآمد شهری، مطالعه موردی: شهر تبریز. مجله دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی دانشگاه تبریز، شماره 180 و 181، 77-35.##پورمحمدی، محمدرضا؛ صدر موسوی، میرستار؛ عابدینی، اصغر. (1391). تحلیلی بر سیاست‌های تأمین مسکن دولت با تأکید بر برنامه‌های توسعه اقتصادی، اجتماعی و فرهنگی. فصلنامه مطالعات شهری، شماره 3.##پیله‌ور، علی‌اصغر؛ افراخته، حسن؛ کریمی‌پور، یدالله؛ سلیمانی، محمد؛ قهرودی تالی، منیژه. (1390). بررسی تأثیر تصمیمات سیاسی بر ناپایداری و تحولات ساختاری زمین و مسکن شهری ناشی از رویکرد سیاسی: مورد بجنورد. مجله جغرافیا و توسعه، 9(23)، 162-141.##چپرلی، حامد. (1387). نقش درآمد در تحول الگوی مسکن روستایی (مورد مطالعه دهستان سلطانعلی شهرستان گنبد)، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی‌ارشد رشته جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی روستایی، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی تهران.##حسینی، سیدعلی. (1385). مبانی فنی و اجرایی حقوق شهری و منطقه‌ای در ایران، رشت: انتشارات حق‌شناس.##رحیمی کاکه‌جوب، آرمان؛ عیسی‌لو، علی‌اصغر؛ محمدیان مصمم، حسن؛ رحمتی، اکبر. (1392). بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر قیمت مسکن شهری با استفاده از مدل هدانیک قیمت (نمونه موردی: منطقه دو شهر سنندج). فصلنامه اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری، 1(3)، 43-33.##زنگنه، یعقوب. (1388). درآمدی بر اقتصاد شهری، سبزوار: انتشارات دانشگاه تربیت معلم سبزوار. ##زیاری، کرامت‌الله. زرافشان، عطاءالله. (1385). بررسی تغییرات کمی و کیفی مسکن در شهر مراغه و پیش‌بینی مسکن مورد نیاز تا سال 1402، مجله جغرافیا و توسعه، 4(8)، 106-85.##زیاری، کرامت‌الله؛ قرخلو، مهدی؛ جان بابانژاد طوری، محمدحسین. (1387). مقایسه تطبیقی شاخص‎های کمی و کیفی مسکن شهر بابل با نقاط شهری کشور با تأکید بر شهر سالم، فصلنامه تحقیقات جغرافیایی، شماره 97، 13360-16327.##ستارزاده، داوود. (1388). شاخص‌های مسکن در استان سیستان و بلوچستان، فصلنامه جغرافیایی چشم‌انداز زاگرس، 1(1).##سجادیان، ناهید. (1380). تحلیل جغرافیایی سیاست‌های مسکن شهری تهران و پیامدهای ناشی از آن، مجله دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی دانشگاه تهران، شماره 158 و 159، 430-407.##شرکت توسعه بین‌المللی صنعت گردشگری پدیده شاندیز. (1393). اطلاعات مربوط به شهر رویایی پدیده، برگرفته از: http://www.padide.com.##صباغ کرمانی، مجید؛ احمدزاده، خالد؛ موسوی‎نیک، سیدهادی. (1389). عوامل تعیین‌کننده قیمت مسکن با رویکرد روابط علیتی در مدل تصحیح خطای برداری: مطالعه موردی تهران. مجله پژوهش‌های اقتصادی، 10(2)، 293-263.##عزیزی، محمدمهدی. (1383). جایگاه شاخص‌های مسکن در فرایند برنامه‌ریزی مسکن. مجله هنرهای زیبا، 17 (17)، 42-31.##عزیزی، محمدمهدی. (1384). تحلیلی بر جایگاه و دگرگونی شاخص‌های مسکن شهری در ایران. مجله هنرهای زیبا، 23(23)، 34-25.##عسگری، علی؛ قادری، جعفر. (1381). مدل هدانیک تعیین قیمت مسکن در مناطق شهری ایران، مجله پژوهش‌های رشد و توسعه پایدار، شماره 4، 106-91.##فنی، زهره؛ دویران، اسماعیل. (1387). پژوهشی در بازار زمین و مسکن (مورد: شهر زنجان، سال‌های 1378 الی 1386). فصلنامه مسکن و محیط روستا، شماره 124.##محمدپور عمران، محمود؛ محمودی پاتی، فرزین. (1387). سیاست‌های مدیریت زمین شهری، تهران: انتشارات شهیدی.##مرکز آمار ایران. (1391). سرشماری عمومی نفوس و مسکن- شهرستان بینالود در سال‌ 1390. تهران: مرکز آمار ایران.## ##Altshuler, A. A., Luberoff, D. (2003). Mega-projects: The changing politics of urban public investment. Brookings Institution Press.##Bourne, I.S. (1981). A Gography of Housing, Prentice-Hall, New York.##Cater, J., Trevor, J. (1989). Social Geography, Routledge, and London.##Cullingworth, B. (1997). Planning in the USA: Policies, Issues, and Processes, Routledge, New York.##Dawkins, C. J., Nelson, A. C. (2002). Urban containment policies and housing prices: an international comparison with implications for future research. Land Use Policy, 19(1), 1-12.##Flyvbjerg, B., Bruzelius, N., Rothengatter, W. (2003). Megaprojects and risk: An anatomy of ambition. Cambridge University Press.##Gallent, N., Shucksmith, M., Tewdwr-Jones, M. (Eds.). (2003). Housing in the European countryside: Rural pressure and policy in western Europe. Routledge.##Gouriéroux, C., Laferrère, A. (2009). Managing hedonic housing price indexes: The French experience. Journal of Housing Economics, 18(3), 206-213.##Hewitt, W. E. (1998). The role of international municipal cooperation in housing the developing world’s urban poor: the Toronto-Sao Paulo example. Habitat International, 22(4), 411-427.##Hui, E. C., Chau, C. K., Pun, L., Law, M. Y. (2007). Measuring the neighboring and environmental effects on residential property value: Using spatial weighting matrix. Building and environment, 42(6), 2333-2343.##Jia, G., Yang, F., Wang, G., Hong, B., You, R. (2011). A study of mega project from a perspective of social conflict theory. International Journal of project management, 29(7), 817-827.##Jim, C. Y., Chen, W. Y. (2006). Impacts of urban environmental elements on residential housing prices in Guangzhou (China). Landscape and Urban Planning, 78(4), 422-434.##Karlik, B., Olgac, A. V. (2011). Performance analysis of various activation functions in generalized MLP architectures of neural networks. International Journal of Artificial Intelligence and Expert Systems, 1(4), 111-122.##Knapp, E. (1982). Housing Problems in the Third World: Theoretical Terms of Reference, Methodology, and Four Case Studies in Bogota, Jakarta, Nairobi and Kasama, University of Stuttgart.##Laurice, J. (2003). Estimating Housing Prices in Southern California Using a Hedonic Pricing Model. M. A. Thesis, California State University, Fullerton.##Milbourne, P., Cloke, P.) 2006). International perspectives on rural homelessness, By: Routledge.##Orueta, F. D., Fainstein, S. S. (2008). The New Mega‐Projects: Genesis and Impacts. International Journal of Urban and Regional Research, 32(4), 759-767.##Plantinga, A. J., Détang-Dessendre, C., Hunt, G. L., Piguet, V. (2013). Housing prices and inter-urban migration. Regional Science and Urban Economics, 43(2), 296-306.##Ponzini, D. (2011). Large scale development projects and star architecture in the absence of democratic politics: The case of Abu Dhabi, UAE. Cities, 28(3), 251-259.##Rangwala, S.C. (1998). Town Planning. Charatar Publishing House, India.##Selim, H. (2009). Determinants of house prices in Turkey: Hedonic regression versus artificial neural network. Expert Systems with Applications, 36(2), 2843-2852.##Sendich, E. (2006). Planning and Urban Standard. Rutledge, New Jersey.##Short, J. R. (2006). Urban Theory Acritical Assessment. Routledge, New York.##Wen, H. Z., Jia, S. H., Guo, X. Y. (2005). Hedonic price analysis of urban housing: An empirical research on Hangzhou, China. Journal of Zhejiang University (Science), 6(8), 907-914.##Wen, H., Goodman, A. C. (2013). Relationship between urban land price and housing price: Evidence from 21 provincial capitals in China. Habitat International, 40, 9-17.##Wen, H., Tao, Y. (2015). Polycentric urban structure and housing price in the transitional China: Evidence from Hangzhou. Habitat International, 46, 138-146.##Westaway, M. S. (2006). A longitudinal investigation of satisfaction with personal and environmental quality of life in an informal South African housing settlement, Doornkop, Soweto. Habitat International, 30(1), 175-189.##Yagi, K., Hata, R. (1992). A Japanese touch for your home. Kodansha International.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>برنامه‎ریزی راهبردی جهت ساماندهی بافت فرسوده شهری (مطالعه موردی: محله شهیدگاه بقعه شیخ صفی‎الدین شهر اردبیل)</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Strategic Planning for the Organizing of Urban Old Textures (Case Study: Shahidgah-Sheikh Safi Neighborhood in Ardabil City)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>در حال حاضر، بافت&#8206;های فرسوده تاریخی در کشور ما به عنوان مشکل اساسی در شهرهای مختلف و حتی روستاها مطرح می&#8206;باشند. ماهیت خاص بافت&#8206;های شهری کهن، توجه به آنها را از جهات مختلفی ضروری می&#8206;سازد؛ لذا پژوهش حاضر سعی دارد راهکارهایی در راستای اصلاح و ساماندهی بافت فرسوده محله شهیدگاه واقع در شهر اردبیل ارائه نماید و نیز درصدد است تا برنامه&#8204;ریزی و طراحی، مطابق با وضع موجود محله و متناسب با اولویت&#8206;های راهبردی باشد. در همین راستا با بهره&#8206;گیری از بررسی اسنادی و کتابخانه&#8206;ای و همچنین مطالعات میدانی، وضع موجود محله مذکور، ارزیابی شد و با استفاده از ماتریس تحلیلی SOWT به جمع&#8206;بندی مطالعات وضع موجود و ارائه راهبردهای ساماندهی و طراحی، اقدام شده است. در ادامه با کمّی کردن مدل راهبردی به کار رفته، راهبردهای اولویت&#8206;دار ساماندهی، تعیین و استخراج گردیده&#8206;اند. نهایتاً در بخش ارائه گزینه&#8206;های طراحی در محدوده، پنج گزینه متناسب با شرایط محله مورد مطالعه، ارائه و مبتنی بر اولویت&#8206;های راهبردی، بررسی و ارزیابی شدند که در گزینه برتر طراحی، سعی شده است با ساماندهی و از میان برداشتن بناهای مخروبه در بخش میانی محدوده، یک محصوریت، ایجاد و با یک طرح مناسب به سمت بقعه سوق داده شود و از فضای میانی نیز برای ایجاد مرکز محله استفاده گردد.&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Currently, old textures are one of the main problems in many cities and even villages in our country. The specific feature of these textures makes it necessary to be considered from different aspects. This study is trying to find strategies to improve and organize old texture in the Shahidgah neighborhood of Ardabil. It also aims to plan and design in accordance with the existing status and consistent with strategic priorities. In this regard, using review of documents and field surveys, existing status of the neighborhood were evaluated using SWOT analysis and planning strategies. Continuing with the quantitative models used, organizing strategies are prioritized. Finally, five design alternatives presented in accordance with texture requirements. Findings indicate that the organizing of the studied area should adopt a systematic approach for 4 dimensions of physical, economic, social and environmental interventions to deal with. The preferred alternative has tried to organize and remove the ruined buildings in the middle of the area, a closeness be created and the central space is used to create a neighborhood center.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>39</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>62</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>نادر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>زالی</Family>
				<NameE>Nader</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Zaali</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>University of Gilan, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مجید</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>زارعی</Family>
				<NameE>Majid</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Zareie</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Imam Khomeini International University, Qazvin, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سامان</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>ابی‌زاده</Family>
				<NameE>Saman</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ebizadeh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Islamic Art University of Tabriz, Tabriz, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>فرشید</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>هاشم‌زاده قلعه‌جوق</Family>
				<NameE>Farshid</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Hashemzadeh Ghalehjogh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>University of Gilan, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Organizing</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>old texture</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Strategic Planning</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>SWOT</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Shahidgah neighborhood</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Ardabil</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ساماندهی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بافت فرسوده</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>برنامه‌ریزی راهبردی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>SWOT</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>محله شهیدگاه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شهر اردبیل</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##ابراهیم‎زاده، عیسی؛ ملکی، گل‎آفرین. (1391). تحلیلی بر ساماندهی و مداخله در بافت‎های فرسوده شهری (مطالعه موردی: بافت فرسوده شهر خرم‎آباد)، پژوهش‌های جغرافیای انسانی، شماره 81.##ادیبی سعدی‌نژاد، فاطمه. (1389). مفهوم بافت فرسوده و ویژگی‎های آن، ماهنامه اطلاع‌رسانی، آموزشی و پژوهشی، شماره 54. ##ایزدی، حسن؛ شیخ‎ها، معصومه. (1387). بررسی نقش سیاست‌های حمایتی و تشویقی دولت در نوسازی بافت‎های فرسوده شهری_ نمونه موردی بافت قدیم شهر شیراز، اولین همایش بهسازی و نوسازی بافت فرسوده شهری، مشهد.##برزگر، زهرا. (1391). شهرنشینی و تأثیرات آن بر امنیت غذا، آب و انرژی در ایران؛ نمونه موردی: شهر شیراز، فصلنامه علمی- تخصصی برنامه‌ریزی منطقه‌ای، 2(5).##برک‌پور، ناصر؛ بهرامی، صدیقه. (1390). قابلیت‌سنجی توسعه مجدد در بافت‎های ناکارآمد شهری (مطالعه موردی: محله انبار نفت منطقه 11 تهران)، فصلنامه شهر ایرانی اسلامی، 1(4).##جهان‎شاهی، محمدحسین. (1382). تحلیل بافت‎های فرسوده و مشکل‎ساز شهری و راهبردهای آن، مجله جستارهای شهرسازی، شماره 5.##حسینی، علی؛ پوراحمد، احمد؛ حاتمی‌نژاد، حسین؛ رضایی‌نیا، حسن. (1392). راهبردهای ساماندهی بافت فرسوده محله قیطریه با استفاده از روش QSPM، مجله باغ نظر، 10(24)، 79-90.##خانی، علی. (1389). ملاحظاتی چند درخصوص شبکه دسترسی و نوسازی بافت‌های فرسوده شهری، نشریه اینترنتی سازمان نوسازی، 2(8).##دویران، اسماعیل؛ مشکینی، ابوالفضل؛ غلامرضا، کاظمیان؛ علی‌آبادی، زینب. (1391). بررسی مداخله در ساماندهی بافت‎های فرسوده و ناکارآمد شهری با رویکرد ترکیبی، نمونه موردی: محله زینبیه زنجان، مجله پژوهش و برنامه‌ریزی شهری، 2(7).##رفیعیان، محسن؛ بمانیان، محمدرضا؛ مجتبی، رفیعیان. (1389). شناسایی پهنه‌های زمینه‌ساز توسعه خلاق بافت‎های فرسوده با رویکرد گردشگری در برنامه‌ریزی شهری؛ نمونه موردی محله امامزاده یحیی، ناحیه 2، منطقه 12 شهرداری تهران، دوفصلنامه مدیریت شهری، شماره 25.##زنگنه، یعقوب؛ فرهادی، جواد؛ توبی. وجیه. (1392). تبیین و اولویت‌بندی مداخله در بافت‌های فرسوده شهری با استفاده از روش AHP  نمونه موردی: مشهد، محله نوغان (قطاع 2)،  فصلنامه پژوهش و برنامه‌ریزی شهری، 4(12).##زیویار، پروانه. (1389). مدیریت بحران در بافت‎های فرسوده شهری با تأکید بر تأسیسات شهری، ماهنامه اطلاع‎رسانی، آموزشی و پژوهشی، شماره 54.##سرور، رحیم. (1390). بررسی ظرفیت‌های بافت فرسوده و توانمندسازی آن (مطالعه موردی: شهر بافق). فصلنامه جغرافیا، 9(31).##عباسی، هادی؛ رضوی، روح‎الله. (1385). طراحی مدل مفهومی اقتصادی برای احیا و بازسازی بافت‎های فرسوده، دومین سمینار ساخت‌وساز در پایتخت، پردیس دانشکده‎های فنی دانشگاه تهران.##عربی، عباس؛ انتظار یزدی، حسن. (1387). بررسی شیوه‎های مداخله در بافت‎های فرسوده شهری و ارائه مدل بهینه مداخله، اولین همایش بهسازی و نوسازی بافت‌های فرسوده شهری.##عزیزی، محمدمهدی. (1379). سیر تحول سیاست‌های مداخله در بافت‌های کهن شهری در ایران، نشریه هنرهای زیبا، شماره 7.##فرجی ملائی، امین. (1389). انواع روش‎های مداخله در بهسازی و نوسازی شهری، ماهنامه اطلاع رسانی، آموزشی و پژوهشی، شماره 54.##فرشیدی، حسین. (1389). رهگیری شیوه‌های مداخله دولت در بافت‎های فرسوده شهری، ماهنامه اطلاع‎رسانی، آموزشی و پژوهشی، شماره 54.##فیروزی، محمدعلی؛ سجادیان، ناهید؛ صحرایی، نسا. (1391). ساماندهی بافت‎های فرسوده در راستای توسعه درون‌زا و پایدار شهری (مطالعه موردی: کوی یوسفی اهواز)، فصلنامه جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی شهری چشم‎انداز زاگرس، 4(13).##کول‌آبادی، فریده. (1387). بازسازی و احیاء در بافت‎های فرسوده شهری، اولین همایش بهسازی و نوسازی بافت‌های فرسوده شهری.##لطفی، صدیقه؛ ملکشاهی، غلامرضا؛ مهدوی، مهدیه. (1389). برنامه‌ریزی راهبردی به منظور بهسازی بافت‌های فرسوده شهری- نمونه موردی شهر بابل، فصلنامه علمی- پژوهشی جغرافیای انسانی، 3(1).##ماجدی، حمید. (1389). توسعه‎های شهری امروز، بافت‎های فرسوده آینده، نشریه هویت شهر، 4(6).##محمدی، جمال؛ شفقی، سیروس؛ نوری، محمد. (1393). تحلیل ساختار فضایی-کالبدی بافت فرسوده شهری با رویکرد نوسازی و بهسازی (مطالعه موردی: بافت فرسوده شهر دوگنبدان)، مجله علمی-پژوهشی برنامه‌ریزی فضایی (جغرافیا)، 4(2).##محمدی، علیرضا؛ نوذری، کمال. (1387). حوزه‎های بهبود: رویکردی در بهسازی نواحی فرسوده شهری؛ موردپژوهی: محله سردزک شهر شیراز، سیزدهمین همایش سیاست‌های توسعه مسکن در ایران.##مطوف، شریف؛ خدایی، زهرا. (1388). الگوهای رونق‎بخشی، نوسازی و بهسازی بافت‎های فرسوده شهری، فصلنامه مطالعات مدیریت شهری، 1(3).##منوچهری، ایوب. (1389). تحلیلی بر مداخله در بافت‎های فرسوده شهری، ماهنامه اطلاع رسانی، آموزشی و پژوهشی، شماره 54.##ناظری، شیفته؛ روحی کلاش، حمید. (1387). بهسازی و نوسازی بافت‎های فرسوده شهری (تبدیل تهدیدها به فرصت‌ها)، مجله فضای جغرافیایی، 8(21).##نسترن، مهین؛ هوشمندفر، سپیده. (1389). برنامه‌ریزی استراتژیک جهت ساماندهی قسمتی از بافت فرسوده شهر ارومیه، فصلنامه جغرافیا و مطالعات محیطی، 1(3).##وارثی، حمیدرضا؛ تقوایی، مسعود؛ رضایی، نعمت‎الله. (1391). ساماندهی بافت فرسوده، نمونه: شهر شیراز، مجله تخصصی برنامه‌ریزی فضایی، 2(2(6)).##Butala, N. M., VanRooyen, M. J., Patel, R. B. (2010). Improved health outcomes in urban slums through infrastructure upgrading. Social science &amp; medicine, 71(5), 935-940.##Chang, H., Wen-Chin. H. (2006). Application of a quantification SWOT analytical method, Mathematical and computer 43, 158-169.##Hao, P., Sliuzas, R., Geertman, S. (2011). The development and redevelopment of urban villages in Shenzhen. Habitat International, 35(2), 214-224.## Mohammad Pur, M., Alam Tabriz, A. (2012). SWOT analysis using of modified fuzzy QFD–a Case study for strategy formulation in Petrokaran film factory. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 41, 322-333.##Rasoolimanesh, S. M., Jaafar, M., Badarulzaman, N. (2014). Examining the contributing factors for the successful implementation of city development strategy in Qazvin City, Iran. Cities, 41, 10-19.##Shahabi, R. S., Basiri, M. H., Kahag, M. R., Zonouzi, S. A. (2014). An ANP–SWOT approach for interdependency analysis and prioritizing the Iran׳ s steel scrap industry strategies. Resources Policy, 42, 18-26.##Shariatmadari, M., Sarfaraz, A. H., Hedayat, P., Vadoudi, K. (2013). Using SWOT analysis and SEM to prioritize strategies in Foreign exchange market in Iran. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 99, 886-892.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تحلیل تأثیرات اقتصادی- اجتماعی موزه ملی فرش تبریز</TitleF>
		<TitleE>An Analysis of Socio-Economic Impacts of National Carpet Museum of Tabriz</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>تحقیق پیش&#8204;رو با هدف شناسایی تأثیرات اجرای پروژه کاخ موزه فرش تبریز، از ابعاد مختلفی، به&#8206;ویژه از بعد اقتصادی و اجتماعی بر گروه&#8206;های مختلف شهروندان و اجتماع محلی انجام شده است. در این ارزیابی سعی شده ارزش ذاتی، ابزاری و نهادی این موزه در قالب اثرات اجتماعی و اقتصادی بررسی شود. این تحقیق با استفاده از رویکرد ترکیبی تکنوکراتیک و مشارکتی، نگاشته شده است که نتایج هر دو روش به اشکال کمی و کیفی در بخش یافته&#8204;های تحقیق، نتیجه&#8206;گیری و مدیریت پیامدها ذکر شده&#8206;اند. تحقیق حاضر به روش پیمایشی انجام شده و حجم نمونه 142 نفر می&#8204;باشد که پاسخگویان را ساکنین و کسبه محل، عابرین و متخصصین حوزه فرش و مدیریت شهری تشکیل داده&#8206;اند. انتخاب مصاحبه&#8206;شوندگان به صورت تصادفی و هدفمند بوده؛ به این صورت که ساکنین محل و عابران به صورت تصادفی ساده، کسبه و متخصصین به&#8206;صورت هدفمند، انتخاب شدند. نتایج تحقیق بیانگر توافق نسبی بین نظرات عموم مردم و افراد متخصص در زمینه اثرات اجتماعی، انسانی و اقتصادی طرح می&#8204;باشد. یافته&#8204;ها نشان می&#8204;دهند که ایجاد کاخ موزه فرش تبریز به لحاظ اقتصادی می&#8204;تواند اثرات مثبتی از قبیل: اشتغال&#8206;زایی، ایجاد زمینه سرمایه&#8206;گذاری، رونق اقتصادی محل و نتایج مثبت اجتماعی از قبیل: توسعه تعاملات اجتماعی عمومی و متخصصین با یکدیگر، افزایش دانش و اطلاعات مردم نسبت به صنعت فرش داشته باشد. از اثرات منفی این طرح نیز می&#8204;توان به ایجاد شلوغی، ترافیک و سلب آسایش ساکنین محل و به هم خوردن بافت همگون اجتماعی محله اشاره نمود.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>This research has been done to identify the impacts of implementing the project of carpet museum of Tabriz from different aspects particularly economic and social dimensions on various groups of citizens and local society. It has been tried to study intrinsic, instrumental, and institutional values of this museum in the form of social and economic impacts. Combined approach of participatory and technocratic has been used and the results of both methods have been listed in research findings, conclusion, and management of consequences. Survey method has been used. 142 people are sample including inhabitants, salespersons, passengers, and experts in the field of carpet and urban management. Respondents were selected both randomly and purposefully so that inhabitants and passengers were selected randomly and salespersons and experts were chosen purposefully. The results indicate relative agreement between people&#8217;s ideas and experts&#8217; about social, economic, and human impacts of the project. The findings show that building this museum may have positive impacts including employment, preparing the ground for investment, economic boom of the area, and socially positive results such as development of social interactions of ordinary people and experts together, and increasing people&#8217;s knowledge about carpet industry. Crowd, traffic, discomfort for residents, and disruption of the social homogeneous texture of the neighborhood can be noted as negative impacts.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>63</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>76</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>کسری</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رهبری‌پور</Family>
				<NameE>Kasra</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rahbaripoor</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Islamic Azad University, Tabriz branch, Tabriz, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسن</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>ستاری ساربانقلی</Family>
				<NameE>Hassan</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Sattari Sarebangholi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Islamic Azad University, Tabriz branch, Tabriz, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>رسول</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>درسخوان</Family>
				<NameE>Rasool</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Darskhan</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Islamic Azad University, Tabriz branch, Tabriz, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>museum</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>assessment of social impact</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>intrinsic value</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>instrumental value</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>institutional value</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>موزه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ارزیابی اثر اجتماعی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ارزش ذاتی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ارزش ابزاری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ارزش نهادی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##آیت‎الله‎زاده شیرازی، باقر. (1371). سیمای موزه‌های کشور، نشریه موزه‎ها، شماره12، سازمان میراث فرهنگی، تهران.##اشرفی، مهناز. (1389). بررسی مقایسه‎ای مفهوم اکوموزه با موزه‌های سنتی، فصلنامه نامه معماری و شهرسازی، شماره4، 75-61.##جواهری، محمدرضا. (1383). موزه‌ها و کارکردهای امروز و آتی. نشریه موزه‌ها، شماره 40.##علی قریب، عباس. (1386). از باغ ایرانی دیروز تا معماری نوین امروز؛ طرح رتبه پنجم مسابقه طراحی مرکز تجاری فرش تبریز، فصلنامه معماری و ساختمان، شماره 13، 75-70.##مرصوصی، نفیسه؛ خانی، محمدباقر. (1390). تحلیل کارکردهای اقتصادی بازار تبریز و حوزه نفوذ آن، فصلنامه پژوهش‌های جغرافیای انسانی، 43(75)، 152-133. ##Appleton, J. (2001). Museum for the People (Conversation in Print).##Barrow, C. J. (2000). Social impact assessment: an introduction. Oxford University Press.##Bedate, A. M., Herrero, L. C., Sanz, J. A. (2009). Economic valuation of a contemporary art museum: correction of hypothetical bias using a certainty question. Journal of Cultural Economics, 33(3), 185-199.##Black, G. (2005). The Engaging Museum London. Oxford, UK: Routledge.##Butler, B. (2007). Return to Alexandria: an ethnography of cultural heritage revivalism and museum memory. Left Coast Press.##Culture Heritage Consortium. (2002). Impact Evaluation of Museums, Archives and Libraries: Quantitative Time Series Data Identification Exercise. London: Resource: The Council of Museums, Archives and Libraries.##Esteves, A. M., Franks, D., Vanclay, F. (2012). Social impact assessment: the state of the art. Impact Assessment and Project Appraisal,30(1), 34-42.##Fenton, M. (2005). Guidebook on social impact assessment. NEW SOUTH WALES DEPARTEMENT OF PLANNING (ed.). Townsville, Queensland.##Foster, S. (2006). The city as an ecological space: social capital and urban land use. Notre Dame law review, 82(2).##Frateschi, C. F., Lazzaro, E. (2009). A comparative econometric analysis of museum attendance by locals and foreigners: The cases of Padua and Seville. Estudios de economía aplicada, 27(1), 177-198.##Frey, B. S., Steiner, L. (2012). Pay as you go: a new proposal for museum pricing. Museum Management and Curatorship, 27(3), 223-235.##Garnett, R. (2002). The impact of science centers/museums on their surrounding communities: summary report. Washington, DC: Association of science-technology centers. Accessed September, 30, 2012.##Hartz-Karp, J., Pope, J. (2011). 15. Enhancing effectiveness through deliberative democracy. New Directions in Social Impact Assessment: Conceptual and Methodological Advances, 253.##Holden, J. (2013). How We Value Arts and Culture, in Mickov B., Doyle J. (edited by), Sustaining Cultural Development. Unified Systems and New Governance in Cultural Life, Gower Publishing Limited.##Hooper-Greenhill, E. (2007). Museums and education: Purpose, pedagogy, performance. Routledge.##ICOM. (2007). Declaration of the International Council of Museums (ICOM) and the World Federation of Friends of Museums (WFFM) for worldwide Sustainable Cultural Tourism. Paris: The International Council of Museums.##Kimble, G. (2014). Children learning about biodiversity at an environment centre, a museum and at live animal shows. Studies in Educational Evaluation, 41, 48-57.##Lampi, E., Orth, M. (2009). Who visits the museums? A comparison between stated preferences and observed effects of entrance fees. Kyklos,62(1), 85-102.##Macfarlane, M. (1999). An Evaluation of Social Impact Assessment Methodologies in the Mining Industry. University of Bath.##Message, K. (2006). The New Museum, Theory, Culture &amp; Society; 23(2-3). 603.##Mozaffary, A. (2007). Modernity and identity: The National Museum of Iran. In S. J. Knell, S. MacLeod, &amp; S. Watson (Eds.), Museum revolutions: How museums change and are changed (pp. 87–104). London: Routledge.##Parry, R., Burton, J.K. (2010). Museums in a Digital Age, London: Routledge.##Piekkola, H., Soujanen, O., Vainio, A. (2014). Economic impact of museums. University of Vaasa LEVON INSTITUTE. ##Plaza, B. (2010). Valuing museums as economic engines: Willingness to pay or discounting of cash-flows?. Journal of Cultural Heritage, 11(2), 155–162.##Plaza, B., Haarich, S. (2009). Museums for urban regeneration? Exploring conditions for their effectiveness. Journal of Urban Regeneration &amp; Renewal,2(3), 259-271.##Rodríguez, J. P., Blanco, V. M. F. (2002). Optimal pricing and grant policies for museums. Papeles de trabajo del Instituto de Estudios Fiscales. Serie economía, (3), 3-22.##Schrijvershop, C. (2007). Do (not) blame the price: A quantitative analysis of the different determinants of the museum demand, MA Thesis, Erasmus University Rotterdam.##Scott, C.A. (2006). Museums, impact and value. Cultural Trends, 15(57), 45-75.##Selwood, S. (2010). Making a difference: the Cultural Impact of Museums, National Museum Directors’Conference(NMDC); http://www.nationalmuseums.org.uk/media/documents/publications/cultural_impact_final.pdf##Throsby, D. (2006). The value of cultural heritage: What can economics tell us?.##Tuck, F. (2015). The Economic Impact of Museums in England. Economic research &amp; business intelligence.##Van Aalst, I., Boogaarts, I. (2002). From museum to mass entertainment the evolution of the role of museums in cities. European Urban and Regional Studies, 9(3), 195-209.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تحلیلی بر قیمت زمین شهری در استان‎های ایران طی سال‌های 1390-1380</TitleF>
		<TitleE>An Analysis on the Price of Urban Land in Iran’s Provinces during 2001 to 2011</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>توجه به زمین، به عنوان یک منبع اصلی و تجدیدناپذیر در توسعه پایدار شهری، امری ضروری است؛ زیرا زمین، جزء منابع اصلی توسعه پایدار شهری تلقی می&#8204;شود. هدف این پژوهش، تحلیلی بر قیمت زمین شهری در استان&#8206;های مختلف ایران طی سال&#8204;های 90-1380 می&#8204;باشد. روش تحقیق این پژوهش، اسنادی است و از تکنینک کتابخانه&#8207;ای برای گردآوری اطلاعات استفاده شده است و نرم&#8207;افزارهای GIS, GeoDa, PASW برای تحلیل اطلاعات به کار رفته&#8204;اند. یافته&#8207;های پژوهش، بیانگر توزیع تصادفی قیمت زمین شهری طی سال&#8204;های 90-1380 در استان&#8206;های مختلف ایران می&#8206;باشند و براساس آزمون رگرسیون همزمان مشخص شد که بین متغیرهای درصد شهرنشینی و متوسط مساحت زمین ساختمان&#8204;های شهری با قیمت زمین شهری در سال 1380، رابطه معناداری وجود نداشته است؛ ولی در سال&#8204;های 1385 و 1390 بین این متغیرها رابطه معناداری وجود دارد. همچنین بین سطح توسعه استان&#8206;ها و قیمت زمین شهری در سال 1390 در برخی استان&#8206;ها در سطح 95 درصد، رابطه معناداری وجود داشته است. پس از بررسی روند تغییرات متوسط قیمت زمین شهری در استان&#8206;های ایران طی سال&#8204;های 90-1380 مشخص گردید که متوسط ضریب تغییرات قیمت زمین شهری در کل کشور، برابر با 828/73 درصد بوده است و استان&#8206;های بوشهر، خراسان رضوی و همدان، به ترتیب دارای بالاترین ضریب تغییرات بوده&#8206;اند و استان&#8206;های کردستان، هرمزگان و خوزستان نیز به ترتیب دارای کمترین ضریب تغییرات بوده&#8206;اند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Attention to land, as one of the principal and renewable sources in urban sustainable development, is a necessary task since it is considered as one of the main sources of urban sustainable development. The purpose of this research is an analysis on the price of urban land in different provinces of Iran during 2001 to 2011. The research method is documentary and library techinque was used for data collection. PASW, GeoDa, and GIS soft wares were used for data analysis. Research findings indicate random distribution of urban land price during 2001 to 2011 in different provinces. According to Enter regression test, it was specified that there is no significant relationship between the variables of urbanization percentage and the average of land area of urban buildings with the price of urban land in 2001, but there was a significant relationship between these variables in 2006 and 2011. However, there is a significant relationship between development level of provinces and the price of urban land in 2011 in some provinces at the level of 95 percent. After studying the changes in the average price of urban land of Iran&#8217;s provinces during 2001 to 2011, it was specified that the average coefficient of variation of urban land price was equal to 827.73 and Bushehr, Khorasan Razavi, and Hamedan provinces had the highest coefficient of variation and Kordestan, Hormozgan, and Khuzestan provinces had the least.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>77</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>99</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>قنبری</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ghanbari</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Mashhad, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>اجزاء شکوهی</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ajza Shokuhi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمدرحیم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رهنما</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad Rahim</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rahnama</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>امیدعلی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>خوارزمی</Family>
				<NameE>Omid Ali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Kharazmi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>price of urban land</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>urbanization</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>province</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>area</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Iran</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>قیمت زمین شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شهرنشینی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>استان</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مساحت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ایران</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##استیگ، اینمارک. (1386). سیستم‌های ثبت، زیرساخت اجرای سیاست‌های زمین، ترجمه روح‎اله رضوی، مجموعه مقالات مرکز مطالعات تکنولوژی دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران، تهران.##باستیه، ژان؛ دزر، برنارد. (۱۳۷۷). شهر. ترجمه عماد اشرفی، تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه هنر.##بانک مرکزی جمهوری اسلامی ایران. (۱۳۹۱).##بحرینی، سیدحسین. (۱۳۸۶). فرایند طراحی شهری، تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه تهران.##پیله‎ور، علی‏اصغر؛ افراخته، حسن؛ کریمی‏پور، یدالله، سلیمانی، محمد؛ قهرودی، منیژه. (1390). بررسی تأثیر تصمیمات سیاسی بر ناپایداری و تحولات ساختاری زمین و مسکن شهری ناشی از رویکرد سیاسی: مورد بجنورد، مجله جغرافیا و توسعه، شماره 23، زاهدان.##حکمت‎نیا، حسن. (۱۳۸۹). برنامه‎ریزی کاربری اراضی شهر بهاباد با استفاده از الگوی تحلیل SWOT، فصلنامه مطالعات شهر ایرانی اسلامی، 1(2).##حیاتی، سلمان. (1391). تحلیل شاخص‌های رشد هوشمند شهری در مشهد، پایان‎نامه کارشناسی‌ارشد جغرافیا و برنامه‎ریزی شهری، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.##دلال‌پورمحمدی، محمدرضا. (1385). برنامه‌ریزی مسکن، تهران: انتشارات سمت.##رضویان، محمدتقی. (1381). برنامه‌ریزی کاربری اراضی شهری، تهران: انتشارات منشی.##رهنما، محمدرحیم؛ ذبیحی، جواد. (1390). تحلیل توزیع تسهیلات عمومی شهری در راستای عدالت فضایی با مدل یکپارچه دسترسی در مشهد، مجله جغرافیا و توسعه، 9(23).##زنگنه، یعقوب. (1388). درآمدی بر اقتصاد شهری، سبزوار: انتشارات دانشگاه تربیت معلم سبزوار.##شابیر چیما، جی. (1379). مدیریت شهر، ترجمه پرویز زاهدی، تهران: انتشارات شرکت پردازش و برنامه‎ریزی شهری.##شمس، مجید؛ پالیزبان، سیاوش. (1389). بررسی تأثیر سیاست‌های اقتصادی مبتنی بر درآمد نفت بر بازار مسکن در ایران، فصلنامه جغرافیای انسانی، 3(1).##صادقیان، سعید. (1379). سیستم اطلاعات زمینی ابزار مدیریت توسعه شهری، همایش زمین و توسعه شهری، مرکز مطالعات و تحقیقات شهرسازی و معماری وزارت مسکن و شهرسازی، تهران.##صمدی، رضا. (1391). تحلیل و مد‌‌ل‌سازی نقش بازار زمین شهری در توسعه فضایی- مکانی شهر مورد منطقه سه شهر مشهد، پایان‎نامه کارشناسی‌ارشد جغرافیا و برنامه‎ریزی شهری، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه گلستان.##عابدین درکوش، سعید. (1389). درآمدی به اقتصاد شهری، تهران: انتشارات مرکز نشر دانشگاهی.##فرجی، یوسف. (1380). تئوری اقتصاد خرد، تهران: شرکت نشر و چاپ بازرگانی.##مجتهدزاده، غلامحسین. (1386). برنامه‏ریزی شهری در ایران، تهران: انتشارات پیام‏نور.##محمودی‎نژاد، هادی. (1385). جستاری بر رویکرد توسعه پایدار در مقوله زمین شهری با تأکید بر مالکیت و فرایند عرضه زمین، ماهنامه شمس.##مرآت‌نیا، منصوره. (1379). رانت اقتصادی (بهره مالکانه) در طرح‌های توسعه شهری، دوفصلنامه مدیریت و برنامه‎ریزی شهری، 1(1).##مهرایی، محمد؛ مهارتی، یعقوب. (1391).  تأثیر اتخاذ مالیات بر ارزش زمین به عنوان منبع درآمدی پایدار بر اقتصاد مسکن شهری، چهارمین کنفرانس برنامه‎ریزی و مدیریت شهری، مشهد.##میرکتولی، جعفر. (1389). مقدمه‎ای بر برنامه‎ریزی عرضه زمین شهری، گرگان: انتشارات دانشگاه علوم کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی.##میرکتولی، جعفر؛ مدانلو جویباری، مسعود؛ صمدی، رضا. (1391). بررسی نقش بنگاه‎های معاملات ملکی در توسعه زمین شهری مطالعه موردی: شهر گرگان، فصلنامه نگرش‎های نو در جغرافیای انسانی، 4(4).##میلز، ادوین؛ همیلتون، بروس. (1375).  اقتصاد شهر، ترجمه عبدالله کوثری، تهران: مرکز مطالعات و تحقیقات شهرسازی و معماری ایران.##وزارت کشور. (1391).##هادیلی، بهمن؛ مهرزاد، جمال. (1388). نقش زمین و مسکن در توسعه فضایی ـ کالبدی شهر تبریز، مجله فضای جغرافیایی، 9(26).##Agunbiade, M. E., Rajabifard, A., Bennett, R. (2014). Land administration for housing production: An approach for assessment. Land Use Policy, 38, 366-377.##El Araby, M. M. (2003). The role of the state in managing urban land supply and prices in Egypt. Habitat International, 27(3), 429-458.##Herington, J. (1984). The outer city, Harper and Row publishers, London.##Taha, M. M. (2001). The Potential Role of GIS in the Development and Applications of Urban Indicators: The Case of Housing in Khartoum, Sudan. Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, Royal Inst. of Technology.##Van der Molen, P. (2002). The dynamic aspect of land administration: an often-forgotten component in system design. Computers, Environment and Urban Systems, 26(5), 361-381.##Yazgı, B., Dökmeci, V. (2007). Analysis of Housing Prices In The Metropolitan Area Of Istanbul.##www.amar.org.ir. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تعیین علیت غیرخطی بین حمل‌ونقل زمینی شهری و غیرشهری و رشد اقتصادی با روش شبکه عصبی موجک (مطالعه موردی: ایران)</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Determining Non-Linear Causality between Urban and Non-Urban Ground Transport and Economic Growth Using Wavelet Neural Network (Case Study: Iran)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>در چند دهه اخیر، ارتباط بین زیرساخت&#8206;های اقتصادی و به ویژه بخش حمل&#8204;ونقل با رشد اقتصادی، موضوع مطالعه بسیاری از پژوهشگران در اقتصادهای مختلف بوده است. کشور ایران با توجه به موقعیت ویژه جغرافیایی، به لحاظ امکانات حمل&#8204;ونقل، دارای مزایای بسیاری است و پل ارتباطی بسیاری از کشورها می&#8206;باشد. در این مطالعه با استفاده از داده&#8206;های فصلی طی دوره 91-1371، رابطه بین حمل&#8204;ونقل زمینی، رشد اقتصادی، تشکیل سرمایه و نیروی کار، بررسی شد. اطلاعات موردنیاز، از آمارهای بانک مرکزی جمهوری اسلامی ایران و سالنامه&#8206;های آماری مرکز آمار، استخراج شدند. مهم&#8204;ترین تفاوت این مطالعه نسبت به سایر مطالعات پیشین، استفاده از روش شبکه عصبی موجک و رویکرد غیرخطی در تبیین ارتباط بین متغیرهای مورد بحث می&#8206;باشد. نتایج آزمون رابطه علّیت بین متغیرها حاکی از وجود رابطه علّیت از حمل&#8204;ونقل زمینی به رشد اقتصادی می&#8206;باشند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>In the last few decades, the relationship between economic infrastructures, particularly transport sector, and economic growth has been the subject of many reserachers in different economies. Iran has many advantages considering particular geographic situation in terms of transport facilities as it connects many countries. In this study, the relationship among ground transport, economic growth, capital formation , and work force was examined by using quarterly data during 1992 to 2012. Required data were extracted from the statistics of Centeral Bank of Islamic Republic of Iran and yearbooks of Statistical Center of Iran. The most important difference of this study compared to other previous studies is using wavelet neural network method and non-linear approach in explaining the relationship among discussed variables. The results of causal relationship test between variables imply the existence of causality from ground transport to economic growth.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>101</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>113</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی حسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>صمدی</Family>
				<NameE>Ali Hosein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Samadi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Economics, University of Shiraz, Shiraz, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>جعفر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>قادری</Family>
				<NameE>Jafar</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Qaderi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Economics, University of shiraz, shiraz, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>زهور</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>نژاد حلافی</Family>
				<NameE>Zahoor</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Nejadhalafi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Economics, University of shiraz, shiraz, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>economic growth</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>transport</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>neural network</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>causality</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Iran</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>رشد اقتصادی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>حمل‌ونقل</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شبکه عصبی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>علّیت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>کشور ایران</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##بابازاده، محمد؛ قدیمی، خلیل؛ محسنی، رضا. (1387). تأثیر سرمایه‎گذاری در بخش حمل‌ونقل و رشد اقتصادی در ایران، فصلنامه پژوهشنامه بازرگانی، 13(50)، 199-157.##رضایی ارجرودی، عبدالرضا؛ تسبیحی، آمنه. (1387). تعیین رابطه ریاضی بین توسعه حمل‌ونقل و رشد اقتصادی در کشور، چهارمین کنگره ملی مهندسی عمران، دانشگاه تهران.##سلیمانی‌کیا، فاطمه. (1386). الگوسازی و پیش‌بینی قیمت بنزین در بورس سنگاپور با استفاده از شبکه عصبی از نوع GMDH براساس الگوریتم ژنتیک، پایان‏نامه کارشناسی ارشد، رشته اقتصاد انرژی، دانشگاه تهران.##مهرگان، نادر؛ دهقانی احمدآباد، هانی. (1389). تخمین اثر رشد اقتصادی بخش حمل‌ونقل بر توزیع درآمد در ایران. پژوهشنامه حمل‌ونقل، 7(4)، 374- 365.##نوری، مهدی. (1389). بررسی تجربی رابطه میان تورم و رشد بهره‌وری در اقتصاد ایران، پایان‎نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه تهران.##Aschauer, D. A. (1989). Public investment and productivity growth in the Group of Seven. Economic perspectives, 13(5), 17-25.##Banister, D., Berechman, Y. (2001). Transport investment and the promotion of economic growth. Journal of transport geography, 9(3), 209-218.##Berechman, Y. (2001). Transport Investment and Economic Development: Is there a Link?, Paper presented to the. In European Conference of Ministers of Transport, Round Table 119: Transport and Economic Development.##Devarajan, S., Swaroop, V., Heng-fu, Z. (1996). The Composition of Public Expenditure and Economic Growth. journal of Monetary Economics, 37, 313-344.##Easterly, W., Rebelo, S. (1993). Fiscal policy and economic growth. Journal of monetary economics, 32(3), 417-458.## Esfahani, H. S., Ramirez, M. T. (2003). Institutions, infrastructure and economic Growth. Journal of Development Economics, Vol. 70, 443- 477.##Fedderke, J. W., Perkins, P., Luiz, J. M. (2006). Infrastructural investment in long-run economic growth: South Africa 1875–2001. World development, 34(6), 1037-1059.##Haque, M. E., Kim, D. H. (2003). Public investment in transportation and communication and growth: a dynamic panel approach. University of Manchester, School of Economic Studies.##Miller, S. M., Russek, F. S. (1997). Fiscal structures and economic growth: international evidence. Economic Inquiry, 35(3).##Munnell, A. H. (1992). Policy watch: infrastructure investment and economic growth. The Journal of Economic Perspectives, 6(4), 189-198.##Phang, S. Y. (2003). Strategic development of airport and rail infrastructure: the case of Singapore. Transport Policy, 10(1), 27-33.##Pradhan, R. P., Bagchi, T. P. (2013). Effect of transportation infrastructure on economic growth in India: the VECM approach. Research in Transportation Economics, 38(1), 139-148.##Ramanathan, R. (2001). The long-run behaviour of transport performance in India: a cointegration approach. Transportation Research Part A: Policy and Practice, 35(4), 309-320.##Short, J., Kopp, A. (2005). Transport infrastructure: investment and planning. Policy and research aspects. Transport Policy, 12(4), 360-367.##Smell, K. A, Verhoef, E. T. (2007). The Economics of Urban Transportation. The edition  Published in the Taylor and Francis e-library.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>عوامل مؤثر بر برند شهری و اولویت‌بندی آنها از دیدگاه گردشگران بین‌المللی (مطالعه موردی: برج میلاد تهران)</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Effective Factors on Urban Brand and Their Prioritization from Perspective of International Tourists (Case Study: Tehran’s Milad Tower)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>گردشگری شهری، بخشی از بازار گردشگری بین&#8204;المللی است که بیشترین پتانسیل توسعه را در سال&#8204;های اخیر داشته است. در سال جاری میلادی (2015 ) تمایل گردشگران ورودی به بازدید از کشور ایران و جاذبه&#8204;های تاریخی، فرهنگی و نمادهای آن، به امری روبه رشد تبدیل شده است. شهر تهران، به&#8204;عنوان پایتخت ایران، مناسب&#8204;ترین گزینه مقصد گردشگری شهری برای گردشگران بین&#8204;المللی است و نمادهای جذاب شهری آن، نقش مهمی را در جذب این گردشگران داشته است؛ از این رو هدف اصلی این پژوهش، شناسایی و تعیین اولویت&#8204;بندی ابعاد برند برج میلاد تهران، از دیدگاه گردشگران بین&#8204;المللی است. این پژوهش از نوع توصیفی- پیمایشی و با هدف کاربردی، با استفاده از مطالعات اسنادی و تحقیقات میدانی است و برای جمع&#8204;آوری داده&#8204;ها، از ابزار پرسشنامه در بین گردشگران بین&#8204;المللی بازدیدکننده از برج میلاد تهران، در بازه زمانی مهرماه و آبان&#8204;ماه سال 1394 استفاده شده است. ابتدا پرسشنامه اولیه&#8204;ای به&#8204;صورت آزمایشی در بین یک گروه 30 نفر از گردشگران بین&#8204;المللی در برج میلاد توزیع گردید و اعتبار و پایایی پرسشنامه، تأیید شد، سپس پرسشنامه اصلاحی که شامل بیست مؤلفه بود در اختیار حجم نمونه 240 نفری که براساس روش نمونه&#8204;گیری در دسترس، انتخاب شده&#8204;اند، قرارگرفت. داده&#8204;ها با استفاده از آزمون فریدمن و نرم&#8204;افزار SPSS تجزیه&#8204;وتحلیل شدند. نتایج حاصل حاکی از آن بودند که از میان این شش بعد، بعد معروفیت نام برند، با میانگین رتبه&#8204;ای 98/4، به&#8204;عنوان مهم&#8204;ترین اولویت در انتخاب مکان مورد بازدید، بعد از دیدگاه گردشگران، مورد شناسایی قرار گرفت.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Urban tourism is a part of international tourism market having the most development potential in the recent years. In 2015, tourists&#8217; willingness to visit Iran and its historical and cultural attractions and symbols has been increased. Tehran, as the capital, is the most suitable alternative of urban tourism destination for international tourists. Its urban attractive symbols have had important role in this regard; therefore, the main purpose of this research is to identify and determine prioritization of Tehran Milad Tower brand aspects from perspective of international tourists. This research is descriptive-survey, with applied purpose, by using documentary and field studies. To collect data, questionnaire was used; it was distributed among international visitors of Tehran Milad Tower during September to November 2015. At first, primary questionnaire was distributed as pilot among a group of 30 international visitors of Milad Tower, and its validity and reliability were confirmed. Then, revised questionnaires, including 20 items, were distributed among 240 people as sample based on available sampling. Data were analyzed by using Friedman test and SPSS software. The results indicated that popularity of brand name, with the ranking average of 4.98, as the most important priority in choosing a visiting place, was identified from perspective of tourists.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>115</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>136</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>ناصر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>امینیان</Family>
				<NameE>Naser</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Aminian</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>University of Science and Culture, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>حسنی</Family>
				<NameE>Ali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Hassani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>University of Science and Culture, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>urban brand</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>aspects of urban brand</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>urban tourist</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Tehran Milad Tower</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>برند شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ابعاد برند شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>آزمون فریدمن</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>گردشگر شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>برج میلاد تهران</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##پورفرج، اکبر؛ تاج‎زاده نمین، ابوالفضل؛ علی پوریان‎زاده، راحیل. (1392). ارزش ویژه مشتری و رضایت‌مندی گردشگران داخلی از هتل‎های پنج ستاره شهر تهران، مطالعات گردشگری، شماره 21.##تاج‌زاده نمین، ابوالفضل؛ اسماعیل مشرفی، فاطمه. (1393). اولویت‌بندی مؤلفه‌های ارزش ویژه برند در مقصد گردشگری از دیدگاه گردشگران داخلی، فصلنامه مطالعات مدیریت گردشگری، 8(24).##تحلیلی بر نقش تصویر برند بر توسعه گردشگری، مطالعه موردی: کلان‌شهر تبریز، مجله پژوهش و برنامه‎ریزی شهری، 6(22).##حیدری چیانه، رحیم؛ صنوبر، ناصر؛ سعدلونیا، حسن. (1394).##دیواندری، علی؛ الهیاری، اشکان؛ براری، مجتبی. (1390). شناسایی و ارزیابی عوامل مؤثر بر تصویر سازمانی با رویکرد آمیخته، مجله چشم‎انداز مدیریت بازرگانی، شماره 39.##رنجبریان، بهرام؛ خزایی پول، جواد. (1392). توسعه مدلی جهت تبیین تأثیر سازه‎های بازاریابی مدیریت شهری بر تمایلات رفتاری نسبت به مقاصد گردشگری، فصلنامه اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری، 1(3).##ضرغام بروجنی، حمید؛ بارزانی، هلیا. (1392). آسیب‎شناسی برند گردشگری در ایران، تحقیقات بازاریابی نوین، 3(1).##کاتلر، فلیپ. (1385). مدیریت بازاریابی، ترجمه بهمن فروزنده، اصفهان: انتشارات آموخته.##کمانرودی، موسی. (1393). آسیب‎شناسی مدیریتی جهت‎گیری‎های برنامه‎ای و اجرایی هویت‎یابی و برندسازی شهری تهران، ششمین کنفرانس ملی برنامه‎ریزی و مدیریت شهری.##محمدپور زرندی، حسین؛ امینیان، ناصر. (1394). ارزیابی قابلیت‌های بازآفرینی پیاده‌راه‌های گردشگری از منظر توسعه پایدار شهری (مطالعه موردی: خیابان 15 خرداد تهران)، فصلنامه اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری، 3(11).##منوریان، عباس؛ ابوئی اردکان، محمد؛ پورموسوی، سیدموسی؛ رحیمیان، اشرف. (1392). مدل فرایندی برندسازی شهری برای کلانشهرهای ایران، چشم‌انداز مدیریت دولتی، شماره 13. ##موحد، علی. (1390). بازاریابی گردشگری برای شهر‌ها، تهران: نشر آذرخش.##نوربخش، سیدمرتضی؛ اکبرپور سراسکانرود، محمد. (1390). گزارشی پیرامون نقش مدیریت در فرایند تبدیل روستا به شهر در پیرامون کلان‌شهر تهران، اقتصاد شهر، شماره 12. ##همشهری آنلاین. (194).##Anholt, S. (2006). The Anholt-GMI city brands index: How the world sees the world's cities. Place Branding and Public Diplomacy, 2(1), 18-31. ##Avraham, E., Ketter, E. (2008). Media Strategies for Marketing Places in Crisis: Improving the Image of Cities, Countries, and Tourist Destinations. Butterworth Heinemann.##Balmer, J.M.T., Greyser, S.A. (2013). Revaling the Corporation. Routledge London,UK.##Bonn, M.A., joseph-mathews, S.M., dal, M,. Hayes, S., Cave, J. (2007). Heritage/ Cultural Attraction Atmospherics: Creating the Right Environment for the Heritage/ Cultural Visitor. Journal of Travel Research, vol. 45, 345-354.##Bradley, A., Hall, T., Harrison, M. (2002). Selling cities: promoting new images for meetings tourism. Cities, 19(1), 61-70.##Braun, E. (2008). City Marketing: Towards an integrated approach (No. EPS-2008-142-ORG).##Braun, E., Zenker, S. (2010). Towards an integrated approach for place brand management. In 50th European Regional Science Association Congress 19-23.##Cai, L. (2002). Cooperative branding for rural destinations. Annals of Tourism Research. 29(3), 720-742.## ##Chen, C. F., Tsai, D. (2007). How destination image and evaluative factors affect behavioral intentions?. Tourism management, 28(4), 1115-1122.##Decline, J. (2010).A Shared Vision on City BrandinginEurope.http://www.eurocities.eu.##Dinnie, K. (2011). City branding: theory and cases. Palgrave macmillan.##Fernández, D. B., Meethan, K. (2014). The Relationship of City Branding and Tourist Promotion: The Case of Plymouth (UK) and Malaga (Spain), Athens Journal of Tourism, 1(3).##Hall, C. M. (2002). Tourism in capital cities. Tourism: An International Interdisciplinary Journal, 50(3), 235-248.##Hankinson, G., Cowking, P. (1993). Branding in action: cases and strategies for profitable brand management. McGraw-Hill Book Company Limited.##Judd, D.R., Faintein, S. (2014). The TOURIST CITY. New Haven: Yale University Press.##Kavaratzis, M., Ashworth, G. J. (2005). City branding: an effective assertion of identity or a transitory marketing trick?. Tijdschrift voor economische en sociale geografie, 96(5), 506-514. ##Lamza–Maronić, M., Glavaš, J., Mavrin, I. (2009). Potentials of Osijek as a Centre of Cultural Tourism. Interdisciplinary Management Research V/Barković, Dražen, 711-721.##Lian Chan, J. K., Baum, T. (2007). Ecotourists' perception of ecotourism experience in Lower Kinabatangan, Sabah, Malaysia. Journal of Sustainable Tourism, 15(5), 574-590.##Munda, G. (2009). A conflict analysis approach for illuminating distributional issues in sustainability policy. European Journal of Operational Research, 194(1), 307-322.##Nasution, H. N., Mavondo, F. T. (2005). The impact of service quality on customer value in the hotel industry. In Tourism marketing, ANZMAC Conference. Monash University: Australia.##OECD. (2009).The Impact of culture on tourism. Paris:Author.##Parkerson, B., Saunders, J. (2005). City branding: Can goods and services branding models be used to brand cities?. Place Branding and Public Diplomacy, 1(3), 242-264.##Poria, Y., Airey, D., Butler, R. (2001). Challenging the present approach to heritage tourism: Is tourism to heritage places heritage tourism?. Tourism Review, 56(1/2), 51-53.##Rabbiosi, C. (2015). Renewing a historical legacy: Tourism, leisure shopping and urban branding in Paris. Cities, 42, 195-203.##Rainisto, S. K. (2003). Success factors of place marketing: A study of place marketing practices in Northern Europe and the United States. Helsinki University of Technology.##Ruiz, D. M., Gremler, D. D., Washburn, J. H., Carrión, G. C. (2008). Service value revisited: Specifying a higher-order, formative measure. Journal of Business Research, 61(12), 1278-1291.##Van Riel, C.B.M., Balmer. J.M.T. (1997). Corporate identiny: The concept, its measurement and management. European Journal of Marketing,31(5).##Wang, Y. J., Wu, C., Yuan, J. (2010). Exploring visitors' experiences and intention to revisit a heritage destination: The case for Lukang, Taiwan. Journal of Quality Assurance in Hospitality &amp; Tourism, 11(3), 162-178.##Young, Y. E. (2012). City branding and urban tourism: a case study of Seoul and Taipei. In 6th Conference of the International Forum on Urbanism (IFoU): TOURBANISM, Barcelona, 25-27 gener (pp. 1-10). International Forum on Urbanism.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>نقش مشاغل غیررسمی در تسکین اسکان غیررسمی (مطالعه موردی: حصارامیر پاکدشت)</TitleF>
		<TitleE>The Role of Informal Jobs in Relieving Informal Settlement (Case Study: Hesaramir of Pakdasht)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>در سال&#8204;های اخیر، نظریات نوین در توانمندسازی، بر نقش راهکارهای خودجوش حاشیه&#8204;نشینان، معطوف شده است. یکی از راهکارهای عملی که ساکنین سکونتگاه&#8204;های غیررسمی برای برون&#8204;رفت از مشکلات حاشیه&#8204;نشینی در پیش گرفته&#8204;اند، روی&#8204;آوردن به اقتصاد غیررسمی و مشاغل خودجوش است. این پژوهش با رویکرد توصیفی- تحلیلی و با تکیه بر روش پرسشنامه&#8204;ای، در پی بررسی نقش این دسته از مشاغل به عنوان راهکاری برخاسته از درون این اجتماعات، برای تسکین مسئله اسکان غیررسمی در میان سکونتگاه&#8204;های غیررسمی حصارامیر در پاکدشت است. برای تعیین حجم نمونه از فرمول کوکران استفاده شد. حجم جامعه آماری، ۲۵۳۰۳ نفر جمعیت کل حصارامیر در&#8204;نظرگرفته شد. بر این اساس تعداد نمونه&#8204;ها ۳۷۸ محاسبه شد. نتایج تکنیک SWOT نشان دادند که توسعه مشاغل خودجوش در سکونتگاه&#8204;های غیررسمی حصارامیر پاکدشت، نقاط قوت بسیار بالایی (33/3 امتیاز از نظر عوامل داخلی و 34/3 امتیاز از نظر عوامل خارجی) دارد. برای تحلیل پرسشنامه&#8204;ها از آزمون&#8204;های آماری تک نمونه&#8204;ای خی&#8204;دو و تی استفاده شده است. نتیجه آزمون خی&#8204;دو نشان داد بین جنسیت افراد مورد مطالعه و گرایش به مشاغل خودجوش، رابطه معناداری در سطح احتمال ۹۵ درصد وجود دارد. آزمون تی و نیز کلموگروف- اسمیرنوف، برای نشان دادن تأثیر مشاغل خودجوش در بهبود وضعیت اقتصادی استفاده شد. نتایج آزمون نشان می&#8204;دهند که گرایش به این گونه اشتغال&#8204;ها سبب بهبود وضعیت اقتصادی افراد گردیده است. آزمون&#8204;ها نشان&#8204;دهنده سطح معناداری کمتر از 05/0 بوده که بیانگر تأثیر این مشاغل در بهبود وضعیت اقتصادی می&#8204;باشد.&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>New theories in empowerment have been focused on the role of spontaneous solutions of suburbanites in the recent years. One of the scientific strategies that inhabitants of informal settlements use for solving the problems of marginalization is to choose informal economy and spontaneous jobs. This research has descriptive-analytical approach emphasizing on questionnaire in order to study the role of such occupations as a solution arisen from these societies in order to relieve the issue of informal settlement among informal habitats of Hesaramir in Pakdasht. Cochran Formula was used to determine sample size. 25303 people of total population of Hesaramir were considered as a statistical population; therefore, 378 people were selected. SWOT technique indicated that development of spontaneous jobs in the informal settlements of Hesaramir of Pakdasht has very high strengths (3.33 scores in terms of internal factors and 3.34 scores in terms of external factors). One sample t tests and chi-square were used to analyze the questionnaires. Chi-square test results showed that there is a significant relationship between the gender of the studied people and tendency to spontaneous jobs with the probability of 95%. T and Kolmogorov-Smirnov tests were used to show the impact of spontaneous jobs on economic recovery. The results of Kolmogorov-Smirnov test indicate that tendency to such jobs has leaded to the improvement of economic situation. T-test indicates the significance level less than 0.05 showing the impact of these jobs on the improvement of economic situation.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>137</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>157</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>فاطمه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>سالاروندیان</Family>
				<NameE>Fatemeh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Salarvandiyan</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Geography, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سیدعلی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>حسینی</Family>
				<NameE>Seyyed Ali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Hosseini</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Geography, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>لیلا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>حبیبی</Family>
				<NameE>Leyla</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Habibi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Handicrafts and Tourism, University of Mazandaran, Mazandaran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مریم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>جعفری مهرآبادی</Family>
				<NameE>Maryam</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Jafari Mehrabadi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Geography, university of Gilan, Gilan, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>informal settlement</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>spontaneous jobs</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>informal economy of the city</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>SWOT</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اسکان غیررسمی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مشاغل خودخوش</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اقتصاد غیررسمی شهر</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>SWOT</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##اجلاس وزرای مسکن. (1387). ایجاد فضای حیاتی برای فعالیت‌های بخش غیررسمی از جمله مشاغل خرد در چارچوب مقررات ملی، سازمان مسکن و شهرسازی. ##اعتماد، گیتی. (1382). ویژگی‌های کالبدی محله‌های حاشیه‌نشین، مجموعه مقالات حاشیه‌نشینی و اسکان غیررسمی، دانشگاه علوم بهزیستی و توانبخشی، تهران.##پیران، پرویز. (1381). باز هم در باب اسکان غیررسمی، مورد شیرآباد زاهدان، مجله هفت شهر، شماره‌های 9 و 10، وزارت مسکن و شهرسازی.##توماس، جی جی؛ ریسکاویچ، رائول؛ سیتو، وینچنزو. (1376). اقتصاد غیررسمی، ترجمه و تلخیص منوچهر نوربخش و کامران سپهری، تهران: مؤسسه تحقیقات پولی و بانکی.##جمالی، فیروز؛ صدرموسوی، میرستار؛ لیوارجانی، پروین‌دخت. (1388). بررسی ویژگی‌های اجتماعی و اقتصادی شاغلان بخش غیررسمی در مادرشهر تبریز، نمونه موردی سبزه میدان، نشریه جغرافیا برنامه‌ریزی دانشگاه تبریز، 14(29). ##حاج‌یوسفی، علی. (1381). حاشیه‌نشینی شهری و فرایند تحول آن (قبل از انقلاب اسلامی)، فصلنامه هفت شهر، شماره 8، وزارت مسکن و شهرسازی.##حافظ‌نیا، محمدرضا. (1387). مقدمه‌ای بر روش تحقیق در علوم انسانی، تهران: انتشارات سمت.##حسین‌اغلی، جواد. (1386). تحلیلی بر اسکان غیررسمی در منطقه کلانشهر تهران، پایان‌نامه دوره دکتری، دانشکده جغرافیا، دانشگاه تهران.##خاتم. اعظم. (1381)، سهم مردم، سهم دولت در طرح‌های توانمندسازی و بهسازی محله، فصلنامه هفت شهر، شماره 8، وزارت مسکن و شهرسازی.##شاه‌حسینی، پروانه. (1382). بررسی ساخت‌یابی ویژگی‌های اجتماعی و اقتصادی سکونتگاه‌های غیررسمی کلانشهر تهران (نمونه موردی: پاکدشت)، دانشکده جغرافیا، دانشگاه تهران.##شریفیان‌ثانی، مریم. (1380). مشارکت شهروندی، حکمروایی شهری و مدیریت شهری، فصلنامه مدیریت شهری، 2(8).##شکویی، حسین. (1380). دیدگاه‌های نو در جغرافیای شهری، جلد اول، تهران: سمت.##شیخی، محمد. (1380).  تبیین فرایند شکل‌گیری و دگرگونی سکونتگاه‌های خودروی پیرامون کلانشهر تهران، پایان‌نامه دکتری شهرسازی، دانشکده هنرهای زیبا، دانشگاه تهران.##صرافی، مظفر. (1381). به سوی تدوین راهبرد ملی ساماندهی اسکان غیررسمی، فصلنامه هفت شهر، شماره 9و10، انتشارات وزارت مسکن و شهرسازی.##عارفی، مهیار. (1380). به سوی رویکرد دارایی- مبنا برای توسعه اجتماع محلی، مجله هنرهای زیبا، شماره10. ##کمیسیون اسکان بشر. (1378). سرپناه برای همه: سیاست‌های مسکن در آستانه هزاره سوم، ترجمه مهرداد جواهری‌پور، تهران: سازمان عمران و بهسازی شهری.##گودرزی، سعید. (1388). کاربرد آمار در علوم اجتماعی، ناشر دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی تویسرکان با همکاری انتشارات جامعه‌شناسان در تهران.##محمودیان، احمد. (1386). حاشیه‌نشینی، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی‌ارشد دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد تهران مرکز.##مرکز آمار ایران. (1355). نتایج تفضیلی سرشماری عمومی نفوس و مسکن سال 1355 شهرستان ورامین.##مرکز آمار ایران. (1365). نتایج تفضیلی سرشماری عمومی نفوس و مسکن سال 1365 شهرستان ورامین.##مرکز آمار ایران. (1375). نتایج تفضیلی سرشماری عمومی نفوس و مسکن سال 1375 شهرستان پاکدشت.##مرکز آمار ایران. (1385). نتایج تفضیلی سرشماری عمومی نفوس و مسکن سال 1385 شهرستان پاکدشت.##نقدی، اسدالله. (1389). مهاجرت و حاشیه‌نشینی، فصلنامه جمعیت، شماره 73-74.##Cobas, J. A. (1986). Paths to Self-Employment among Immigrants An Analysis of Four Interpretations. Sociological Perspectives, 29(1), 101-120.##Davis, M. (2006). Planet of Slums, New Perspectives Quarterly, 23(2).##Frota, L. (2008). Securing decent work and living conditions in low-income urban settlements by linking social protection and local development: A review of case studies. Habitat International, 32(2).##Henry, A. (2008). Understanding strategic management. Oxford University Press, USA.##Kantor, P. (2009). Women’s exclusion and unfavorable inclusion in informal employment in Lucknow, India: barriers to voice and livelihood security. World development, 37(1), 194-207.##Majale, Michael. )2008(. Employment creation through participatory urban planning And slum upgrading: The case of Kitale, Kenya, Habitat International 32,270_282##McGrath, S., Kenneth, K., Leach, F., Carr-Hill, R. )1994(. Education and training for the informal sector, Education Research Paper No. 11,332.##OECD (organization for Economic Cooperation and Development). )1986(. Self-employment in OECD Countries, in OECD employment outlook.##Rappaport, Julian. (1987). Terms of Empowerment/Exemplars of Prevention: Toward a Theory for Community Psychology, American Journal of Community Psychology, 15(2), 1987##Shane, S. A. (2003). A general theory of entrepreneurship: The individual-opportunity nexus. Edward Elgar Publishing.##Ungson, G. R., Wong, Y. Y. (2014). Global strategic management. Routledge.##Yuki, K. (2007). Urbanization, informal sector, and development. Journal of Development Economics, 84(1), 76-103.##Yunus, M. (2007). Creating a world without poverty: Social business and the future of capitalism. Public Affairs.##http://www.Asiannews.peit,p.v##http://www.tehran.ir/scad##http//www.Grameen-info.org## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>

</ARTICLES>

</JOURNAL>
</XML>
