<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>2019</YEAR>
<VOL>7</VOL>
<NO>26</NO>
<MOSALSAL>0</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>130</PAGE_NO>


<ARTICLES>

	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>ارزیابی شاخص‌های فضای معماری ساختمان‌های تجاری بزرگ‌مقیاس با رویکرد تهدیدات و مخاطرات شهری</TitleF>
		<TitleE>An Evaluation of Large-Scale Commercial Buildings Architectural Space Indicators with an Approach to Urban Threats and Risks</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>چکیده:&#160;دستیابی به معیارهای فنی که با به&#8204;کار بستن آن&#8204;ها در مرحله طراحی معماری ساختمان&#8204;های تجاری بزرگ&#8204;مقیاس که به عنوان یکی از کاربری&#8204;های مهم در برنامه&#8204;ریزی شهری محسوب می&#8204;گردد، می&#8204;تواند سطح امنیت شهروندان را در برابر انواع تهدیدات و مخاطرات طبیعی، افزایش دهد و موجب کاهش آسیب&#8204;پذیری و ارائه استمرار خدمات و فعالیت این ساختمان&#8204;ها می&#8204;شود. پژوهش حاضر با ماهیت توسعه&#8204;ای- کاربردی و روش توصیفی- پیمایشی، به بررسی موضوع در ساختمان&#8204;های تجاری بزرگ مقیاس پرداخته است. در این پژوهش، برای ارزیابی فضای معماری ساختمان&#8204;های تجاری بزرگ&#8204;مقیاس، پنج معیار استمرار فعالیت در شرایط اضطراری، هزینه، تسهیل خروج اضطراری، کاهش اثر انفجار و زلزله در نظر گرفته شده است. این پژوهش، با بهره&#8204;گیری از روش&#8204;های Swara و Smart به بررسی موضوع و ارائه مدل جهت ارزیابی آسیب&#8204;پذیری فضای معماری، پرداخته است. نتایج حاصل از ارزیابی معیارها و شاخص&#8204;های فضای معماری، نشان می&#8204;دهد معیارهای قابلیت کاهش اثر انفجار، تسهیل خروج اضطراری، استمرار فعالیت در شرایط بحران، زلزله و هزینه با وزن&#8204;های ۳۰۵۶/۰، ۲۷۷۸/۰، ۲۳۱۵/۰، ۱۸۵۲/۰ و ۱۵۴۳/۰ در رتبه&#8204;های اول تا پنجم قرار گرفته&#8204;اند. با بهره&#8204;گیری از مدل ارائه شده، می&#8204;توان فضای معماری ساختمان&#8204;های تجاری بزرگ&#8204;مقیاس در برابر تهدیدات و مخاطرات شهری را مورد ارزیابی آسیب&#8204;پذیری قرار داد و همچنین میزان آسیب&#8204;پذیری و نقاط ضعف این ساختمان&#8204;ها در هر شاخص و معیار را بررسی کرد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Abstract: Achieving to technical criteria that by applying them in architectural design stage of large commercial buildings, considered as one of the most important uses in urban planning, can increase the level of citizens&#8217; security against all kinds of natural hazards and threats, and reduce vulnerability and it can provide continuation of the services and activities of these buildings. The present study has a developmental-applied nature. By descriptive-survey method, the issue is investigated in large-scale commercial buildings. In this research, to assess the architectural space of large-scale commercial buildings, five criteria including continuity of activities in emergencies, costs, facilitating emergency exit, reducing the impact of explosions and earthquakes are considered. In this research, using Swara and Smart methods, the subject matter and the proposed model for evaluating the vulnerability of the architectural space are discussed. The results of the evaluation of the criteria and indicators of the architectural space indicate that the criteria for reducing the effect of the explosion, facilitating emergency exit, the continuity of activities in crisis, earthquake and cost with the weights of 0.3056, 0.2778, 0.2315, 1852.0 and 0.1543 are ranked first to fifth. Using the proposed model, the architecture of large-scale commercial buildings can be evaluated against urban threats and vulnerabilities, as well as the vulnerability and weaknesses of these buildings in each indicator and criterion.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>14</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>منصور</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>باقرصادرنانی</Family>
				<NameE>Mansour</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Baghersad Ranani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Geography and Planning, University of Isfahan, Isfahan, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده علوم جغرافیایی و برنامه‌ریزی، دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حمیدرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>وارثی</Family>
				<NameE>Hamidreza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Varesi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Geography and Planning, University of Isfahan, Isfahan, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده علوم جغرافیایی و برنامه‌ریزی، دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>h.varesi@geo.ui.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مسعود</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>تقوائی</Family>
				<NameE>Masoud</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Taghvaei</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Geography and Planning, University of Isfahan, Isfahan, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده علوم جغرافیایی و برنامه‌ریزی، دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Architectural space</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>threats</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>compatibility</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>vulnerability</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>passive defense</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>large-scale commercial building</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>فضای معماری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تهدیدات</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سازگاری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>آسیب‌پذیری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پدافند غیرعامل</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ساختمان تجاری بزرگ‌مقیاس</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##اباذری، یوسفعلی؛ کاظمی، علی. (1384). خرید رویکردهای نظری خرید: مطالعات جامعه‌شناسی و فرهنگی. نشریه نامه علوم اجتماعی، 25(25)، 195-167.##ابراهیم‎نیا، وحیده؛ رسولی، مژگان؛ زندیه، سمیه. (1388). روش‌ها و مدل‎های تخصیص کاربرد زمین. نشریه آرمانشهر، شماره 2، 9-22. ##ابراهیمیان قاجاری، یاسر؛ آل‌شیخ، علی‌اصغر؛ مدیری، مهدی؛ حسنوی، رضا؛ عباسی، مرتضی. (1393). مدل‌سازی آسیب‌پذیری ساختمان‌های شهری با استفاده از روش‎های دلفی و تحلیل سلسله‌مراتبی در محیط GIS (مطالعه موردی: منطقه 6 شهر تهران). فصلنامه اطلاعات جغرافیایی، 23(91)، 20-5.##اصغرپور، محمدجواد. (1387). تصمیم‌گیری‌های چندمعیاره. چاپ پنجم، تهران: دانشگاه تهران. ##پورموسوی، سیدموسی؛ شماعی، علی؛ احدنژاد، محسن؛ عشقی چهاربرج، علی؛ خسروی، سمیه. (1391). ارزیابی آسیب‌پذیری ساختمان‌های شهر با مدل Fuzzy AHP و GIS (مطالعه موردی: منطقه 3 شهرداری تهران). نشریه جغرافیا و توسعه شهری. 12(34)، 138-121.##جلالی ‎فراهانی، غلامرضا؛ عراقی‎زاده، مجتبی. (1391). تبیین جایگاه طراحی معماری در تأمین اهداف پدافند غیرعامل ساختمان. نشریه معماری و شهر پایدار. 1(1)، 75-67.##حسینی، سیدبهشید. (1389). معیارهای پدافند غیرعامل در طراحی معماری ساختمان‌های جمعی شهری. تهران: عابد.##حسینی، سیدتیمور؛ آریانا، محمد؛ آبرودی، سیدمجتبی. (1395). الزامات و ملاحظات معماری ساختمان‎های اداری شهری از منظر پدافند غیرعامل. اولین همایش بین‎‎المللی اقتصاد شهری. ##حسینی، سیدعلی؛ زیتونی، حسین. (1396). مکان‎یابی بهینه مجتمع‌های تجاری با استفاده از فرایند تحلیل سلسله‌مراتبی در محیط سیستم اطلاعات جغرافیایی (مورد: مجتمع تجاری شهر رامسر). نشریه مطالعات ساختار و کارکرد شهری، 4(13)، 43-24.##دیبا، داراب؛ انصاری، مجتبی. (1374). چگونگی شکل‎گیری ارتباط انسان با محیط مصنوع. کنگره تاریخ معماری و شهرسازی ایران.##سلطانی‎فرد، هادی؛ زنگانه، احمد؛ نوده، مرضیه؛ حسینی، فرزانه‎السادات. (1395). تحلیل فضایی اثرات شبکه معابر بر آسیب‎پذیری محلات شهری در برابر زلزله موردمطالعه: محله امیریه شهر سبزوار). نشریه تحلیل فضایی مخاطرات محیطی، 3(1)، 49-31.##شاهیوندی، احمد. (1396). سنجش میزان آسیب‎پذیری محلات شهری در تطابق با اصول پدافند غیرعامل (مطالعه موردی: شهر شهرکرد). دو فصلنامه علمی پژوهشی مدیریت بحران، 6(1(پیاپی 11))، 62-47.##شهاب‎زاده، مرجان؛ پیوسته‎گر، یعقوب؛ حیدری، علی‎اکبر. (1395). تحلیل توزیع فضایی مراکز تجاری نوین شهری و مکان‎یابی بهینه آنها با استفاده از GIS و AHP (موردپژوهشی: کلان‌شهر شیراز). فصلنامه برنامه‎ریزی منطقه‎ای، 6(23)‌، 112-99.##علی‌اکبری، اسماعیل؛ میرایی، نفیسه‎سادات. (1394). آسیب‌پذیری معابر در شهرهای لرزه‎خیز براساس مدل IHWP در ناحیه سه منطقه یک کلان‎شهر تبریز. نشریه تحلیل فضایی مخاطرات محیطی، 2(1)، 16-1.##فلاحت، محمدصادق؛ شهیدی، صمد. (1394). نقش مفهوم توده- فضا در تبیین مکان معماری. مجله باغ نظر، 12(35)، 38-27.##فون‎مایس، پی‎یر. (1392). نگاهی به مبانی معماری از فرم تا مکان. مترجم سیمون آیوازیان، چاپ ششم، تهران: دانشگاه تهران.##کرمی، محمد؛ کرمی، سونیا. (1394). ارزیابی میزان آسیب‌پذیری ساختمان‌های اداری از منظر مدیریت بحران شهری (مطالعه موردی: ساختمان‎های اداری شهر جوانرد). اولین کنفرانس تخصصی معماری و شهرسازی ایران.##لاوسون، برایان. (1391). زبان فضا. مترجم علیرضا عینی‎فر و فواد کریمیان، تهران: دانشگاه تهران. ##نخعی؛ جلال، پیری، حسن. (1394). کاهش خطرپذیری ناشی از آسیب‌پذیری در مقابل تهدیدات انسان‎ساخت با استفاده از سامانه هوشمند ساختمان BMS در ساختمان‎های اداری. دو فصلنامه مدیریت بحران. 4‌(ویژه‎نامه)، 28-15.##Bitarafan, M., Hosseini, S. B., Abazarlou, S., &amp; Mahmoudzadeh, A. (2015). Selecting the optimal composition of architectural forms from the perspective of civil defense using AHP and IHWP methods. Architectural Engineering and Design Management, 11(2), 137-148.##Gebbeken, N., &amp; Döge, T. (2010). Explosion protection—architectural design, urban planning and landscape planning. International Journal of Protective Structures, 1(1), 1-21.##Koccaz, Z. (2004). Blast Resistant Building Design (Doctoral dissertation, MSc Thesis, Istanbul Technical University, Istanbul, Turkey).##Nakhaei, J., Bitarafan, M., Lale Arefi, S., &amp; Kapliński, O. (2016). Model for rapid assessment of vulnerability of office buildings to blast using SWARA and SMART methods (a case study of swiss re tower). Journal of Civil Engineering and Management, 22(6), 831-843.##Rashed, T., Weeks, J., Couclelis, H., &amp; Herold, M. (2007). An integrative GIS and remote sensing model for place-based urban vulnerability analysis. Integration of GIS and remote sensing. Wiley, Chichester, 199-224.##Sinha, R., &amp; Goyal, A. (2004). A national policy for seismic vulnerability assessment of buildings and procedure for rapid visual screening of buildings for potential seismic vulnerability. Report to Disaster Management Division, Ministry of Home Affairs, Government of India, Hindistan.##Walker, G. R. (2011). Modelling the vulnerability of buildings to wind—a review. Canadian Journal of Civil Engineering, 38(9), 1031-1039. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی عوامل ‌تعیین‌کننده‌ ‌اجاره مسکن در شهر ایلام با رویکرد اقتصادسنجی‌ فضایی هدانیک</TitleF>
		<TitleE>The Study of Determinants of Rent Housing in Ilam City Based on Hedonic Spatial Econometrics</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>چکیده: واحد مسکونی، &#8204;کالایی ناهمگن و چندبُعدی است؛ از این&#8204;رو برای تعیین عوامل مؤثر بر اجاره&#8204;بهای واحدهای مسکونی، از روش هدانیک استفاده می&#8204;شود. برای تبیین این عوامل، از چهار ویژگی برای مسکن استفاده می&#8204;شود که عبارتند از: متغیرهای&#8204;کالبدی- فیزیکی واحدهای &#8204;مسکونی، متغیرهای دسترسی، متغیرهای محیطی (همسایگی) و &#8204;ویژگی&#8204;های &#8204;اقتصادی و اجتماعی&#8204; خانوارها. متغیرهای مربوط به ویژگی فضایی، با استفاده از هدانیک فضایی و به منظور مقید ساختن تابع اجاره&#8204;بها به مکان، به کار می&#8204;روند. تکنیک هدانیک فضایی، به خوبی قادر است ضمن تعیین عوامل مؤثر بر اجاره مسکن، تأثیرپذیری اجاره مسکن از سایر ویژگی&#8204;های مسکن&#8204;های مجاور را نیز بررسی &#8204;کند. در این مقاله، با بهره&#8204;گیری از فرم&#8204;های خطی، نیمه&#8204;لگاریتمی، لگاریتمی و مدل باکس- کاکس، تأثیر هرکدام از ویژگی&#8204;های مختلف واحدهای مسکونی استیجاری بر قیمت اجاره&#8204;بهای آن با استفاده از تابع&#8204; هدانیک ساده و فضایی، بررسی شده است. نتایج به&#8204;دست آمده بیانگر این است که بهترین مدل، مدل خطی است و در بین واحدهای مسکونی آپارتمانی شهر ایلام، عوامل فیزیکی و اقتصادی- اجتماعی، بیشتر از متغیرهای همسایگی و دسترسی، اجاره واحد&#8204;های مسکونی را تحت تأثیر قرار می&#8204;دهند، همچنین اثر متغیر وابسته فضایی در مدل هدانیک فضایی بر اجاره&#8204;بها، کاملاً معنی&#8204;دار و مثبت می&#8204;باشد. مدل برآورد شده از روش اقتصاد&#8204;سنجی فضایی از لحاظ خوبی برازش، درصد معنی&#8204;داری ضرایب و همچنین توضیح&#8204;دهندگی اثر متغیرهای موجود در مدل، نسبت به روش اقتصادسنجی، متعارف، کاراتر و بهتر می&#8204;باشد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Abstract: Housing unit is heterogeneous and multidimensional commodity; therefore, to determine effective factors on rent, hedonic pricing model is used. To explain the factors, four properties are used for housing, which are physical variables of residential units, access variables, environmental variables (neighborhood), and economic and social characteristics. The variables related to the spatial property are used by spatial hedonics to bind the lease function to the location. Spatial hedonic technique is able to determine the effective factors on the rental of housing, also the impact of renting housing from other properties of adjacent ones. In this paper, using linear, semi-logarithmic, logarithmic and box-cox models, the effect of each of the properties of leased residential units on their rental prices has been investigated using simple and spatial hedonic function. The results indicate that the best model is the linear model. Moreover, among the residential apartments in Ilam, physical and socioeconomic factors affect the rental of residential units more than neighborhoods and access variables, as well as the effect of spatial dependent variable in spatial hedonic model on rentals is quite significant and positive. The estimated model of spatial econometric method is well fitted; the percentage of coefficients and the explanation of the effect of the variables in the model are more efficient and better than conventional econometric methods.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>15</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>27</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سجاد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رضائیان</Family>
				<NameE>Sajad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rezaeian</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Literature and Humanities, University of Ilam, Ilam, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه ایلام، ایلام، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حشمت‌الله</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>عسگری</Family>
				<NameE>Heshmatolah</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Asgari</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Economics, Faculty of Literature and Humanities, University of Ilam, Ilam, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه ایلام، ایلام، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>he.asgari@ gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>باقر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>درویشی</Family>
				<NameE>Bagher</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Darvishi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Economics, Faculty of Literature and Humanities, University of Ilam, Ilam, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه ایلام، ایلام، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Rent</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Hedonic</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Spatial Econometric</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Spatial Dependence</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Spatial Heterogeneity</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اجاره‌بها</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>هدانیک</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اقتصادسنجی فضایی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>وابستگی فضایی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ناهمسانی فضایی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##ابونوری، اسمعیل؛ تقی‎نژاد عمران، وحید؛ صیامی، علی. (1387). برآورد تابع قیمت هدانیک اجاره‎بها (مطالعه موردی شهرهای تبریز و  اردبیل). نشریه بررسی‎های بازرگانی، شماره 33، 60-52.##اکبری، نعمت‎الله؛ عمادزاده، مصطفی؛ رضوی، سیدعلی. (1383). بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر قیمت مسکن در شهر مشهد رهیافت اقتصادسنجی فضایی در روش هدانیک. فصلنامه پژوهش‎های اقتصادی، شماره 11 و 12، 117-97.##امیرنژاد، حمید؛ نبی‎زاده ذوالپیرانی، مجتبی؛ حیدری کمال‎آبادی، رضا. (1395). تأثیر تالاب عینک شهر رشت بر قیمت مسکن منطقه با استفاده از روش قیمت‎گذاری هدانیک. فصلنامه اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری، 4(16)، 53-37.##پورمحمدی، محمدرضا؛ قربانی، رسول؛ تقی‎پور، علی‎اکبر. (1392). بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر قیمت مسکن در شهر تبریز با استفاده از مدل هدانیک. نشریه آمایش جغرافیایی فضا، 3(9)، 104-83.##حسنی صدرآبادی، محمدحسین؛ مشفق، سارا. (1390). بررسی رابطه علّی عوامل تأثیرگذار در تقاضای مسکن شهری استان تهران. مجله پژوهش‎های اقتصادی (رشد و توسعه پایدار)، 11(1)، 18-1.##خلیلی‌عراقی، سیدمنصور؛ کمیجانی، اکبر؛ مهرآرا، محسن؛ عظیمی، سیدرضا. (1392). اثر انتشار فضایی تغییرات قیمت مسکن در ایران با استفاده از مدل وقفه فضایی و داده‌های ترکیبی. فصلنامه پژوهش‌ها و سیاست‌های اقتصادی، 21(67)، 48-25.##صداقتی، عاطفه، نوریان، فرشاد. (1395). به‌کارگیری روش هدانیک در ارزش‌گذاری واحدهای مسکونی موردشناسی: محله باغ صبا در منطقه 7 تهران. فصلنامه جغرافیا و آمایش شهری، 6(21)، 186-171.##عبداله میلانی، مهنوش؛ حدادی، مهرنوش. (1391). مترو و تأثیر آن بر قیمت املاک مسکونی (شهر تهران). مجله تحقیقات اقتصادی، 47(4)، 96-79.##قادری، جعفر؛ ایزدی، بهنام. (1395). بررسی تأثیر عوامل اقتصادی و اجتماعی بر قیمت مسکن در ایران (1391-1350). فصلنامه اقتصاد شهری، 1(1)، 75-55.##کهزادی، نوروز؛ دهقان‌دهنوی، محمدعلی؛ سلطانی‎نژاد، حامد. (1395). بررسی عوامل تعیین‎کننده اجاره‎بهای یک واحد مسکونی در مناطق شهری ایران با استفاده از مدل رگرسیون هدانیک (موردمطالعه: شهرهای اصفهان، سمنان و گلپایگان). کنفرانس جهانی مدیریت، اقتصاد، حسابداری و علوم انسانی در آغاز هزاره سوم.##محمدزاده، پرویز؛ منصوری، مسعود؛ کوهی‌لیلان، بابک. (1391). تخمین قیمت هدانیک ساختمان‎های مسکونی در شهر تبریز با رویکرد اقتصادسنجی فضایی. فصلنامه مدلسازی اقتصادی، 6(18)، 38-21.##مرتضوی، سمیرا. (1395). شناسایی و اولویت‎بندی عوامل ساختاری مؤثر در تعیین اجاره‎بهای مسکن در شهر شاهرود. پایان‎نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه سمنان.##مهرگان، نادر؛ غفاری، وحید. (1395). عوامل مؤثر بر اجاره‎بها در شهرهای ایران با استفاده از داده‎های ترکیبی. فصلنامه اقتصاد مسکن، شماره 56، 100-77.##نصرالهی، خدیجه؛ آزادغلامی، اعظم. (1392). تحلیل تأثیر تسهیلات بانکی بر قیمت مسکن در کلان‎شهرهای ایران. فصلنامه روند، 20(63-64)، 38-15.##Bivand, R., &amp; Piras, G. (2015). Comparing implementations of estimation methods for spatial econometrics. American Statistical Association.##Fannin, J. M., &amp; Barnes, J. N. (2009). Spatial model specification for contractual arrangements between rural hospitals and physicians. The Review of Regional Studies, 39(2), 189-211.##Gouriéroux, C., &amp; Laferrère, A. (2009). Managing hedonic housing price indexes: The French experience. Journal of Housing Economics, 18(3), 206-213. ##Helbich, M., Brunauer, W., Vaz, E., &amp; Nijkamp, P. (2014). Spatial heterogeneity in hedonic house price models: the case of Austria. Urban Studies, 51(2), 390-411.##Karlik, B., &amp; Olgac, A. V. (2011). Performance analysis of various activation functions in generalized MLP architectures of neural networks. International Journal of Artificial Intelligence and Expert Systems, 1(4), 111-122.##Keskin, B. (2008). Hedonic analysis of price in the Istanbul housing market. International Journal of Strategic Property Management, 12(2), 125-138.##Li, Y., Wang, X., Zhu, Q., &amp; Zhao, H, Li, Y., Wang, X., Zhu, Q., &amp; Zhao, H. (2014). Assessing the spatial and temporal differences in the impacts of factor allocation and urbanization on urban–rural income disparity in China, 2004–2010. Habitat International, 42, 76-82.##Liew, C., &amp; Haron, N. A. (2013). Factors influencing the rise of house price in Klang Valley.##Ligus, M., &amp; Peternek, P. (2016). Measuring structural, location and environmental effects: A hedonic analysis of housing market in Wroclaw, Poland. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 220, 251-260.##Panduro, T. E., &amp; Veie, K. L. (2013). Classification and valuation of urban green spaces—A hedonic house price valuation. Landscape and Urban planning, 120, 119-128.##Selim, H. (2009). Determinants of house prices in Turkey: Hedonic regression versus artificial neural network, Expert System With Application, 36(2), 2843 -2852.##Sobrino, J. (2014). Housing prices and submarkets in Mexico City: A hedonic assessment. Estudios económicos, 29(1).##Tan, R., Zhou, K., &amp; Xu, H. (2019). Effects of Urban Road Centrality on Property Values: Spatial Hedonic Analysis of the Housing Market in Wuhan, China. Journal of Urban Planning and Development, 145(2), 05019005.##Waltert, F., &amp; Schläpfer, F. (2010). Landscape amenities and local development: A review of migration, regional economic and hedonic pricing studies. Ecological Economics, 70(2), 141-152.##Wen, H. Z., Sheng-hua, J., &amp; Xiao-yu, G. (2005). Hedonic price analysis of urban housing: an empirical research on Hangzhou, China. Journal of Zhejiang University-Science A, 6(8), 907-914. ##Wen, H., Gui, Z., Tian, C., Xiao, Y., &amp; Fang, L. (2018). Subway Opening, Traffic Accessibility, and Housing Prices: A Quantile Hedonic Analysis in Hangzhou, China. Sustainability, 10(7), 2254. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بهینه‌سازی تخصیص بودجه مناطق شهری براساس شاخص‎های عدالت فضایی (مورد مطالعه: کلان‎شهر مشهد)</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Optimization of Urban Budget Allocation Based on Spatial Justice Indicators (Case: Mashhad Metropolis)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>چکیده: یکی از وظایف اصلی مدیران شهری، ایجاد عدالت در زمینه دسترسی عادلانه و برابر شهروندان به خدمات شهری است. با اجرای عینی مفهوم عدالت فضایی، ضمن بهره&#8206;مندی مناسب شهروندان از خدمات، زمینه کاهش مسائل و مشکلات شهری فراهم می&#8206;شود. عدالت فضایی، یکی از مفاهیم اصلی توسعه پایدار شهری، قلمداد می&#8206;شود. این امر از طریق تصمیم&#8206;گیری صحیح در مورد تخصیص بودجه شهری، قابل&#8206;دستیابی است. شناسایی مناطق برخوردار و غیربرخوردار و تخصیص عادلانه و آگاهانه منابع مالی بین مناطق شهری، نیازمند به&#8206;کارگیری تکنیکی است که بتواند معیارهای متفاوت و گه&#8206;گاه متضاد را در تصمیم&#8206;گیری، لحاظ کند. در این تحقیق با به&#8206;کارگیری تکنیک پرامتی وی- سی اپتیمال تلاش شده تا در قالب مطالعه موردی، تخصیص منابع مالی کلان&#8206;شهر مشهد در مناطق سیزده&#8204;گانه با در نظر گرفتن معیارهای عدالت فضایی صورت پذیرد. نتایج این پژوهش، حاکی از آن هستند که شهر مشهد مقدس، از لحاظ شاخص&#8206;های عدالت فضایی، در وضعیت مطلوبی قرار ندارد. منطقه ثامن، به&#8204;عنوان برخوردارترین و منطقه سه، محروم&#8206;ترین منطقه کلان&#8206;شهر مشهد، شناسایی شده&#8206;اند. توانایی بالای تکنیک پیشنهادی در تخصیص عادلانه بودجه با در نظر گرفتن شاخص&#8206;های متعدد، در این پژوهش نشان داده شده است؛ لذا این تکنیک می&#8206;تواند به&#8204;عنوان ابزاری کارآمد در تصمیم&#8206;گیری&#8206;های شهری استفاده شود.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Abstract: One of the main responsibilities of urban managers is to create justice in the area of fair and equal access of citizens to urban services. By objective realization of spatial justice concept, while providing the citizens with the appropriate services, the ground of reducing urban problems is prepared. Spatial justice is one of the main concepts of sustainable urban development. This can be achieved by making the right decision about the allocation of the city budget. Recognizing prosperous and non-prosperous areas fair and informed allocation of financial resources among urban areas require the use of a technique that takes into account different and sometimes conflicting criteria for decision making. In this research, using PROMETHEE V-C technique, it has been tried to examine Mashhad metropolitan financial resources to thirteen areas, taking into account the criteria of spatial justice, in the form of a case study. The results indicate that the holy city of Mashhad is not in desirable position in terms of spatial justice indicators. Samen area is recognized as the most prosperous and district 3 as the most deprived area in the city of Mashhad. The high ability of the proposed technique to allocate budget equitably with multiple indicators has been shown in this study; therefore, this technique can be used as an effective tool for urban decision-making.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>29</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>44</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مرتضی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>مرتضوی</Family>
				<NameE>Morteza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Mortezavi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Industris and Management, Shahrood University of Technology, Shahrood, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده صنایع و مدیریت، دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود، شاهرود، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>mortazavimorteza@rocketmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>رضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شیخ</Family>
				<NameE>Reza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Sheykh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Industris and Management, Shahrood University of Technology, Shahrood, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده صنایع و مدیریت، دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود، شاهرود، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Spatial Justice</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Resource Allocation</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Urban Facilities</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Multi-Criteria Decision-Making Techniques</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>PROMETHEE V-C</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عدالت فضایی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تخصیص بودجه شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>امکانات شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تکنیک‎های تصمیم‎گیری چندمعیاره</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پرامتی وی- سی اپتیمال</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>کلان‎شهر مشهد</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##اجزاء‎شکوهی، محمد؛ خاکپور، براتعلی؛ دانایی‎فرد، عمار. (1391). بررسی و تحلیل توزیع فضایی مراکز درمانی شهر مشهد با استفاده از GIS. چهارمین کنفرانس برنامه‎ریزی و مدیریت شهری، مشهد. ##امان‌پور، سعید؛ رزمگیر، فاطمه؛ دامن‌باغ، صفیه؛ حسینی سیاه گلی، مهناز. (1393). تحلیل تطبیقی توزیع خدمات شهری در شهر اهواز با استفاده از تحلیل سلسله‎مراتبیFAHP . فصلنامه جغرافیایی چشم‌انداز زاگرس، 6(20)، 159-137.##تابعی، نادر؛ موحد، علی؛ تولایی، سیمین؛ کمانرودی، موسی. (1395). بررسی نقش عدالت فضایی در مدیریت شهری (محدوده مطالعه: محلات منطقه 6 تهران). فصلنامه برنامه‎ریزی فضایی، 6(2)، 36-23.##تقوایی، علی‎اکبر؛ بمانیان، محمدرضا؛ پورجعفر، محمدرضا. (1394). میزان سنجش عدالت فضایی در چارچوب نظریه شهر عدالت‎محور؛ موردپژوهشی: مناطق 22گانه شهرداری تهران. فصلنامه مدیریت شهری، شماره 38، 423-391.##حاتمی‌نژاد، حسین؛ مهدیان بهنمیری، معصومه؛ مهدی، علی. (1391). بررسی و تحلیل عدالت فضایی برخورداری از خدمات بهداشتی- درمانی با استفاده از مدل‌های Topsis، Morris و Taxonomy، مطالعه موردی: شهرستان‌های استان مازندران. مجله آمایش جغرافیایی، 5(2)، 97-76.##خاکپور، براتعلی؛ باون‎پوری، علیرضا. (1388). بررسی و تحلیل نابرابری در سطوح توسعه‎یافتگی مناطق شهر مشهد. مجله دانش و توسعه، 15(27)، 202-183. ##داداش‎پور، هاشم؛ رستمی، فرامرز. (1390). سنجش عدالت فضایی یکپارچه خدمات عمومی شهری بر اساس توزیع جمعیت، قابلیت دسترسی و کارایی در شهر یاسوج. مجله مطالعات و پژوهش‌های شهری و منطقه‎ای، 3(10)، 22-1.##دلایی‌میلان، ابراهیم؛ خیرالدین، رضا. (1396). سنجش عدالت فضایی در بستر نظام حمل‌ونقل عمومی با مدل تحلیل شبکه‌ای (موردپژوهی: مناطق 2، 3، 4 و 5 شهر تهران). مجله نگرش‌های نو در جغرافیای انسانی، 9(3)، 39-1.‎##رحمتی، خسرو. (1393). تحلیل نابرابری‌های فضایی بر پایه شاخص‌های اجتماعی در شهرهای میانه‌اندام (مطالعه موردی: میاندوآب). پایان‌نامه کارشناسی‎ارشد جغرافیا و برنامه‎ریزی شهری، دانشکده جغرافیا، دانشگاه تبریز.##روستایی، شهریور؛ بابایی، الی‌ناز؛ کاملی‌فر، زهرا. (1392). ارزیابی عدالت فضایی در پراکنش خدمات شهری: مطالعه موردی کلان‎شهر تبریز. مجله آمایش جغرافیایی فضا، 3(10)، 100-81.##رهنما، محمدرحیم؛ ذبیحی، جواد. (1390). تحلیل توزیع تسهیلات عمومی شهری در راستای عدالت فضایی با مدل یکپارچه دسترسی در مشهد. مجله جغرافیا و توسعه، 9(23)، 26-5.##زیاری، کرامت‎اله؛ مهدیان بهنمیری، معصومه؛ مهدی، علی. (1392). بررسی و سنجش عدالت فضایی بهره‎مندی از خدمات عمومی شهری براساس توزیع جمعیت و قابلیت دسترسی در شهر بابلسر. نشریه تحقیقات کاربردی علوم جغرافیایی، 13(28)، 241-217.##سرور، رحیم؛ عشقی چهاربرج، علی؛ علوی، سعیده. (1396). تحلیل فضایی عدالت اجتماعی در بهره‎مندی از خدمات عمومی شهر، مطالعه موردی: حوزه‎های 16گانه شهر اردبیل. دو فصلنامه پژوهش‎های بوم‎شناسی شهری، 8(2)، 36-23.##شکویی، حسین. (1382). اندیشه‌های نو در فلسفه جغرافیا. جلد دوم: فلسفه‌های محیطی و مکتب‌های جغرافیایی. تهران: انتشارات گیتاشناسی. ##ضرابی، اصغر؛ وارثی، حمیدرضا؛ قنبری، محمد. (1391). تحلیل کاربری اراضی شهر جدید بینالود. نشریه برنامه‎ریزی فضایی (جغرافیا)، 2(1)، 66-49.##طهماسبی‎‎زاده، فرشاد؛ خادم‎الحسینی، احمد. (1397). تحلیل فضایی عدالت اجتماعی در مناطق شهری (مطالعه موردی مناطق شهر اصفهان). فصلنامه جغرافیا و مطالعات محیطی، 7(26)، 28-17.##قادری‎حاجت؛ مصطفی؛ مختاری‌هشی، حسین. (1396). عدالت فضایی در ایران و سامان‌دهی سیاسی فضایی شهر تهران. آمایش سیاسی فضا، 1(1)، 38-31.‎##کلانتری، خلیل. (1380). نقدی بر متدولوژی سنجش توسعه انسانی  .UNDPفصلنامه تحقیقات جغرافیایی، 16(2(پیاپی 61))، 163-156.##مرصوصی، نفیسه؛ خزایی، کاظم. (1393). توزیع فضایی خدمات شهری و نقش آن در توسعه پایدار شهر مطالعه موردی مادرشهر تهران. مجله پژوهش و برنامه‌ریزی شهری، 5(18)، 40-21.##مستوفی‎الممالکی، رضا؛ بسطامی‎نیا، امیر؛ تازش، یوسف. (1392). بررسی و تحلیل توسعه تسهیلات شهری از دیدگاه عدالت فضایی (مطالعه موردی شهر یاسوج). فصلنامه جغرافیا و مطالعات محیطی، 2(6)، 16-7.##میرآبادی، مصطفی؛ رجبی، آزیتا؛ مهدوی حاجیلویی، مسعود. (1396). تحلیل نابرابری‌های بین نواحی شهری براساس شاخص‌های اجتماعی، اقتصادی و کالبدی با استفاده از مدل‌های کمی و آمار فضایی (نمونه موردی: شهر مهاباد). نشریه مطالعات مدیریت شهری، 9(32)، 85-69.‎##نظم‌فر، حسین؛ عشقی چهاربرج، علی؛ بهروزی، مستجاب؛ علوی، سعیده. (1395). سنجش نابرابری‎های فضایی مناطق شهری از منظر عدالت اجتماعی (مطالعه موردی: مناطق ده‎گانه شهر تبریز). فصلنامه تحقیقات جغرافیایی، 31(1)، 18-1.##وارثی، حمیدرضا؛ قنبری، محمد. (1391). بررسی و تحلیل احساس تعلق خاطر و خدمات شهری در شهرهای جدید ایران (مطالعه موردی: شهر جدید بینالود). مجله جغرافیا و توسعه شهری، 1(2)، 161-139.##یزدانی، محمدحسین؛ فیروزی‌مجنده، ابراهیم. (1396). بررسی توزیع فضایی کاربری‌های عمومی از منظر عدالت فضایی مطالعه موردی؛ شهر اردبیل. نشریه جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی، 21(61)، 283-263.‎##یغفوری، حسین؛ قاسمی، سجاد؛ قاسمی، نرگس. (1396). بررسی عدالت فضایی در توزیع خدمات، با تأکید بر مدیریت شهری مطالعه موردی: محلات منطقه 19 تهران. فصلنامه تحقیقات جغرافیایی، 32(9)، 128-114.##Boone, C. G. (2013). Social dynamics and sustainable urban design. In Resilience in Ecology and Urban Design (pp. 47-61). Springer, Dordrecht. ##Boyles, S. D. (2015). Equity and network-level maintenance scheduling. EURO Journal on Transportation and Logistics, 4(1), 175-193.##Cho, C. M. (2004). Study on effects of resident-perceived neighborhood boundaries on public services accessibility &amp; its relation to utilization: using Geographic Information System, focusing on the case of public parks in Austin, Texas (Doctoral dissertation, Texas A&amp;M University).##de Almeida, A. T., &amp; Vetschera, R. (2012). A note on scale transformations in the PROMETHEE V method. European Journal of Operational Research, 219(1), 198-200.##Feng, T., &amp; Timmermans, H. J. (2014). Trade-offs between mobility and equity maximization under environmental capacity constraints: A case study of an integrated multi-objective model. Transportation Research Part C: Emerging Technologies, 43, 267-279.##Ghaedrahmati, S., Khademalhoosini, A., &amp; Tahmasebi, F. (2018). Spatial analysis of social justice in city of Isfahan, Iran. Annals of GIS, 24(1), 59-69.##Heydari Chianeh, R., Mohamadi Torkamani, H., &amp; Vaezi, M. (2017). Assessing the Spatial justice and therapeutic application based on GIS: A case report in Tabriz Metropolitan. Journal of Hospital, 16(3), 19-29.##Li, B., Li, T., Yu, M., &amp; Chen, B. (2017). Can equalization of public services narrow the regional disparities in China? A spatial econometrics approach. China Economic Review, 44, 67-78.##Liu, W., Chen, W., &amp; Dong, C. (2017). Spatial decay of recreational services of urban  ##parks: Characteristics and influencing factors. Urban Forestry &amp; Urban Greening, 25, 130-138.##Livert, F., &amp; Gainza, X. (2018). Distributive politics and spatial equity: the allocation of public investment in Chile. Regional Studies, 52(3), 403-415.##Lotfi, S., &amp; Koohsari, M. J. (2009). Measuring objective accessibility to neighbourhood facilities in the city (a case study: Zone 6 in Tehran, Iran). Cities, 26(3), 133–140.##Mavrotas, G., Diakoulaki, D., &amp; Caloghirou, Y. (2006). Project prioritization under policy restrictions. A combination of MCDA with 0–1 programming. European Journal of Operational Research, 171(1), 296-308##Morrill, R. (2015). Spatial Equity. University of Washington, Seattle, WA, USA.##Omer, I. (2006). Evaluating accessibility using house-level data: A spatial equity perspective. Computers, environment and urban systems, 30(3), 254-274.##Ouyang, W., Wang, B., Tian, L., &amp; Niu, X. (2017). Spatial deprivation of urban public services in migrant enclaves under the context of a rapidly urbanizing China: An evaluation based on suburban Shanghai. Cities, 60, 436-445.##Pitarch Garrido, M. D. (2013). Measuring Equity and social sustainability through accessibility to public services by public transport: the case of the Metropolian area of Valencia (Spain). European Journal of Geography, 2013, 4(1). 64-85.##Pringle, H. (2014). The ancient roots of the 1%.##Pugh, C. (2013). Sustainable cities in developing countries. Routledge.##Tan, P. Y., &amp; Samsudin, R. (2017). Effects of spatial scale on assessment of spatial equity of urban park provision. Landscape and Urban Planning, 158, 139-154. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تأثیر مدیریت دانش فردی بر عملکرد سازمانی شهرداری تهران</TitleF>
		<TitleE>The Effect of Individual Knowledge Management on Organizational Performance of Tehran Municipality</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>چکیده: محیط چندبعدی و پرچالش امروز، شرایط پویا و پیچیده&#8204;ای را برای بسیاری از سازمان&#8204;ها به وجود آورده است. بنابراین، پرورش و توسعه بسیاری از مهارت&#8204;ها و توانایی&#8204;ها، به منظور بهبود عملکرد سازمانی، ضروری به نظر می&#8204;رسد. یکی از مهارت&#8204;های کلیدی افراد برای موفقیت سازمان، مدیریت دانش فردی است. این مقاله، تأثیر عوامل مدیریت دانش فردی بر عملکرد سازمانی در شهرداری تهران را بررسی می&#8204;کند. نوع تحقیق از نظر هدف، کاربردی و از نظر روش انجام، توصیفی- پیمایشی می&#8204;باشد. جامعه آماری این تحقیق شامل: مدیران، مشاوران و کارشناسان متخصص و فنی شهرداری تهران در بالاترین مراتب شغلی سازمانی (سه رده) در مراتب شغلی ۱۴- ۱۵-۱۶ و تعداد آنها برابر با ۲۴۶۷ نفر می&#8204;باشد. نمونه آماری مناسب برای پژوهش حاضر برابر با ۳۳۲ نفر بر اساس روش نمونه&#8204;گیری از جوامع محدود در سطح خطای ۰۵/۰ محاسبه شده است. در این تحقیق، از ابزار پرسشنامه برای جمع&#8204;آوری داده&#8204;ها استفاده شده است. جهت بررسی مدل نهایی تحقیق، از روش معادلات ساختاری و نرم&#8204;افزار لیزرل استفاده شد. یافته&#8204;های پژوهش تأثیر مؤلفه&#8204;های ارزیابی خودآموزی، مدیریت یادگیری خویشتن، سواد اطلاعاتی، هوشیاری دانشی، مهارت&#8204;های خلاقانه، مهارت&#8204;های مشارکتی و شبکه همیاری بر عملکرد سازمانی را مورد تأیید قرار داد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Abstract: Today&#8217;s multidimensional and challenging environment has created dynamic and complex conditions for many organizations. Therefore, the development of many of the knowledge workers&#8217; skills and abilities is necessary in order to improve organizational performance. One of the key skills of individuals for organizational success is individual knowledge management. This paper examines the effects of individual knowledge management factors on organizational performance in Tehran municipality. This research is applied and a descriptive survey in terms of purpose. The statistical population of this research is managers, consultants, and technical experts of Tehran Municipality in the highest organizational occupation (three categories) in terms of career 15-16 14-16 including 2467 people. The statistical sample suitable for the present study is equal to 332 people based on the sampling method of limited communities at the error level of 0.05. In this research, a questionnaire was used to collect data. Structural Equation Modeling and LISREL software were used to study the final model of the research. The findings of the study confirmed the effect of components of self-learning evaluation, self-learning management, information literacy, knowledge consciousness, creative skills, participatory skills and collaborative network on organizational performance.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>45</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>58</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>وجه‌الله</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>قربانی‌زاده</Family>
				<NameE>Vajhollah</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ghorbanizadeh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Management and Accounting, Allameh Tabatabaei University, Tehran, Iran Habib Roodsaz</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>vghorbanizadeh@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حبیب</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رودساز</Family>
				<NameE>Habib</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Roodsaz</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Management and Accounting, Allameh Tabatabaei University, Tehran, Iran Fatah Sharifzadeh</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>فتاح</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شریف‌زاده</Family>
				<NameE>Fatah</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Sharifzadeh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Management and Accounting, Allameh Tabatabaei University, Tehran, Iran Mohammad Sadeghi</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>صادقی</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Sadeghi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Management and Accounting, Allameh Tabatabaei University, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Individual Knowledge Management</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Collaboration Network</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Learning Management</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Knowledge Intelligence</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Organizational Performance</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدیریت دانش فردی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شبکه همکاری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدیریت یادگیری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>هوشمندی دانشی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عملکرد سازمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شهرداری تهران</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##ابراهیم‌زاده، عیسی. (1391). اصول و فرایند برنامه‌ریزی راهبردی توسعه توریسم. مشهد: صحرا (شرق).##امیری، محمدرضا؛ سکاکی، محمدرضا. (1387). دانشگاه علوم و تکنولوژی منچستر، راهنمای ارزیابی عملکرد سازمان بر اساس مدل تعالی EFQM. تهران: سرآمد.##انتظاری‌یزدی، مسعود. (1394). تعیین سبک رهبری اثربخش در شهرداری مشهد. کنفرانس بین‌المللی معماری، شهرسازی و مهندسی عمران، تهران.##باسمری، نسیمه؛ کشته‎گر، عبدالعلی؛ مهدی‌بیگی، نجمه. (1397). بررسی تأثیر کارکردهای مدیریت منابع انسانی الکترونیک بر نوآوری سازمانی با نقش میانجیگری قابلیت‎های مدیریت دانش. نشریه پژوهش‎های مدیریت عمومی، 11(41)، 164-139.##باقری، امین. (1394). مدیریت دانش فردی: شایستگی رقابتی دانشگران. نشریه پژوهش‌های تربیتی، شماره 30، 22-1.##بیک‎زاده، جعفر؛ صادقی، محمد؛ ابراهیم‌پور، داود. (1391). تأثیر عوامل سازمانی بر رشد اخلاق حرفه‌ای کارکنان. فصلنامه اخلاق در علوم و فناوری، 7(2)، 66-57.##رجبی‎فرجاد، حاجیه؛ مطیعیان نجار، مجید. (1397). تأثیر مدیریت دانش بر عملکرد سازمانی با ملاحظه نقش میانجی اقدامات راهبردی مدیریت منابع انسانی. نشریه پژوهش‎های مدیریت منابع انسانی دانشگاه جامع امام حسین، 10(3)، 191-124.##رحیمی، ابراهیم. (1396). بررسی تأثیر مدیریت دانش بر عملکرد مالی با میانجی‎گری یادگیری سازمانی. نشریه نوآوری‎های مدیریت آموزشی، 12(4(پیاپی 48))، 21-7.##رضائی، روح‌اله؛ صلاحی‎مقدم، نفیسه؛ شعبانعلی قمی، حسین. (1393). بررسی اثر مدیریت دانش بر عملکرد سازمانی در سازمان جهاد کشاورزی استان البرز. نشریه پژوهش‌های ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی، 7(4(پیاپی 28))، 91-77.##رهنوردآهن، فرج‌الله. (1387). عوامل مؤثر بر ارتقای عملکرد سازمان‌های بخش دولتی ایران. نشریه پژوهشنامه مدیریت، 8(4(پیاپی31))، 100-77.##سعادت، اسفندیار. (1392). مدیریت منابع انسانی. چاپ هجدهم، تهران: سمت.##عباسقلی، رضا. (1391). بررسی رابطه میان مدیریت دانش و عملکرد سازمانی شرکت‌های صادرکننده محصولات با فناوری بالا (های تک). پایان‎نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی.##فضلی، صفر؛ علیشاهی، آیدین. (1391). بررسی اثر عوامل درون‎سازمانی بر عملکرد سازمان با در نظر گرفتن نقش مدیریت دانش. نشریه پژوهش‌های مدیریت منابع انسانی، 4(2(پیاپی 12))، 100-73.##قربانی‌زاده، وجه‌الله؛ جعفری فارسانی، جواد. (۱۳۸۸). توسعه قابلیت‌های سازمانی و استراتژی‌های مدیریت دانش. دومین کنفرانس ملی مدیریت دانش، تهران.##قربانی‌زاده، وجه‌الله؛ حبیبی بدرآبادی، حسین؛ ابراهیم‌زاده، حسین. (1391). نقش تعدیل‌کننده فرایند یادگیری در رابطه بین سرمایه فکری و عملکرد سازمانی. فصلنامه پژوهش‌های مدیریت عمومی، 5(16)، 161-135.##قربانی‌زاده، وجه‌الله؛ محمدی‌مقدم، یوسف. (1391). الگوی مدیریت دانش در سازمان ناجا. نشریه مطالعات مدیریت انتظامی، 7(3)، 345-328.##قنبری، فائزه؛ فضل‎الله تبار، حامد. (1396). طراحی سیستم بازاریابی هوشمند برای شرکت‎های کوچک و متوسط. نشریه مطالعات مهندسی صنایع و مدیریت تولید، 3(2)، 52-39.##کاپلان، رابرت. نورتون، دیوید. (1389). سازمان استراتژی‌محور. ترجمه پرویز بختیاری، تهران: سازمان مدیریت صنعتی.##محمدی، رضا. (1396). بررسی رابطه مدیریت دانش با عملکرد سازمانی در سازمان‎های پروژه‎محور. دوماهنامه کاربردی در علوم مدیریت و توسعه، 2(1(پیاپی 3))، 14-1.##نمامیان، فرشید؛ فیض‎الهی، صادق. (1394). تأثیر فرهنگ سازمانی بر عملکرد سازمان با نقش میانجی نوآوری (مطالعه موردی شهرک صنعتی ایلام). نشریه فرهنگ ایلام، 16(46 و 47)، 161-174.##Alrubaiee, L., Alzubi, H. M., Hanandeh, R. E., &amp; Al Ali, R. (2015). Investigating the relationship between knowledge management processes and organizational performance the mediating effect of organizational innovation. International Review of Management and Business Research, 4(4 Part 1), 989.##Byars, L.I &amp; Rue, L.W. (2008). Human Resource Management: 9 th Edition. New York: Mc GrawHill.##Ha, S. T., Lo, M. C., &amp; Wang, Y. C. (2016). Relationship between knowledge management and organizational performance: a test on SMEs in Malaysia. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 224, 184-189.##Hatum, A. (2007). Adaptation or expiration in family firms: Organizational flexibility in emerging economies. Edward Elgar Publishing.##Jaradat, N. M. S., &amp; Al Maani, A. I. (2014). The impact of knowledge management infrastructure on performance effectiveness in Jordanian organizations. Arab Economic and Business Journal, 9(1), 27-36.##Liao, S. H., &amp; Wu, C. C. (2009). The relationship among knowledge management, organizational learning, and organizational performance. International journal of business and management, 4(4), 64-76.##Muthuveloo, R., Shanmugam, N., &amp; Teoh, A. P. (2017). The impact of tacit knowledge management on organizational performance: Evidence from Malaysia. Asia Pacific Management Review, 22(4), 192-201.##Noe, R.A, Hollenbeck, J. R, Gerhurt, B &amp; Wright, P.M. (2008). Human Resource Management: gaining Competitive advantage. New York: Mc GrawHill.##Theriou, N., Maditinos, D., &amp; Theriou, G. (2011). Knowledge management enabler factors and firm performance: an empirical research of the Greek medium and large firms. European Research Studies, 14(2), 97.##Verma, S. (2009). Personal knowledge management: a tool to expand knowledge about human cognitive capabilities. International Journal of Engineering and Technology, 1(5), 435.##Zheng, W., Yang, B., &amp; McLean, G. N. (2010). Linking organizational culture, structure, strategy, and organizational effectiveness: Mediating role of knowledge management. Journal of Business research, 63(7), 763-771.##Zhou, D., &amp; He, E. (2009, December). Notice of Retraction Research on Web_Based Personal Knowledge Management. In 2009 Pacific-Asia Conference on Knowledge Engineering and Software Engineering (pp. 116-119). IEEE ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تحلیل پراکنده‌رویی شهری با استفاده از فن تحلیل‌عاملی (مورد مطالعه: نواحی شهر قزوین)</TitleF>
		<TitleE>An Analysis of Urban Sprawl Using Factor Analysis Technique (Case: Qazvin City Districts)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>چکیده: پراکنده&#8204;رویی، یکی از معضلات شهرهای سراسر جهان است که اثرات منفی فراوانی بر زندگی شهری داشته است. به طور کلی، این پدیده به گسترش افقی و چندپاره شهرها ناشی از تمایل شهروندان برای خروج از ناحیه مرکزی شهر و اسکان در حومه اطلاق می&#8204;شود. اولین گام در مواجهه با این معضل، شناسایی مکان و عوامل مؤثر بر این پدیده در پهنه&#8204;های شهری است. از همین رو، مقاله حاضر به تحلیل پدیده پراکنده&#8204;رویی در نواحی شهر قزوین می&#8204;پردازد. با تکیه بر متون نظری مرتبط، شاخص&#8204;های مختلف برای سنجش این پدیده، معرفی شده و ۱۳ شاخص منتخب، استخراج گردید. این شاخص&#8204;ها با توجه به شرایط ایران، بومی&#8204;سازی شده و داده&#8204;های مرتبط با هر یک از آن&#8204;ها با استفاده از آمار سرشماری و سیستم اطلاعات جغرافیایی (GIS) استخراج شدند. سپس با استفاده از تحلیل&#8204;عاملی داده&#8204;ها به کمک نرم&#8204;افزار SPSS، شاخص&#8204;ها در ذیل چهار عامل تراکم، پیکربندی، کاربری و دسترسی قرار گرفتند. هر یک از این عوامل به ترتیب ۸/۲۷، ۶/۲۱، ۳/۱۱ و ۵/۹ درصد از واریانس پدیده پراکنده&#8204;رویی را تبیین می&#8204;کنند. بر این اساس مشخص شد که شاخص شکل و بعد فرکتال به عنوان شاخص&#8204;های جدید معرفی&#8204;شده برای سنجش پراکنده&#8204;رویی، به میزان بالایی بر پراکنده&#8204;رویی اثرگذار هستند. همچنین نتایج نشان می&#8204;دهند که نواحی ۴، ۵، ۷، ۱۱ و ۱۲ بیشترین پراکنده&#8204;رویی و نواحی ۱۷، ۲۸، ۳۸ و ۳۹، کمترین پراکنده&#8204;رویی را دارند. این دو شاخص جدید، در مطالعات ایران می&#8204;توانند در سایر مطالعات مربوط به پراکنده&#8204;رویی در شهرهای کشور نیز به&#8204;کار گرفته شوند. همچنین نتایج این پژوهش می&#8204;توانند هدایت&#8204;گر مدیریت شهری قزوین برای هدایت جهات توسعه شهر باشند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Abstract: Urban sprawl is an issue in many cities throughout the world, which has affected many aspects of urban life negatively. Urban sprawl, which is generally attributed to horizontal and leapfrogged extension of city boundaries caused by citizen&#8217;s will to leave central urban areas and live in urban countryside. The first step for tackling this problem is the identification of sprawled places and the influential factors on sprawl in urban land. Therefore, this article analyses urban sprawl phenomenon in Qazvin city districts. Relying on relevant theoretical texts, 13 indicators are chosen among others in literature for measuring urban sprawl in Qazvin districts. These indices are localized according to the conditions of Iran and the data associated with each of them are extracted using census statistics and Geographic Information System (GIS). Then, factor analysis technique is implemented by SPSS software and the indicators are attributed to four factors. By assessing the contributing indicators to each factor, they are named density, configuration, land-use and accessibility respectively. The results of factor analysis are very consistent with literature. These factors explain the variance of urban sprawl by 27.8, 21.6, 11.3 and 9.5 percent respectively. It is shown that &#34;shape index&#34; and &#34;fractal dimension&#34; as new indicators for measuring urban sprawl are significantly effective on this phenomenon. Results show that districts 4, 5, 7, 11 and 12 are the most sprawled and districts 17, 28, 38 and 39 are the least sprawled districts in Qazvin. These two new indexes in Iranian urban literature can be used in other sprawl studies in the country. In addition, the results of this study can guide Qazvin municipality to make important decisions about the direction of city development.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>59</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>78</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>اسفندیار</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>زبردست</Family>
				<NameE>Esfandiyar</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Zebardast</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Urban Development, College of Fine Arts, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran Hossein Ghanooni</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده شهرسازی، پردیس هنرهای زیبا، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>zebardst@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>قانونی</Family>
				<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ghanooni</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>School of Architecture and Urban Development, Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده معماری و شهرسازی، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Urban Sprawl</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Factor Analysis</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Configuration</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Qazvin</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پراکنده‌رویی شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تحلیل‌عاملی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پیکربندی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شهر قزوین</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##احمدی، قادر؛ عزیزی، محمدمهدی؛ زبردست، اسفندیار. (1389). بررسی تطبیقی پراکنده‌رویی در سه شهر میانی ایران (نمونه موردی: شهرهای اردبیل، سنندج و کاشان). نشریه نامه معماری و شهرسازی، 3(5)، 43-25.##حسینی، سید ‌هادی؛ حسینی، معصومه. (1394). تحلیل عوامل مؤثر بر ایجاد پراکنده‌رویی در مناطق شهری ایران. نشریه برنامه‌ریزی و آمایش فضا، 19(4)، 66-33.##رئیسی جلودار، حامد؛ اسفندیاری، محمد اسماعیل. (1392). تبیین روند رشد کالبدی پراکنده (پراکنده‌رویی) شهری بر اساس مدل هلدرن (مطالعه موردی: شهر ساری). نشریه مطالعات محیطی هفت حصار، 2(5)، 26-21. ##زبردست، اسفندیار. (1390). درسنامه روش‌های برنامه‌ریزی شهری و منطقه‌ای 2. دانشکده شهرسازی، پردیس هنرهای زیبا، دانشگاه تهران.##زبردست، اسفندیار؛ حبیبی، سارا. (1388). بررسی پدیده پراکنده‌رویی و علل آن در شهر زنجان. نشریه هنرهای زیبا- معماری و شهرسازی، شماره 38، 124-115.##سرداری، محمدرضا؛ براتی، ناصر. (1388). برنامه توسعه راهبردی (استراتژیک) شهری: برنامه توسعه راهبردی شهر قزوین تا سال 1410 (از تئوری تا عمل). تهران: نشر آرتابابا.##عزیزی، محمدمهدی؛ آراسته، مجتبی. (1390). تبیین پراکنده‌رویی شهری براساس شاخص تراکم ساختمانی (مطالعه موردی شهر یزد). نشریه هویت شهر، 5(8)، 15-5.##مهندسین مشاور شهر و برنامه. (1384). طرح توسعه و عمران و حوزه نفوذ شهر قزوین.##موسوی، میرنجف؛ آهار، حسن؛ منوچهری، ایوب؛ قیصری، حدیث. (1394). تحلیل اثرات رشد پراکنده‌رویی شهری بر سرمایه اجتماعی (رهیافت رگرسیون وزنی جغرافیایی (GWR)- نمونه موردی: شهر مراغه). نشریه شهر پایدار، 2(2)، 66-51.##Angel, S., Parent, J., &amp; Civco, D. (2007, May). Urban sprawl metrics: an analysis of global urban expansion using GIS. In Proceedings of ASPRS 2007 Annual Conference, Tampa, Florida May (Vol. 7, No. 11). Citeseer.##Bhatta, B., Saraswati, S., &amp; Bandyopadhyay, D. (2010). Urban sprawl measurement from remote sensing data. Applied geography, 30(4), 731-740.##Bogart, W. T. (2006). Don't Call it Sprawl: Metropolitan Structure in the 21st century. Cambridge University Press.##Braçe, O. (2016). Study of the Effects of Urban Morphology on Physical Activity. Revista De Estudios Andaluces, 33 (1), 24–39.##Cutsinger, J., Galster, G., Wolman, H., Hanson, R., &amp; Towns, D. (2005). Verifying the multi-dimensional nature of metropolitan land use: Advancing the understanding and measurement of  ##sprawl. Journal of Urban Affairs, 27(3), 235-259.##Ehrlich, M. V., Hilber, C. A., &amp; Schöni, O. (2018). Institutional settings and urban sprawl: Evidence from Europe. Journal of Housing Economics, 42, 4-18.##Estiri, H. (2014). Building and household X-factors and energy consumption at the residential sector: A structural equation analysis of the effects of household and building characteristics on the annual energy consumption of US residential buildings. Energy Economics, 43, 178-184.##Ewing, R. H., Pendall, R., &amp; Chen, D. D. (2002). Measuring sprawl and its impact (Vol. 1, p. 55). Washington, DC: Smart Growth America.##Ewing, R., Brownson, R. C., &amp; Berrigan, D. (2006). Relationship between urban sprawl and weight of United States youth. American journal of preventive medicine, 31(6), 464-474.##Frenkel, A., &amp; Ashkenazi, M. (2008). The integrated sprawl index: measuring the urban landscape in Israel. The Annals of Regional Science, 42(1), 99-121.##Galster, G., Hanson, R., Ratcliffe, M. R., Wolman, H., Coleman, S., &amp; Freihage, J. (2001). Wrestling sprawl to the ground: defining and measuring an elusive concept. Housing policy debate, 12(4), 681-717.##Garrido-Cumbrera, M., Ruiz, D. G., Braçe, O., &amp; Lara, E. L. (2018). Exploring the association between urban sprawl and mental health. Journal of Transport &amp; Health, 10, 381-390.##Habibi, S., &amp; Asadi, N. (2011). Causes, results and methods of controlling urban sprawl. Procedia Engineering, 21, 133-141.##Hamidi, S., &amp; Ewing, R. (2014). A longitudinal study of changes in urban sprawl between 2000 and 2010 in the United States. Landscape and Urban Planning, 128, 72-82.##Hennig, E. I., Schwick, C., Soukup, T., Orlitová, E., Kienast, F., &amp; Jaeger, J. A. (2015). Multi-scale analysis of urban sprawl in Europe: Towards a European de-sprawling strategy. Land Use Policy, 49, 483-498.##Jaeger, J. A., &amp; Schwick, C. (2014). Improving the measurement of urban sprawl: Weighted Urban Proliferation (WUP) and its application to Switzerland. Ecological indicators, 38, 294-308.##Jaeger, J. A., Bertiller, R., Schwick, C., Cavens, D., &amp; Kienast, F. (2010). Urban permeation of landscapes and sprawl per capita: New measures of urban sprawl. Ecological Indicators, 10(2), 427-441.##Kahn, M. E. (2001). Does sprawl reduce the black/white housing consumption gap?. Housing Policy Debate, 12(1), 77-86.##Liu, Z., Liu, S., Qi, W., &amp; Jin, H. (2018). Urban sprawl among Chinese cities of different population sizes. Habitat International, 79, 89-98.##Navamuel, E. L., Morollón, F. R., &amp; Cuartas, B. M. (2018). Energy consumption and urban sprawl: Evidence for the Spanish case. Journal of cleaner production, 172, 3479-3486.##Nazarnia, N., Schwick, C., &amp; Jaeger, J. A. (2016). Accelerated urban sprawl in Montreal, Quebec City, and Zurich: Investigating the differences using time series 1951–2011. Ecological indicators, 60, 1229-1251.##Nechyba, T. J., &amp; Walsh, R. P. (2004). Urban sprawl. Journal of economic perspectives, 18(4), 177-200.##Patacchini, E., Zenou, Y., Henderson, J. V., &amp; Epple, D. (2009). Urban sprawl in Europe. Brookings-Wharton Papers on Urban Affairs, 125-149.##Paulsen, K. (2014). Geography, policy or market? New evidence on the measurement and causes of sprawl (and infill) in US metropolitan regions. Urban Studies, 51(12), 2629-2645.##Terzi, F., &amp; Bolen, F. (2009). Urban sprawl measurement of Istanbul. European Planning Studies, 17(10), 1559-1570.##Tian, L., Li, Y., Yan, Y., &amp; Wang, B. (2017). Measuring urban sprawl and exploring the role planning plays: A shanghai case study. Land Use Policy, 67, 426-435.##Torrens, P. M. (2006). Simulating sprawl. Annals of the Association of American Geographers, 96(2), 248-275.##Weilenmann, B., Seidl, I., &amp; Schulz, T. (2017). The socio-economic determinants of urban sprawl between 1980 and 2010 in Switzerland. Landscape and Urban Planning, 157, 468-482.##Yue, Wenze; Zhang, Linlin &amp; Liu, Yong (2016). Measuring sprawl in large Chinese ctities along the Yangtze River via combined single and multidimensional metrics. Habitat International (57), 43-52.##Zhang, C., Miao, C., Zhang, W., &amp; Chen, X. (2018). Spatiotemporal patterns of urban sprawl and its relationship with economic development in China during 1990–2010. Habitat International, 79, 51-60.##Zhang, T. (2000). Land market forces and government's role in sprawl: The case of China. Cities, 17(2), 123-135. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>شبیه‌سازی تحت شبکه تولید غیرمتمرکز برق تجدیدپذیر در بخش روشنایی معابر شهری در چارچوب الگوی مدیریت پایدار شهری (مورد مطالعه: شهرستان مشهد)</TitleF>
		<TitleE>On-Grid Simulation of Distributed Generation (DG) of Renewable Electricity in Urban Lighting in the Context of Sustainable Urban Management (Case: Mashhad)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>چکیده: روشنایی معابر برای رفاه شهروندان و هم&#8204;زمان با اوج مصرف شبکه، از زمان غروب خورشید تا زمان طلوع آن برقرار می&#8204;شود. در این پژوهش با هدف طراحی یک الگوی مدیریت پایدار شهری در زمینه تأمین انرژی روشنایی معابر، از شبیه&#8204;سازی به&#8204;کارگیری تکنولوژی LED&#8204;های فتوولتاییک به&#8204;جای لامپ&#8204;های سدیمی و هالوژن استفاده&#8204; شده است. بر این اساس در یک شبیه&#8204;سازی سیستمی تحت شبکه، سناریوهای تعدیل ورود ظرفیت&#8204;های مختلف فتوولتاییک به سیستم تولید تأمین&#8204;کننده برق شهرستان مشهد، بررسی شده است. نتایج برنامه&#8204;ریزی آنالیزی تحت شبکه به&#8204;کارگیری این الگوی تولید غیرمتمرکز (پراکنده) نشان می&#8204;دهد که با در نظر گرفتن ظرفیت ۲۰۰ واتی و ضریب بهره&#8204;برداری ۲۰ درصدی برای هر یک از &#8204;LEDهای فتوولتاییک و نصب یک LED فتوولتاییک به جای چراغ&#8204;های سدیمی و هالوژنی، تمامی توان موردنیاز برای تأمین برق روشنایی معابر شهری با تکنولوژی خورشیدی فتوولتاییک تأمین می&#8204;شود و با ایجاد قابلیت جانشین&#8204;پذیری میان تولید فسیلی و تجدیدپذیر، انتشار آلاینده زیست&#8204;محیطی نیز به میزان ۱۰۴ هزار تن کاهش می&#8204;یابد. بنابراین می&#8204;توان از این روش برای مدیریت پاک و پایدار انرژی در مقیاس مصارف شهری استفاده کرد و ضمن کمک به محیط&#8204;زیست و کاهش آلودگی هوا، از تلفات ناشی از انتقال انرژی الکتریکی از نیروگاه به محل مصرف نیز جلوگیری نمود.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Abstract: Lighting passages is done for citizens&#8217; welfare simultaneously with the peak of the consumption of the network, from sunset to sunrise. The present study aimed at designing a model of sustainable urban management in the field of lighting, with simulation of the use of photovoltaic LEDs instead of sodium and halogen lamps. Accordingly, in a system simulation of the network, the scenarios for adjusting the input of various photovoltaic capacities to the electricity supply system of the city of Mashhad have been investigated. The results of on-grid analysis by using this decentralized production pattern shows, taking into account the 200 watts capacity and the 20% utilization factor for each photovoltaic LEDs and installing a photovoltaic LED instead of sodium and halogen lamps, all the power needed to lighting of city streets is provided by photovoltaic solar technology. Moreover, by reducing the potential between fossil and renewable production, emissions of pollutants are reduced by 104,000 tons. Therefore, this method can be used to manage clean and sustainable energy in urban scale consumption, and, while helping the environment and reducing air pollution, it prevents losses caused by the transfer of electrical energy from the plant to the place of consumption.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>79</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>92</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهدی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>قائمی‎اصل</Family>
				<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ghaemi Asl</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Economic, Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran Davoud Manzoor</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده اقتصاد، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>m.ghaemi@khu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>داود</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>منظور</Family>
				<NameE>Davoud</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Manzoor</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Islamic Studies &#38; Economics, Imam Sadiq University (I.S.U.), Tehran, Iran Seyyed Mahdi Mousavi Barrodi</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده معارف اسلامی و اقتصاد، دانشگاه امام صادق (ع)، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهدی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>موسوی بررودی</Family>
				<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Mousavi Barrodi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Islamic Studies &#38; Economics, Imam Sadiq University (I.S.U.), Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده معارف اسلامی و اقتصاد، دانشگاه امام صادق (ع)، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>On-Grid Simulation</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Sustainable Urban Management</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Photovoltaic Technology</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شبیه‌سازی تحت شبکه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدیریت پایدار شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تکنولوژی فتوولتاییک</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شهرستان مشهد</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##اصغری‌زاده، عزت‌الله؛ مهرگان، محمدرضا؛ شکوری، حامد؛ مدرس‌یزدی، محمد؛ تقی‌زاده یزدی، محمدرضا. (1396). ارائه مدل ریاضی برای توسعه ظرفیت نیروگاه‎ها با در نظر گرفتن واحدهای تولید پراکنده و با هدف کنترل دی‎اکسیدکربن. فصلنامه مدیریت صنعتی، 4(9)، 608-587.##آمار تفصیلی صنعت برق ایران. (1391). توزیع نیروی برق، وزارت نیرو، شرکت مادرتخصصی توانیر، تهران.##تهامی‎پور، مرتضی؛ عابدی، سمانه؛ بابا احمدی، رضا کریمی؛ ابراهیمی‎زاده، مرتضی. (1395). بررسی تأثیر انرژی‌های تجدیدپذیر بر سرانه رشد اقتصادی واقعی ایران، پژوهشنامه اقتصاد انرژی ایران، 5(19)، 77-53.##حاتمی، مهدی؛ ناظمی، علی؛ دولت‎آبادی، اعظم؛ مصطفی‎پور، مصطفی. (1393). ارزیابی اقتصادی استفاده از سیستم فتوولتائیک مستقل از شبکه در روستاها با شبیه‎سازی مونت‌کارلو (مطالعه موردی: تهران). نشریه راهبردهای توسعه روستایی، 1(2)، 33-19.##حسینی، سیدباقر؛ رضازاده، راضیه؛ باقری، محمد؛ عظمتی، حمیدرضا؛ قنبران، عبدالحمید. (1388). پایداری زیست‌محیطی در فضاهای باز شهری: ارزیابی کیفی محلات مسکونی در تبریر. فصلنامه علوم و تکنولوژی محیط‎زیست، 4(11)، 184-173.##خلاصه تحولات اقتصادی کشور. (1391). بانک مرکزی جمهوری اسلامی ایران، تهران.##رازدان، مهسا. (1385). ‎‌سیاست‌های بهره‌گیری از انرژی‌های تجدیدپذیر غیربرق- آبی در کشورهای منتخب و جایگاه ایران. نشریه مطالعات اقتصاد انرژی‎، شماره 10، 115-68.##رجبی‎مشهدی، حبیب. (1389). بررسی اثربخشی فعالیت‌های مدیریت مصرف در سکتورهای مختلف پس از واقعی شدن قیمت‌های برق. گزارش پروژه اینترنشیپ، شرکت برق منطقه‌ای خراسان، مشهد.##رستمی، ثریا؛ حق‌پرست کاشانی، آرش؛ لاری، حمیدرضا (1392) مطالعه و برآورد قیمت برق تولیدی از نیروگاه‌های بادی، خورشیدی و بیوگاز. نخستین کنفرانس ملی انجمن انرژی ایران، تهران.##زینل‌زاده، رضا؛ صادقی، زین‌العابدین؛ دهقان‎پور، محمدرضا؛ قائدی، مهدی. (1391). ‎‌ارزیابی اقتصادی و زیست‌محیطی سیستم‌های فتوولتاییک: مطالعه‌ موردی منطقه‌ جنوب شرق ایران. ‎‌نشریه مطالعات اقتصاد انرژی‎، 9(33)، 149-115.##سازمان انرژی‌های نو ایران (سانا) (1386) گزارش پتانسیل منابع زیست‌توده در ایران، وزارت نیرو، معاونت امور انرژی.##سعیدخانی، محمد؛ فلاحی، اسماعیل، بانشی، مهدی. (1395). ارائه مدل مدیریت تأمین انرژی در ایران براساس معیارهای فنی، اقتصادی و زیست‌محیطی. پژوهشنامه اقتصاد انرژی ایران، 5(18)، 60-29.##شرکت برق منطقه‌ای خراسان. (1391 الف). گزارش اقدامات شرکت برق منطقه‎ای خراسان در زمینه توسعه انرژی‎های تجدیدپذیر، مشهد.##شرکت برق منطقه‎ای خراسان. (1391 ب). بودجه مصوب سال 1391، معاونت برنامه‌ریزی و تحقیقات، دفتر بودجه و مطالعات اقتصادی.##طاهری‎فرد، علی؛ شهاب، سمیه. (1389). بررسی جنبه‌های فنی و اقتصادی تولید برق زمین‌گرمایی. نشریه اقتصاد انرژی، شماره 125 و 126، 39-31.##عباسی‎ورده، محمدعلی؛ حنیفی، محمدفرید؛ فخاری، اکبر. (1387). بررسی میدانی کاربرد چراغ‎های روشنایی معابر با منبع نور.LED  بیست وسومین کنفرانس بین‎المللی برق.##فطرس، محمد‌حسن؛ آقازاده، اکبر؛ جبرائیلی، سودا. (1391). ‎‌بررسی میزان تأثیر مصرف انرژی‌های تجدیدپذیر و تجدیدناپذیر بر رشد اقتصادی کشورهای منتخب درحال‌توسعه (شامل ایران)، دوره‌ زمانی 2009 – 1980. ‎‌نشریه مطالعات اقتصاد انرژی‎، 9(32)، 72-51.##قائمی‎اصل، مهدی؛ سلیمی‌فر، مصطفی؛ مهدوی‎عادلی، محمدحسین. (1395). شبیه‌سازی ایجاد شهر زیست‌محیطی کم‌کربن با بهره‎گیری از پسماندهای شهری و تکنولوژی فتوولتائیک: برنامه‎ریزی پایدار انرژی بخش شهری مشهد مقدس. نشریه اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری، 5(17)، 81-67.##کاظمیان، غلامرضا؛ رسولی، افشین؛ خزایی، محمدمهدی. (1396). جایگاه انرژی‌های نو و تجدیدپذیر در زیست‎پذیرانه کردن شهرها، مطالعه موردی شهر تهران. فصلنامه پژوهش و برنامه‎ریزی شهری، 8(29)، 118-99.##کهنسال، محمدرضا؛ شایان مهر، سمیرا. (1395). آثار متقابل مصرف انرژی، رشد اقتصادی و آلودگی محیط‌زیست: کاربرد الگوی معادلات همزمان فضایی داده‌های تابلویی. پژوهشنامه اقتصاد انرژی ایران، 5(19)، 216-179.##معاونت هماهنگی توزیع شرکت توانیر. (1390). نظام‌نامه مدیریت مصرف انرژی الکتریکی:##مهدوی‎عادلی، محمدحسین؛ سلیمی‎فر، مصطفی؛ قزلباش، اعظم. (1393). ارزیابی اقتصادی استفاده از انرژی برق خورشیدی (فتوولتاییک) و برق فسیلی در مصارف خانگی (مطالعه موردی مجتمع سه واحدی در شهرستان مشهد. نشریه سیاست‎گذاری اقتصادی، 6(11)، 147-123.##مهرابی بشرآبادی، حسین؛ صادقی، زین‎العابدین؛ شجاع‎الدینی، حمیده. (1397). ارزیابی اقتصادی و زیست‌محیطی سیستم‎های فتوولتاییک در کاربری تجاری و شبیه‎سازی پویای قمیت برق. نشریه اقتصاد انرژی ایران، 7(27)، 201-159. ##نوا‌بخش، مهرداد؛ ثابتی، مریم. (1394). طراحی و ارائه الگو جهت سنجش تأثیر سرمایه فرهنگی بر ابعاد توسعه پایدار شهری با تأکید بر انرژی‎های پاک. مجله مطالعات توسعه اجتماعی ایران، 8(1)، 50-37.##Ali, M., Orabi, M., Abdelkarim, E., Qahouq, J. A. A., &amp; El Aroudi, A. (2011, December). Design and development of energy-free solar street LED light system. In 2011 IEEE PES Conference on Innovative Smart Grid Technologies-Middle East (pp. 1-7). IEEE.##Bohn, R. E., Caramanis, M. C., &amp; Schweppe, F. C. (1984). Optimal pricing in electrical networks over space and time. The Rand Journal of Economics, 360-376.##Danish Energy Agency. (2012). Assumptions for socio‐economic analysis on energy. Danish Energy Agency.##Das, N., Pal, N., &amp; Pradip, S. K. (2015). Economic cost analysis of LED over HPS flood lights for an efficient exterior lighting design using solar PV. Building and Environment, 89, 380-392.##Galvão, J. R., Moreira, L. M., Ascenso, R. M., &amp; Leitão, S. A. (2015). Energy systems models for efficiency towards Smart Cities. In IEEE EUROCON 2015-International Conference on Computer as a Tool (EUROCON) (pp. 1-6). IEEE.##Lund, H. (2014) Advanced Energy Systems Analysis Computer Model, Documentation Version 11.4, Aalborg University, Denmar.##Smith, E., Simpson, R., &amp; Nicola, S. (2013). Lighting up the streets, The cases of Sydney, Australia، and Nagpur, India,  ##ICLEI-Local Governments for Sustainability and IRENA- International Renewable Energy Agency##Wu, M. S., Huang, H. H., Huang, B. J., Tang, C. W., &amp; Cheng, C. W. (2009). Economic feasibility of solar-powered led roadway lighting. Renewable energy, 34(8), 1934-1938.##Zelinka, I. (2001). Analytic programming by means of new evolutionary algorithms. In Proceedings of 1st International Conference on New Trends in Physics (Vol. 1, pp. 210-214).##Zelinka, I. (2002 a). Analytic programming by means of soma algorithm. In Proceedings of the 8th International Conference on Soft Computing, Mendel (Vol. 2, pp. 93-101).##Zelinka, I. (2002b). Analytic programming by means of soma algorithm، Proc. 8th International Conference on Soft Computing, VUT Brno, Mendel’02 Czech Republic, 93–101.##Zelinka, I., Oplatkova, Z., &amp; Nolle, L. (2005). Analytic programming- symbolic regression by means of arbitrary evolutionary algorithms, In: Special Issue on Inteligent Systems of International Journal of Simulation, Systems, Science and Technology, 6(9), 44–55. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>طراحی الگوی بهبود محیط کسب‌وکار شهر تهران</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Designing a Model for Improving Business Environment in the City of Tehran</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>چکیده: بهبود محیطی که کسب&#8204;وکارها در درون آن فعالیت می&#8204;کنند برای موفقیت کسب&#8204;وکارها حائز اهمیت است. به&#8204;ویژه بهبود محیط، هزینه مبادله را کاهش و توان رقابتی کسب&#8204;وکارها را ارتقا می&#8204;دهد. محیط کسب&#8204;وکار شهری، ویژگی&#8204;های منحصر&#8204;به&#8204;فردی دارد که برای درک، تحلیل و کاربرد آن، به شناخت آن در ابعاد گوناگون آن، نیاز است. این پژوهش، درصدد است الگویی برای بهبود محیط کسب&#8204;وکار شهر تهران طراحی کند. برای این منظور، ابتدا دانش صریح موجود در ادبیات، مرور و سپس با استفاده از روش پژوهش کیفی، دانش ضمنی از طریق مصاحبه با ۲۲ نفر از خبرگان دریافت شد. پس از مستندسازی، داده&#8204;های حاصل از مصاحبه&#8204;ها با استفاد از رویکرد زمینه&#8204;ای در سه مرحله، کدگذاری و با نرم&#8204;افزار Atlas Ti پردازش شدند. در پایان، با تلفیق یافته&#8204;های حاصل از مطالعات و تحلیل مصاحبه&#8204;ها، الگوی بهبود محیط کسب&#8204;وکار در شهر تهران ارائه شد. شایان ذکر است این الگو عوامل محیطی مؤثر بر بهبود محیط کسب&#8204;وکار شهر تهران را در چهار سطح سازمانی، خرد، کلان و بین&#8204;المللی، شناسایی و طبقه&#8204;بندی کرده است. مؤلفه&#8204;های محیط شهری عبارتند از: زیرساخت&#8204;های فیزیکی، زیرساخت&#8204;های غیرفیزیکی، قوانین و مقررات، نهادهای مسئول بهبود کسب&#8204;وکار، حکمرانی محلی- مشارکتی، تدابیر شهروندمداری، همکاری&#8204;های نهادی، توسعه رقابت در سطح شهر، مشارکت کسب&#8204;وکارهای خصوصی، ساماندهی مشاغل در فضای داخل و اقماری شهر، شناسایی و توسعه فرصت&#8204;ها، دانش و فناوری نوین، درآمد پایدار برای توسعه شهری، توسعه آمایش شهری، هزینه مبادله، حمایت&#8204;های مالیاتی. مؤلفه&#8204;های محیط خرد؛ شامل تأمین&#8204;کنندگان، بازار کار، بازار اعتبارات، رسانه و مشتری هستند. مؤلفه&#8204;های محیط کلان عوامل کلان فرهنگی، عوامل جمعیتی (مدیریت مهاجرت)، زیست&#8204;محیطی، قانونی، سیاسی، فناوری، اقتصادی و اجتماعی هستند و در نهایت مؤلفه&#8204;های محیط بین&#8204;الملل؛ شامل مؤلفه&#8204;های فرهنگی، سیاسی، فناوری و نوآوری و قانونی است.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Abstract: Improving the environment in which businesses operate is important to business success. In particular, improving the environment reduces transaction costs and improves the competitiveness of businesses. The business environment of the city has unique characteristics that need to be understood and analyzed in various aspects. This research aims to design a model for improving the business environment in the city of Tehran using exploratory approach to identify the components and dimensions of the model. For this purpose, firstly explicit knowledge exists in the literature is reviewed and then a qualitative research methodology is employed to explore the implicit knowledge of experts obtained through interviews with 22 experts. After documenting the data obtained from the interviews, a three stage coding method is used to analyze&#160; the collected information and data using Atlas Ti. In the end, by combining the findings from the literature and the findings from the analysis of the interviews, a model is designed for improving the business environment in Tehran. It is worth noting that this model has identified and classified environment factors affecting the improvement of the business environment at the four levels of organizational, micro, macro, and international. Urban environment components include physical infrastructure, non-physical infrastructure, laws and regulations, institutions, local-participatory governance, policy for citizenship, institutional co-operation, urban-level competition development, private-public partnerships, organising businesses in the interior and exterior of the city, identification and development of opportunities, implication of new knowledge and technology, sustainable income for urban development, urban spatial development, transaction costs and tax support. The components of the micro-environment include suppliers, the labor market, credit market, the media and the customer. The components of the macroeconomic environment are demographic (immigration management), environmental, legal, political, technological, economic and social factors, and ultimately the components of the international environment include cultural, political, technological, and innovation components and law factors.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>93</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>113</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمدعلی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>مرادی</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad Ali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Moradi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Entrepreneurship, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده کارآفرینی، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>mamoradi@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Improvement of Business Environment</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Designing Model</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Qualitative Method</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Coding approach</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>City of Tehran.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بهبود محیط کسب‌وکار</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>طراحی الگو</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>روش کیفی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>کدگذاری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شهر تهران</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##اتاق بازرگانی، صنایع، معادن و کشاورزی ایران. (1396). پایش ملی محیط کسب‌وکار ایران.##بختیاری، صادق؛ شایسته، افسانه. (1391). بررسی تأثیر بهبود فضای کسب‎وکار بر رشد اقتصادی در کشورهای منتخب با تأکید بر ایران. فصلنامه علوم اقتصادی، 6(19)، 204-175.##براتی، جواد؛ رسول‎زاده، مریم، دارانی، هادی؛ مظهری، محمد. (1393). مدیریت راهبردی در فضای کسب‎وکار اقتصاد شهری؛ (مطالعه موردی: گردشگری مذهبی شهر مشهد مقدس). فصلنامه اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری، 2(6)، 125-109.##بلیکی، نورمن. (1384). طراحی پژوهش‎های اجتماعی. تهران: نشر نی.##عباس‎زاده، محمد. (1391). تأملی بر اعتبار و پایایی در تحقیقات کیفی. نشریه جامعه‎شناسی کاربردی، 23(1)، 34-19.##محمدپور، احمد. (1392). روش تحقیق کیفی (ضد روش1). تهران: جامعه‎شناسان.##مختاری‎هشی، حسین؛ ناصرالاسلامی، گلناز؛ مرادی، امین. (1395). نقش بهبود فضای کسب‌وکار در کشور در ساماندهی شهر تهران. فصلنامه تحقیقات جغرافیایی، 31(4(پیاپی 123))، 87-74.##مرادی، محمدعلی. (1396). محیط کسب‎وکار: نظریه‎ها، تکنیک‎ها و شاخص‎ها. چاپ سوم، تهران: مؤسسه انتشارات دانشگاه تهران. ##مرکز پژوهش‎های مجلس شورای اسلامی. (1395). پایش محیط کسب‎وکار ایران.##نیک‌نشان، شقایق؛ نوروزی، رضاعلی؛ نصراصفهانی، احمدرضا. (1389). تحلیلی بر رویکردهای روایی در پژوهش کیفی. نشریه روش‌شناسی علوم انسانی، 16(62)، 160-141.##Cite as River, M. )2018(. Branding and marketing the city as business ecosystem: How smart specialization can be instrumental. URBACT-InFocus Thematic Note.##Duncan, R. B. (1972). Characteristics of organizational environments and perceived environmental uncertainty. Administrative science quarterly, 313-327.##Gibson, J., Robinson, M., &amp; Cain, S. (2015). CITIE—City Initiatives for Technology, Innovation and Entrepreneurship; A Resource for City Leadership.##Johnson, P., Buehring, A., Cassell, C., &amp; Symon, G. (2006). Evaluating qualitative management research: Towards a contingent criteriology. International Journal of Management Reviews, 8(3), 131-156.##Kettl, D. F. (2015). The transformation of governance: Public administration for the twenty-first century. JHU Press.##McFarland, C., Seeger, K., Geary C. (2010). The role of local elected officials in economic development: Ten things you should know. Washington, DC: National League of Cities.## ##Milward, H. B., &amp; Provan, K. G. (2000). Governing the hollow state. Journal of public administration research and theory, 10(2), 359-380.##Morçöl, G., &amp; Wolf, J. F. (2010). Understanding business improvement districts: A new governance framework. Public Administration Review, 70(6), 906-913.##Morcol, G., Hoyt, L., Meek, J. W., &amp; Zimmermann, U. (Eds.). (2017). Business improvement districts: Research, theories, and controversies. Routledge.##Morrison, J. (2006). The international business environment: global and local marketplaces in a changing world. Palgrave.##Nicolescu, O., &amp; Nicolescu, C. (2013). Entrepreneurs' perceptions of the state implication in the business environment modelling in Romania. Transylvanian Review of Administrative Sciences, 9(38), 106-124.##Norwood, S. (2011). Tatum’s Survey of Business Conditions. Tatum. Retrieved July, 7, 2013.##Papilaya, J., Soisa, T. R., &amp; Akib, H. (2015). The influence of implementing the strategic policy in creating business climate, business environment and providing support facilities towards business empowerment on small medium craft enterprises in Ambon Indonesia. International Review of Management and Marketing, 5(2), 85-93.##Reichert, J., &amp; Municipality, C. H. D. (2006). Business enabling environment survey report conducted in Queenstown. Unpublished report prepared for the Border-Kei Chamber of Business, Queenstown.##Rogerson, C. M. (2010). Economic governance and the local business environment: Evidence from two economically lagging provinces of South Africa. In Urban Forum, 21(4), 349-366. Springer Netherlands.##Roxas, H. B., Lindsay, V., Ashill, N., &amp; Victorio, A. (2007). An institutional view of local entrepreneurial climate. Journal of Asia entrepreneurship and sustainability, 3(1), 1-28.##Salamon, L. M. (2000). The new governance and the tools of public action: An introduction. Fordham Urb. LJ, 28, 1675.##Schou-Zibell, L., &amp; Madhur, S. (2010). Regulatory reforms for improving the business environment in selected Asian economies-How monitoring and comparative benchmarking can provide incentive for reform.##Škof, B., &amp; Bradaschia, N. (2010). Public-Public Partnerships: The Role of Slovenian Local Authorities in Carrying out the Joint Tasks. Lex Localis-Journal of local self-government, 8(4), 329-342.##Stanković, J., Janković-Milić, V., &amp; Bosković, G. (2013). Business Friendly Environment–The Key Task of the Local Self-Government. The Economic Crisis and the Future of European Integration, 18, 353-362.##Stern, N., (2002). A Strategy for development. In Pleskovic, Boris e Stern, Nicholas in: Annual world bank conference on development economics-2001, Washington, DC: The World Bank (pp. 11-35).##Vesna, J. M., Stanković, J., &amp; Marinkovic, S. (2014). The capacity of local governments to improve business environment: Evidence from Serbia. Zbornik radova Ekonomskog fakulteta u Rijeci, časopis za ekonomsku teoriju i praksu-Proceedings of Rijeka Faculty of Economics, Journal of Economics and Business, 32(2), 233-254.##Vokoun, M., &amp; Daza Aramayo, L. G. (2017). Business environment index for developing countries: The case of Latin America. Latin American Business Review, 18(2), 121-137.##White, S. (2004). Donor approaches to improving the business environment for small enterprises. Washington: Working Group on Enabling Environment, Committee of Donor Agencies for Small Enterprise Development.##World Bank. (2015-2018). Ease of doing business, various report.##Worthington, I., &amp; Britton, C. (2009). Business environment. Pearson education. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>عوامل اقتصادی و محیطی تعیین‎کننده میزان انتشار گاز دی‎اکسیدکربن در کشورهای منطقه منا</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Economic and Environmental Factors Determining the Amount of Carbon Dioxide Emissions in the MENA Countries</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>چکیده: گرم شدن تدریجی کره زمین و اثرات منفی اقتصادی و زیست&#8204;محیطی آن، توجه به توسعه پایدار را بسیار حائزاهمیت کرده است. از آنجایی که عامل اصلی تغییرات آب&#8204;وهوایی، انتشار گازهای گلخانه&#8204;ای؛ از جمله CO۲ است، کشورها به دنبال جلوگیری از رشد سریع انتشار آلاینده&#8204;ها به منظور کاهش تغییرات آب&#8204;و&#8204;هوایی در سراسر جهان هستند. بر این اساس و با توجه به اهمیت موضوع، مطالعه حاضر، به بررسی تأثیر متغیرهایی؛ مانند درآمد سرانه، جمعیت، ساختار مصرف انرژی، شدت انرژی، درجه باز بودن تجاری، سهم صنعت از GDP بر انتشار دی&#8204;اکسیدکربن در کشورهای منطقه منا، طی دوره ۲۰۱۵-۱۹۹۳ بر مبنای الگوی رگرسیون اثرات تصادفی جمعیت، رفاه و فناوری تعمیم&#8204;یافته(STRIPAT)&#160; و مدل اقتصادسنجی پانل دوربین فضایی (SDPDM) پرداخته است. نتایج این مطالعه نشان می&#8204;دهند که لگاریتم GDP، جمعیت، ساختار مصرف انرژی و شدت انرژی، دارای تأثیر مثبت و معنی&#8204;داری بر انتشار دی&#8204;اکسیدکربن هستند و درجه باز بودن تجاری، تأثیر منفی و معنی&#8204;داری بر انتشار کربن دارد. همچنین تأثیر مثبت و معنی&#8204;دار متغیر فضایی باوقفه، بیانگر آن است که انتشار کربن در میان مناطق مختلف، بسیار مرتبط است. به طور کلی نتایج حاصل از برآورد مدل، نشان می&#8204;دهد که توجه هر چه بیشتر به همبستگی مکانی، ناهمگنی و اثرات بیرونی در سیاست&#8204;گذاری بسیار حائز&#8204;اهمیت است.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Abstract: The gradual warming of the earth and its negative environmental and economic impacts contributed to pay attention to sustainable development considerably. Since climate change is a major cause of greenhouse gas emissions, including CO2, countries are seeking to prevent the rapid growth of emissions to reduce global climate change. Accordingly, and considering the importance of the subject, the present study examines the effects of variables such as per capita income, population, energy consumption structure, energy intensity, degree of trade openness, industry share of GDP on carbon dioxide emissions in MENA countries, during 1993-2015 based on the regression model of population stochastic effects, Stochastic Impacts by Regression on Population, Affluence and Technology (STRIPAT) and Spatial Durbin Panel Data Model (SDPDM). The results of this study indicate that the logarithm of GDP, population, energy structure and energy intensity have a positive and significant effect on carbon dioxide emissions, and the degree of trade openness has a negative and significant effect on carbon emissions. In addition, the positive and significant effect of the intermittent spatial variable indicates that carbon emissions are highly relevant among different regions. In general, the results of model estimation show that attention is more important to spatial correlation, heterogeneity and external effects in policymaking.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>115</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>130</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علیرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>تمیزی</Family>
				<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Tamizi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Payam Noor University, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه پیام‎نور، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>al_tamizi@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Carbon Dioxide Emission</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Spatial Durbin Panel Data Model</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>STIRPAT</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عوامل اقتصادی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عوامل محیطی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>انتشار دی‌اکسیدکربن</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدل دوربین فضایی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>داده‌های تابلویی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>STIRPAT</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##بهبودی، داود، سلمانی، بهزاد؛ دهقانی، صدیقه. (1394). اثر تجارت بین‌الملل بر محیط‌زیست در کشورهای عضو اپک. نشریه اقتصاد کلان، 10(19)، 23-13.##پورعبدالهان کویچ، محسن؛ برقی اسگویی، محمدمهدی؛ پناهی، حسین؛ صالحی ابر، خدیجه؛ قاسمی، ایرج. تجزیه عوامل مؤثر بر انتشار آلودگی دی‎اکسیدکربن در صنایع محصولات کانی غیرفلزی ایران. فصلنامه مطالعات اقتصادی کاربردی ایران، 4(16)، 75-43.##تمیزی، علیرضا. (1394). عوامل مؤثر بر انتشار گاز دی‌اکسیدکربن در کشورهای در‎حال‎توسعه با استفاده از رویکرد اقتصادسنجی بیزینی. نظریه‎های کاربردی اقتصاد، 2(4)، 168-145.##دلفان، محبوبه. (1391). آزمون فرضیه پناهگاه آلودگی از سوی کشورهای عضو گروه جی 8 به کشورهای عضو گروه دی 8 با استفاده از داده‎های پانل. پایان‎نامه کارشناسی‎‎ارشد علوم اقتصادی. دانشکده علوم اقتصادی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی.##رفیعی، حامد؛ غزنوی، شیوا؛ صالح، ایرج. (1396). بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر انتشار دی‎اکسیدکربن در ایران؛ با تأکید بر آثار بیانیه 21 ریو. نشریه پژوهش‌های محیط‎زیست، 8(15)، 164-153.##روزی‎طلب، آناهیتا؛ حسین‎پور، عبدالکریم. (1396). بررسی رابطه علی بین عوامل مؤثر بر آلودگی محیط‎زیست در ایران طی سال‎های 1355-1394. فصلنامه سیاست‎های راهبردی و کلان، 5(20)، 45-27.##صادقی، زین‌العابدین؛ گلستانی، شهرام؛ پوربافرانی، احسان. (1392). بررسی اثرات القایی قیمت انرژی بر روی تغییرات فناوری کارگاه‌های صنعتی ایران و ارزیابی آثار محیط‎زیستی. فصلنامه مطالعات اقتصادی کاربردی در ایران، 2(5)، 177-153.##صادقی، سیدکمال؛ ابراهیمی، سعید. (1392). تأثیر توسعه مالی، تولید ناخالص داخلی و مصرف انرژی بر آلودگی محیط‌زیست در ایران (رهیافت ARDL). نشریه پژوهشنامه اقتصاد انرژی ایران، 2(7)، 73-43.##صادقی، سیدکمال؛ سجودی، سکینه؛ احمدزاده دلجوان، فهیمه. (1395). بررسی تأثیر متغیرهای جمعیتی بر کیفیت محیط‎زیست بر مبنای مدل STIRPAT. مجله علوم و تکنولوژی محیط‎زیست، 18(ویژه‎نامه شماره 3)، 257-275.##عسگری،‌ علی؛ اکبری، نعمت‌الله. (1380). روش‎شناسی اقتصادسنجی فضایی؛ تئوری و کاربرد. مجله پژوهشی علوم انسانی دانشگاه اصفهان، 12(1-2)، 122-93.##علیشیری، هدیه؛ محمدخانلی، شهرزاد؛ محمدباقری، اعظم. (1396). مطالعه عوامل مؤثر بر انتشار دی‌اکسیدکربن در کشور (با رویکرد تحلیل تجزیه لاسپیرز اصلاح شده). فصلنامه علوم و تکنولوژی محیط‎زیست، 19(2)، 62-51.##فطرس، محمدحسن؛ صحرایی، راضیه؛ یاوری، معصومه. (1396). بررسی اثر جنگ بر امنیت غذایی در کشورهای منتخب منطقه منا 1393-1369 (رویکرد پانل دیتای نامتوازن). نشریه پژوهش‎های رشد و توسعه اقتصادی، 8(30)، 66-55.##فلاحی، فیروز؛ حکمتی‎فرید، صمد. (1392). بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر میزان انتشار گاز دی‎اکسیدکربن در استان‎های کشور (رهیافت داده‎های تابلویی). فصلنامه اقتصاد محیط‌زیست و انرژی، 2(6)، 150-129.##کهنسال، محمدرضا؛ شایان‎مهر، سمیرا. (1395). آثار متقابل مصرف انرژی، رشد اقتصادی و آلودگی محیط‎زیست: کاربرد الگوی معادلات هم‌زمان فضایی داده‎های تابلویی. نشریه پژوهش‎نامه اقتصاد انرژی ایران، 5(19)، 216-179.##محمدزاده، پرویز؛ اکبری، اکرم. (1393) بررسی عوامل تعیین‌کننده انتشار دی‌اکسیدکربن توسط خانوارهای شهری: کاربرد مدل‌های هکمن. نشریه مطالعات اقتصادی کاربردی ایران، 3(10)، 82-59.##محمدی، حسین؛ تیرگری سراجی، محمد. (1392). بررسی ارتباط میان رشد اقتصادی، آزادسازی تجاری و آلودگی محیط‎زیست: بررسی کشورهای منتخب منطقه خاورمیانه. فصلنامه اقتصاد محیط‎زیست و انرژی، 2(6)، 207-183.##Balogh, J. M., &amp; Jámbor, A. (2017). Determinants of CO2 emission: A global evidence. International Journal of Energy Economics and Policy, 7(5), 217-226.##LeSage, J., &amp; Pace, R. K. (2009). Introduction to spatial econometrics. Chapman and Hall/CRC.5.##Liddle, B. (2015). What are the carbon emissions elasticities for income and population? Bridging STIRPAT and EKC via robust heterogeneous panel estimates. Global Environmental Change, 31, 62-73.##Liu, Y., Xiao, H., Zikhali, P., &amp; Lv, Y. (2014). Carbon emissions in China: a spatial econometric analysis at the regional level. Sustainability, 6(9), 6005-6023.##Long, R., Yang, R., Song, M., &amp; Ma, L. (2015). Measurement and calculation of carbon intensity based on ImPACT model and scenario analysis: A case of three regions of Jiangsu province. Ecological indicators, 51, 180-190.##Ozturk, I., &amp; Acaravci, A. (2013). The long-run and causal analysis of energy, growth, openness and financial development on carbon emissions in Turkey. Energy Economics, 36, 262-267.##Poumanyvong, P., &amp; Kaneko, S. (2010). Does urbanization lead to less energy use and lower CO2 emissions? A cross-country analysis. Ecological Economics, 70(2), 434-444.##Satterthwaite, D. (2009). The implications of population growth and urbanization for climate change. Environment and Urbanization, 21(2), 545-567.##Wang, Y., &amp; Zhao, T. (2015). Impacts of energy-related CO2 emissions: evidence from under developed, developing and highly developed regions in China. Ecological Indicators, 50, 186-195.##Wang, Z., Yin, F., Zhang, Y., &amp; Zhang, X. (2012). An empirical research on the influencing factors of regional CO2 emissions: evidence from Beijing city, China. Applied Energy, 100, 277-284.##‌World Bank. (2015). World Development Indicators CD-ROM.##York, R., Rosa, E. A., &amp; Dietz, T. (2003). STIRPAT, IPAT and ImPACT: analytic tools for unpacking the driving forces of environmental impacts. Ecological economics, 46(3), 351-365.##Zhu, Q., &amp; Peng, X. (2012). The impacts of population change on carbon emissions in China during 1978–2008. Environmental Impact Assessment Review, 36, 1-8. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>

</ARTICLES>

</JOURNAL>
</XML>
