<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</title>
<title_fa>فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری</title_fa>
<short_title>IUESA</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iueam.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2345-2870</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-6398</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/iueam</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>en</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1398</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2019</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>7</volume>
<number>27</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تحلیل عوامل اقتصادی اثرگذار بر زیست‌پذیری شهری (موردمطالعه: کلان‎شهر تبریز)</title_fa>
	<title>An Analysis of Effective Economic Factors on Urban Livability (Case: Tabriz Metropolis)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:yekanyw;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;چکیده&lt;/strong&gt;: از پیش&#8204;شرط&#8204;های اساسی برای برنامه&#8204;ریزی به&#8204;منظور ارتقای کیفیت زندگی و افزایش سطح پایداری در جوامع مختلف، شناسایی عوامل و عناصر تأمین&#8204;کننده و مؤثر بر زیست&#8204;پذیری شهری است. بُعد اقتصادی زیست&#8204;پذیری، از مهم&#8204;ترین ابعاد تأثیرگذار بر کیفیت زندگی شهری و ارتقای آن می&#8204;باشد. بنابراین پژوهش حاضر با رویکرد توصیفی- تحلیلی در پی دو هدف اصلی می&#8204;باشد: شناسایی و بررسی وضعیت شاخص&#8204;های اقتصادی مؤثر بر زیست&#8204;پذیری کلان&amp;lrm;شهر تبریز و سطح&#8204;بندی شاخص&#8204;های اقتصادی اثرگذار بر زیست&#8204;پذیری کلان&amp;lrm;شهر تبریز و ارائه مدل مناسبی با وضعیت زیست&#8204;پذیری کلان&amp;lrm;شهر تبریز. در این پژوهش شاخص&#8204;های مربوط به بعد اقتصادی زیست&#8204;پذیری در قالب ۱۲ شاخص از طریق مطالعه ادبیات پژوهش&#8204;های مرتبط و مصاحبه با خبرگان، شناسایی و سپس از تکنیک مدل&#8204;سازی ساختاری- تفسیری و نرم&#8204;افزار میک&#8204;مک برای بیان روابط و نوع شاخص&#8204;ها استفاده شد و در نهایت جهت بررسی وضعیت زیست&#8204;پذیری اقتصادی کلان&amp;lrm;شهر تبریز، از آزمون t تک&#8204;نمونه&#8204;ای استفاده شده است. نتایج پژوهش، بیانگر آن است که شاخص&#8204;هایی از قبیل: وضعیت امنیت شغلی، درآمد مناسب و کافی، داشتن شغل مناسب، فرصت&#8204;های شغلی مناسب و وجود فرصت&#8204;های درآمدزایی، اثرگذاری بیشتری نسبت به سایر شاخص&#8204;ها بر زیست&#8204;پذیری کلان&amp;lrm;شهر تبریز دارند. همچنین وضعیت زیست&#8204;پذیری اقتصادی کلان&amp;lrm;شهر تبریز، در حد پایین می&#8204;باشد؛ از میان ۱۲ متغیر پژوهش، تنها دو متغیر، توانایی جهت تأمین کالا و خدمات و داشتن شغل مناسب با امتیازهای ۱۰/۳ و ۰۷/۳ در وضعیت مطلوبی قرار دارند و سایر متغیرهای دیگر، پایین&#8204;تر از حد متوسط قرار دارند. بنابراین بهره&#8204;برداری از اقتصاد قوی بازار در راستای ایجاد شغل مناسب و سرمایه&#8204;گذاری در منطقه، پیشنهاد می&#8204;شود.&lt;/span&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:Times New Roman;&quot;&gt;One of the basic preconditions for planning to improve the quality of life and increase the level of sustainability in different societies is identifying the factors and elements that influence urban biodiversity. The economic dimension of livability is one of the most important dimensions affecting the quality of urban life and its promotion. Therefore, the present study is based on descriptive-analytical approach following two main aims: A- Identification and study of the status of economic indicators affecting the livability of the Tabriz Metropolis, B- Leveling economic indicators affecting the livability Tabriz Metropolis and providing appropriate model with livability of Tabriz Metropolis. In this research, the indices related to the economic dimension of livability in 12 indicators were identified by studying relevant research literature and interviews with experts, then structural-interpretive modeling technique and MICMAC software were used to express the relationships and type of indicators. Finally, to evaluate the status of economic livability of Tabriz Metropolis, one-sample t-test was used. The results of the study show the indicators of job security; enough income; proper employment opportunities; appropriate employment and opportunity to earn money were the most effective indicators on improving the livability of Tabriz Metropolis. In addition, the economic livability of the Tabriz Metropolis is low and unacceptable; among the 12 variables of research, only two variables, the ability to provide goods and services, and having a suitable job with the score of 3.10 and 3.07 are in a good condition and other variables are below the average. Therefore, exploiting a strong market economy is recommended in order to create a good job and invest in the region.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>زیست‌پذیری شهری, بعد اقتصادی, توسعه پایدار, کیفیت زندگی, کلان‎شهر تبریز</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Urban Livability, Economic Dimension, Sustainable Development, Quality of Life, Tabriz Metropolis</keyword>
	<start_page>31</start_page>
	<end_page>45</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-857-11&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Borhan</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Veysi Nab</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>برهان</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>ویسی‎ناب</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>borhanveysi@gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846006084</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846006084</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Planning and Environmental Sciences, University of Tabriz, Tabriz, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده برنامه‎ریزی و علوم محیطی، دانشگاه تبریز، تبریز، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Fereidoon</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Babaei Aghdam</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>فریدون</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بابایی اقدم</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846006085</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846006085</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Planning and Environmental Sciences, University of Tabriz, Tabriz, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده برنامه‎ریزی و علوم محیطی، دانشگاه تبریز، تبریز، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Rasoul</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ghorbani</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>رسول</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>قربانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846006086</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846006086</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Department of Geography and Urban Planning, Faculty of Planning and Environmental Sciences, university of Tabriz, Tabriz, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده برنامه‎ریزی و علوم محیطی، دانشگاه تبریز، تبریز، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
