@article{ 
author = {Shabanzadeh, Parvin and Baniasadi, Mostafa and Hayati, Babollah and Raheli, Hossei},  
title = {Economic Pricing of Recreational Services and Determining Visitors’ Willingness to Pay Costs for Visiting Urban Tourist Places  (Case Study: Garden of Flowers in Isfahan)}, 
abstract ={Cities have many tourism attractions and they always absorb many tourists to themselves; therefore, development of urban tourism and its wise management require planning. Considering the importance of tourism in urban economy and job creation, economic pricing of urban tourism services enjoys a special place in urban management. Garden of flowers is one of the most important tourism areas in the city of Isfahan. Thus, its recreational pricing can be effective in predicting needs and tourism development in Isfahan. The purpose of this research is estimating recreational value of Isfahan&#8217;s garden of flowers and determining the rate of visitors&#8217; willingness to pay for it with contingent valuation method. Data were collected by interview questionnaire with 110 people. Logit model was used to measure people&#8217;s WTP and the parameters were estimated based on maximum likelihood method. Dual two-dimensional method has been used to extract bids. According to the estimated coefficients, revenue and age variables had positive and negative effects respectively on WTP, and women&#8217;s WTP is more than men. The average of people&#8217;s WTP is 4752.49 Rials for recreational use of garden of flowers.},  
Keywords = {Contingent valuation,urban tourism,WTP,urban economy},
volume = {4},
Number = {13}, 
pages = {1-17}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-312-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-312-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Tabatabaeimozdabadi, Seyyed Mohse},  
title = {Assessing the Effectiveness of Specialized Courses for Financial and Urban Economic Experts of Tehran Municipality Based on Patrick Model}, 
abstract ={Training is a convenient tool for investing in human resources. Tehran Municipality, as an institution that its mission is servicing to the public, is responsible for important mission of staff&#8217;s training and development that they should attempt in line with servicing to citizens. This is much more delicate in areas involving in financial and economic issues. The remarkable point is that training is not profitable by itself, unless presented training to be evaluated and specified whether they have had necessary effectiveness or not. This research is applied in terms of purpose, and it is descriptive-survey considering method. The effectiveness of seven specialized courses of financial and urban economy experts of Tehran Municipality held in 2014 has been assessed. Statistical population is all financial and urban economy experts of Tehran Municipality who they were 227 people. 143 of them were selected as available sample attended in these courses by using simple random method. 36 people were direct managers. Data collection tool is research-made questionnaire based on Kirkpatrick Model. Its validity was verified by professors and experts in the field of training and assessment and its reliability has been verified using Cronbach&#8217;s alpha coefficient. One sample t test was used for the first, third, and fourth levels (reaction, behavior change and results), and paired samples t test was used for the second level (learning). The results indicate that specialized training courses have had appropriate efficacy at all four assessment levels of Patrick model special for financial and urban economy experts of Tehran Municipality held in 2014 including employees&#8217; reaction to training courses, learning gained from training courses, behavioral changes in employees, and changes in organizational performance.},  
Keywords = {Educational assessment, effectiveness, Patrick model, financial and urban economy experts, Tehran Municipality},
volume = {4},
Number = {13}, 
pages = {19-33}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-313-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-313-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Saraei, Mohammad Hossein and Iraji, Samaneh},  
title = {A Study of Spatial Compliance Rate of Socio-Economic Inequalities in Eight Areas of Yazd City}, 
abstract ={urbanization process has been faced with servicing inequalities, population distribution, and unbalanced urban growth in developing countries. Instability caused by the unbalanced growth has been represented in the form of lack of spatial-social balances with manifestations of urban poverty, informal housing and employment, and environmental pollution. This research studies existing social and spatial inequalities in different areas and districts of Yazd City and their relationship with each other. Research methodology is descriptive-analytical and necessary data have been collected through library method and mostly using the information of Yazd detailed plan in 2009. Ranking Yazd areas and districts regarding social development using 15 indexes and TOPSIS and Taxonomy method showed that district 3, areas 2-2 are in the first rank, and area 1-2 is in the last place. Choosing the average of land price as a criterion for assessing economic inequality among different areas of the city and comparing this index using ANOVA test indicate that there is a difference among different areas of Yazd so that area 2-3 has the highest value and area 1-1 has the least. Correlation test among the rate of social development of areas and land price in them done with Pearson&#8217;s correlation coefficient indicates significant and positive relationship between these two variables. Thus, we consider increase in land price in line with social development rise in different areas of Yazd city.},  
Keywords = {social inequality, economic inequality, land price, sustainable development, Yazd city},
volume = {4},
Number = {13}, 
pages = {35-50}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-314-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-314-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Safavi, Rashed and Rezazadeh, Seyyed Mohamm},  
title = {The Impact of Construction Projects in the Last Four Years in the Development of Urban Economy Management and Citizens’ Satisfaction (Case Study: Qazvin’s Citizens)}, 
abstract ={Today, urban public spaces play a fundamental role in urban development plans. This indicates the importance of the spaces in improving cultural-social aspect of cities. In other words, a culture creates behavioral patterns that determine and reflect how people to use the spaces. Therefore, it is natural that the use of the public spaces varies in different cultures. The nature and manner of activities that take place in urban areas can be related to two basic factors; culture and environment (spatial-local features). Statistical society is all Qazvin&#8217;s citizens who have taken advantage of the projects in last few years. Sample has obtained by report and interview with 425 Qazvin&#8217;s citizens. In terms of purpose, this research is applied-developmental and it is descriptive-analytical and survey one regarding method. The method of data analysis has been accomplished by using qualitative methods, particularly criteria and sub-criteria of citizens&#8217; satisfaction. The purpose of the research is the study of construction projects in last four years and its impact on management and development of urban economy and citizens&#8217; satisfaction. The results have indicated that macro policies, citizens&#8217; satisfaction, and giving the cities identity are three basic variables in constructing development projects.},  
Keywords = {space, construction projects, management, urban economy, satisfaction},
volume = {4},
Number = {13}, 
pages = {51-66}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-315-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-315-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Mirzaei, Hossein and Sohrabi, Roy},  
title = {Determining the Poverty Line of Urban Households in East Azerbaijan Province by Using Linear Expenditure System}, 
abstract ={Measuring poverty can make the process of poverty evolutions understandable in every society and present an image of these developments during the time. Government can target and adopt appropriate decisions to do necessary measures as a result. In this regard, statistical study of poverty and its analysis at the level of province can be a guide for planners to reduce penury. The poverty line of urban areas in east Azerbaijan was estimated by using dynamic linear expenditure system (DLES) method assuming the formation of habits and using seemingly unrelated regression (SUR) model during 2001 to 2011. Components of eight commodity groups including food, clothing, housing, appliances and furniture, healthcare, transport and communication, recreation and education, and a group for other issues were used as well as their price index published by statistical center of Iran. The results obtaining from estimations by using STATA and Eviews soft wares indicate that poverty of urban areas in east Azerbaijan has ascending trend with an average growth rate of 23% during the period under review. The percentage of urban households below the poverty line of the Province is 50 percent on average, and poverty gap and severity of poverty indices have been reduced with average values of 42% and 23% respectively at the end of the period. Thus, according to the results for indicators of poverty, it can be said that although poverty eradication policies during the ten-year period of this research have improved the welfare of the poor people partially, the number of people below the poverty line has increased considerably during this period. The process of escalating prices can be one of the main reasons for this increase that can be solved by the government with curbing inflation.},  
Keywords = {poverty line, linear expenditure system with the formation of habits, seemingly unrelated Iterative Regression, Poverty indices},
volume = {4},
Number = {13}, 
pages = {67-84}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-316-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-316-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Daroudi, Mohammardreza and Jahanshahlou, Laala and Shahriyari, Seyyed Kamaledi},  
title = {A Measurement of Economic Factors of the City on Satisfaction and Residential Displacement of Family (Case Study: Narmak Neighborhood-Tehran)}, 
abstract ={Satisfaction achievement in residential areas is formed by different factors; one of them is economic factor of city. Economic indicators are effective along with physical, cultural, social, cultural and other components on the amount of maintenance and absorption of population in urban context, in the assessment of residents from their home environments. It is raised as one of the effective factor on family&#8217;s motivation for residential displacement. The goal of this article is assessing economic factors on residential satisfaction and its impact on family&#8217;s displacement in Narmak neighborhood according to its background in Tehran. Descriptive-analytic method has been used for data collection in this paper, and 375 questionnaires have been prepared, due to the sample size. Data analysis has been done by SPSS method and CSM indicator. The results of this research show consent of access, transport and security in that area and low discontent of residents from residential unit, services and facilities. These issues caused 59.2% willingness to movement and 40.8% unwillingness to residential displacement despite current problems.},  
Keywords = {Economic factors of city, residential satisfaction, residential displacement, Narmak},
volume = {4},
Number = {13}, 
pages = {85-99}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-317-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-317-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Irandoost, Kiyoumars and Isaloo, Ali Asghar and Shahmoradi, Behz},  
title = {Viability Index in Urban Environments  (Case Study: The Central Part of Holy City of Qom)}, 
abstract ={Improvement of living conditions in urban environments not only increases their attractiveness, but it also prepares an appropriate context for achieving to major goals of sustainable development. However, rapid growth of urbanization and other related issues with urban development have caused the problems of these habitants be increased. The situation is well understood in many Iran&#8217;s cities suffering from the consequences of rapid growth of urbanization and lack of adequate financial and human resources in the process of management. Thus, this research tries to identify the characteristics of viable urban societies, assess the viability of central part of Qom city, and find the situation of the city regarding viability indexes. Research method is descriptive-analytical as well as documentary, survey, and field studies such as adopted techniques and measures in this research. According to the research findings, policies for decentralization of activities, change in development policy based on automobile, attempt to stabilize old residents of the region (renovation, improve the quality of neighborhood services), and such issues should be adopted in order to improve the quality of life in this part of the city.},  
Keywords = {viability, viability criteria, city management, central part of the city},
volume = {4},
Number = {13}, 
pages = {101-118}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-318-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-318-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Ziyaei, Mahmood and AbbasiKarjegan, Davoud and Kazemian, Gholamreza and Karoobi, Mahdi},  
title = {Identification and Determination of Dimensions of Tourism Management Model in Tehran}, 
abstract ={Tourism, as a modern phenomenon, has an economic nature. It is of great importance for countries having this capacity. The purpose of this research is identification and determination of dimensions of tourism management model in Tehran based on managers and experts&#8217; opinions in tourism field by using the ramification pattern of the tertiary branches for designing and developing urban tourism management model in accordance with economic, socio-cultural, political and environmental conditions of Tehran. This research has quantitative entity. It is applied in terms of purpose done in descriptive-survey method. To collect primary data, the assessment tool in the form of closed questionnaire included 55 items in five options Likert scale was designed after studying theoretical foundations and literature tourism subject. Face and content validity were used for questionnaire. To assess reliability, Cronbach's alpha coefficient was used and the value of 0.94 was estimated. Statistical sample were 400 academic experts and managers in the field of tourism in Tehran. 371 valid questionnaires were collected from them.&#160; In this research, three hypotheses were proposed, and for data analysis, factor analysis and structural equation modeling were used as well. The results of the data analysis show that factors affecting the management of urban tourism in Tehran are in three dimensions including structural, environmental, and content. Designing three-dimensional model of urban tourism management based on the pattern of three ramifications can be a base for tourism policy and planning in Tehran.},  
Keywords = {tourism, Tehran tourism, Tehran, management, model},
volume = {4},
Number = {13}, 
pages = {119-141}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-319-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-319-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {AbolhasaniHastiyani, Asghar and Banar, Shokrollah},  
title = {A Comparison of Influential Indexes in Classification of Urban Projects of Tehran Municipality with other Selected Cities}, 
abstract ={Undoubtedly, the manner of financing for intended projects depends on the features of each project in any level of existing organizations; therefore, defined and applied indexes and standards should be fitted and overlapped with characteristics of each project. In fact, each project is categorized based on its qualities and appropriate financial instruments are determined according to this criterion. Urban projects have been classified and effective factors on the categorization in urban projects have been identified in this article. Tehran Municipality is compared with some large cities, in this respect. In order to study the issue, equality of external financing of urban projects with transport missions, urban services, and other missions have been examined by using ANOVA analysis, according to the separation of municipal projects to different missions. Better financing can be obtained by better identification and emphasis on the qualities of urban projects of Tehran Municipality and its comparison with other selected cities in the world including Seoul, Shanghai, Kuala Lumpur, New York, London, and Istanbul. According to the results, the hypothesis of equivalent amount of external financing municipal projects with municipal service mission in Tehran and other intended cities is not rejected.},  
Keywords = {urban projects, Tehran Municipality, financing},
volume = {4},
Number = {13}, 
pages = {143-164}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-320-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-320-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {SadeghiShahdani, Mahdi},  
title = {Systematic Approach to the Budgeting of Municipalities in Terms of Applying Adjustment Policies of Energy Prices}, 
abstract ={Implementation of targeted subsidies law has influenced the revenue and costs of these organizations directly or indirectly. In this regard, studying the impacts of mentioned plan on revenue resources and municipalities&#8217; costs of the country is of great importance with systematic approach in municipalities&#8217; budgeting. The impacts of adjustment policies of energy prices on municipalities&#8217; revenue and costs can be evaluated systematically based on input-output models. What complicates the issue is the adjustment of municipalities&#8217; costs issues. Rise in the price of energy carriers may directly lead to increase in revenue from value added tax act for municipalities through increasing revenues from duties related to fuel and electricity. In order to estimate the impact of the implementation of the first stage of law on the income item, Consumption and price of energy carriers were used in the years before and after of the law. Having information about price and consumption after targeting, this makes it possible to calculate the increase of Rial value of use of different energy carriers in the year and calculate the rate of increase in duties of each fuel for all municipalities and rural municipalities in the country by using obtained figure and applying toll collection rates related to municipalities, specified in VAT act, as well. The impact of adjustment of energy prices on the inflation of different products can be stimulated by using price model based on input-output table. Increase in the costs of municipalities can be calculated according to obtained inflation in goods and services of the total economy. This type of stimulation will be based on systematic approach and all direct and indirect effects are considered in it. Budgeting of municipalities based on mentioned approach will result in balanced budget.},  
Keywords = {balanced budgeting, input-output model, municipalities’ revenue and cost, price model, policy of adjustment in energy prices},
volume = {4},
Number = {13}, 
pages = {165-178}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-321-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-321-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Saraei, Mohammad Hossein and Jamshidi, Zahra and Ahangari, Navi},  
title = {Prioritization of Management Indexes of Municipal Solid Waste in Line with Sustainable Development (Case Study: City of Bokan)}, 
abstract ={Non-systematic management of municipal solid waste prepares the ground for the creation of human and environmental problems in long run. Therefore, sustainable and effective municipal waste management strategy is needed to balance the development, quality of life and environment. This paper has been developed to evaluate the management indicators of municipal solid waste in accordance with sustainable development in Bukan by using TOPIS technique. Research method is survy (questionnaire and field study) and describtive- analytical data analysis was used. The statistical population was the city&#8217;s population of 171,773 people with the sample of 384 people. It was reduced to 330 due to the limitations of the study. Findings show that 150 tons of waste are produced daily on average in the city of Bukan and the waste per capita is 0.740 kg per day. The most amount of produced solid waste is related to organic materials with 75.82 and the least amount is related to wood with 0.65 percent. The final obtained ranking of satisfaction rate of sustainable development indexes of solid waste management by TOPSIS method has indicated that the factor of tip request was in the first rank and the factor of advertisement attractiveness was in the 20th rank that is the least important one.},  
Keywords = {Municipal solid waste management, sustainable development, TOPSIS technique, city of Bukan},
volume = {4},
Number = {14}, 
pages = {1-17}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-392-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-392-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Anabestani, Zahra and Sarvar, Rahim and MahdaviHajilouei, Masou},  
title = {Factors Affecting Land and Housing Market Changes (Case Study: Padideh Tourism Compony-Shandiz City in 2009-2014)}, 
abstract ={When the large urban projects (Mega Project) to be loaded on a national scale in a small town, you can see dramatic changes in the market for land and housing in urban settlements. This paper attempts to study the impact of presence and activity of Padideh Shandiz Tourism Company on land and housing market changes examined in 2009 to 2014 from the perspective of citizens. Regarding purpose, this research is applied. Data were collected via library, field study (questionnaire), and descriptive method was used for data analysis (mean, standard deviation) and inferential statistics (factor analysis and one-sample t-test) were performed. The statistical population community, including families living in Shandiz City on the basis of the 2011 census, with a 10,428 population of 3056 households and is required sample size of 160 households was based on Cochran formula. The findings indicate that the direct effects caused by the presence and activities of Padideh Shandiz Tourism Company in the time interval studied, the statistic 43.6% of the biggest impacts on the land and housing market changes have had on the town. Also based on one sample t-test showed a significant difference between the mean and median of the theoretical (3) Shandiz City from the perspective of citizens that are substantially influence of these factors on land and housing market changes. According to the findings, strategies including attention to urban managements of land and housing market changes in the future, due to the low-income indigenous housing, prevention of social conflicts, provision of infrastructure, etc. have been proposed.},  
Keywords = {Padideh Tourism Company, environmental factors, urban management, urban housing, Shandiz City},
volume = {4},
Number = {14}, 
pages = {19-38}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-393-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-393-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Zaali, Nader and Zareie, Majid and Ebizadeh, Saman and HashemzadehGhalehjogh, Farshi},  
title = {Strategic Planning for the Organizing of Urban Old Textures (Case Study: Shahidgah-Sheikh Safi Neighborhood in Ardabil City)}, 
abstract ={Currently, old textures are one of the main problems in many cities and even villages in our country. The specific feature of these textures makes it necessary to be considered from different aspects. This study is trying to find strategies to improve and organize old texture in the Shahidgah neighborhood of Ardabil. It also aims to plan and design in accordance with the existing status and consistent with strategic priorities. In this regard, using review of documents and field surveys, existing status of the neighborhood were evaluated using SWOT analysis and planning strategies. Continuing with the quantitative models used, organizing strategies are prioritized. Finally, five design alternatives presented in accordance with texture requirements. Findings indicate that the organizing of the studied area should adopt a systematic approach for 4 dimensions of physical, economic, social and environmental interventions to deal with. The preferred alternative has tried to organize and remove the ruined buildings in the middle of the area, a closeness be created and the central space is used to create a neighborhood center.},  
Keywords = {Organizing, old texture, Strategic Planning, SWOT, Shahidgah neighborhood, Ardabil},
volume = {4},
Number = {14}, 
pages = {39-62}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-394-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-394-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Rahbaripoor, Kasra and SattariSarebangholi, Hassan and Darskhan, Rasool},  
title = {An Analysis of Socio-Economic Impacts of National Carpet Museum of Tabriz}, 
abstract ={This research has been done to identify the impacts of implementing the project of carpet museum of Tabriz from different aspects particularly economic and social dimensions on various groups of citizens and local society. It has been tried to study intrinsic, instrumental, and institutional values of this museum in the form of social and economic impacts. Combined approach of participatory and technocratic has been used and the results of both methods have been listed in research findings, conclusion, and management of consequences. Survey method has been used. 142 people are sample including inhabitants, salespersons, passengers, and experts in the field of carpet and urban management. Respondents were selected both randomly and purposefully so that inhabitants and passengers were selected randomly and salespersons and experts were chosen purposefully. The results indicate relative agreement between people&#8217;s ideas and experts&#8217; about social, economic, and human impacts of the project. The findings show that building this museum may have positive impacts including employment, preparing the ground for investment, economic boom of the area, and socially positive results such as development of social interactions of ordinary people and experts together, and increasing people&#8217;s knowledge about carpet industry. Crowd, traffic, discomfort for residents, and disruption of the social homogeneous texture of the neighborhood can be noted as negative impacts.},  
Keywords = {museum, assessment of social impact, intrinsic value, instrumental value, institutional value},
volume = {4},
Number = {14}, 
pages = {63-76}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-395-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-395-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Ghanbari, Mohammad and AjzaShokuhi, Mohammad and Rahnama, Mohammad Rahim and Kharazmi, Omid Ali},  
title = {An Analysis on the Price of Urban Land in Iran’s Provinces during 2001 to 2011}, 
abstract ={Attention to land, as one of the principal and renewable sources in urban sustainable development, is a necessary task since it is considered as one of the main sources of urban sustainable development. The purpose of this research is an analysis on the price of urban land in different provinces of Iran during 2001 to 2011. The research method is documentary and library techinque was used for data collection. PASW, GeoDa, and GIS soft wares were used for data analysis. Research findings indicate random distribution of urban land price during 2001 to 2011 in different provinces. According to Enter regression test, it was specified that there is no significant relationship between the variables of urbanization percentage and the average of land area of urban buildings with the price of urban land in 2001, but there was a significant relationship between these variables in 2006 and 2011. However, there is a significant relationship between development level of provinces and the price of urban land in 2011 in some provinces at the level of 95 percent. After studying the changes in the average price of urban land of Iran&#8217;s provinces during 2001 to 2011, it was specified that the average coefficient of variation of urban land price was equal to 827.73 and Bushehr, Khorasan Razavi, and Hamedan provinces had the highest coefficient of variation and Kordestan, Hormozgan, and Khuzestan provinces had the least.},  
Keywords = {price of urban land, urbanization, province, area, Iran},
volume = {4},
Number = {14}, 
pages = {77-99}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-397-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-397-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Samadi, Ali Hosein and Qaderi, Jafar and Nejadhalafi, Zahoor},  
title = {Determining Non-Linear Causality between Urban and Non-Urban Ground Transport and Economic Growth Using Wavelet Neural Network (Case Study: Iran)}, 
abstract ={In the last few decades, the relationship between economic infrastructures, particularly transport sector, and economic growth has been the subject of many reserachers in different economies. Iran has many advantages considering particular geographic situation in terms of transport facilities as it connects many countries. In this study, the relationship among ground transport, economic growth, capital formation , and work force was examined by using quarterly data during 1992 to 2012. Required data were extracted from the statistics of Centeral Bank of Islamic Republic of Iran and yearbooks of Statistical Center of Iran. The most important difference of this study compared to other previous studies is using wavelet neural network method and non-linear approach in explaining the relationship among discussed variables. The results of causal relationship test between variables imply the existence of causality from ground transport to economic growth.},  
Keywords = {economic growth, transport, neural network, causality, Iran},
volume = {4},
Number = {14}, 
pages = {101-113}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-398-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-398-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Aminian, Naser and Hassani, Ali},  
title = {Effective Factors on Urban Brand and Their Prioritization from Perspective of International Tourists (Case Study: Tehran’s Milad Tower)}, 
abstract ={Urban tourism is a part of international tourism market having the most development potential in the recent years. In 2015, tourists&#8217; willingness to visit Iran and its historical and cultural attractions and symbols has been increased. Tehran, as the capital, is the most suitable alternative of urban tourism destination for international tourists. Its urban attractive symbols have had important role in this regard; therefore, the main purpose of this research is to identify and determine prioritization of Tehran Milad Tower brand aspects from perspective of international tourists. This research is descriptive-survey, with applied purpose, by using documentary and field studies. To collect data, questionnaire was used; it was distributed among international visitors of Tehran Milad Tower during September to November 2015. At first, primary questionnaire was distributed as pilot among a group of 30 international visitors of Milad Tower, and its validity and reliability were confirmed. Then, revised questionnaires, including 20 items, were distributed among 240 people as sample based on available sampling. Data were analyzed by using Friedman test and SPSS software. The results indicated that popularity of brand name, with the ranking average of 4.98, as the most important priority in choosing a visiting place, was identified from perspective of tourists.},  
Keywords = {urban brand, aspects of urban brand, urban tourist, Tehran Milad Tower},
volume = {4},
Number = {14}, 
pages = {115-136}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-401-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-401-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Salarvandiyan, Fatemeh and Hosseini, Seyyed Ali and Habibi, Leyla and JafariMehrabadi, Maryam},  
title = {The Role of Informal Jobs in Relieving Informal Settlement (Case Study: Hesaramir of Pakdasht)}, 
abstract ={New theories in empowerment have been focused on the role of spontaneous solutions of suburbanites in the recent years. One of the scientific strategies that inhabitants of informal settlements use for solving the problems of marginalization is to choose informal economy and spontaneous jobs. This research has descriptive-analytical approach emphasizing on questionnaire in order to study the role of such occupations as a solution arisen from these societies in order to relieve the issue of informal settlement among informal habitats of Hesaramir in Pakdasht. Cochran Formula was used to determine sample size. 25303 people of total population of Hesaramir were considered as a statistical population; therefore, 378 people were selected. SWOT technique indicated that development of spontaneous jobs in the informal settlements of Hesaramir of Pakdasht has very high strengths (3.33 scores in terms of internal factors and 3.34 scores in terms of external factors). One sample t tests and chi-square were used to analyze the questionnaires. Chi-square test results showed that there is a significant relationship between the gender of the studied people and tendency to spontaneous jobs with the probability of 95%. T and Kolmogorov-Smirnov tests were used to show the impact of spontaneous jobs on economic recovery. The results of Kolmogorov-Smirnov test indicate that tendency to such jobs has leaded to the improvement of economic situation. T-test indicates the significance level less than 0.05 showing the impact of these jobs on the improvement of economic situation.},  
Keywords = {informal settlement, spontaneous jobs, informal economy of the city, SWOT},
volume = {4},
Number = {14}, 
pages = {137-157}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-399-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-399-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Rastegari, Mohammad and Saraei, Mohammad Hossei},  
title = {A Comparative Analysis of Facility Level and Population Distribution in Urban Network of Yazd Province}, 
abstract ={During last three decades, because of rapid influx of population into the cities, many problems have been emerged for cities. Thus, it is necessary to plan and present models in order to regulate urban network to reduce and organize emerging problems. Finding factors resulting from these events, presenting solution in order to reduce unfavorably existing situation, and move toward balance in population and activity distribution are some of the most concerns of planners and city managers. In this research, the relationship between urban facilities and population distribution in urban network was studied by evaluating level of enjoying municipal facilities in urban areas of Yazd Province. In terms of research type, it is developmental-applied and in terms of method, it is descriptive-analytical. Data were collected by library studies, documents of Iran&#8217;s Statistical Center, statistical yearbook, and relevant documents. To analyze data and reach to practical results, numerical Taxonomy model and numerical analysis process were used. The results indicate that presented facilities and services in urban areas have fairly big influence on balanced distribution of population; therefore, deductive rank of Taxonomy analysis that indicates level of enjoying facilities in the areas is in line with the rank of population distribution. In this regard, indexes relevant with municipal facilities and services can considerably play effective role on absorbing population, avoiding immigration, and decentralization in different areas.&#160;},  
Keywords = {municipal facilities and services, numerical Taxonomy, city of Yazd},
volume = {4},
Number = {15}, 
pages = {1-17}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-459-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-459-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Movahhed, Ali and ValiNoori, Saman and Hataminejad, Hossein and Zanganeh, Ahmad and KamanroodiKajouri, Moos},  
title = {Spatial Analysis of Urban Poverty in Tehran Metropolis}, 
abstract ={Urban poverty is one of the main concerns of the 21st century and fighting against it is at the top of the millennium development goals. This paper has been done aiming to identify and analyze spatially areas of urban poverty. It has been done with quantitative method and survey based on secondary analysis in Tehran Metropolis in a way that calculated items were categorized based on four main factors of housing including economic, social, cultural, and educational ones and 43 indexes. They were selected by using statistical blocks data of Tehran Metropolis based on population and housing census in 2011. The results indicated that four extracted factors determine 72.7 percent of distribution of the total variance including housing poverty (28.7 percent), economic poverty (18.4 percent), social poverty (14.1 percent), and educational-cultural poverty (11.5 percent) respectively. They also indicated that districts 17, 19, 18, and 16 had the highest ranks regarding all poverty factors including economic, social, cultural, and educational ones. It is recommended to prioritize poverty alleviation and empowerment in development measures. However, the results of fuzzy VIKOR showed that there were 2312 very poor blocks (38.5 percent), 2049 poor blocks (34.1 percent), 1068 average blocks (17.8 percent), 458 rich blocks (7.6 percent), and only 114 very rich blocks.},  
Keywords = {spatial analysis, urban poverty, Tehran Metropolis},
volume = {4},
Number = {15}, 
pages = {19-36}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-460-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-460-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {MohammadpourZarandi, Hossein and Daroudi, Mohammadrez},  
title = {Ranking Components of Household’s Residential Movement Model Emphasizing on Economic View of Housing  (Case Study: Seyyed Khandan Neighborhood-Tehran District 3)}, 
abstract ={One of the aspects of city dynamism is households&#8217; movement from one residential neighborhood to other ones inside the city. These movements that affect city structure have various reasons. Assessing the reasons of household&#8217;s residential movement is very complex task since it is due to the concept of residential satisfaction or dissatisfaction. However, this movement, depending on the type of ownership, can be done based on people&#8217;s indexes and factors. Therefore, this paper aims to analyze and prioritize importance of residential movement indexes emphasizing on the type of people and households&#8217; ownership in Seyyed Khandan neighborhood of Tehran. To determine sample size of the case study, Cochran formula was used and 175 questionnaires were distributed in the neighborhood. However, in order to prioritize residential indexes in two aspects of (owner/tenant), Entropy and qualitative method of SAW were used. This paper indicates that educated landowners have high tendency and jobless landowners have low tendency to move. This may be due to their fear of losing the ownership of their residential units because of fluctuations in the housing market. However, tenants who earn high income tend to have successive movements greatly and those who are unemployed or earn low revenue prefer to stay in their residential environment. Therefore, it is recommended that banking facilities and urban projects to be increased in line with providing houses for households in order to reduce their repetitive movements.},  
Keywords = {residential movement, prioritization, type of ownership, Seyyed Khandan neighborhood},
volume = {4},
Number = {15}, 
pages = {37-53}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-461-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-461-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {ZandHesami, Hesam and Shahramfar, Shiv},  
title = {Identification of Effective Dimensions on Forecasting Urban Planning with Economic Approach (Case Study: Sustainable Development of Qazvin)}, 
abstract ={This paper aims to identify effective aspects of forecasting on city management in order to illustrate opportunities and discover the advantages of available tools with economic approach. In terms of purpose, this research is applied, and in terms of data collection, it is descriptive-survey. Sampling method is purposeful and 10 experts were considered as sample size. Consolidated questionnaire was used for data collection. In order to measure validity of the questionnaire, convergent validity test was used. To check reliability, Cronbach&#8217;s alpha coefficient was calculated as 0.793. KMO and Bartlett&#8217;s tests, developed mean-variance approach t-test were used. To perform statistical operations, PLS and SPSS 17 were used. In this research, the indexes were identified by using Delphi technique and eight major indexes including quality of life, environmental thinking, transport, compatibility of economic environment, economic infrastructures of the society, economic health of the society, housing, and energy were selected and all hypotheses were confirmed. Finally, three types of forecasting were proposed. This paper tries to present a model for participatory forecast based on urban economy in city management (case study: city of Qazvin). However, three scenarios were proposed considering economic conditions of Qazvin entitled continuation of status, rapid growth and interconnectedness with the global economy, and balanced growth and interconnectedness with the global economy. Therefore, according to these scenarios, practical suggestions were proposed in line with much dynamism of Qazvin urban economy.},  
Keywords = {forecast, urban planning, sustainable development, urban economy},
volume = {4},
Number = {15}, 
pages = {55-73}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-462-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-462-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {NasiriHendehKhaleh, Esmael and Hadavi, Faramarz and Zamani, Mahdi},  
title = {Identification of the Relationship between Tourism Industry Development and Economic Growth of Zanjan Province}, 
abstract ={Today, tourism industry, as a dynamic industry, has devoted an important part of production activities in the world by its development-oriented features. Hence its development in a country requires factors such as an appropriate strategy, planning and efficient management. In this paper, the status of tourism industry in Zanjan Province has been evaluated using SWOT technique and Input-Output table. The use of expert judgment of &#8220;Delphi&#8221; is used so that the judgment of the expert group a list of internal factors (strengths and weaknesses) and external (opportunities and threats) influencing the approach taken and the quantification was carried out .Methods of data collection and data analysis are applied and descriptive-analytical. According to the research findings, Zanjan province can become one of the big tourism hubs in the country because of its special geographical location and being between two industrial hubs of Tehran and East. Azerbaijan Provinces. Its strategy is defensive one, and strategies were proposed based on QSPM matrix at the end. Based on research findings in Zanjan province, tourism industry and its related sectors, in terms of linking with other sectors of the economy, can be considered as leading sectors in the economy of Zanjan Province. Therefore, this industry can boost the whole economy of Zanjan by supplying tourism services, demand for enjoying them, and producing tourism goods in other sectors. With regard to these potentials, tourism should be placed on the priority of the province planners in order to exploit them in line with the economy of this province.},  
Keywords = {Tourism industry, Economy development, Zanjan province, Input-Output table, SWOT technique},
volume = {4},
Number = {15}, 
pages = {75-94}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-463-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-463-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Hosseini, Seyyed Teymoor and Ariyana, Mohammad and Abroodi, Seyyed Mojtab},  
title = {Transport and Urban Traffic Management in Tehran with Economic View}, 
abstract ={One of the management issues in the city of Tehran is urban traffic. In the city of Tehran, population increase and limited resources have resulted in confusion and disorganization in dealing with this matter. Identification of difficulties and effective factors on traffic and transport management of Tehran, particularly dealing with urban sectors, meets the need of city management in a relatively short time. Given the importance of this issue, identification of effective factors on traffic and transport management can have significant impacts on solving traffic problems and it can prepare the ground for application of optimal city management. Thus, the purpose of this research is to identify and prioritize effective components on traffic and transport management of Tehran with economic view and application of AHP method. Statistical population includes experts in different fields of servicing, economic, social, and military ones that is estimated about 100 people and 50 of them were selected by purposive quota sampling to for paired comparisons. In this regard, data were collected by questionnaire, and they were examined by AHP technique and Expert Choice software. The results indicated the component of access priority toward movement that results in reducing traffic and consequently costs, is the most important component in urban traffic and transport management in Tehran; therefore, it is recommended that movement at different levels and range of public transport, as major components in policy-making, should be included in the priority of urban plans in order to reduce costs.},  
Keywords = {transport, traffic management, urban planning, public arena},
volume = {4},
Number = {15}, 
pages = {95-109}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-464-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-464-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Masoomzadeh, Jafar and Rahmani, Morteza and Jafari, Azozollah},  
title = {Cost Management of Urban Green Space (Case Study: Tehran)}, 
abstract ={Urban green space is one of the most important components in city management and cities&#8217; development given its social and environmental functions and financial and economic aspects. Different species of plants including trees, shrubs, cover crops and flowers or seasonal plants have specific features in terms of climate-compatible of Tehran and water demand. They also have different roles in meeting expected functions of urban green space, particularly prettification and reducing air pollution by producing oxygen. Thus, this paper tries to study selection criteria, assess plant species, and determine appropriate criterion for Tehran green space. Then, it determines relative weight of each one by surveying 35 experts&#8217; view in the form of group analytical hierarchy process (GAHP) method. The obtained weights are instruments for valuation of 60 Tehran&#8217;s main plant species done by simple valuation (linear) and TOPSIS methods.&#160; The results indicated that evergreen oak, elm, and silver cypress are the most valuable species. Ranking of plant species were obtained by two mentioned methods in each of four groups that they were almost matched with each other. Using these ranks has increased at least 33 percent of productivity cost of urban green space in replanting project of municipality districts as well as increasing citizens&#8217; satisfaction and life of plant species that is in line with resistance economy.},  
Keywords = {Analytical Hierarchy Process (AHP), urban green space, cost management, TOPSIS model},
volume = {4},
Number = {15}, 
pages = {111-125}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-465-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-465-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {TabatabaeiMozdabadi, Seyyed Mohse},  
title = {Investigation of Educational Needs with Job Analysis Approach  (Case Study: Financial and Urban Economy Experts of Tehran Municipality)}, 
abstract ={Progress and development of organizations depend on improving the level of knowledge, insight, and skills of their human resources so that organizations can achieve to competitive advantage in line with their scientific and economic goals as well as innovation. The first step of educational planning in organizations is to determine educational needs and present educational plans for employees&#8217; growth and education. Educational needs are related to the knowledge, attitude or skills that human resources need them in order to carry out their job responsibilities optimally. Thus, this paper has been done aiming to investigate educational needs with the approach of job analysis. Research method is mixed exploratory. In qualitative part, research samples were 13 financial and urban economy experts selected by purposive sampling. Data were collected by semi-structured interview. In this part, required knowledge, skill, technology, and instrument for four jobs of accountant, auditor, document expert, and urban economy expert of Tehran Municipality were identified and four questionnaires were developed based on it. In quantitative part, 143 people were selected by simple random sampling method among financial and urban economy experts of Tehran Municipality including 62 urban economy experts, 49 accountants, 22 auditors, and 10 document experts. In order to analyze data statistically, Lee Hee and one sample t-tests were used. Finally, educational needs of four jobs including accountant, auditor, document expert, and financial and urban economy expert of Tehran Municipality were obtained. According to the priorities, for high priority needs, educational plan was proposed for the first year.},  
Keywords = {: Educational needs, job analysis, financial and urban economy experts, Tehran Municipality},
volume = {4},
Number = {15}, 
pages = {127-146}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-466-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-466-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Taghavifard, Mohammad Taghi and KhatamiFiroozabadi, Seyyed Mohammad Ali and Sajjadi, Seyyed Khalilollah},  
title = {Increasing Citizens’ Satisfaction from Bank Shahr ATMs and Reducing Bank’s Economic Costs by Applying Simulation Model of Inventory Control}, 
abstract ={One of the most important indicators of citizens&#8217; satisfaction in metropolises is to provide efficiently banking tools in city.&#160; Keeping cash in ATMs is very important for banks. In this paper, increasing citizens&#8217; satisfaction from Bank Shahr ATMs has been investigated by using questionnaire among 200 citizens who used them before and after implementing inventory control policy of ATMs&#8217; cash. This paper investigates the relationship between citizens&#8217; satisfaction evaluation and active ATMs by presenting a model of minimizing total costs of missed opportunity for ATMs. In order to simulate consumer behavior of ATMs, Arena software was used. The results indicated that this model can present reorder point, money order, and combination of notes for each ATM. One of the most important findings is identification of effective factors on citizens&#8217; satisfaction from ATMs and a model to optimize missed client&#8217;s costs and surplus money in them. By the help of this model, satisfaction has been increased. The results represented that citizens&#8217; satisfaction from services has been reached to 80 percent from 25 percent. Finally, daily total cost of each ATM has been reduced from 1859000 Rials for each ATM to 1147000 Rials.},  
Keywords = {citizens’ satisfaction, ATM, simulation, inventory control, Bank Shahr},
volume = {4},
Number = {16}, 
pages = {1-18}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-542-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-542-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Maqsoodpoor, Mohammad Ali},  
title = {The Impact of Service Sector on Forming Primate City Phenomenon in Khuzestan Province}, 
abstract ={In the literature of urban economics, primate city is a phenomenon that a very large city is formed among small cities in urban system of a region that a major part of population and its economic activities of that region is concentrated in it. According to urban economics theories, GFP is one of the factors that can be influential in forming a primate city phenomenon. Given service sector in the economy of Khuzestan Province and despite this province is industrial one, more than half of employed people are engaged in service sector. In this research, the effectiveness of service sector on forming the phenomenon of primate city in this province has been addressed by separating GDP based on sectors&#8217; VAT. To do this research, time series data during 1991-2011 and Autoregressive Distributed Lag (ARDL) model by using Microfit software were used. The results indicated that service sector has significant impact on primate city of Khuzestan Province both in short-term and long-term. According to the findings, for balanced growth of urban system in the province, it is recommended that to change supportive policies from service sector to other economic sectors of the province, particularly agriculture sector.},  
Keywords = {urban economy, urban concentration, primate city, Khuzestan Province},
volume = {4},
Number = {16}, 
pages = {19-35}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-543-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-543-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Amirnejad, Hamid and NabizadehZolpirani, Mojtaba and HeydariKamalabadi, Rez},  
title = {The Impact of Rasht Eynak Lagoon on Housing Price of the Region by Using Hedonic Pricing Method}, 
abstract ={One of the most considerable issues in large cities is environmental impacts of lagoons on housing price. Thus, this research investigates the impact of Rasht Eynak Lagoon on housing price of the region by using Hedonic-pricing method. The studied area included residential units of Rasht area 2, district 4 near Eynak Lagoon. In terms of purpose, this research is applied, and it is survey in terms of methodology. Statistical population includes all residential units in area4, district 4 in the city of Rasht. 90 of them were selected as simple random sampling method and Cochran formula as sample. Statistical data were collected through filling questionnaire in autumn 2013 and analyzed by OLS method and Eviews 8 software. The results indicated that Eynak Lagoon (environmental factors) had negative impact on the price of residential units in the region. As distance from the lagoon increases, housing price rises. However, the variables of land area, type of housing, type of skeleton, and access to medical centers had positive impact on housing price. Contrarily, the variables of distance from Main Street, distance to city center, and access to park had negative impact on housing price in the studied area. Moreover, the variable of distance from Eynak Lagoon affected the most on dependent variable.},  
Keywords = {urban economy and management, Hedonic function, Eynak Lagoon, housing price, Rasht},
volume = {4},
Number = {16}, 
pages = {37-53}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-544-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-544-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Alizadeh, Katayoon and MirzaeianKhamseh, Peyvand and Ettehadi, Shaghayegh},  
title = {Explanation of the City Brand Equity Role on Specialists’ Immigration  (Case of Study: Mashhad)}, 
abstract ={Brand equity is one of the significant categories in the international competition field, through which we can decrease the rate of immigration from cities and protect urban human resources. The purpose of this text is to find an organized and a coherent answer in regards to reasons of reduction of immigration of specialists who are post graduated in Mashhad and their sense of belonging to their own city as well. There are numbers of reasons for promotion of sense of attachment, so city identity shall be deemed as an important topic in this regard. However, branding topic in this area is what has been underestimated in former researches. Now the question is how an urban brand can leave an impression on the immigration of experts who are post graduated. Therefore, the current Manuscript presents a creative real model for explanation of the city brand role on reduction of specialists&#8217; immigration rate from Mashhad, emphasizing the role of identity as a mediator. The data being required for this research have been collected by questionnaires, through an accessible targeted non-random sampling from specialists from Mashhad who are post graduated. This research is an applied-surveying type in which the structural equations method is used by use of Smart PLS software for data analysis. The results show that the city brand is effective on identification and reduction of rate of immigration from Mashhad. The role of identity as a mediator in impression of city brand on reduction of rate of immigration from Mashhad has been proved in review of indirect effect of this study.&#160;},  
Keywords = {City Brand Equity, Immigration, Identity, Mashhad},
volume = {4},
Number = {16}, 
pages = {55-69}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-545-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-545-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {MohammadpourZarandi, Hamed and Abbaspour, Majid and Arjmandi, Rez},  
title = {Formulating Managerial Strategies for Development of Green Buildings (Case Study: Tehran Municipality-district1)}, 
abstract ={&#160;Planning is researchers&#8217; main concern in recent years to enhance environmental standards in metropolises and one of the pillars to achieve to sustainable development. One of the presented strategies to improve environment quality in urban areas is architecture and constructing consistent with the environment. In addition to economic function in saving energy resources, this idea has environmentally favorable impacts. In this research, it has been tried to specify strategic location of construction development consistent with the environment (green buildings) in Tehran Municipality by using SWOT analysis. According the results, strategic location in relation with construction development consistent with the environment in Tehran Municipality- district 1 is conservative; therefore, seven strategies were proposed in order to eliminate current weaknesses by using opportunities. The most important managerial strategies for construction development consistent with the environment include absorbing international investments from actively environmental bodies in order to reduce primary costs, encouraging investors in order to increase public willingness to invest, and necessity to construct green buildings by governmental bodies (banks) to motivate society.},  
Keywords = {managerial strategies, green buildings, urban environment, urban sustainable development, SWOT analysis, Tehran Municipality},
volume = {4},
Number = {16}, 
pages = {71-86}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-546-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-546-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Baqeri, Hossein and Ebnereza, Seyyed Majid and Sahrayi, Faramarz},  
title = {Identifying Economic Globalization Strategies in Urban Diplomacy  (Case Study: Tehran Metropolis)}, 
abstract ={In the past two decades, economic globalization has changed many human life arenas in different areas of the world. In this regard, metropolises, affected by manifestations of globalization, create a new form of diplomacy, called as urban diplomacy, by promoting their economic status, infrastructures, etc. It has been tried in this paper to explain and analyze the relationship between economic globalization and urban diplomacy by using quantitative-analytical SWOT model, qualitative method of brainstorming to present a systematic image of strengths, weaknesses, threats, and opportunities of economic globalization effects on urban diplomacy of Tehran Metropolis and its diplomacy structure facing with manifestations of economic globalization. The methodology is descriptive-analytical by using library resources and SWOT analytical model by weighting indexes through brainstorming method with 30 economics and diplomacy experts to explain the relationship between economic globalization and urban diplomacy, and the role of Tehran Metropolis in this arena. Research findings indicated that a type of globalization entitled globalization-localization model has better fitness for Tehran Metropolis. This model is consistent with globalization necessities and urban diplomacy aspects of Tehran Metropolis with local conditions in order to balance localization with globalization.},  
Keywords = {Metropolises, globalization, global economy, urban diplomacy, globalization-localization, SWOT analysis, Tehran},
volume = {4},
Number = {16}, 
pages = {87-106}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-547-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-547-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Safari, Saeid and Beyginiya, Abdolreza and Samizadeh, Mahdi and Zakerifar, Seyyed Jamal},  
title = {Designing and Organizing Measurement Components of Urban Management Function by Emphasizing on Good Urban Governance and Balanced Evaluation}, 
abstract ={Much attempt has been focused on changing and improving the structure and form of designing performance evaluation systems so far and less attention has been paid to content of issues.&#160; Thus, this research aims to design performance measurement indicators in urban management by integrating balanced evaluation model (for structural aspect) and components of good governance approved by the United Nations Development Programme (for content aspect) in the field of organizational performance. In order to access to research purpose, after redefining the components of good governance in four aspects of balanced evaluation via semi-structured depth interviews with executive managers of municipality and university professors, 103 indicators in the first step, and 95 indicators in the second step were extracted to measure the performance of urban management. In the following, these indicators were evaluated with Delphi method by academic and organizational experts. The results indicated that 73 indicators were confirmed by academic and organizational experts among designed ones given eight good governance components and four aspects of balanced evaluation for performance measurement. Thus, these indicators are appropriate guides for better development of performance evaluation system in urban economics for managers to be aware of impacts and consequences of organization&#8217;s administrative decisions and plans.},  
Keywords = {performance measurement, good governance, balanced evaluation, urban management},
volume = {4},
Number = {16}, 
pages = {107-125}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-548-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-548-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Kia, Ali Asqar and Latifi, Gholamreza and Rasooli, Mohammadreza and Kazemnia, Mohammad Ehs},  
title = {The Role of the Mass Media in Urban Management  (Case Study: 22-district of Tehran Municipality)}, 
abstract ={Urban management in today&#8217;s competitive world should be able to identify city&#8217;s strengths and weaknesses and improve its competitive advantages. The importance of urban management in order to access to urban sustainable development is to improve citizens&#8217; conditions and quality of life, protect city&#8217;s physical environment, enhance citizens&#8217; trust level to urban management, and improve their participation level in managing urban affairs. On the other hand, media, as a powerful component of civil society, affect different parts of the community; therefore, this research explains the role of mass media in urban management. Research methodology is survey. Statistical population includes clients of 22-district of Tehran Municipality in 2014. 400 of them were selected as sample research by stratified cluster random sampling. To collect data, research-made questionnaire, including 24 questions, was used. It was obtained by interviewing with experts. Its face validity was confirmed and its reliability was calculated by Cronbach&#8217;s alpha. In order to analyze data statistically, one-sample t-test, ANOVA, and Lee Hee tests were used. The results indicated that the role of mass media in urban management is more than average. However, mass media influence more on improvement of citizen&#8217;s participation in administering urban affairs and it affects citizen&#8217;s trust level less.&#160;},  
Keywords = {mass media, urban management, 22 districts, Tehran Municipality},
volume = {4},
Number = {16}, 
pages = {127-138}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-549-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-549-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2016}  
}

