<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</title>
<title_fa>فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری</title_fa>
<short_title>IUESA</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iueam.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2345-2870</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-6398</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/iueam</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>en</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1398</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2019</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>7</volume>
<number>26</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی عوامل ‌تعیین‌کننده‌ ‌اجاره مسکن در شهر ایلام با رویکرد اقتصادسنجی‌ فضایی هدانیک</title_fa>
	<title>The Study of Determinants of Rent Housing in Ilam City Based on Hedonic Spatial Econometrics</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:yekanyw;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;چکیده:&lt;/strong&gt; واحد مسکونی، &#8204;کالایی ناهمگن و چندبُعدی است؛ از این&#8204;رو برای تعیین عوامل مؤثر بر اجاره&#8204;بهای واحدهای مسکونی، از روش هدانیک استفاده می&#8204;شود. برای تبیین این عوامل، از چهار ویژگی برای مسکن استفاده می&#8204;شود که عبارتند از: متغیرهای&#8204;کالبدی- فیزیکی واحدهای &#8204;مسکونی، متغیرهای دسترسی، متغیرهای محیطی (همسایگی) و &#8204;ویژگی&#8204;های &#8204;اقتصادی و اجتماعی&#8204; خانوارها. متغیرهای مربوط به ویژگی فضایی، با استفاده از هدانیک فضایی و به منظور مقید ساختن تابع اجاره&#8204;بها به مکان، به کار می&#8204;روند. تکنیک هدانیک فضایی، به خوبی قادر است ضمن تعیین عوامل مؤثر بر اجاره مسکن، تأثیرپذیری اجاره مسکن از سایر ویژگی&#8204;های مسکن&#8204;های مجاور را نیز بررسی &#8204;کند. در این مقاله، با بهره&#8204;گیری از فرم&#8204;های خطی، نیمه&#8204;لگاریتمی، لگاریتمی و مدل باکس- کاکس، تأثیر هرکدام از ویژگی&#8204;های مختلف واحدهای مسکونی استیجاری بر قیمت اجاره&#8204;بهای آن با استفاده از تابع&#8204; هدانیک ساده و فضایی، بررسی شده است. نتایج به&#8204;دست آمده بیانگر این است که بهترین مدل، مدل خطی است و در بین واحدهای مسکونی آپارتمانی شهر ایلام، عوامل فیزیکی و اقتصادی- اجتماعی، بیشتر از متغیرهای همسایگی و دسترسی، اجاره واحد&#8204;های مسکونی را تحت تأثیر قرار می&#8204;دهند، همچنین اثر متغیر وابسته فضایی در مدل هدانیک فضایی بر اجاره&#8204;بها، کاملاً معنی&#8204;دار و مثبت می&#8204;باشد. مدل برآورد شده از روش اقتصاد&#8204;سنجی فضایی از لحاظ خوبی برازش، درصد معنی&#8204;داری ضرایب و همچنین توضیح&#8204;دهندگی اثر متغیرهای موجود در مدل، نسبت به روش اقتصادسنجی، متعارف، کاراتر و بهتر می&#8204;باشد.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: Housing unit is heterogeneous and multidimensional commodity; therefore, to determine effective factors on rent, hedonic pricing model is used. To explain the factors, four properties are used for housing, which are physical variables of residential units, access variables, environmental variables (neighborhood), and economic and social characteristics. The variables related to the spatial property are used by spatial hedonics to bind the lease function to the location. Spatial hedonic technique is able to determine the effective factors on the rental of housing, also the impact of renting housing from other properties of adjacent ones. In this paper, using linear, semi-logarithmic, logarithmic and box-cox models, the effect of each of the properties of leased residential units on their rental prices has been investigated using simple and spatial hedonic function. The results indicate that the best model is the linear model. Moreover, among the residential apartments in Ilam, physical and socioeconomic factors affect the rental of residential units more than neighborhoods and access variables, as well as the effect of spatial dependent variable in spatial hedonic model on rentals is quite significant and positive. The estimated model of spatial econometric method is well fitted; the percentage of coefficients and the explanation of the effect of the variables in the model are more efficient and better than conventional econometric methods.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>اجاره‌بها, هدانیک, اقتصادسنجی فضایی, وابستگی فضایی, ناهمسانی فضایی</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Rent, Hedonic, Spatial Econometric, Spatial Dependence, Spatial Heterogeneity</keyword>
	<start_page>15</start_page>
	<end_page>27</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-857-2&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Sajad </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Rezaeian</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سجاد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رضائیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846005260</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846005260</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Literature and Humanities, University of Ilam, Ilam, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه ایلام، ایلام، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Heshmatolah </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Asgari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حشمت‌الله</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عسگری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>he.asgari@ gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846005261</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846005261</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Department of Economics, Faculty of Literature and Humanities, University of Ilam, Ilam, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه ایلام، ایلام، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Bagher </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Darvishi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>باقر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>درویشی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846005262</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846005262</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Department of Economics, Faculty of Literature and Humanities, University of Ilam, Ilam, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه ایلام، ایلام، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
