<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>2020</YEAR>
<VOL>8</VOL>
<NO>30</NO>
<MOSALSAL>0</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>153</PAGE_NO>


<ARTICLES>

	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>ارائه استراتژی‎های ضروری جهت راه‎اندازی پارکینگ هوشمند دوربین‌محور</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Provide the Necessary Strategies for Launching Intelligent Camera-based Parking</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>یکی از موضوعات مهم و قابل&#8206;توجه وضعیت حمل&#8206;ونقل شهری، مسئله پارکینگ خودروهای سیار در فضای شهر می&#8204;باشد. ضرورت توجه به این امر باعث شده که در دهه&#8204;های اخیر، راهکارهای متعددی برای ساماندهی و مدیریت وضعیت پارک خوردوها در فضاهای درون شهری ارائه گردد که در این میان، توجه به تکنولوژی&#8204;های روز و نقش و جایگاه آنها در مدیریت این فضاها روز به روز در حال افزایش می&#8204;باشد. در این ارتباط شاید یکی از به&#8204;روزترین پارکینگ&#8204;های هوشمند در سطح دنیا، پارکینگ&#8206;های دوربین&#8206;محور می&#8206;باشد که ظرفیت قابل&#8204;توجهی را هم از نظر مدیریت حمل&#8206;ونقل شهری و هم از نظر درآمدزایی، برای مدیریت شهری فراهم نموده است. این تحقیق با هدف بررسی نقش و اهمیت پارکینگ&#8204;های هوشمند دوربین&#8204;محور در فضاهای شهری و استخراج زمینه&#8204;ها و راهبردهای لازم برای استفاده مدیریت شهری در بهره&#8204;برداری بهتر از این نوع پارکینگ&#8204;ها، انجام شده است. از این رو با ۱۵ نفر از خبرگان دانشگاهی و اجرایی در حوزه&#8204;های مربوط به مدیریت و حمل&#8206;ونقل شهری مصاحبه انجام شد و سپس با استفاده از روش تحلیل مضمون، شش کد محوری به عنوان زمینه&#8204;های اصلی راه&#8204;اندازی این نوع پارکینگ&#8204;ها شناسایی گردید. در گام بعدی با استفاده از روش تحلیل SWOT به تحلیل نقاط قوت و ضعف و فرصت&#8204;ها و تهدیدات مربوط به استفاده از دوربین&#8204;های هوشمند در مکان&#8204;یابی جای پارک در سطح شهر پرداخته شده و مهم&#8204;ترین راهبردهای لازم جهت استفاده مدیران شهری از پارکینگ&#8204;های دوربین&#8204;محور استخراج گردیده است. در نهایت با استفاده از ماتریس برنامه&#8204;ریزی کمی QSPM، راهبردهای کلیدی انتخابی، اولویت&#8204;بندی شدند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>One of the most important and significant issues in urban transportation is the issue of mobile car parking in the city. The need to pay attention to this has led to the introduction of several strategies in recent decades to organize and manage the condition of car parks in urban areas. Meanwhile, attention to modern technologies and their role and position in the management of these spaces is increasing day by day. In this regard, perhaps one of the best intelligent parking lots in the world is camera-based parking lots, which has provided significant capacity for urban management, both in terms of urban transportation management and revenue generation. The aim of this study was to investigate the role and importance of intelligent camera-based parking lots, focusing on urban spaces and extracting the necessary grounds and strategies for the use of urban management in the better use of this type of parking. Therefore, interviews were conducted with 16 academic and executive experts in the fields of urban management and transportation, and then, using the thematic analysis method, six central codes were identified as the main areas for launching this type of parking. In the next step, using SWOT analysis method, the strengths, weaknesses, opportunities and threats related to using smart cameras in locating parking spaces in the city are analyzed and the most important strategies necessary for city managers to use camera-oriented parking lots are extracted. Finally, using the QSPM quantitative programming matrix, key strategies were selected and prioritized.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>22</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سید جلال‌الدین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>فرجی</Family>
				<NameE>Seyed Jalalaldin</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Faraji</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Public and Urban Management, Faculty of Management and Accounting, Allameh Tabataba'i University, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>f.jalalfaraji@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>علیخانی</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Alikhani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Justice University, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه عدالت، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مرجان</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>جعفری نوذر</Family>
				<NameE>Marjan</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Jafari Nozar</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Management and Accountant, Allameh Tabataba'i University, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سید محسن</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>طباطبایی مزدآبادی</Family>
				<NameE>Seyyed Mohsen</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Tabatabaei Mozdabadi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Allameh Tabatabai University, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Smart City</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Smart Transportation</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Intelligent Parking</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Intelligent Camera-based Parking</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شهر هوشمند</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>حمل‎ونقل هوشمند</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پارکینگ هوشمند</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پارکینگ دوربین‌محور</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##ابوطالبی اصفهانی، محسن؛ کیانی، شادان. (1393). ارزیابی سیستم پارکینگ هوشمند و زیرساخت‌های لازم آن. کنفرانس مهندسی عمران، معماری و مدیریت پایدار شهر.##پورمحمدی امامیه، حامد؛ امین‌نیا، ایرج؛ خدادادی، لاریسا. (1395). طراحی سیستمی جهت هوشمندسازی پارکینگ بیمارستان با استفاده از سنسورهای التراسونیک و پردازش تصویر. کنفرانس ملی پژوهش‌های نوین در مهندسی برق.##حافظ‌نظامی، علیرضا. (1391). اصول و ضوابط پیشنهادی احداث پارکینگ‌های مشاعی در محلات. یازدهمین کنفرانس بین‌المللی مهندسی حمل‎ونقل و ترافیک.##حکمت‌نیا؛ حسن؛ موسوی، میرنجف. (1390). کاربرد مدل در جغرافیا. چاپ دوم، تهران: علم نوین. ##روشندل، تکتم؛ اکبری، الهه. (1393). ساماندهی مکان پارکینگ عمومی در شهر سبزوار با استفاده از GIS. ششمین کنفرانس ملی برنامه‌ریزی و مدیریت شهری با تأکید بر مؤلفه‌های شهر اسلامی.##رئوفی کاظم؛ رجبی، فرشید؛ میرعباسی، رمضان. (1388). بهره‌گیری از فناوری هوشمند در سیستم راهنمای جای پارک خودرو. کنفرانس شهر الکترونیک.##صادقی دروازه، سعید؛ قاسمی، احمدرضا؛ رسولی تیله نوئی، ندا؛ شول، عباس. (1396). مکانیابی پارکینگ‌های مکانیزه با رویکرد توسعه پایدار (مورد مطالعه: شهر قم). فصلنامه اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری، 6(21)، 127-111.##طالب‌زاده، رضا؛ طالب‌زاده، پروین. (1393) طراحی سیستم پارکینگ هوشمند برای توسعه پایدار شهری مبتنی بر تکنیک‌های پردازش تصویر. دومین کنگره بین‌المللی سازه، معماری و توسعه شهری. ##قنبری، حسین؛ نوبخت حبیبی، شهاب، محمدی، مریم. (1394). پارکینگ اختصاصی در شهر رشت. مجله پژوهش‎های بوم‎شناسی شهری، 8(15)، 64-43.##معاونت عمرانی دفتر حمل‌ونقل و دبیرخانه شورای عالی هماهنگی ترافیکی شهرهای کشور. (1386). راهنمای روش‌های مدیریت پارک حاشیه‌ای در معابر شهری.##Bilal, M., Persson, C., Ramparany, F., Picard, G., &amp; Boissier, O. (2012, June). Multi-agent based governance model for machine-to-machine networks in a smart parking management system. In 2012 IEEE International Conference on Communications (ICC) (pp. 6468-6472). IEEE.##Caicedo, F. (2012). Charging parking by the minute: What to expect from this parking pricing policy?. Transport Policy, 19(1), 63-68.##Faraji, S. J., &amp; Nozar, M. J. (2019). Smart parking: an efficient approach to city’s smart management and air pollution reduction. Journal of Air Pollution and Health.##Gupta, A., Kulkarni, S., Jathar, V., Sharma, V., &amp; Jain, N. (2017). Smart car parking management system using IoT. Am. J. Sci. Eng. Technol, 2, 112.##Huang, C. C., Tai, Y. S., &amp; Wang, S. J. (2013). Vacant parking space detection based on plane-based Bayesian hierarchical framework. IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology, 23(9), 1598-1610.##Ichihashi, H., Notsu, A., Honda, K., Katada, T., &amp; Fujiyoshi, M. (2009, August). Vacant parking space detector for outdoor parking lot by using surveillance camera and FCM classifier. In 2009 IEEE International Conference on Fuzzy Systems (pp. 127-134). IEEE.##Jun, Y. (2010, August). A system framework of active parking guidance and information system. In 2010 WASE International ## Conference on Information Engineering (Vol. 2, pp. 150-154). IEEE.##Khanna, A., &amp; Anand, R. (2016, January). IoT based smart parking system. In 2016 International Conference on Internet of Things and Applications (IOTA) (pp. 266-270). IEEE.##Kianpisheh, A., Mustaffa, N., Limtrairut, P., &amp; Keikhosrokiani, P. (2012). Smart parking system (SPS) architecture using ultrasonic detector. International Journal of Software Engineering and Its Applications, 6(3), 55-58.##Lin, T. S. (2015). Smart parking: network, infrastructure and urban service (Doctoral dissertation, Lyon, INSA).##Lin, T., Rivano, H., &amp; Le Mouël, F. (2017). A survey of smart parking solutions. IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems, 18(12), 3229-3253.##Manville, M., &amp; Shoup, D. (2005). Parking, people, and cities. Journal of urban planning and development, 131(4), 233-245.##Mouskos, K. C., Boile, M., &amp; Parker, N. (2007). Technical solutions to overcrowded park and ride facilities (No. FHWA-NJ-2007-011). New Jersey. Dept. of Transportation.##Paidi, V., Fleyeh, H., Håkansson, J., &amp; Nyberg, R. G. (2018). Smart parking sensors, technologies and applications for open parking lots: a review. IET Intelligent Transport Systems, 12(8), 735-741.##Polycarpou, E., Lambrinos, L., &amp; Protopapadakis, E. (2013, June). Smart  parking solutions for urban areas. In 2013 IEEE 14th International Symposium on&quot; A World of Wireless, Mobile and Multimedia Networks&quot; (WoWMoM) (pp. 1-6). IEEE.##Sathya, V., Sai, S., Tharad, A., Kumar, A., Kumar, S., &amp; Verma, U. (2020). Cloud Based Smart Parking System. Journal of Computational and Theoretical Nanoscience, 17(4), 1578-1583.##Shaheen, S. (2005). Smart parking management field test: A bay area rapid transit (bart) district parking demonstration.##Shoup, D. C. (2006). Cruising for parking. Transport Policy, 13(6), 479-486.##Tumlin, J. (2012). Sustainable Transportation Planning: Tools for Creating Vibrant and resilient communities, New Jersey, John Wiley press.##Vera-Gómez, J. A., Quesada-Arencibia, A., García, C. R., Suárez Moreno, R., &amp; Guerra Hernández, F. (2016). An intelligent parking management system for urban areas. Sensors, 16(6), 931.##Vianna, M. M. B., da Silva Portugal, L., &amp; Balassiano, R. (2004). Intelligent transportation systems and parking management: implementation potential in a Brazilian city. Cities, 21(2), 137-148.##Wang, R., &amp; Yuan, Q. (2013). Parking practices and policies under rapid motorization: The case of China. Transport Policy, 30, 109-116. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر شاخص‌های غیرمالی بر پیش‌بینی وقوع درماندگی مالی از دیدگاه مدیران شهری (مورد مطالعه: بانک شهر)</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Investigating the Effect of Non-financial Indicators on Forecasting the Occurrence of Financial Distress  from the View of Urban Managers (Case Study: Bank Shahr)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>هدف این پژوهش، بررسی تأثیر شاخص&#8204;های غیرمالی بر پیش&#8204;بینی وقوع درماندگی مالی در بانک شهر از دیدگاه مدیران شهری با استفاده از رویکرد مدل&#8204;یابی معادلات ساختاری می&#8204;باشد. این پژوهش از نظر هدف، کاربردی و از نظر روش، توصیفی- پیمایشی است. جامعه آماری پژوهش را ۵۳ نفر از مدیران سطح ارشد و میانی شهرداری تهران و بانک شهر تشکیل دادند. به منظور جمع&#8204;آوری اطلاعات از روش&#8204;های کتابخانه&#8204;ای و میدانی (پرسشنامه) استفاده شد. روش تجزیه&#8204;وتحلیل داده&#8204;های تحقیق، روش مدل&#8204;یابی معادلات ساختاری در نرم&#8206;افزار Smart PLS بود. نتایج نشان دادند که از دیدگاه مدیران شهری شاخص&#8204;های حاکمیت شرکتی، توانایی مدیریت و رقابت&#8204;پذیری، شاخص&#8204;هایی با ماهیت غیرمالی هستند که می&#8204;توانند در پیش&#8204;بینی وقوع درماندگی مالی بسیار مؤثر باشند؛ به&#8204;طوری که حاکمیت شرکتی ۶۵ درصد، توانایی مدیریت ۴۷ درصد و شاخص رقابت&#8204;پذیر&#8204;ی ۵۶ درصد تغییرات مربوط به متغیر پیش&#8204;بینی وقوع درماندگی مالی را به طور مستقیم تبیین می&#8204;کنند. همچنین بررسی نهایی نتایج نشان می&#8204;دهد که بین شاخص&#8204;های غیرمالی و پیش&#8204;بینی وقوع درماندگی مالی، همبستگی مثبت و معناداری وجود دارد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The purpose of this study was to investigate the effect of non-financial indicators on forecasting The occurrence of financial distress in the Shahr Bank from the point of view of urban managers using the structural equation modeling approach. This research is an applied research in terms of purpose And in terms of method, it was a descriptive-survey study. The statistical population of the study consisted of 53 senior and middle managers of Tehran Municipality and Shahr Bank. gathering of information has been done in the library form and field study method (questionnaires) were used to collect information. The method of analyzing the research data was structural equations modeling in Smart PLS software. The results showed that from the perspective of urban managers, corporate governance indicators, management ability and competitiveness are indicators with a non-financial nature Which can be very effective in forecasting The occurrence of financial distress So that corporate governance 65%, management ability 47% and competitiveness index 56% directly determine the changes related to the variable of forecasting the occurrence of financial distress. Also, the final study results shows that there is a positive and significant correlation between non-financial indicators and forecasting the occurrence of financial distress.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>23</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>38</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>بهنام</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>محبی هره‌دشت</Family>
				<NameE>Behnam</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Mohebbi Herdasht</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Humanities, Qom Branch, Islamic Azad University, Qom, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده علوم انسانی، واحد قم، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، قم، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سید کاظم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>چاوشی</Family>
				<NameE>Seyed Kazem</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Chavoshi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Business Administration, Faculty of Management, Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>chavoshi@khu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>جهانگیرنیا</Family>
				<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Jahangirnia</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Accounting and Finance, Faculty of Humanities, Qom Branch, Islamic Azad University, Qom, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده علوم انسانی، واحد قم، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، قم، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>رضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>غلامی جمکرانی</Family>
				<NameE>Reza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Gholami Jamkarani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Accounting and Finance, Faculty of Humanities, Qom Branch, Islamic Azad University, Qom, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده علوم انسانی، واحد قم، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، قم، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Non-financial Indicators</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Financial Distress</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Corporate Governance</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Management Ability</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Competitiveness</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>City Managers</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Bank Shahr</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شاخص‌های غیرمالی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>درماندگی مالی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>حاکمیت شرکتی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>توانایی مدیریت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>رقابت‌پذیر‌ی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدیران شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بانک شهر</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##چالاکی، پری؛ منصورفر، غلامرضا؛ کرمی، امیر. (1397). بررسی تأثیر توانایی مدیریت بر درماندگی مالی با تأکید بر انعطاف‎پذیری مالی. نشریه دانش حسابداری مالی، 5(1(پیاپی 16))، 180-153.##حساس یگانه، یحیی؛ حبیبی، رضا؛ نازی، بهزاد. (1396). تأثیر کیفیت دارایی بر درماندگی مالی بانک‌ها. فصلنامه مطالعات مالی و بانکداری اسلامی، 3(6 و 7)، 58-25.##حیدری، مهدی؛ منصورفر، غلامرضا؛ قاسم‎‎زاده، مرتضی. (1397). عوامل تعیین‎کننده ساختار سرمایه و نقش تعدیلگری درماندگی مالی؛ رویکرد الگوسازی معادلات ساختاری. نشریه پژوهش‌های حسابداری مالی، 10(2(پیاپی 36))، 23-44.##خاکی، غلامرضا. (1390). روش تحقیق با رویکردی با پایان‌نامه‌نویسی. چاپ نهم، تهران: بازتاب.##داوری، علی؛ رضازاده، آرش. (1392). مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری با نرم‌افزار PLS. تهران: جهاد دانشگاهی. ##رستمی، سعید. (1397). تأثیر حاکمیت شرکتی و مدیریت سود بر ورشکستگی شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. فصلنامه مطالعات مدیریت و حسابداری، 4(3)، 144-123. ##سراج، سودابه؛ طاهری، ماندانا. (1391). نظارت بانکی براساس سیستم ‎هشدار سریع، با استفاده از نسبت‎های CAMEL، در قالب مدل لاجیت. نشریه پژوهش‎های پولی-بانکی، شماره 12، 70-45.##علوی، موسی. (1392). مدل‎یابی معادلات ساختاری در پژوهش‌های مرتبط با آموزش علوم سلامت: معرفی روش و کاربرد آن. مجله ایرانی آموزش در علوم پزشکی، 13(6)، 530-519. ##علی‌فری، ملیحه؛ محمودیان، امیر؛ دخانی، نوید. (1397). بررسی رابطه متغیرهای سیستماتیک (اقتصاد کلان) و غیرسیستماتیک (حاکمیت شرکتی) بر درماندگی مالی شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. کنگره ملی تحقیقات بنیادین در مدیریت اقتصاد و حسابداری. ##غیور، فرزاد. (1396). تبیین عوامل مالی و غیرمالی مؤثر بر پیش‌بینی درماندگی مالی و مقایسه توانایی مدل‌های پارامتریک و ناپارامتریک. پایان‎نامه دکتری، دانشکده علوم اقتصادی و اداری، دانشگاه مازندران. ##مشیری، سعید؛ نادعلی، محمد. (1392). شناسایی عوامل مؤثر در بروز بحران بانکی در اقتصاد ایران. فصلنامه پژوهشنامه اقتصادی، 13(48)، 27-1.##وقفی، سید حسام؛ دارابی، رویا. (1397). رویکرد مدل معادلات ساختاری در تحلیل سه سطحی درماندگی مالی در شرکت‎های پذیرفته‌شده بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. نشریه راهبرد مدیریت مالی، 6(3)، 215-189. ##Altman, E. I., Iwanicz-Drozdowska, M., Laitinen, E. K., &amp; Suvas, A. (2015). Financial and non-financial variables as long-horizon predictors of bankruptcy. Available at SSRN 2669668.##Chairunesia, W., &amp; Bintara, R. (2019). The Effect of Good Corporate Governance and Financial Distress on Earnings Management in Indonesian and Malaysia Companies Entered in Asean Corporate Governance Scorecard. International Journal of Academic Research in Accounting, Finance and Management Sciences, 9(2), 224-236.##Chi, X., Lou, C. &amp; Yu, X. (2011). Financial distress prediction based on SVM and MDA methods: the case of Chinese listed companies. Quality and Quantity, 45(3), 671-686.##Chiaramonte, L., &amp; Casu, B. (2017). Capital and liquidity ratios and financial distress. Evidence from the European banking industry. The British Accounting Review, 49(2), 138-161.##Chin, W. W. (2010). How to write up and report PLS analyses. In Handbook of partial least squares (pp. 655-690). Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg.##Chino, F., Peppercorn, J. M., Rushing, C., Kamal, A. H., Altomare, I., Samsa, G., &amp; Zafar, S. Y. (2017). Out-of-pocket costs, financial distress, and underinsurance in cancer care. JAMA oncology, 3(11), 1582-1584.##Fornell, C., &amp; Larcker, D. F. (1981). Evaluating structural equation models with unobservable variables and measurement error. Journal of marketing research, 18(1), 39-50.##Gao, P., Parsons, C. A., &amp; Shen, J. (2018). Global relation between financial distress and equity returns. The Review of Financial Studies, 31(1), 239-277.##Gul, F. A., Khedmati, M., Lim, E. K., &amp; Navissi, F. (2018). Managerial ability, financial distress, and audit fees. Accounting Horizons, 32(1), 29-51.##Hazak, A., Männasoo, K., &amp; Virkebau, M. (2017). Effects of work arrangements on creative R&amp;D work outcomes. Eastern European Economics, 55(6), 500-521.##Henseler, J., Ringle, C. M., &amp; Sinkovics, R. R. (2009). The use of partial least squares path modeling in international marketing. In New challenges to international marketing. Emerald Group Publishing Limited.##Hoffmann, S., &amp; Rodrigo, P. (2011). Determinants of the Profitability of the US Banking Industry.##Idrees, S., &amp; Qayyum, A. (2018). The impact of financial distress risk on equity returns: A case study of non-financial firms of Pakistan Stock Exchange. Journal of Economics Bibliography, 5(2), 49-59.##Kaplan, S. N., &amp; Zingales, L. (1997). Do investment-cash flow sensitivities provide useful measures of financing constraints?. The quarterly journal of economics, 112(1), 169-215.##Khurshid, M. K., Sabir, H. M., Tahir, S. H., &amp; Abrar, M. (2018). Impact of Corporate Governance on the Likelihood of Financial Distress: Evidence from Non-Financial Firms of Pakistan. PACIFIC BUSINESS REVIEW INTERNATIONAL, 11(4), 134-149.##Li, S., Ragu-Nathan, B., Ragu-Nathan, T. S., &amp; Rao, S. S. (2006). The impact of  ##supply chain management practices on competitive advantage and organizational performance. Omega, 34(2), 107-124.##Madrid-Guijarro, A., García-Pérez-de-Lema, D., &amp; Van Auken, H. (2011). An analysis of non-financial factors associated with financial distress. Entrepreneurship and Regional Development, 23(3-4), 159-186.##Mafiroh, A., &amp; Triyono, T. (2016). Effect of corporate governance financial performance and mechanism on financial distress (Empirical Study of Manufacturing Companies Listed on Indonesia Stock Exchange Period 2011-2014). Riset Akuntansi dan Keuangan Indonesia, 1(1),45-63.##Mahtani, U. S., &amp; Garg, C. P. (2018). An analysis of key factors of financial distress in airline companies in India using fuzzy AHP framework. Transportation Research Part A: Policy and Practice, 117, 87-102.##McLean, R. D., &amp; Pontiff, J. (2016). Does academic research destroy stock return predictability?. The Journal of Finance, 71(1), 5-32.##Mselmi, N., Lahiani, A., &amp; Hamza, T. (2017). Financial distress prediction: The case of French small and medium-sized firms. International Review of Financial Analysis, 50, 67-80.##Sánchez, C. P., de Llano Monelos, P., &amp; López, M. R. (2013). A parsimonious model to forecast financial distress, based on audit evidence. Contaduría y Administración, 58(4), 151-173.##Van Gestel, T., Baesens, B., Suykens, J. A., Van den Poel, D., Baestaens, D. E., &amp; Willekens, M. (2006). Bayesian kernel based classification for financial distress detection. European journal of operational research, 172(3), 979-1003.##Werts, C. E., Linn, R. L., &amp; Jöreskog, K. G. (1974). Intraclass reliability estimates: Testing structural assumptions. Educational and Psychological measurement, 34(1), 25-33. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>پیامدهای اقتصادی زمان‎بندی استراتژیک اعلام سود پیش‎بینی شده مدیریت</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Consequences of Economic Consequences Strategic Scheduling Announcing Management Profits</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>بازار سرمایه، نقش بسزایی در شکوفایی اقتصادی هر کشور دارد؛ از این رو شناخت عوامل مؤثر بر بازار سرمایه، اهمیت بسیار زیادی دارد. برنامه شرکت&#8206;ها برای حداکثر کردن واکنش مثبت بازار اوراق بهادار به عملکرد خوب شرکت&#8206;ها و حداقل کردن واکنش نامناسب به عملکرد منفی، در سال&#8206;های اخیر مورد توجه قرار گرفته است. یکی از استراتژی&#8206;ها برای منحرف کردن توجه بازار از عملکرد ضعیف شرکت&#8206;ها، ارائه گزارش&#8206;های عملکرد، پس از ساعات کار بازار یا در روزهای تعطیلی بازار می&#8206;باشد. فرضیه این است که مدیران فرصت&#8206;طلب به این دلیل، اخبار منفی را در ایام تعطیل منتشر می&#8206;کنند تا در این زمان&#8206;ها، کمتر مورد توجه رسانه&#8206;ها قرار گیرند و تأثیر اخبار بد را از بازار پنهان کنند. در این مقاله، به آزمون مشاهداتی می&#8206;پردازیم که زمان اعلان سودهایشان را از بین روزهای کاری هفته به ایام تعطیل، تغییر داده&#8206;اند. نتایج آزمون فرضیه&#8206;ها، نشان می&#8206;دهد که مدیران شرکت&#8206;های پذیرفته در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران به طور راهبردی اقدام به زمان&#8206;بندی اعلان سودهایشان نمی&#8206;کنند ولی یافته&#8206;های پژوهش، حاکی از وجود رابطه&#8206;ای مثبت و معنادار بین اخبار منفی از پیش&#8206;بینی سود و زمان اعلام آن در ایام تعطیل، همچنین یک رابطه مثبت و معنادار بین اخبار مثبت از پیش&#8206;بینی سود و زمان اعلام آن در ایام کاری بورس بوده است. از این رو، سود انباشته غیرعادی، پیامد اقتصادی دارد؛ بنابراین می&#8206;تواند به عنوان یک معیار، بر تصمیم&#8206;گیری سرمایه&#8206;گذاران تأثیر بگذارد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Corporates provide different dates for presenting information about financial status and future prospects of corporate to stockholders. Stockholders and stock market participants consider the information obtained from the corporate as good news or bad news and they react on this basis. In recent years, corporate programs have been considered by analysts and accounting researchers in order to maximize the positive reaction of the securities market to good performance of corporates and minimize inappropriate reaction to their negative performance. In this research, multivariate regression model was used to test the hypotheses. The statistical population was Tehran Stock Exchange corporates. After Sampling, 120 corporates were selected during the 2014-2017.According to the results, some managers change the timing to hide bad news. The obtained results showed that there is a direct relationship between the negative reports of earning prediction and its announcement time on holidays. This relationship is positive and significant statistically. Morever there is a direct relationship between the positive news reports of earning prediction and its announcement time on usual days (Exchange working days). Therefore, unusual accumulated profits have an economic consequence, and this shows that it can affect investors' decisions as a criterion.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>39</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>50</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>اصغر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>کریمی خرمی</Family>
				<NameE>Asghar</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Karimi Khorami</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Islamic Azad University, Isfahan (Khorasgan) Branch, Isfahan, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد اصفهان (خوراسگان)، اصفهان، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علیرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>زارعی سودانی</Family>
				<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Zarae Sodani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Accounting, Istamic Azad University, Falavarjan Branch, Isfahan, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد فلاورجان، اصفهان، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Zarealireza.cpa@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سعید</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>علی احمدی</Family>
				<NameE>Saeed</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Aliahmadi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Accounting, Islamic Azad University, Isfahan (Khorasgan) Branch, Isfahan, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد اصفهان (خوراسگان)، اصفهان‌، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Market Reaction</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Good and Bad News</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Earnings Announcement Time</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Result Economic</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>واکنش بازار</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اخبار خوب و بد</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>زمان اعلان سود</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پیامدهای اقتصادی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##بادآور نهندی، یونس؛ تقی‌زاده خانقاه، وحید. (1396). تأثیر پرداخت سود سهام و عدم‌انتشار اخبار بد بر خطر سقوط قیمت سهام با تأکید بر عدم‌تقارن اطلاعاتی. مجله بررسی‎های حسابداری و حسابرسی، 24(1)، 40-19.##بزرگ اصل، موسی؛ ادیبی، آزاده. (1395). بررسی رابطه بین محتوای اطلاعاتی اعلامیه‎های سود فصلی و اخبار منفی در طول فصل. نشریه مطالعات تجربی حسابداری مالی، 13(51)، 54-35.##بهبهانی‎نیا، پریسا؛ مشایخی، بیتا. (1395). طراحی مدل تبیینی واکنش به سود در ایران. نشریه دانش حسابرسی، شماره 63، 88-63.##حمیدیان، نرگس؛ عرب صالحی، مهدی؛ امیری، هادی. (1399). بررسی واکنش سرمایه‎گذاران به سود غیرمنتظره در شرایط عدم‌اطمینان بازار. نشریه مدیریت دارای و تأمین مالی، 1(28)، 41-56.##دارابی، رویا؛ چناری، حسن؛ مسعودی، مرجان. (1395). کیفیت افشاء پیامد اقتصادی اطلاعات حسابداری. فصلنامه حسابداری مدیریت، 9(31)، 63-51.##ذوالفقاری، مهدی. (1398). بررسی تأثیر متغیرهای کلان اقتصادی بر ارزش معاملات سهام اوراق بهادار. فصلنامه بورس اوراق بهادار، شماره 166، 51-38.##فروغی، داریوش؛ مهرداد آیسک، سید سعید. (1394). بررسی واکنش بازار به زمان اعلام سود هر سهم پیش‎بینی شده. نشریه پژوهش‎های تجربی حسابداری، 5(17)، 139-162.##قائمی، محمدحسین؛ تقی‎زاده، مصطفی. (1395). بررسی تأثیر ریسک اطلاعاتی و هزینه‌های معاملات بر واکنش بازار سهام به اخبار سود. نشریه بررسی‎های حسابداری و حسابرسی، 23(2)، 252-235.##کاشانی‎پور، محمد؛ رضایی، اسعد. (1390). بررسی تأثیر تغییر میزان سهام شناور آزاد بر بازده سهام شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. فصلنامه پژوهش‎های حسابداری مالی، 3(3)، 112-95.##محمدی، سمیه. (1397). بررسی تأثیر افشای اخبار بد بر محتوای اطلاعاتی سود در شرکت‎های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. پایان‎نامه کارشناسی ارشد. ##مسلمی، بهناز. (1397). بررسی ارتباط بین انتشار اخبار سود و بازده سهام در شرکت‎های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد.##نیکبخت، محمدرضا؛ مرادی، مهدی. (1384). ارزیابی واکنش بیش از اندازه سهامداران عادی در بورس اوراق بهادار. فصلنامه مطالعات حسابداری، شماره 9، 26-2. ##Bagella, M., Becchetti, L., &amp; Ciciretti, R. (2007). Earning forecast error in US and european stock markets. European Journal of Finance, 13(2), 105-122.##Cullinan, C. P., Wang, F., Yang, B., &amp; Zhang, J. (2012). Audit opinion improvement and the timing of disclosure. Advances in Accounting, 28(2), 333-343.## ##DeHaan, E., Shevlin, T., &amp; Thornock, J. (2015). Market (in) attention and the strategic scheduling and timing of earnings announcements. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 60(1), 36-55.##DellaVigna, S., &amp; Pollet, J. (2008). Investor inattention and Friday earnings announcements. Journal of Finance, forthcoming.##DellaVigna, S., &amp; Pollet, J. M. (2005). Strategic release of information on Friday: evidence from earnings announcements. Available at SSRN 586702.##Doyle, J. T., &amp; Magilke, M. J. (2009). The timing of earnings announcements: An examination of the strategic disclosure hypothesis. The Accounting Review, 84(1), 157-182.##Leventis, S., &amp; Weetman, P. (2004). Timeliness of financial reporting: applicability of disclosure theories in an emerging capital market. Accounting and Business Research, 34(1), 43-56.##Livnat, J., &amp; Zhang, L. (2015). Is There News in the Timing of Earnings Announcements?. The Journal of Investing, 24(4), 17-26.##Lonkani, R., &amp; Firth, M. (2005). The accuracy of IPO earnings forecasts in Thailand and their relationships with stock market valuation. Accounting and Business Research, 35(3), 269-286.##Lyle, M. R., Rigsby, C., Stephan, A., &amp; Yohn, T. L. (2017). Volatility and the timing of earnings  announcements, journal finance managemen.##Roychowdhury, S., &amp; Sletten, E. (2012). Voluntary disclosure incentives and earnings informativeness. The Accounting Review, 87(5), 1679-1708.##Truong, C. (2010). Strategic timing of earnings announcements?. Accounting &amp; Finance, 50(3), 719-738.##Vidari, N, &amp; Subroto, B. (2016). Market reaction on the information of relate party transaction disclosure. journal of interdisciplinary research, 2, P7. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تأثیر شوک‌های اقتصاد کلان بر سرمایه‌گذاری در بخش مسکن در ایران با استفاده از روش خودرگرسیونی برداری بیزین</TitleF>
		<TitleE>The Impact of Macroeconomic Shocks on Iran’s Housing Investment by Using BVAR</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>سرمایه&#8206;گذاری در بخش مسکن، یکی از اجزای اصلی سرمایه&#8206;گذاری است که نقش اساسی در تولید و اشتغال ایفا می&#8206;کند. شواهد تجربی نشان می&#8204;دهند که سرمایه&#8204;گذاری در این بخش، واکنش قابل&#8204;توجهی به شوک&#8204;های اقتصاد کلان نشان می&#8204;دهد. در این مقاله با استفاده از روش خودرگرسیونی برداری بیزین، تأثیرات شوک&#8204;های اقتصاد کلان بر سرمایه&#8204;گذاری در بخش مسکن ایران طی بازه زمانی ۱۳۵۷ تا ۱۳۹۶ مطالعه شده است. چهار شوک اقتصاد کلان وارد مدل شده است که عبارتند از: شوک&#8206;های پولی، مالی، درآمد نفتی و نرخ ارز. با توجه به آزمون&#8204;های انجام شده، تابع پیشین سیمز-ژا (نرمال- ویشارت) نسبت به توابع پیشین بررسی شده، مناسب&#8204;تر است. با توجه به نتایج حاصل از توابع واکنش آنی شوک پولی و شوک درآمد نفتی، به ترتیب بیشترین و کمترین اثر ماندگاری را بر سرمایه&#8204;گذاری حقیقی در بخش مسکن ایران داشته&#8204;اند. بیشترین نوسان سرمایه&#8204;گذاری به ترتیب مربوط به شوک&#8206;های مالی، پولی، نرخ ارز و درآمد نفتی بوده است؛ از این رو این تفاوت در اندازه و ماندگاری شوک&#8204;ها باید مورد توجه سیاست&#8204;گذاران قرار گیرد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Residential investment is the main component of investment and has a crucial rule in output and employment. The residential investment is affected by macroeconomic shocks. This paper provides an empirical assessment of the pace at which housing investment has responded to different macroeconomics shocks in Ian in the 1978- 2017 period by using the BVAR method. Four macroeconomic shocks are introduced to the model i.e. exchange rate, monetary, fiscal, and oil income shocks. The Sims-Zha (Normal-Wishart) was recolonized the most appropriate prior function for our data set. The Impulse response functions reveal that one standard deviation positive shocks to exchange rate, interest rate, government expenditure, and oil income initially increased housing investment and then gradually returned to its steady-state value. Oil price and monetary shocks had the shortest and longest duration impact on residential investment.&#160; The highest volatility in residential investment created by the fiscal, monetary, exchange rate, and oil income shocks respectively. The results indicate that the policymaker should consider the difference in the amount and duration of the impacts of four macroeconomic shocks on residential investment in the policymaking.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>51</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>66</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>معصومه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>خوشه‌گل گروسی</Family>
				<NameE>Mahsoomeh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Khooshegol Garusi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Economics, Alzahra University, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده اقتصاد، دانشگاه الزهراء (س)، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>زهرا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>افشاری</Family>
				<NameE>Zahra</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Afshari</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Economics, Faculty of Economics, Alzahra University, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده اقتصاد، دانشگاه الزهراء (س)، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>z.afshari@alzahra.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Residential Investment</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Monetary Shock</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Fiscal Shock</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Oil Price Shock</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>BVAR</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سرمایه‎گذاری مسکن</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شوک‌ پولی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شوک مالی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شوک‌ درآمد نفتی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>خودرگرسیونی برداری بیزین</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##ابوالحسنی، اصغر؛ ابراهیمی، ایلناز؛ پورکاظمی، محمدحسین؛ بهرامی‎نیا، ابراهیم. (1395). اثر تکانه‌های پولی و تکانه‌های نفتی بر تولید و تورم بخش مسکن در اقتصاد ایران: رویکرد تعادل عمومی پویای تصادفی نیوکینزی. فصلنامه پژوهش‌های رشد و توسعه اقتصادی، 7(25)، 132-113.##اکبرنژاد، زکیه؛ عیوضی، حمید. (1395). تحلیل تأثیر شوک‌های قیمتی بازارهای رقیب بازار مسکن بر متغیر قیمت مسکن. فصلنامه اقتصاد مسکن، شماره 57، 101-77.##اکبری، احمد؛ ‎پهلوانی، مصیب؛ زمانیان، غلامرضا؛ حیدری، معصومه. (۱۳۹۱). تأثیر شوک‎های مالی بر اشتغال و سرمایه‌گذاری در بخش مسکن. اولین همایش بین‎المللی اقتصادسنجی، روش‎ها و کاربردها. ##بانک مرکزی جمهوری اسلامی ایران. آمار و داده‎های اقتصادی، بانک اطلاعات سری‎های زمانی اقتصادی. ##بهرامی، ‌جاوید؛ اصلانی، ‌پروانه. (1390). بررسی آثار شوک‎های نفتی بر سرمایه‌گذاری بخش خصوصی در مسکن در یک الگوی تعادل عمومی تصادفی پویا مبتنی بر ادوار تجاری حقیقی. نشریه تحقیقات مدل‎سازی اقتصادی، 4(1)، 57-82.##رحمانی، تیمور؛ اصفهانی، پوریا. (1395). ارزیابی رابطه بین سیکل‌های بخش مسکن، تسهیلات بخش مسکن و مطالبات معوق. فصلنامه اقتصاد مسکن، شماره 57، 31-11.##زروکی، شهریار؛ موتمنی، مانی. (1396). اثر نامتقارن قیمت نفت بر بازار مسکن در ایران: کاربردی از رهیافت ARDL غیرخطی. نشریه پژوهشنامه اقتصاد کلان، 12(23)، 81-105.##سلمان‌پور، علی؛ جهاندیده، فاطمه؛ بهلولی، پریسا. (1390). ارتباط بین سرمایه‎گذاری در بخش مسکن و سیکل‌های تجاری در ایران. فصلنامه مد‌‎ل‎سازی اقتصادی، 5(1)، 125-144.##سلمانی بی‌شک، محمدرضا؛ برقی اسکویی، محمدمهدی؛ لک، سودا. (1394). تأثیر شوک‎های سیاست پولی و مالی بر بازار سهام ایران. نشریه تحقیقات مدلسازی، شماره 22، 131-93.##شاه‌آبادی، ابوالفضل؛ گنجی، مهسا. (1393). تحلیل عوامل مؤثر بر سرمایه‌گذاری در بخش مسکن و ساختمان ایران. دوفصلنامه اقتصاد توسعه و برنامه‌ریزی، 2(1)، 1-21.##شهبازی، کیومرث؛ کلانتری، زهرا. (1391). اثرات شوک‎های سیاست‎های پولی و مالی بر متغیرهای بازار مسکن در ایران: رهیافت SVAR. نشریه پژوهش‎ها و سیاست‎های اقتصادی، 20(61)، 77-104.##عباسی‌نژاد، حسین؛ یاری، محمد. (1387). تأثیر شوک‌های نفتی بر قیمت مسکن در ایران. فصلنامه پژوهش‌های اقتصادی، 9(1)، 77-59.##فیشر، استنلی؛ دورنبوش، رودیگر؛ استارتز، ریچارد. (1388). اقتصاد کلان. ترجمه یدالله دادگر و محمدرضا منجذب. تهران: نشر آسیم.##قلی‌زاده، علی‌اکبر؛ اکبریان، حجت. (1389). سرمایه‌گذاری مسکن و رشد اقتصادی در ایران. فصلنامه اقتصاد مقداری، 7(1)، 133- 105.##قلی‌زاده، علی‎اکبر؛ براتی، جواد. (1389). نقش تجارت خارجی در اثرگذاری اجزای GDP بر سرمایه‎گذاری مسکونی. نشریه پژوهشنامه اقتصاد کلان، 8(15)، 35-60.##قلی‌زاده، علی‌اکبر؛ سجادی، حسن. (1389). تخمین تابع سرمایه‌گذاری مسکن در نقاط شهری ایران با رویکرد توبین - Q. نشریه سیاست‌گذاری اقتصادی، 2(3)، 71-105.##قلی‎زاده، علی‎اکبر؛ براتی، جواد. (1390). تأثیر سیاست‎های پولی و مالی بر سرمایه‎گذاری مسکونی در اقتصاد باز. فصلنامه پژوهش‎ها و سیاست‌های اقتصادی، 19(58)، 31-50.##کاغذیان، سهیلا؛ نقدی، یزدان؛ پاشایی، حسین. (1394). بررسی تأثیر نوسانات نرخ ارز بر سرمایه‌گذاری بخش مسکن در ایران. نشریه راهبرد اقتصادی، 3(12)، 181-196. ##مهرگان، نادر؛ تیموری، یونس. (1395). تحلیل وابستگی فضایی در تغییرات قیمت مسکن؛ مطالعه بین استانی در اقتصاد ایران. فصلنامه علمی اقتصاد مسکن، شماره 57، 33- 60.##Breitenfellner, A., Cuaresma, J. C., &amp; Mayer, P. (2015). Energy inflation and house price corrections. Energy Economics, 48, 109-116.##Calza, A., Monacelli, T., &amp; Stracca, L. (2013). Housing finance and monetary policy. Journal of the European Economic Association, 11(suppl_1), 101-122.##Cerutti, E., Claessens, S., &amp; Laeven, L. (2017). The use and effectiveness of macroprudential policies: New evidence. Journal of Financial Stability, 28, 203-224.##Christou, C., Gupta, R., &amp; Nyakabawo, W. (2019). Time-varying impact of uncertainty shocks on the US housing market. Economics Letters, 180, 15-20.##Dias, D. A., &amp; Duarte, J. B. (2019). Monetary policy, housing rents, and inflation dynamics. Journal of Applied Econometrics, 34(5), 673-687.##Fang, H., Chang, T. Y., Lee, Y. H., &amp; Chen, W. J. (2016). The impact of macroeconomic factors on the Real Estate Investment Trust Index return on Japan, Singapore and China. Investment Management and Financial Innovations, 13(4), 242-253.##Garriga, C., Manuelli, R., &amp; Peralta-Alva, A. (2019). A macroeconomic model of price swings in the housing market. American Economic Review, 109(6), 2036-72.##Gete, P. (2020). Expectations and the Housing Boom and Bust. An Open Economy View. Journal of Housing Economics, 101690.##Killins, R. N., Egly, P. V., &amp; Escobari, D. (2017). The impact of oil shocks on the housing market: Evidence from Canada and US. Journal of Economics and Business, 93, 15-28.##Kok, S. H., Ismail, N. W., &amp; Lee, C. (2018). The sources of house price changes in Malaysia. International Journal of Housing Markets and Analysis.##Koop, G., &amp; Korobilis, D. (2010). Bayesian multivariate time series methods for empirical macroeconomics. Now Publishers Inc. ##Le, T. H. (2015). Do soaring global oil prices heat up the housing market? Evidence from Malaysia. Economics: The Open-Access, Open-Assessment E-Journal, 9(2015-27), 1-30.##Luciani, M. (2015). Monetary policy and the housing market: A structural factor analysis. Journal of applied econometrics, 30(2), 199-218.##Piazzesi, M., &amp; Schneider, M. (2016). Housing and macroeconomics. In Handbook of macroeconomics (Vol. 2, pp. 1547-1640). Elsevier.##Sutton, G. D., Mihaljek, D., &amp; Subelyte, A. (2017). Interest rates and house prices in the United States and around the world.##Tenreyro, S., &amp; Thwaites, G. (2016). Pushing on a string: US monetary policy is less powerful in recessions. American Economic Journal: Macroeconomics, 8(4), 43-74. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تبیین استراتژی‌های اجتماعی- اقتصادی تجدیدحیات شهری در بافت‎های تاریخی (مورد مطالعه: شهر سمنان)</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Explaining Social-Economic Strategies of Urban Regeneration in Historical Contexts (Case Study: Semnan's Historical Context)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>هسته تاریخی، بخشی از تمامیت شهر است که در روند توسعه شهرنشینی متناسب با نیازهای روز رشد نکرده و فرسوده شده&#8206;اند. به منظور حل مشکلات ناشی از پدیده فرسودگی شهری، رهیافت&#8204;های متعددی ارائه شده است که هیچ&#8204;کدام به طور پایدار نتوانستند این پدیده را رفع یا کنترل کنند. در این میان رهیافت تجدید حیات شهری به عنوان راهکاری متفاوت با نگرشی همه&#8204;جانبه و رویکردی منسجم و یکپارچه به منظور بازگرداندن روند رشد اقتصادی گذشته با در نظر گرفتن بعد پایداری، مورد توجه قرار گرفته است. از این رو هدف پژوهش حاضر، تبیین استراتژی&#8204;های اجتماعی- اقتصادی تجدید حیات شهری در بافت&#8206;های تاریخی شهر سمنان می&#8206;باشد. روش تحقیق به صورت توصیفی- تحلیلی می&#8204;باشد و برای جمع&#8206;آوری داده&#8206;ها نیز از روش کتابخانه&#8206;ای و پیمایشی استفاده شده است. نتایج مدل SWOT نشان داد که نمره نهایی نقاط قوت و ضعف، برابر با ۸۱/۲ شده است که این مقداری بزرگ&#8204;تر از میانگین مورد نظر (۵/۲) می&#8204;باشد. نتیجه آنکه بافت تاریخی سمنان از نظر عوامل داخلی دارای قوت می&#8206;باشد؛ لذا می&#8206;توان از توان بالقوه و بالفعل موجود در راستای تعدیل نقاط تهدید و ضعف در راستای تجدید حیات استفاده کرد. همچنین نتایج نشان دادند که مجموع نمره نهایی فرصت&#8206;ها و تهدیدها، برابر با ۹۷/۲ شده است که این میزان مانند نمره نهایی قوت&#8206;ها و ضعف&#8206;ها مقداری بزرگ&#8204;تر از میانگین مورد نظر (۵/۲) است. نتیجه آنکه فرصت&#8204;ها در بافت تاریخی، بیشتر از تهدیدات می&#8204;باشد و بنابراین برای تجدید حیات بافت تاریخی می&#8204;توان از فرصت&#8206;ها یا موقعیت&#8206;ها، بهره&#8206;برداری و از عواملی که موجب تهدید می&#8206;شود دوری کرد. تجزیه و تحلیل عوامل درونی و عوامل بیرونی نشان داد که راهبرد تهاجمی (حداکثر- حداکثر) به عنوان مهم&#8204;ترین راهبرد در سیاست تجدید حیات شهری در بافت تاریخی سمنان، اتخاذ شده است.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The historic core is part of the city's integrity that has not grown and worn out in the process of urban development in line with the needs of the day. In order to solve the problems caused by the phenomenon of urban burnout, several approaches have been proposed, none of which have been able to permanently eliminate or control this phenomenon. Meanwhile, the urban regeneration approach has been considered as a different approach with a comprehensive approach and a coherent and integrated approach to restore the trend of past economic growth, taking into account the sustainability dimension. The aim of this study is to explain the socio-economic strategies of urban regeneration in historical contexts. The research method is descriptive-analytical and library and survey methods have been used to collect data. The results of SWOT model showed that the final score of strengths and weaknesses is equal to 2.81, which is slightly higher than the desired average (2.5). The result is that the historical context of Semnan is strong in terms of internal factors; Therefore, it is possible to use the existing potential and actual power in order to adjust the threat points and weakness in order to revitalize. The results also showed that the total final score of opportunities and threats was 2.97, which is slightly higher than the average score (2.5) as the final score of strengths and weaknesses. As a result, the opportunities in the historical context are greater than the threats, and therefore, in order to revive the historical context, opportunities or situations can be exploited and the factors that cause the threat can be avoided. Analysis of internal and external factors showed that the offensive strategy (maximum-maximum) has been adopted as the most important strategy in urban regeneration policy in the historical context of Semnan.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>67</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>86</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>امیر بهنام</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>والا</Family>
				<NameE>Amirbehnam</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Vala</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>واحد سمنان، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، سمنان، ایران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>واحد سمنان، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، سمنان، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>عباس</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>ارغان</Family>
				<NameE>Abbas</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Arghan</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Geography and Urban Planning, Semnan Branch, Islamic Azad University, Semnan, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>واحد سمنان، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، سمنان، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>abbas.arghan@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>زینب</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>کرکه‌آبادی</Family>
				<NameE>Zeynab</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Korke Abadi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Geography and Urban Planning, Semnan Branch, Islamic Azad University, Semnan, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>واحد سمنان، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، سمنان، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Urban Regeneration</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Worn-out Texture</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Historical Texture</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Strategy</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Semnan City</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تجدید حیات شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بافت فرسوده</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بافت تاریخی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدل SWOT</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شهر سمنان</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##اسکندری، ندا؛ سعیده زرآبادی، زهراسادات. (1395). بازآفرینی شهری و تأثیر آن بر بافت‎های فرسوده شهری. کنفرانس بین‎المللی مهندسی معماری و شهرسازی. ##اسمعیلی، شیوا؛ رضایی، محمدرضا. (1395). تجدید حیات محلات تاریخی در راستای توسعه پایدار شهری با تکیه بر رویکرد TND نمونه موردی: محله سنگ سیاه شیراز. کنفرانس بین‌المللی عمران، معماری، مدیریت شهری و محیط‎زیست در هزاره سوم.##اکبری ارمکی، زکیه. (1391). استفاده از رهیافت تجدید حیات شهری برای رویارویی با فقر در شهرها (منطقه 19 تهران). پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، گروه شهرسازی، دانشکده معماری و شهرسازی، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی.##آقاملایی، ریحانه. (1396). تجدید حیات شهری با رویکرد فرهنگی. نشریه علمی منظر، 9(39)، 59-50. ##بابایی، جواد؛ قاسمی، مهدی؛ هدایت‎پور، مهتا. (1394). رویکردهای تجدید و احیای بافت‎های فرسوده شهری. دومین کنگره علمی- پژوهشی افق‌های نوین در حوزه مهندسی عمران، معماری، فرهنگ و مدیریت شهری ایران. ##بنیادی‎نایینی، علی؛ ایزدی، نشیمن. (1395). رهیافت راهبردی تجدید حیات شهری فرهنگ‌محور. نشریه مطالعات مدیریت راهبردی، شماره 27، 45-19.##جهانیان، منوچهر؛ پژوهان، موسی. (1390). بررسی و طبقه‎بندی انواع بافت‎های فرسوده شهری کلان‎شهر تهران و راهکارهای مداخله در آن. نشریه جغرافیای انسانی، 3(2)، 106-93.##حاتمی‎نژاد، حسین؛ اکبرپور سراسکانرود، محمد؛ یعقوبی،رضا. (1396). به سوی رهیافت تجدید حیات شهری. نشریه شهرداری‌ها، 9(96)، 47-37.##حیدری، یاسر؛ موحد، علی؛ تابعی، حسن. (1396). تجدید حیات بافت‌های فرسوده شهری با تأکید بر رویکرد TND (مطالعه موردی: محله لاله‎زار تهران). نشریه پژوهش‌های نوین علوم جغرافیایی، معماری و شهرسازی، 1(9)، 112-87.##دویران، اسماعیل؛ مشکینی، ابوالفضل؛ کاظمیان، غلامرضا، علی‎آبادی، زینب. (1390). بررسی مداخله در ساماندهی بافت‌های فرسوده و ناکارآمد شهری با رویکرد ترکیبی (نمونه موردی: محله زینبیه زنجان). مجله پژوهش و برنامه‎ریزی شهری، 2(7)، 90-71.##رجایی‎تبار، زهرا. (1395). تجدید حیات بافت کهن با تأکید بر رویکرد نوشهرگرایی؛ نمونه موردی: محله سنگ سیاه شیراز. کنفرانس ملی یافته‌های نوین پژوهشی و آموزشی عمران، معماری شهرسازی و محیط‎زیست ایران.##رمضانی روشن، سیده عذرا. (1395). بررسی تجارب تجدید حیات شهری بافت‎های تاریخی: مطالعه موردی شهرهای آسیایی هانوی، اینتراماروس و کوتاتوآ. چهارمین کنگره بین‌المللی عمران، معماری و توسعه شهری. ##سازمان مسکن و شهرسازی استان سمنان. (1395). طرح نوسازی بهسازی بافت مسکن و فرسوده شهرسازی سمنان.##شاطریان، محسن؛ اکبری ارمکی، زکیه. (1393). رهیافت تجدید حیات شهری در راستای کاهش فرسودگی و فقر شهری (مطالعه موردی بافت قدیم کاشان). فصلنامه جغرافیا، 13(44)، 142-119.##شماعی، علی؛ پوراحمد، احمد. (1385). بهسازی و نوسازی شهری از دیدگاه علم جغرافیا. تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه.##شهاب‎زاده، مرجان. (1395). تجدید حیات در بافت‌های تاریخی از طریق راهبرد اصالت‎بخشی (نمونه موردی بافت تاریخی شیراز). نشریه معماری و اقلیم گرم و خشک، 4(4)، 80-65.##صالحی نجف‎آبادی، مولود؛ فتحی هفشجانی، رحمت‎اله. (1394). سنجش میزان فرسودگی بافت‎های مسکونی در محلات فرسوده مبتنی بر رهیافت بازنوسازی و تجدید حیات شهری (منطقه 9 شهرداری تهران). کنفرانس بین‎المللی عمران، معماری و زیرساخت‎های شهری.##طرح جامع شهر سمنان. (1395). اداره کل مسکن و شهرسازی سمنان.##کهزادی، عمران، طالبی حبیب‎آبادی، بابک. (1398). بازآفرینی در بافت‎های فرسوده شهری با تأکید بر رویکرد تجدید حیات شهری (نمونه موردی: محله علی قلی آقا شهر اصفهان). اولین کنفرانس بین‎المللی مهندسی عمران، معماری و بازآفرینی شهری. ##مشهدی‎زاده دهاقانی، ناصر. (1386). تحلیلی از ویژگی‌های برنامه‌ریزی شهری در ایران. چاپ هفتم، تهران: دانشگاه علم و صنعت.##نادری مغانجوقی، افسانه. (1398). تدوین راهبردهای تجدید حیات شهری در راستای ساماندهی بافت‎های فرسوده (مورد مطالعه: شهرک صادقیه منطقه 18 شهرداری تهران). اولین کنفرانس بین‎المللی و دومین کنفرانس بین‎المللی به سوی شهرسازی، معماری، عمران و هنر دانش‎بنیان. ##ندافیان، راضیه. (1392). تجدید حیات شهری اجتماع‎‎گرا با تأکید ویژه بر برنامه‌ریزی همکارانه نمونه موردی: منطقه ‎۱۵ شهر تهران. پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، گروه طراحی و برنامه‎ریزی مجتمع‎های زیستی گرایش برنامه‎ریزی شهر، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی.##وارثی، حمیدرضا؛ تقوایی، مسعود؛ رضایی، نعمت‎الله. (1391). ساماندهی بافت فرسوده شهری (نمونه موردی: شهر شیراز). مجله برنامه‎ریزی فضایی، 2(2)، 156-129.##یزدانیان امیری، فاطمه. (1392). به‌کارگیری رهیافت تجدید حیات شهری اجتماع‌محور در برنامه‌ریزی دهکده‌های شهری (نمونه موردی: محله ده‌ونک شهر تهران). پایان‎نامه کارشناسی‌ارشد، رشته برنامه‎ریزی شهری، دانشکده معماری و شهرسازی، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی.##Askarizad, R., Safari, H., &amp; Pourimanparast, M. (2017). The Influence of Organizing Historical Textures on Citizenry Satisfaction in the Old Texture Neighbourhoods of Rasht. Emerging Science Journal, 1(3), 118-128.##Beiglu, F. B. N., Ghafari, S. M. H., &amp; Taheri, A. (2019). Infill Architecture as a Solution for Livability and Historical Texture Quality Promotion. Civil Engineering Journal, 5(1), 165-171.##De la Roca, J., Navarrete, J., &amp; Larraín, I. (2017). Urban revitalization: assessment methodologies and expected impacts. Inter-American Development Bank Felipe Herrera Library.##Hassani, M. R., Fard, A. A., &amp; Safashahr, I. (2016). Renewal of insufficient urban textures emphasizing on empowerment approach (case study: hejrat street to pirnia briadge in shiraz city, region 3). turkish online journal of design art and communication, 6, 1956-1974.##Jaroszewska, E. (2019). Urban Shrinkage and Regeneration of an Old Industrial City: the Case of Wałbrzych in Poland. Quaestiones Geographicae, 38(2), 75-90.##Jin, X., Chin, T., Yu, J., Zhang, Y., &amp; Shi, Y. (2020). How Government’s Policy Implementation Methods Influence Urban Villagers’ Acceptance of Urban Revitalization Programs: Evidence from China. Land, 9(3), 77.##Khayami, F., &amp; Fakhri, S. (2019). Urban Form Resilience in Physical-Social Regeneration Approach. International Journal of Urban Management and Energy Sustainability, 2(1), 39-45.##Mohammadpoor, S., &amp; Zolpirani, M. N. (2019). Improvement of Urban Space Quality in Worn Textures with Urban Regeneration Approach (Case study: Khahar-emam neighborhood, Rasht, Iran).##Muminović, E., Radosavljević, U., &amp; Beganović, D. (2020). Strategic Planning and Management Model for the Regeneration of Historic Urban Landscapes: The Case  ##of Historic Center of Novi Pazar in Serbia. Sustainability, 12(4), 1323.##Penića, M., Svetlana, G., &amp; Murgul, V. (2015). Revitalization of historic buildings as an approach to##preserve cultural and historical heritage. Procedia engineering, 117, 883-890.##Rozati, S. H., Kazemzadeh, M., &amp; Vaseghi, A. (2015). Sustainable Urban Development with Emphasis on Worn Out Texture Regeneration (Case Study: Isfahan, Iran). Current Urban Studies, 3(03), 241.##Samiei, A., &amp; Sayafzadeh, A. (2016). Analysis of the worn-out tissues characteristics and providing of intervention pattern, case study: Eslamshahr city, Tehran. Current Urban Studies, 4(03), 267.##Sutton, S. A. (2008). Urban revitalization in the United States: Policies and practices. United States Urban Revitalization Research Project (USURRP).##Wilczkiewicz, M., &amp; Wilkosz-Mamcarczyk, M. (2015). Revitalization–definition, genesis, examples. Geomatics, Landmanagement and Landscape.##Zhang, J. (2019). New functionalism: rejuvenating historical and cultural heritage through urban revival. International Journal of Anthropology and Ethnology, 3(1), 8. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>شناسایی و رتبه‌بندی شاخص‌های مؤثر بر عملکرد تیمی در بنگاه‌های اقتصادی آموزشی (مورد مطالعه: دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران، دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد)</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Identification and Ranking of Effective Indicators on Team Performance in Educational Enterprises (Case Study: Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch of Tehran, Faculty of Management and Economics)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>در سال&#8204;های اخیر، اهمیت تیم&#8204;های کاری در حوزه عملکرد سازمانی بسیار مورد توجه قرار گرفته است. در همین راستا نیاز به شناسایی و رتبه&#8204;بندی شاخص&#8204;های تأثیرگذار بر عملکرد تیمی در سازمان&#8204;ها دیده می&#8204;شود. دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی به عنوان یکی از بنگاه اقتصادی آموزشی نیز از این قاعده مستثنی نمی&#8204;باشد. این پژوهش با هدف شناسایی و رتبه&#8204;بندی شاخص&#8204;ها و معیارهای تأثیرگذار بر عملکرد تیمی در دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران انجام شده است. به این منظور با استفاده از مطالعات میدانی، شاخص&#8204;های تأثیرگذار بر عملکرد تیمی، شناسایی و در اختیار ۲۰ نفر از خبرگان قرار داده شد تا براساس قلمروی مکانی تحقیق امتیازدهی صورت گیرد. در گام بعد براساس نتایج استخراج شده، شش شاخص و زیرمعیارهای هر شاخص مشخص گردید. در ادامه تحقیق، رتبه&#8204;بندی شاخص&#8204;ها و معیارها براساس روش دیمتل و تحلیل سلسله&#8204;مراتبی فازی انجام شد. نتایج تحقیق نشان دادند شاخص ترکیب تیم از نظر خبرگان بیشترین تأثیر را بر روی عملکرد تیمی در دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد دارد. همچنین معیار رویکرد فعالانه نیز بیشترین تأثیر را بر روی عملکرد تیمی خواهد گذاشت.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>In recent years, the importance of work teams in the field of organizational performance has been very much considered. In this regard, the identification and ranking of indicators affecting team performance in organizations should be considered. Azad University, as one of the educational enterprises, is not a part of this. The purpose of this research was to identify and rank the indexes and criteria affecting team performance at the Faculty of Management and Economics of Tehran Science and Research Branch. Qualitative research method. To this end, using field studies, identifiers that have an impact on team performance have been identified and made available to 20 experts in order to score points based on the realm of research. In the next step, based on the results obtained, 6 indicators and sub-criteria of each indicator are determined. In the further research, the indexes and criteria are ranked according to the method of Dimetal and Fuzzy Hierarchical Analysis (AHP). Paired comparisons are based on expert opinion. According to the results of the research, it appears that the team composition index in terms of experts has the greatest impact on teamwork at the faculty of management. Also, the active approach criterion will have the greatest impact on team performance.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>87</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>104</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>فاطمه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>اسکندر</Family>
				<NameE>Fatemeh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Eskandar</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Management and Economics, Science and Research Branch, Islamic Azad University, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، واحد علوم و تحقیقات، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>رضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رادفر</Family>
				<NameE>Reza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Radfar</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Industrial Management, Faculty of Management and Economics, Science and Research Branch, Islamic Azad University, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، واحد علوم و تحقیقات، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>radfar@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>Abbas</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>Tolouee Ashleghi</Family>
				<NameE>Abbas</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Tolouee Ashleghi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Industrial Management, University of Science and Research, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، واحد علوم و تحقیقات، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Performance Indicator - Enterprise - Working Group - Fuzzy Dimetal Method - Fuzzy Hierarchy Process Analysis</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شاخص</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عملکرد</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بنگاه اقتصادی آموزشی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تیم کاری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>روش دیمتل فازی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>رویکرد تحلیل سلسله‌مراتبی فازی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##احمدی، امید؛ کمالیان، امین رضا؛ یعقوبی، نورمحمد؛ قاسمی، محمد. (1397). ارائه الگوی جامع تعیین و استقرار بهسازی عملکرد کارکنان با رویکرد فراترکیب. فصلنامه پژوهش‎های مدیریت منابع انسانی دانشگاه جامع امام حسین (ع)، 10(4(پیاپی 34))، 103-79.##اسماعیل‌پور، رضا؛ آذر، عادل؛ شاه‎محمدی، محمد. (1396). ارائه مدل ساختاری تفسیری از شاخص‌های انتخاب تأمین‌کننده مبتنی بر مسئولیت اجتماعی شرکت. فصلنامه مطالعات مدیریت صنعتی، 15(47)، 70-45.##تولایی، روح‎الله. (1386). رویکردهای نوین به ارزیابی عملکرد سازمان‎ها. دو ماهنامه توسعه انسانی پلیس، 4(12)، 30-9. ##خلیلی، کرم؛ سلطانی، ایرج؛ نفر، مهدی. (1394). شناسایی مؤلفه‌ها و شاخص‌های عملکرد تیمی در سازمان‌های دولتی ایران. نشریه مدیریت دولتی، 7(1)، 70-55.##خیراندیش، مهدی؛ خدایی، ارشیا؛ محمدی، علیرضا. (1394). مدل جامع عوامل مؤثر بر کارتیمی اثربخش در بستر سازمان و مقیاس‌های سنجش آن. فصلنامه مطالعات رفتار سازمانی، 4(3(پیاپی 14))، 31-60.##دانیالی ده حوض، محمود؛ منصوری، حسین. (1398). بررسی اثر تعدیل‎کنندگی بهره‎وری نیروی انسانی در رابطه بین اعتماد سازمانی و رفتار شهروندی سازمانی. فصلنامه تحقیقات مدیریت آموزشی،10(39)، 40-17.##رجب‎زاده، علی؛ علیزاده ثانی، محسن. (1388). مدل سیستمی اثربخشی کار تیمی در سیستم بانکی (مورد مطالعه بانک کشاورزی). دوفصلنامه راهبردهای بازرگانی، 7(38)، 104-91.##زارع، سیدمحسن؛ شائمی برزکی، علی؛ انصاری، محمد اسماعیل؛ ابزری، مهدی. (1397). بررسی ابعاد اقتضایی نظام ارزیابی عملکرد کارکنان کلیدی با رویکرد معماری منابع انسانی. فصلنامه پژوهش‎های مدیریت منابع انسانی، 10(4)، 50-25.##طهرانی، مریم؛ هادیزاده مقدم، اکرم؛ طبرسا، غلامعلی؛ حمیدی‎زاده، محمدرضا. (1393). تبیین عوامل سازمانی مؤثر بر عملکرد تیم‎های کاری. نشریه چشم‎انداز مدیریت دولتی، شماره 18، 71-47.##علیزاده، حمید؛ ثابت، عظیم. (1398). ارزیابی تأثیر کارکردهای مدیریت منابع انسانی بر عملکرد کارکنان از طریق نقش میانجی چابکی سازمانی (مورد مطالعه: شرکت‌های تأمین سرمایه شهر تهران). فصلنامه رویکردهای پژوهشی نوین در مدیریت و حسابداری، 3(14)، 31-17.##فرهی، رضا؛ محمودی، امیررضا؛ زارعی، امیرحسن؛ افخمی اردکانی، مهدی. (1389). طراحی معیارهای اثربخشی کار گروهی. فصلنامه مدیریت و منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، 4(10)، 70-39.##قلاوندی، حسن؛ کبیری، افشار؛ سلطان‎زاده. وحید. (1393). رابطه مسئولیت‎پذیری اجتماعی و کار تیمی کارکنان دانشگاه ارومیه. نشریه جامعه‎شناسی کاربردی، 25(1(پیاپی 53))، 120-111.##کاپلان، رابرت؛ نورتون، دیوید. (1391). سازمان استراتژی‎محور. پرویز بختیاری، چاپ سیزدهم، تهران: انتشارات سازمان مدیریت صنعتی.##محمدی، نبی‎اله؛ نجف‌بیگی، رضا؛ موسی‎خانی، مرتضی؛ عالم‎تبریز، اکبر. (1396). آسیب‌شناسی انتخاب و پایداری اعضای هیئت علمی در دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی با رویکرد راهبردی. نشریه پژوهش‎های مدیریت راهبردی، 23(64)، 54-31.##میرباقری، سیدمحسن؛ رفیعی آتانی، عطاالله؛ دشتی، رضا. (1398). معرفی الگویی برای مدیریت عملکرد کارکنان در مراکز تحقیقاتی نظامی. فصلنامه علمی راهبرد دفاعی، 17(66)، 130-97.##نادی، مجتبی؛ آهنچیان، محمدرضا؛ نوغانی دخت بهمنی، محسن. (1396). مطالعه کیفی وضعیت تیم‎سازی و کار تیمی در دانشگاه‌های دولتی ایران. فصلنامه مطالعات رفتار سازمانی، 6(1)، 120-81.##Adams, A., Bond, S., &amp; Arber, S. (1995). Development and validation of scales to measure organisational features of acute hospital wards. International Journal of Nursing Studies, 32(6), 612-627.##Aldrin, N., &amp; Utama, A. P. (2019). Analysis of the Effect of Coaching on Teamwork Performance. International Journal of Research in Business and Social Science (2147-4478), 8(3), 24-32.##Antoni, C., &amp; Hertel, G. (2009). Team processes, their antecedents and consequences: Implications for different types of teamwork. European Journal of Work and Organizational Psychology, 18(3), 253-266.##Aybas, M., &amp; Uyargil, C. B. (2017). An Integrated Model Recommendation about Team Performance Measurement and Evaluation. International Journal of Business and Management, 12(2).##Bateman, B., Wilson, F. C., &amp; Bingham, D. (2002). Team effectiveness–development of an audit questionnaire. Journal of Management Development.##De Wet, C., Spence, W., Mash, R., Johnson, P., &amp; Bowie, P. (2010). The development and psychometric evaluation of a safety climate measure for primary care. Qual Saf Health Care, 19(6), 578-584.##Gautam, M. H. P. (2018). Team Effectiveness and Perceived Employees’ Performance in Nepalese Service Sector. International Journal of Research in Business Studies and Management, 5(2).##Gil, F., Alcover, C. M., &amp; Peiró, J. M. (2005). Work team effectiveness in organizational contexts. Journal of Managerial Psychology.##Gittell, J. H., Seidner, R., &amp; Wimbush, J. (2010). A relational model of how high-performance work systems work. Organization science, 21(2), 490-506.##Hart, O. (2011). Thinking about the firm: A review of Daniel Spulber's The Theory of the Firm. Journal of Economic Literature, 49(1), 101-13.##Hwang, M. I. (2019). Relationship between teamwork and team performance: Experiences from an ERPsim competition. Journal of Information Systems Education, 29(3), 4.##Kantarelis, D. (2007). Theories of the Firm. Geneve: Inderscience. Description &amp; review.##Kioko, F. (2018). An Evaluation of the Role of Teamwork on Employee Performance at Machakos County Government, Kenya. International Academic Journal of Social Sciences, 5(1), 55-61.##Kriksciuniene, D., &amp; Strigunaite, S. (2011). Virtual Team Tasks Performance Evaluation Based on Multi-level Fuzzy Comprehensive Method. In The Third International Conference on Future Computational Technologies and Applications (in press, 2011).##Mâsse, L. C., Moser, R. P., Stokols, D., Taylor, B. K., Marcus, S. E., Morgan, G. D., ... &amp; Trochim, W. M. (2008). Measuring collaboration and transdisciplinary integration in team science. American journal of preventive medicine, 35(2), S151-S160. ##McGreevy, M. (2006). Team working: part 2–how are teams chosen and developed?. Industrial and commercial training.##Nawaz, N., &amp; Gomes, A. M. (2020). The Relationship between organizational citizenship behavior and team performance: The mediating effect of team conflict. Available at SSRN 3520345.##Paris, C. R., Salas, E., &amp; Cannon-Bowers, J. A. (2000). Teamwork in multi-person systems: a review and analysis. Ergonomics, 43(8), 1052-1075.##Poženel, M. (2013). Assessing teamwork in a software engineering capstone course. World Trans. on Engng. and Technol. Educ, 11(1), 6-12.##Rojas-Villafane, J. A. (2010). An agent-based model of team coordination and performance.##Senior, B., &amp; Swailes, S. (2004). The dimensions of management team performance: a repertory grid study. International Journal of Productivity and Performance Management, 53(4), 317-333.##Spulber, D. F. (2019). The economics of markets and platforms. Journal of Economics &amp; Management Strategy, 28(1), 159-172.##Štorga, M., Škec, S., Martinec, T., &amp; Perišić, M. M. (2016). Monitoring, measurement and simulation of individual and teamwork performance in collaborative product development and design. In Proceedings of the Human Life Design (HLD) International Symposium JAIST 2016.##Sudhakar, G. (2013). Different dimensions of teams. Ecoforum Journal, 2(2), 29-35.##Sycara, K., &amp; Lewis, M. (2008). Agent-based approaches to dynamic team simulation (No. NPRST-TN-08-9). CARNEGIE-MELLON UNIV PITTSBURGH PA.##Vinokur-Kaplan, D. (1995). Treatment teams that work (and those that don't): An application of Hackman's group effectiveness model to interdisciplinary teams in psychiatric hospitals. The Journal of applied behavioral science, 31(3), 303-327. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>شناسایی و رتبه‌بندی چالش‌های مدیریت نوسازی شهری (مورد مطالعه: منطقه 10 شهرداری تهران)</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Identifying and Rating Challenges of Urban Regeneration Management (Case Study: District Ten of Municipality of Tehran)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>مناطق ناکارآمد شهری، با طیف گسترده&#8204;ای از مسائل اقتصادی، اجتماعی و کالبدی درگیر هستند و نوسازی شهری، پاسخ مناسبی به وضعیت نامطلوب آنهاست. منطقه ده شهرداری تهران در محدوده مرکزی تهران واقع شده و ۵۵ درصد مساحت آن، بافت فرسوده است. با توجه به تنوع وظایف مدیریت شهری، بازیگران متعددی در فرایند نوسازی شهری، نقش دارند. پژوهش حاضر از نظر هدف، کاربردی، از نظر ماهیت، تحلیلی و از نظر روش جمع&#8204;آوری داده&#8204;ها، پیمایشی است. این پژوهش، در پی پاسخگویی به این سؤال است که مهم&#8204;ترین چالش&#8206;های مدیریت نوسازی شهری در منطقه ده شهرداری تهران کدامند. برای پاسخ به این سؤال، پس از مطالعه متون نظری و تجربی مرتبط با موضوع و شناخت نمونه مطالعاتی پژوهش، چالش&#8206;های مدیریت نوسازی بافت&#8204;های ناکارآمد منطقه، با مصاحبه و استفاده از روش تحلیل محتوا، شناسایی شدند. سپس با کمک روش کدگذاری باز، چالش&#8206;های شناسایی شده بر اساس دو حوزه قلمروهای فضایی و عملکردهای شهری، دسته&#8204;بندی شدند. ترسیم شبکه روابط میان چالش&#8206;های شناسایی شده، نشان داد که روابط قابل&#8204;توجهی میان آنها وجود دارد. در گام بعدی، با کمک تحلیل PESTEL و فرایند تحلیل شبکه&#8204;ای (ANP) مشخص شد که تضاد منافع میان سازمان نوسازی شهرداری تهران و شهرداری منطقه و همچنین برخوردار نبودن سازمان نوسازی شهرداری تهران از منابع مالی لازم، مهم&#8204;ترین چالش&#8206;های موجود در مدیریت نوسازی شهری در منطقه ده شهرداری تهران هستند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Distressed urban areas suffer from a wide range of economic, social and physical issues and urban regeneration can be a proper response to these unfavorable conditions. District ten of municipality of Tehran (DTMT) located in central area of Tehran and 55 percent of its area is covered with decayed texture. As a result of diversity of tasks of urban management, there are numerous stakeholders involved in the urban regeneration process. This paper is practical in term of the goal, analytical in term of nature and survey in term of data collection. This paper seeks to answer what are the main challenges in the way of urban regeneration management in the DTMT? To answer this questions; First, theoretical and experimental literature on urban regeneration management was studied and features of DTMT as our case study were assessed. Second, the challenges of urban regeneration management in distressed textures of this district were identified through interviewing and content analysis method. Then, by open coding method, the identified challenges were classified according to two domains: spatial territory and urban functions. Drawing up a network of relationships between identified challenges proved that there are dominant relationships between them. In the next step, by PESTEL analysis and Analytical Network Process (ANP), it was determined that the conflict of interests between Renovation Organization of Municipality of Tehran (ROMT) and municipality of Tehran district ten and also the lack of adequate funding in ROMT are the main challenges in the way of urban regeneration management in the DTMT.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>105</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>128</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>اسفندیار</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>زبردست</Family>
				<NameE>Esfandiar</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Zebardast</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Urban Planning, Faculty of Urban Planning, College of Fine Arts, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده شهرسازی، پردیس هنرهای زیبا، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Zebardst@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>میرزایی</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad Reza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Mirzaei</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Urban Planning, College of Fine Arts, Tehran University, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده شهرسازی، پردیس هنرهای زیبا، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Challenges of Urban Management System</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Urban Regeneration</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Decayed Textures</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>District Ten of Municipality of Tehran (DTMT)</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Analytic Network Process (ANP).</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>چالش‎های نظام مدیریت شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نوسازی شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بافت‎های فرسوده</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>منطقه ده شهرداری تهران</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>فرایند تحلیل شبکه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##آقاصفری، عارف؛ حاتمی‎نژاد، حسین؛ پوراحمد، احمد؛ رهنمایی، محمدتقی؛ منصوری، سیدامیر؛ کلانتری خلیل‎آباد، حسین. (1389). بررسی نوسازی و بهسازی بافت فرسوده محله شهید خوب‎بخت (تهران). فصلنامه مطالعات شهر ایرانی- اسلامی، 1(1)، 71-59.##امینیان، مهدی؛ امینیان، محسن. (1393). توسعه پایدار فضای سبز شهری با رویکرد مدیریت یکپارچه شهری. ششمین کنفرانس ملی برنامه ریزی و مدیریت شهری با تأکید مؤلفه‎های شهرهای اسلامی.##برک‎پور، ناصر؛ اسدی، ایرج. (1395). مدیریت و حکمروایی شهری. چاپ سوم، تهران: دانشگاه هنر.##جعفری، طوفان. (1394). الگوی مدیریت پروژه‌های نوسازی شهری (نمونه موردی: شهر تهران). نشریه باغ نظر، 12(37)، 60- 53.##رضایی، نعیمه؛ فرجی، فرناز. (1397). ارزیابی نقش سازمان‎های غیردولتی در حفاظت از میراث معماری و شهری؛ مطالعه تطبیقی ایران و فرانسه. نشریه هویت شهر، 12(33)، 36-27. ##روستا، مجید؛ حسین‌آبادی، مصطفی. (1392). تبیین نقش و جایگاه نهادهای دولتی، عمومی، خصوصی و مردم‌نهاد در نوسازی بافت‎های فرسوده شهری با تأکید بر شهر تهران. نشریه اینترنتی نوسازی، 5(22)، 1-14. ##زبردست، اسفندیار. (1389). کاربرد فرایند تحلیل شبکه‌ای (ANP) در برنامه‌ریزی شهری و منطقه‎ای. نشریه هنرهای زیبا (معماری و شهرسازی)، 2(41)، 90-79.##زبردست، اسفندیار؛ خلیلی، احمد؛ دهقانی، مصطفی. (1392). کاربرد روش تحلیل عاملی در شناسایی بافت‌های فرسوده شهری. نشریه هنرهای زیبا (معماری و شهرسازی)، 18(2)، 42-27.##عندلیب، علیرضا؛ روشن‌علی، فاطمه. (1397). مسئله‌یابی بافت‌های ناکارآمد شهری؛ مهم‌ترین مرحله مشارکت‌دهی ساکنان در موفقیت برنامه‌های نوسازی (نمونه مطالعاتی: محله شهید خوب‌بخت تهران). فصلنامه مدیریت شهری، شماره 52، 108- 93.##گلرخ، شمین. (1391). بازاندیشی در تعریف مفهوم فرسودگی بافت بر مبنای فرسودگی مکان. نشریه صفه، شماره 57، 93-79.##موسوی، حمید؛ بخشنده نصرت، عباس؛ الیاس‌زاده، نورالدین. (1397). تحلیل رویکرد مشارکت‌جویانه در ساماندهی بافت‌های فرسوده منطقه 12 شهر تهران. فصلنامه مدیریت شهری، شماره 51، 308- 297.##مهندسین مشاور طرح و معماری. (1384). الگوی توسعه و طرح تفصیلی منطقه ده شهرداری تهران.##نادری خورشیدی، علیرضا؛ درویش‌زاده، فریدون؛ حاجی علی‌اکبری، کاوه. (1392). طراحی نظام برون‌سپاری نوسازی بافت‎های فرسوده شهر تهران. فصلنامه اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری، 2(7)، 116- 101.##نوروزی، وحید. (1394). بررسی مسائل و مشکلات بافت‎های فرسوده (مطالعه موردی: منطقه ده شهر تهران). کنفرانس بین‎المللی انسان، معماری، عمران و شهر.##نوریان، فرشاد؛ نتاج، آزاده. (1395). بررسی معیارهای ظرفیت‌سنجی توسعه مجدد در محدوده بافت قدیم بابل. نشریه هنرهای زیبا (معماری و شهرسازی)، 21(3)، 38-27.##وان دیک، ماین پیتر. (1394). مدیریت شهری از نظریه تا عمل: اداره شهرها در کشورهای در حال توسعه. ترجمه حامد رستگار و غلامرضا کاظمیان، تهران: تیسا.##وب‌سایت سازمان شهرداری تهران.##وب‌سایت سازمان شهرداری منطقه ده تهران.##وب‌سایت سازمان نوسازی شهرداری تهران.##Alpopi, C., &amp; Manole, C. (2014). Integrated urban regeneration-sustainable management alternative. Calitatea, 15(S1), 138.##Boisseuil, C. (2015, July). Comparing integrated urban regeneration in France and the United Stated: is there a European model versus an American one? In International Conference on Public Policy, Panel Urban regeneration policies in Europe: Theory and practice.##Egolum, C. C., &amp; Emoh, F. I. (2017). The issues and challenges of urban renewal in a developing economy. International  ##journal of development and economic sustainability, 5(1), 32-44.##Galdini, R. (2005). Urban Regeneration Process-The Case of Genoa, an Example of Integrated Urban Development Approach.##Jones, P., &amp; Evans, J. (2013). Urban regeneration in the UK: Boom, bust and recovery. Sage.##Kampelmann, S., Van Hollebeke, S., &amp; Vandergert, P. (2016). Stuck in the middle with you: the role of bridging organisations in urban regeneration. Ecological economics, 129, 82-93.##Marra, G., Barosio, M., Eynard, E., Marietta, C., Tabasso, M., &amp; Melis, G. (2016). From urban renewal to urban regeneration: Classification criteria for urban interventions. Turin 1995–2015: Evolution of planning tools and approaches. Journal of Urban Regeneration &amp; Renewal, 9(4), 367-380.##McCartney, G., Hearty, W., Taulbut, M., Mitchell, R., Dryden, R., &amp; Collins, C. (2017). Regeneration and health: a structured, rapid literature review. Public health, 148, 69-87.##Musa, J., &amp; Dung-Gwom, J. Y. (2018). Assessment of urban regeneration activities in the central area of Jos town, Nigeria. UPLanD-Journal of Urban Planning, Landscape &amp; environmental Design, 3(1), 75-88.##Natividade-Jesus, E., Almeida, A., Sousa, N., &amp; Coutinho-Rodrigues, J. (2019). A Case Study Driven Integrated Methodology to Support Sustainable Urban Regeneration Planning and Management. Sustainability, 11(15), 4129.##Naya, R. B., de la Cal Nicolás, P., Medina, C. D., Pérez, S. G., &amp; Fraga, F. J. M. (2018). From the theory to practice: Five years of urban regeneration workshops. JOTSE, 8(3), 179-191.##Nello, O. (2010). The challenges of urban renewal. Ten lessons from the Catalan experience. Análise Social, 685-715.##Qiu, Y. (2019). Stakeholders and Partnership in Urban Regeneration: The Case of Shanghai West Bund (Doctoral dissertation, Columbia University).##Rădulescu, C. M., Ştefan, O., Rădulescu, G. M., Rădulescu, A. T., &amp; Rădulescu, M. V. (2016). Management of stakeholders in urban regeneration projects. Case study: Baia-Mare, Transylvania. Sustainability, 8(3), 238.##Rezaei, N. (2017). The policies for intervention in the urban fabrics in Iran: a century of evolution. International Journal of Human Settlements, 1(2), 24-37.##Roberts, P., Sykes, H., &amp; Granger, R. (Eds.). (2016). Urban regeneration. Sage.##Tanrıkul, A., &amp; Hoşkara, Ş. (2019). A New Framework for the Regeneration Process of Mediterranean Historic City Centres. Sustainability, 11(16), 4483.##Zheng, H. W., Shen, G. Q., &amp; Wang, H. (2014). A review of recent studies on sustainable urban renewal. Habitat International, 41, 272-279. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>طراحی مدل کسب‎وکار شهری</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Designing an Urban Business Model</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>مدل کسب&#8207;وکار، نحوه تولید ارزش، جذب مشتری، ساختار درآمدزایی و هزینه را تشریح می&#8206;کند و همه کسب&#8207;وکارها از طریق این ساختار، از هم جدا شده و هویت می&#8206;یابند. امروزه طراحی مدل کسب&#8207;وکار را در چهار سطح قابل اجرا دانسته&#8207;اند: سطح محصول یا خدمات، سطح واحد تجاری، سطح شرکت و سطح صنعت. نظر به اینکه شهرها مراکز اصلی فعالیت&#8206;های اقتصادی هستند، تدوین مدل کسب&#8207;وکار برای شهر نیز حائز اهمیت است. هدف این مطالعه، افزودن یک لایه جدید به نام لایه شهری به ادبیات موضوع مدل کسب&#8207;وکار است. این تحقیق از نوع اکتشافی (کیفی) می&#8204;باشد و داده&#8207;های کیفی از روش پژوهش فراترکیب و با روش جمع&#8207;آوری داده&#8207;ها و اطلاعات اسنادی و نیز مصاحبه عمیق کارشناسی، گردآوری شدند. ماهیت پژوهش استقرایی است و در آن اطلاعات به دست آمده با روش مرور نظام&#8207;مند، تحلیل محتوا و تحلیل منطقی و از طریق نرم&#8207;افزارMAXQDA &#160;مورد تجزیه&#8207;وتحلیل قرار گرفتند. نتایج نشان می&#8206;دهند فضای پیچیده مدیریت شهری، ضرورت سیاست&#8207;گذاری اقتصادی و تسهیل امور کسب&#8207;وکارهای شهر، لزوم تدوین مدل کسب&#8207;وکار برای شهرها را ضروری کرده است. در این تحقیق پس از بررسی و تحلیل&#8206;های به عمل آمده، ابعاد مدل استخراج و روابط بین آنها تبیین گردید و در نهایت مدل کسب&#8206;وکار شهری طراحی شد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Business model, how to production value, absorb customer, explain the structure of make money and cost, and all business on the way of this structure will be disparate and find identity. Now a day&#8217;s ،designing of the business model have known applicable in the four level: the product or services level, business unit level, company level and industry level. Whereas cities is the main center of economic activities, developing a business model is important. Add a new layer with name of the &#34;urban layer&#34; to the literature on the business model is the goal of this study. This research is of exploratory (qualitative) type and qualitative data were collected from the research method and with the method of data collection and documentary information as well as in-depth expert interviews. The nature of the research is inductive and the information obtained was analyzed by systematic review method, content analysis and logical analysis through MAXQDA software. The results show that the complex space of urban management, the need for economic policy and the facilitation of business affairs in the city, have necessitated the development of a business model for cities. In this study, after review and analysis, the dimensions of the extraction model and the relationships between them were explained, and finally the urban business model was designed.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>129</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>153</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهدی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>طلایی</Family>
				<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Talaei</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Social Sciences, Razi University, Kermanshah, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه رازی، کرمانشاه، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سهراب</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>دل‎انگیزان</Family>
				<NameE>Sohrab</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Delangizan</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Economics, Faculty of Social Sciences, Razi University, Kermanshah, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه رازی، کرمانشاه، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>delangizan@razi.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>نادر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>نادری</Family>
				<NameE>Nader</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Naderi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Management &#38; Entrepreneurship, Faculty of Social Sciences, Razi University, Kermanshah, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه رازی، کرمانشاه، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Urban Business</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Business Model</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Urban Management</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Urban Economy</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Model Design</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Qualitative Approach</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>کسب‎وکار شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدل کسب‎وکار</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدیریت شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اقتصاد شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>طراحی مدل</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>رویکرد کیفی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##اسکات، آلن جان. (1384). شهر- منطقه‌های جهانی. ترجمه پانته‌آ لطفی، تهران: انتشارات پردازش و برنامه‌ریزی شهری.##بستام، هادی؛ مشبکی، اصغر؛ کردنائیج، اسداله؛ آذر، عادل. (1394). طراحی مدل کسب‎وکار انطباقی (موردمطالعه: صنایع غذایی). دوفصلنامه کاوش‎های مدیریت بازرگانی، 7(14)، 149-179.##رضوانی، مهران؛ اصلاحی، محمد. (1395). ارائه مدل کسب‌وکار الکترونیکی صنعت بانکداری کشور با استفاده از روش‎شناسی پژوهش آمیخته. مجله پژوهش‎های مدیریت منابع سازمانی، 6(4)، 19-41. ##ریاضی، سید ابوالحسن. (1392). شهر، پدیده‎ای میان رشته‎ای. فصلنامه مطالعات میان رشته‎ای در علوم انسانی، 6(1)، 101-115.##زعفریان، رضا؛ نیرومند، پوراندخت؛ رنجبر، محبوبه. (1390). الگوهای طراحی مدل کسب‌وکار. ماهنامه اجتماعی، اقتصادی، علمی و فرهنگی کار و جامعه. شماره 135، 10-5.##گودرزی، مریم؛ قاضی نوری، سید سروش؛ رادفر، رضا؛ کبریایی‎زاده، عباس. (1398). واکاوی اجزای مدل کسب‎وکار در شرکت‎های زیست دارویی. مجله پیاورد سلامت، 13(5)، 335-344.##مختاری هشی، حسین؛ ناصرالاسلامی، گلناز؛ مرادی، امین. (1395). نقش بهبود فضای کسب‌وکار در کشور در ساماندهی شهر تهران، فصلنامه تحقیقات جغرافیایی، 31(4(پیاپی 123))، 74-87.##مرادی، محمدعلی. (1397). طراحی الگوی بهبود محیط کسب‌وکار شهر تهران. فصلنامه اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری، 7(2(پیاپی 26))، 114-93.##منطقی، منوچهر؛ ثاقبی سعیدی، فاطمه. (1392). مدل‌های کسب‌وکار؛ مبانی، ارزیابی، نوآوری. فصلنامه تخصصی پارک‎ها و مراکز رشد، 9(35).##نظریان، اصغر؛ رحیمی، محمد. (1392). ضرورت بازبینی مدل مدیریت شهر تهران و انتخاب مدل برتر. مجله مدیریت شهری، شماره 31، 138-125.##هاروی، دیوید؛ مری فیلد، اندی. (1391). حق به شهر ریشه‎های بحران‎های مالی. ترجمه خسرو کلانتری. تهران: مهرویستا.##هال، پیتر؛ پین، کتی. (1391). شهرهای جدید چندهسته‎ای. کرامت‌الله زیاری، تهران: دانشگاه تهران. ##Abhishek, V., Guajardo, J., &amp; Zhang, Z. (2020). Business models in the sharing economy: Manufacturing durable goods in the presence of peer-to-peer rental markets. Available at SSRN 2891908.##Al-Debei, M. M., &amp; Avison, D. (2010). Developing a unified framework of the business model concept. European Journal of Information Systems, 19(3), 359-376.##Armour, J., &amp; Sako, M. (2020). AI-enabled business models in legal services: from traditional law firms to next-generation law companies?. Journal of Professions and Organization, 7(1), 27-46.##Bocken, N. M., De Pauw, I., Bakker, C., &amp; van der Grinten, B. (2016). Product design and business model strategies for a circular economy. Journal of Industrial and Production Engineering, 33(5), 308-320.##Bora, B., Borah, S., &amp; Chungyalpa, W. (2017). Crafting Strategic Objectives: Examining the Role of Business Vision and Mission Statements. Journal of Entrepreneurship and Organizational Management, 6(1), 205-212.##Bouwman, H., Haaker, T., &amp; de Vos, H. (2005). Designing Business Models: a practical and holistic approach. Telematica Institute, Enschede.##Brousseau, E., &amp; Pénard, T. (2007). The economics of digital business models: A framework for analyzing the economics of platforms. Review of network Economics, 6(2).##Casadesus-Masanell, R., &amp; Ricart, J. E. (2010). From strategy to business models and onto tactics. Long range planning, 43(2-3), 195-215.##CURCIC, D., &amp; STIPANKOV, A. (2019). Business model dimensions affecting the speed of internationalization.##Duranton, G. (2009). Are cities engines of growth and prosperity for developing countries?. Urbanization and growth, (3), 67-114.##Faber, E., Ballon, P., Bouwman, H., Haaker, T., Rietkerk, O., &amp; Steen, M. (2003, June). Designing business models for mobile ICT services. In Workshop on concepts, metrics &amp; visualization, at the 16th Bled electronic commerce conference etransformation, Bled, Slovenia.##Fife, E. (2006). The convergence in Fixed Wireless Applications: Requirements for Successful New Business Models, Presented at FITCE 45th Congress, Athens Greece, September.##Frumkin, H. (Ed.). (2016). Environmental health: from global to local. John Wiley &amp; Sons.##George, G., &amp; Bock, A. J. (2011). The business model in practice and its implications for entrepreneurship research. Entrepreneurship theory and practice, 35(1), 83-111.## Ghezzi, A., &amp; Cavallo, A. (2020). Agile business model innovation in digital entrepreneurship: Lean startup approaches. Journal of business research, 110, 519-537.##Giriwati, N., Homma, R., &amp; Iki, K. (2013). Urban tourism: Designing a tourism space in a city context for social sustainability. The Sustainable City VIII (2 Volume Set): Urban Regeneration and Sustainability, 179, 1165.##Gordijn, J., Osterwalder, A., &amp; Pigneur, Y. (2005). Comparing two business model ontologies for designing e-business models and value constellations. BLED 2005 Proceedings, 15.##Gressgård, L. J., Methlie, L. B., &amp; Stensaker, I. G. (2003). Mobile internet services: integration models and structural determinants.##Jonker, J. (2014). Nieuwe business modellen. Samen Werken Aan Waardecreatie. Stichting Our Common Future, 2.##Korterik, N. (2019). Urban Business Models  ##Creating collective value in European urban environments.##Lambert, S. C. (2012). Deconstructing business model frameworks using a reference model. Centre for Accounting, Governance and Sustainability, University of South Australia.##Landry, C. (2012). The creative city: A toolkit for urban innovators. Earthscan.##Lee, J. (2001). A grounded theory: integration and internalization in ERP adoption and use.##Li, F. (2020). The digital transformation of business models in the creative industries: A holistic framework and emerging trends. Technovation, 92, 102012.##Lynch, K. (2007). The image of the city. The MIT Press, Cambridge, in S.S Jadon, Basic Concept of Urban Design: A Research Review, ITPI Journal, 4(1), 70-72.##Mason, K., &amp; Spring, M. (2011). The sites and practices of business models. Industrial Marketing Management, 40(6), 1032-1041.##Methlie, L., &amp; Pedersen, P. (2002). A taxonomy of intermediary integration strategies in online markets. BLED 2002 Proceedings, 1.##Morris, M. H., Shirokova, G., &amp; Shatalov, A. (2013). The business model and firm performance: the case of Russian food service ventures. Journal of Small Business Management, 51(1), 46-65.##Onetti, A., Zucchella, A., Jones, M. V., &amp; McDougall-Covin, P. P. (2012). Internationalization, innovation and entrepreneurship: business models for new technology-based firms. Journal of Management &amp; Governance, 16(3), 337-368.##Osterwalder, A., &amp; Pigneur, Y. (2010). Business model generation: a handbook for visionaries, game changers, and challengers. John Wiley &amp; Sons.##Osterwalder, A., &amp; Pigneur, Y. (2011). Aligning profit and purpose through business model innovation. Responsible management practices for the 21st century, 61-75.##Osterwalder, A., Pigneur, Y., &amp; Tucci, C. L. (2005). Clarifying business models: Origins, present, and future of the concept. Communications of the association for Information Systems, 16(1), 1.##Paterson, B. L., Thorne, S. E., Canam, C., &amp; Jillings, C. (2001). Meta-study of qualitative health research: A practical guide to meta-analysis and meta-synthesis (Vol. 3). Sage.##Renz, E. (2015). Business Models and the Creative City: Amsterdam’s Knowledge Mile in the limelight. CREATE-IT Applied Research Research Group Crossmedia.##Richardson, J. E. (2005). The business model: an integrative framework for strategy execution. Available at SSRN 932998.##Rosati, U., &amp; Conti, S. (2016). What is a smart city project? An urban model or a corporate business plan?. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 223, 968-973.##Schallmo, D., &amp; Brecht, L. (2010, December). Business model innovation in business-to-business markets–procedure and examples. In Proceedings of the 3rd ISPIM Innovation Symposium: “Managing the art of innovation: turning concepts into reality (Vol. 12, p. 15).##Shubar, A., &amp; Lechner, U. (2004, June). The public WLAN market and its business models-an empirical study. In Proceedings of the 17th Bled eCommerce Conference (pp. 1-18).##Solaimani, S., Heikkilä, M., &amp; Bouwman, H. (2018). Business model implementation within networked enterprises: A case study on a Finnish pharmaceutical project. European Management Review, 15(1), 79-96.##Stewart, D. W., &amp; Zhao, Q. (2000). Internet marketing, business models, and public policy. Journal of public policy &amp; marketing, 19(2), 287-296.##Teece, D. J. (2010). Business models, business strategy and innovation. Long range planning, 43(2-3), 172-194.##Teece, D. J. (2018). Business models and dynamic capabilities. Long Range Planning, 51(1), 40-49.##Timmers, P. (1998). Business models for electronic markets. Electronic markets, 8(2), 3-8.##Tucci, C. L. (2001). Internet business models and strategies: text and cases. McGraw-Hill Irwin.##UN-Habitat. (2011). The Economic role of cities.##UN-Habitat. (2017). Strengthening partnerships in support of the New Urban Agenda and the Sustainable Development Goals.##Upward, A. (2013). Towards an ontology and canvas for strongly sustainable business models: A systemic design science exploration.##Valsamidis, D., Pappas, D., Ferelis, V., &amp; Nikolaidis, M. (2018). Best Strategies For The Ideal Business Model. Scientific Bulletin-Economic Sciences, 17(1), 24-38.##Van Vliet, H. (2014). Cross-Mediascapes. Amsterdam. Amsterdam University Press.##Wirtz, B. W. (2011). Business model management. Design–Instrumente–Erfolgsfaktoren von Geschäftsmodellen, 2.##Zhang, L., &amp; Zhao, S. X. (2009). City branding and the Olympic effect: A case study of Beijing. Cities, 26(5), 245-254.##Zott, C., Amit, R., &amp; Massa, L. (2011). The business model: recent developments and future research. Journal of management, 37(4), 1019-1042. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>

</ARTICLES>

</JOURNAL>
</XML>
