@article{ 
author = {Estiri, Mehrdad and Rayej, Hamzeh and HosseiniTooli, Farshi},  
title = {Developing a Model to Measure Shopping Center Attractiveness in Tourism Regions (Case: Kish Island)}, 
abstract ={The importance of commercial centers as a major driver of tourism has been widely acknowledged in theoretical studies of tourism marketing. This study combines quantitative and qualitative approaches to determine the effective measures on the attractiveness of commercial centers as one of the effective dimensions on the attractiveness of tourism areas and the research data have been collected and analyzed in two main phases. The first phase by conducting qualitative exploratory research through semi-structured interviews with active managers in the urban planning and tourism area of Kish Island and analyzing the content of the responses presented confirmed that the attractiveness of commercial marketing could be considered as one of the criteria determining the attractiveness of the tourist areas. In the second phase of the study, in two separate studies, with the participation of tourists from Kish Island, with the aim of identifying the criteria affecting the attractiveness of commercial shopping centers in terms of buyers based on confirmatory and exploratory factor analysis methods as well as structural equation modeling (SEM), a five-dimensional model tangible factors, store space, product, sellers, and convenience shopping is designed.},  
Keywords = {Place Marketing, Shopping centers, tourism marketing, customer satisfaction, Kish Island},
volume = {6},
Number = {24}, 
pages = {1-15}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-974-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-974-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Bagheri, Noushin and HaghshenasKashani, Farideh},  
title = {Credit Risk Assessment of Urban Cooperatives Using Neural Network Method}, 
abstract ={One of the most important issues for institutions that provide financial facilities to others is the issue of credit risk. One of the ways to quantify and measure credit risk and, consequently, its proper management, is to use a credit rating. Credit rating is a model for measuring the performance of facility recipients, which is based on quantitative criteria such as corporate financial information, in order to allow prospective clients to obtain a similar profile with facilities and customers with a proper and inappropriate credit position. To be identified. According to the mission of the organization, the Central :::::union::::: of Cooperative of Workers of Iran has numerous member cooperatives from across the country, which provides their products there. In this research, the effect of each of the factors involved in determining the risk of credit in this cooperative has been tested first. Then, using the self-organizing mapping algorithm, we will cluster the data to exclude clusters that are very remote and far-reaching. The credit risk of each of the cooperatives has been calculated through the algorithm of the multi-layer perceptron neural networks in MATLAB software and a model for predicting credit risk in the future. The main purpose of this research was to use this algorithm to classify cooperatives by calculating credit risk numbers and use it to predict the future credit risk of the future cooperatives. &#160;},  
Keywords = {Scoring, Neural Network Algorithm, Validation, Credit Risk},
volume = {6},
Number = {24}, 
pages = {17-33}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-967-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-967-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Rostamzadeh, Parviz and Mirghaderi, Seyed Hadi and Diyanatkhah, Seyed Navi},  
title = {Effective Factors on the Difference between the Amount of Initial Estimation and the Cost of Construction Projects (Case: Shiraz Municipality)}, 
abstract ={Actual (Final) price of construction projects are usually deviations compared to their initial estimates. At runtime, these projects face increasing in costs for various reasons and may lose their economic justification. Therefore, identifying factors affecting this price difference are one of the most important issues in this field. This study identifies the importance of the factors affecting the difference between the amount of initial estimation and the actual cost of five mega-projects of the Shiraz municipality as example. This research is descriptive-survey and data collection was done using questionnaire and interviewing tool. In order to determine the weight, priority and categories of factors, the best-worst method, gray TOPSIS and weight-quality matrix were used, respectively. The results of this study show that nine important price deviations are effective in five superstructures that fall into three broad categories: &#34;high quality and high weight&#34;, &#34;low quality, high weight or vice versa&#34;, &#34;low quality and weight&#34;. According to the research findings, the &#34;existence of adversaries&#34; is the most influential factor in the price deviation of Shiraz municipality's superstructures.},  
Keywords = {construction projects, price deviation factors, Gray TOPSIS, BWM, Shiraz Municipality},
volume = {6},
Number = {24}, 
pages = {35-50}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-968-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-968-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Abroodi, Seyed Mojtaba and Kashfi, Seyed Saeid and Hosseini, Seyed Teymoor},  
title = {The Effect of New Law on Traffic Violations on Deterrence and reducing Traffic Accidents and Violations (Case: City of Tehran)}, 
abstract ={Driving without observance of driving laws and regulations threatens the order and safety of any society and disrupts the comfort of the people of that society. According to the new law on defamation and 289 percent increase in violations in 2016 compared to 2010, the purpose of this study is to investigate the deterrent effect of the new law on the investigation of violations of accidents and offenses in Tehran. In terms of purpose, this research is applied and analytical-descriptive survey type in terms of method. To collect the research data, a researcher-made questionnaire with a main hypothesis and three sub-hypotheses with 43 items was used and distributed among the statistical community that is the same as the heads of the 26th districts of Tehran police corridor and after completing the questionnaire by SPSS software and PLS and the T-test and Friedman tests have been analyzed. The results indicate that there is a positive and significant effect on accidents and violations at 99% confidence level, between severity, prudence or certainty, and the speed of new law enforcement and deterrence. The results also show that immediate treatment and severe punishment such as record keeping, vehicle seizure and the use of additional penalties, social exclusion, dismissal of liability in specific cases, etc. have a positive and significant effect on deterrence of violations and accidents. Increasing smart systems for recording road violations affects preventing violations and accidents, and reducing violations. It was also found that equipping the police with the appropriate equipment to accelerate the handling of incident violations had a significant positive effect on the deterrence of violations and accidents. Declaring driving disqualifications by judicial authorities and controlling them by specific means is effective in deterring offenses.},  
Keywords = {},
volume = {6},
Number = {24}, 
pages = {51-62}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-969-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-969-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Shamai, Ali and YousofiBabadi, Saei},  
title = {An Analysis of Good Governance Role on Sustainable Tourism Revenues (Case: City of MasjedSeleyman)}, 
abstract ={Various strategies have been proposed to promote sustainable incomes through good urban governance. One of the good strategies for good urban governance is the development of sustainable tourism in order to achieve sustainable urban incomes. Tourism as the second industry plays an important role in the cycle of economic activity, employment development, currency and tax revenue, and compensation for the lack of credit for other sectors of the economy in small and medium-sized cities. The purpose of this research is to analyze the role of good urban governance in promoting sustainable urban tourism through tourism in Masjed Soleyman city. The method of this research is mixed-exploratory and according to the data, it is quantitative and qualitative research and data access method is documentary and survey. The population of the sample is 30 urban experts and the sampling method is selective and targeted. In order to analyze the data, inferential statistics (sample t-test) was used in SPSS software and also for weighting the variables considered by multi-criteria decision-making models ANP and Super Decision software were used. The findings indicate that among the good urban governance variables that have an impact on sustainable urban incomes, the indicators for equipping the infrastructure, and facilities for attracting private investment in tourism is the most important and the index of equality of all shareholders against the benefits and plans of tourism development, has taken the lowest weight. The analytical results of the study of good urban governance variables that could be effective in increasing sustainable urban tourism through tourism have not been considered. The reasons for this unsatisfactory state of tourism infrastructure are inadequate facilities for attracting private sector investment (with a score of 0.12), lack of incentives for private sector investors in tourism (0.98), weakness in integrated urban management, including tourism development policies and lack of sufficient supervision over the performance of urban management and local institutions (0.016).},  
Keywords = {good urban governance, sustainable revenue, tourism industry, Masjed Seoleyman},
volume = {6},
Number = {24}, 
pages = {63-79}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-970-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-970-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Poorahmad, Ahmad and Piri, Esmaeil and Mohammadi, Yadegar and Parsa, Shahram and Heydari, Sam},  
title = {Good Urban Governance in Urban Neighborhoods (Case: Marivan City)}, 
abstract ={Good urban governance is one of the concepts that it takes into consideration the general welfare of citizens and its policies and programs are within the framework of specific indicators. Therefore, the purpose of this study is to investigate good urban governance indicators in the central neighborhoods of Marivan city, (1, 2, 4, 14). The data and information of this research were collected in two ways, library and survey, that in the survey method, the questionnaire tool was used that validity and reliability were confirmed by experts in this field. The total sample size was estimated at 380 people using the Cochran formula, the sampling method is non-random and questionnaires were distributed randomly among citizens. SPSS and Excel software were used to analyze the data, and given the normality of the data, ANOVA test was used. Using Tukey&#8217;s test, the differences between each neighborhood were investigated. The results indicated that in the neighborhoods studied, good urban governance indexes are not in desirable condition. The first and 14th neighborhoods do not have a significant difference in terms of accountability, consistency orientation and justice, and in other indices, these two neighborhoods have significant differences with each other. This significant difference is not high due to the difference in the average of the indices studied in both neighborhoods, and it can be said that the status of urban governance indicators in these two neighborhoods, like the two and four neighborhoods, is not in a desirable situation, and all of them are on almost the same level.},  
Keywords = {Good Urban Governance, Urban Management, Neighborhood, Marivan},
volume = {6},
Number = {24}, 
pages = {81-98}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-971-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-971-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Ahangari, Navid and Mohammadi, Robab and Najafi, Hakimeh},  
title = {Identification and Prioritization Factors Affecting the Domestic Tourist’s Behavior (Case: Isfahan)}, 
abstract ={Relevant researches in connection with models and purchase behavior of tourists provide useful information for tourism planning and its promotion. To this end, this paper is aimed at identifying and prioritizing the factors that influence the purchase behavior of domestic tourists in Isfahan city. In terms of purpose, it is cognitive research and data analysis is descriptive- analytical and the data collection tool is survey. Data were collected by library and field studies. Data collection tools consisted of a researcher-made questionnaire and a survey of domestic tourists. The statistical population of this research is all domestic tourists who visited Isfahan city in 2013. Thus, the sample size was estimated by Cochran without N, 96, but to improve the validity of the instrument was increased to 200 cases. The findings show that most of items bought by tourists (37/5%) are food items and souvenirs. Most methods used in purchase, instantaneous choice and immediately of the market (39%) and the main purpose of purchase items are to buy souvenirs (33/5%). The highest score was allocated to the highest index (0.25) and the lowest score was allocated to the lowest index (0.03) of the total score of one. In the final ranking, the component of the variety of items available for purchase in priority and the high price of souvenirs on the volume of purchases, ranked 18th.},  
Keywords = {Prioritization, Effective Factors, Purchase Behavior of Tourists, Souvenir, Isfahan},
volume = {6},
Number = {24}, 
pages = {99-115}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-972-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-972-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Heydari, Ali and Amiri, Mojtaba and Jamour, Hossei},  
title = {The Role of Internal Organizational Factors in Implementing the Budgeting System Based on Performance: An Interpretative Structural Modeling Approach (Case: Tehran Municipality)}, 
abstract ={It is essential to create the context for the strategic change in the organization. One of the necessity of reforming the municipal economic structure, modifying the method of budgeting and distributing resources, from traditional budgeting to an advanced budgeting system. Performance-based budgeting (PBB) by assigning targeted credit to activities can provide operational monitoring and facilitate access to resource allocation results while clarifying the distribution of resources. Accordingly, in this research, while introducing the internal factors affecting the implementation of the PBB, it has been attempted to express the relation between factors in the form of a conceptual model according to the extent of the impact and the effectiveness of each of the factors. This research is qualitative-quantitative in nature and is an applied in target dimension. In the process of identifying the factors, the content analysis method is used and in the classification stage of the known factors, an interpretative structural modeling tool is used. Data collection was gathered through reviewing organizational documents and interviewing managers, advisors and deputies of the Directorate of Program and Budget of Tehran Municipality. The results of the research show that in general, 11 main internal organizations are effective in implementing PBB. The citizenry agent has the least impact on the integrated information systems and has the most impact. According to the results of MICMAC analysis, none of the factors in the self-management area and two factors in the dependent region and eight factors in the communication area and the only factor of &#34;integrated information systems&#34; in the independent region.},  
Keywords = {PBB, Intra-organizational factors, Interpretative structural modeling, Tehran Municipality},
volume = {6},
Number = {24}, 
pages = {117-133}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-973-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-973-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

