<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<language>en</language>
<journal_id_issn></journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi></journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_isnet></journal_id_isnet>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>5</volume>
<number>19</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ارزیابی تعالی سازمانی براساس تحلیل سلسله‌مراتبی (AHP) با تأکید بر توسعه قابلیت‌های اقتصادی بانک شهر</title_fa>
	<title>Assessment of Organizational Excellence Based on Analytical Hierarchy Process (AHP) Emphasizing on the Development of Bank Shahr Economic Capabilities</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>به&#8204;کارگیری مدل&#8204;های تعالی سازمانی، در ارزیابی عملکرد سازمان&#8204;ها، به&#8204;منظور شناسایی نقاط&#8204; قوت و ضعف و میزان دستیابی سازمان&#8204;ها به کیفیت و عملکرد بهتر، مؤثر است. تعالی سازمانی، تابع شرایط خاص، فرهنگ، محیط داخلی و خارجی، ویژگی نیروی انسانی سازمان، نقاط &#8204;قوت و ضعف و فرصت&#8204;ها و تهدیدهایی است که سازمان را دربر گرفته است&#8204;. براین&#8206;اساس، شناسایی و تشخیص مسیر برتری و تعالی سازمانی، توسعه و گسترش موفقیت در یک سازمان است&#8204;. هدف پژوهش حاضر، ارزیابی تعالی سازمانی بانک شهر براساس مدل تعالیEFQM ، با استفاده از تحلیل سلسله&#8204;مراتبی است. پژوهش حاضر، مطالعه&#8204;ای توصیفی، میدانی و مقطعی است که به ارزیابی تعالی سازمانی بانک شهر از دیدگاه مدیران شعب شهر تهران در سال 1393 پرداخته است&#8204;. جامعه پژوهش، 139 نفر از مدیران شعب بانک شهر در سال 1393 می&#8204;باشد که با استفاده از فرمول کوکران، 100 نفر با روش تصادفی ساده به عنوان نمونه انتخاب شده&#8204;اند. به&#8204;منظور گردآوری داده&#8204;ها، از پرسشنامه محقق&#8204;ساخته استفاده شده که این پرسشنامه با توجه به تکنیک فرایند تحلیل سلسله&#8204;مراتبی و برگرفته از معیارهای شایستگی مدل بنیاد اروپایی کیفیت جامع، ساخته شده است&#8204;. روایی ابزار، از نظر اساتید و خبرگان و پایایی آن، با استفاده از ضریب آلفای کرونباخ، تأیید شد. برای تحلیل داده&#8204;های جمع&#8204;آوری شده، از تحلیل سلسله&#8204;مراتبی استفاده شده است. نتایج پژوهش با توجه به وزن معیارهای مدل نشان دادند که بالاترین رتبه مربوط به معیار استراتژی و سیاست&#8204;گذاری و پایین&#8204;ترین رتبه مربوط به نتایج کسب&#8204;&#8204;وکار در بانک شهر می&#8204;باشد.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Applying organizational excellence models has been effective on assessment of organization&#8217;s performance in order to identify strengths, weaknesses, and organizations&#8217; achievement to better quality and performance. Organizational excellence is subject to certain conditions, culture, internal and external environment, characteristics of organization&#8217;s human force, strengths, weaknesses, opportunities, and threats that covered the organization. In this regard, identification the path of organizational excellence leads to organization&#8217;s development and success. This research aims to assess organizational excellence of Bank Shahr based on EFQM Excellence Model by using the analytic hierarchy process (AHP). This research is descriptive, field survey, and cross-sectional addressing to assess organizational excellence of Bank Shahr from perspective of Tehran branches&#8217; managers in 2014. Statistical population includes 193 branch managers of Bank Shahr in 2014. 100 of them were selected as sample by using Cochran formula with simple random sampling. Data were collected through researcher-made questionnaire according to the Analytical Hierarchy Process (AHP) and taken from the competence criteria of the European Foundation for Quality Management (EFQM) model. The validity was confirmed by professors and experts&#8217; opinion and its reliability was confirmed by Cronbach&#8217;s alpha. To analyze data collection, AHP was used. According to the model&#8217;s criteria weight, the results indicated that the highest rank is related to strategy and policy-making, and the lowest one is related to business results at Bank Shahr.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>assessment, organizational excellence, Bank Shahr, AHP, EFQM</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>ارزیابی, تعالی سازمانی, بانک شهر, تحلیل سلسله‌مراتبی, EFQM</keyword>
	<start_page>1</start_page>
	<end_page>13</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-158-60&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Azadeh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ghamari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Management, Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>آزاده</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>قمری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Azadehghamari@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846003498</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846003498</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Bijan</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Abdollahi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Management, Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>بیژن</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عبدالهی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>0031947532846003499</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846003499</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Hasan Reza </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Zeinabadi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Management, Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>حسن‌رضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>زین آبادی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>0031947532846003500</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846003500</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Gholam Hossein </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Tabeshfar</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Institute for Management And Planning Studies, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>غلامحسین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>تابش‌فر</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>0031947532846003501</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846003501</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>مؤسسه عالی آموزش و پژوهش مدیریت و برنامه‌ریزی، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی نقش فرهنگ سازمانی در ارتقای توانمندسازی روان‌شناختی کارکنان نظام بانکی (مورد مطالعه: بانک شهر)</title_fa>
	<title>Investigating the Role of Organizational Culture in Improving Psychological Empowerment of Banking System Employees (Case: Bank Shahr)</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>فرهنگ سازمانی، یکی از مقوله&#8204;های بسیار مهم در مدیریت رفتار سازمانی می&#8204;باشد که پژوهش&#8204;&#8204;های وسیعی در خصوص نقش این عامل در ارتقای بهره&#8204;وری سازمانی و نیل به اهداف سازمانی انجام شده است. یکی از عواملی که نقش بسزایی در بهره&#8204;وری و حصول موفقیت سازمانی دارد، توانمندسازی روان&#8204;شناختی کارکنان می&#8204;باشد. امروزه در مدیریت نوین، برنامه&#8204;های راهبردی و ساختاری سازمان&#8204;های پیشرو، منطبق بر توسعه و ارتقای توانمندی نیروی انسانی آن تدوین می&#8204;گردند. در این راستا، توجه به نقش فرهنگ سازمانی، برای دستیابی به این هدف، حائز اهمیت می&#8204;باشد. بدین منظور و با توجه به تعدد الگوهای فرهنگ سازمانی، در این پژوهش ابتدا به بررسی الگوهای متنوع فرهنگ سازمانی، پرداخته شده و سپس به نقش فرهنگ سازمانی در توانمندسازی روان&#8204;شناختی کارکنان برای کسب مزیت رقابتی در قلمرو مکانی بانک شهر پرداخته شده است. نتایج پژوهش نشان می&#8204;دهند که فرهنگ سازمانی بر توانمندسازی روان&#8204;شناختی کارکنان بانک شهر تهران، تأثیر مثبت، مستقیم و معناداری دارد. بر این اساس بهبود یا عدم&#8204;بهبود فرهنگ سازمانی، منجر به افزایش یا کاهش توانمندسازی روان&#8204;شناختی کارکنان می&#8204;&#8204;شود و این امر تأثیر مستقیمی بر بازدهی اقتصادی آنها نیز دارد. همچنین بررسی مدل از حیث نیکویی برازش نشان داد که مدل نظری از لحاظ آماری، دارای معنا و مفهوم نظری و کاربردی است و از لحاظ مطلوبیت وضعیت برازش، با توجه به آماره&#8204;های محاسبه شده توسط نرم&#8204;افزارهای آماری، در وضعیت قابل&#8204;قبولی، برآورد می&#8204;&#8206;شود.&#160;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Organizational change is one of the most important issues in organizational behavior management that many studies have been done regarding the role of this factor in improving organizational efficiency and achieving to organizational goals. One of the factors that have an influential role in organizational efficiency and success is psychological empowerment of employees. Today, in new management, strategic and structural plans of leading organizations are formulated consistent with the development and enhancement of its manpower. In this regard, attention to the role of organizational culture is of great importance to achieve this objective. For this purpose and given the diversity of organizational culture models, in this research, different organizational culture patterns have been investigated, and then, the role of organizational culture in improving psychological empowerment of employees to attain competitive advantage at Bank Shahr was studied. The results indicated that organizational culture has positive, direct and significant impact on improving psychological empowerment of Bank Shahr employees. In this regard, improvement of organizational culture or its failure leads to an increase or decrease in the psychological empowerment of employees. Accordingly, this has a direct impact on their economic efficiency. Furthermore, the study of the model in terms of goodness of fit showed that the theoretical model is statistically significant and the theoretical concept is practical, and in terms of the desirability of fitness, according to the statistics calculated by statistical software, it is estimated in an acceptable situation.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>empowerment, psychological, organizational culture, banking system, Bank Shahr</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>توانمندسازی, روان‌شناختی, فرهنگ سازمانی, نظام بانکی, بانک شهر</keyword>
	<start_page>15</start_page>
	<end_page>27</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-158-61&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Hossein</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mohammadpour Zarandi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>University of Science and Culture, President of Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association (IUESA)</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>حسین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>محمدپورزرندی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>0031947532846003502</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846003502</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه علم و فرهنگ و رئیس انجمن علمی اقتصاد شهری ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Maryam</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Fahima</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Management, Islamic Azad University, Central Tehran Branch, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>مریم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>فهیما</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>maryamxfahima@gmail.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846003503</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846003503</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Alireza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Amirkabiri</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Management, Islamic Azad University, Central Tehran Branch, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>علیرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>امیرکبیری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>0031947532846003504</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846003504</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>پیش‌بینی قیمت مسکن برای شهر اهواز: مقایسه مدل هدانیک با مدل شبکه عصبی مصنوعی</title_fa>
	<title>Forecasting the House Price for Ahvaz City: the Comparison of the Hedonic and Artificial Neural Network Models</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>تعیین و برآورد قیمت مسکن در مناطق شهری، از اهمیت زیادی برای دولت، سرمایه&#8204;گذاران خصوصی و دولتی و افراد عادی برخوردار است. این تخمین می&#8204;تواند در برنامه&#8204;ریزی و تصمیم&#8204;گیری&#8204;های آینده در بسیاری از سیاست&#8206;های شهری و منطقه&#8204;ای مورد استفاده قرار گیرد. در این راستا به دلیل اهمیت بالای قیمت مسکن در دهه&#8204;های اخیر، استفاده از توابع قدرتمند و کارا برای پیش&#8204;بینی و تخمین قیمت مسکن مرسوم شده است. پژوهش حاضر، با هدف ارائه مدلی بهینه برای پیش&#8204;بینی قیمت مسکن و تعیین عوامل تأثیرگذار بر قیمت مسکن در کلان&#8204;شهر اهواز و نیز مقایسه&#8204;ای بین دو مدل هدانیک و شبکه عصبی مصنوعی انجام شده است. ماهیت پژوهش، توسعه&#8204;ای-کاربردی و روش انجام آن، توصیفی- تحلیلی می&#8204;باشد. در این پژوهش، 286 نمونه واحد مسکونی در سال 1394 براساس 27 متغیر مربوطه به منظور پیش&#8204;بینی قیمت مسکن، مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفته است. در این تحقیق از تابع هدانیکی نیمه&#8204;لگاریتمی و شبکه عصبی پرسپترون چند لایه (MLP) استفاده شده است. برای مقایسه دو مدل از لحاظ توانایی پیش&#8204;بینی، از معیارهای R2، MSE، RMSE، MAPE، MAE و ضریب TIC استفاده شده است. نتایج مدل هدانیک نشان دادند از میان 27 متغیر مدل، 18 متغیر معنی&#8204;دار بودند و با مقایسه نتایج و مقدار برآوردها، مشخص شد که قیمت مسکن در اهواز بیشتر از عوامل فیزیکی و ساختاری تأثیر می&#8204;پذیرد. برای بررسـی تفاوت در دقت پیش&#8204;بینـی مدل&#8204;های مختلف بـرای پیش&#8204;بینی قیمت مسـکن در شهـر اهواز، از آزمـون مورگان-گرنجر- نیوبلد استفاده شده است. نتایج به&#8206;دست آمده از آزمون نشان دادند که تفاوت قدرت پیش&#8204;بینی دو مدل از لحاظ آماری نیز معنی&#8204;دار است که نشان&#8204;دهنده کارایی بهتر و عملکرد مناسب&#8204;تر شبکه عصبی مصنوعی (98 درصد) نسبت به مدل رگرسیون هدانیک (88 درصد) است.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Determination and the estimation of the house price in urban areas has a great importance for governments, individual and state investors and common people. The mentioned estimation can be used in future planning and decision making of many urban and regional policies. In this regard, due to the vital importance of the house price in recent decades powerful and effective functions have been used in order to forecast and estimate the house price. The main purpose of the current study was to present an optimal model to forecast and identify the determinants of the house price in Ahvaz metropolitan by the comparison of the Hedonic and Artificial Neural Network Models and the choice of the optimal model. The present study has a developmental-applied nature which follows a descriptive-analytical approach. The sample included 286 statistical unit in 2015 based on 27 related variables were evaluated to forecast the house price in Ahvaz city. This study used semi-log hedonic function and Neural Network Multilayer Perceptron (MLP) approaches. To compare the results of the two models in terms of predictability the criteria of R2, MSE, RMSE, MAPE, MAE and TIC coefficient were utilized. The results of the Hedonic model indicated that that among 27 variables, 18 variables were significant model and by the comparison of the results and the estimated value, it turned out that housing prices in Ahvaz is mainly influenced by the physical and structural factors. Moreover, the comparison between all criteria demonstrated that the Artificial Neural Network had a better performance than the Hedonic regression model in forecasting the house price. In order to test the difference of precision in forecasts of the house price in Ahvaz the Morgan-Granger-Newbold test was conducted as an appropriate instrument. The results of test indicated that the there was a significant difference between the predicative power of the two models which confirmed the greater performance of the ANN (%98) model in comparison with Hedonic regression model (88%).</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>forecasting, house price, house, ahvaz, hedonic model, Artificial Neural Network (ANN) model</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>پیش‌بینی, قیمت مسکن, مسکن, شهر اهواز, مدل هدانیک, مدل شبکه عصبی مصنوعی</keyword>
	<start_page>29</start_page>
	<end_page>44</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-158-62&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Salar </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ghorbani</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Economics and Social Sciences, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz, Ahvaz, Iran</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>سالار</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>قربانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>salar.ghorbany66@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846003505</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846003505</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، اهواز، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Seyyed Morteza </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Afgheh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Economics and Social Sciences, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz, Ahvaz, Iran</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>سیدمرتضی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>افقه</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>0031947532846003506</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846003506</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، اهواز، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تحلیل فضایی رقابت‌پذیری آموزشی استان‌های کشور</title_fa>
	<title>The Spatial Analysis of Educational Competitiveness of Iran Provinces</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>امروزه رقابت&#8204;پذیری، به یکی از مفاهیم پرکاربرد در عرصه مباحث شهری و منطقه&#8204;&#8206;ای تبدیل شده است. علت توجه بیش از حد به این مفهوم، تغییرات در اقتصاد جهانی، ساختار دموگرافیکی بیشتر ملت&#8204;ها، ساختارهای اجتماعی و فعالیت&#8204;ها است. هدف این پژوهش، تحلیل فضایی رقابت&#8204;پذیری استان&#8204;های کشور در زمینه شاخص&#8204;های آموزشی است. این پژوهش از لحاظ هدف، کاربردی و از لحاظ ماهیت و روش تحقیق، توصیفی- تحلیلی است. به منظور تحلیل رقابت&#8204;پذیری آموزشی استان&#8204;های کشور، 75 معیار از سرفصل آموزش سرشماری عمومی نفوس و مسکن سال 1390، انتخاب و تحلیل شدند. برای انجام تحلیل از مدل&#8204;های ضریب پراکندگی، ویکور و رگرسیون وزن&#8204;دار جغرافیایی در نرم&#8204;افزار ArcGIS استفاده شد. یافته&#8204;های پژوهش حاکی از عدم&#8204;پراکنش مناسب شاخص&#8204;های آموزشی در سطح استان&#8204;های کشور هستند. در مجموع 46 درصد شاخص&#8204;های آموزشی از وضعیت پراکنشی مناسبی برخوردار نیستند و استان&#8204;های سیستان و بلوچستان، کردستان و ایلام، از بیشترین نابرابری و استان&#8204;های آذربایجان غربی، اصفهان و آذربایجان شرقی، از کم&#8204;ترین نابرابری پراکنش برخوردار بوده&#8204;اند. نتایج نهایی بیانگر آن بودند که از لحاظ رقابت&#8204;پذیری آموزشی، در سطح اول، استان تهران، در سطح دوم، استان&#8204;های خراسان رضوی، خوزستان، فارس، اصفهان، آذربایجان شرقی، کرمان، مازندران و در سطح سوم، استان&#8204;های گیلان، سیستان و بلوچستان، آذربایجان غربی، لرستان، هرمزگان، گلستان، کرمانشاه، همدان، مرکزی، کردستان، البرز، قزوین، اردبیل، کهگیلویه و بویراحمد، بوشهر، یزد، چهارمحال و بختیاری، زنجان، سمنان، خراسان جنوبی، قم، ایلام و خراسان شمالی قرار دارند. به&#8204;طور کلی، بررسی نتایج حاکی از آن بودند که وضعیت توسعه استان&#8204;های کشور از لحاظ شاخص&#8204;های آموزشی، سنخیت مناسبی با عدالت اجتماعی و فضایی ندارد که نیازمند توجه از پایین به بالا و برنامه&#8204;ریزی غیرمتمرکز است. علاوه&#8204;بر این، رشد اقتصادی نیازمند پایه&#8206;گذاری سیستم آموزشی کاربردمحور است.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Today, competitiveness has become one of the most applied concepts in regional and urban studies. The reason, why much attention has been devoted to this concept is the changes in the world economy, demographical changes of countries, changes in social structures and activities. This research aimed to conduct a spatial analysis of competitiveness of Iran provinces based on educational factors. In terms of scope, this research is an applied study and in terms of nature and research method is descriptive analytic one. 75 factor from education section of national population and housing consensus of 1390 (2011) have selected and analyzed. For analyzing Coefficient of Variant (C.V), VIKOR and geographically weighted regression in the Arc GIS were used. The research findings indicate inappropriate distribution in the educational factors between provinces of Iran. Totally, 46% of educational factors distributed in unsuitable way, and Sistan and Baluchestan, Kurdistan and Ilam provinces are in most inequality but in turn, West Azerbaijan, Isfahan and East Azerbaijan are in the good situation. Final results shows that, in terms of educational competitiveness, Tehran province is in the first level, Razavi Khorasan, Khuzestan, Fars, Isfahan, East Azerbaijan, Kerman, Mazanderan provinces are placed in the second level, and in the third level Gilan, Sistan and Baluchestan, West Azerbaijan, Lorestan, Hormozgan, Golestan, Kermanshah, Hamadan, Markazi, Kurdistan, Alborz, Qazvin, Ardebil, Kohgiluyeh and Boyer-Ahmad, Boushehr, Yazd, Chaharmahal and Bakhtiari, Zanjan, Semnan, South Khorasan, Qom, Ilam and North Khorasan provinces are located. Overall conclusions indicate that development situations of Iran provinces in terms of educational factors are not in good consistent with concepts of social and spatial justice and required bottom-up approach and decentralized planning. Moreover, economic growth depends on establishment of performance-oriented education system.&#160;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>spatial analysis, competitiveness, education, Iran provinces</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>تحلیل فضایی, رقابت‌پذیری, آموزش, استان‌های کشور, شاخص‌های آموزشی</keyword>
	<start_page>45</start_page>
	<end_page>61</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-158-63&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Farzaneh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Sasanpour</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Faculty of  Geograophical Sciences, Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>فرزانه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>ساسان‌پور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>f.sasanpour@gmail.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846003507</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846003507</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Afshar</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Hatami</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Faculty of  Geograophical Sciences,  Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>افشار</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حاتمی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>0031947532846003508</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846003508</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>درآمدی بر اشتغال در بخش‌های عمده استان تهران براساس داده- ستانده بخشی</title_fa>
	<title>An Introduction to Employment in Main Parts of Tehran Province Based on Output-Input Division</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>این پژوهش با هدف شناسایی و بررسی وضع موجود بازار کار و تحلیل زوایای آشکار و پنهان بیکاری و توسعه اشتغال با روش کمی در استان تهران انجام شده است. ابتدا با استفاده از اطلاعات آماری و از طریق تعیین سهم بخش&#8204;های اقتصادی از بازار کار و میزان دادوستد نیروی کار بین بخشی، برای تمامی شهرستان&#8204;های استان تهران، میزان کمی جذب و مازاد نیروی کار مشخص شد و سپس در افق چشم&#8204;انداز ایران 1404، اندازه واقعی تقاضای نیروی کار برآورد گردید. در این تحقیق، از روش&#8204;های مبتنی بر داده- ستانده به بازار کار استفاده شده است که عبارتند از: روش اول، مبتنی بر آمار شاغلان بخش&#8204;های اقتصادی که شامل روش تغییر سهم و روش ضریب مکانی است. روش دوم، روش داده- ستانده مبتنی بر ارزش&#8204;افزوده تولید است که برای ارزیابی جذب یا صدور نیروی کار در سه بخش عمده اقتصادی، کشاورزی، خدمات و صنعت در هر شهرستان استفاده شده است. یافته&#8204;های تحقیق نشان می&#8204;دهند که سهم اشتغال در بخش کشاورزی از سال 1385 تا سال 1394، با 1/0 درصد کاهش مواجه بود و از سال 1395 تا سال 1404، با 1/0 درصد افزایش روبه&#8204;رو خواهد شد. سهم اشتغال در بخش صنعت از سال 1385 تا سال 1394، 3/0 درصد افزایش داشته و سپس تا سال 1404 با کاهش تقریباً پنج درصدی همراه خواهد بود. سهم بخش خدمات از سال 1385 تا سال 1394 تقریباً ثابت بوده (2/0 درصد کم شده) و سپس از سال 1394 تا سال 1404 به روند افزایشی خود ادامه می&#8204;دهد و تقریباً به رشد 5 درصدی خواهد رسید. بیشترین تغییر در اشتغال مربوط به سهم بخش خدمات می&#8204;باشد، بیشترین ضریب مکانی با روش اشتغال، مربوط به شهر تهران در بخش خدمات و پایین&#8204;ترین نیز مربوط به شهر تهران در بخش کشاورزی و صنعت می&#8204;باشد.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>This paper has been done in order to recognize and review the existing job market, to analyze obvious and hidden aspects of unemployment, and to develop employment field in Tehran province. First, by using statistical information and determining economic parts ratio of job market and work force&#8217;s divisional transition, the quantity and additive parts of work force for all towns of Tehran province were specified and then the real amount of work force demand was estimated in Iran horizon prospects up to 2025. In this paper, some models were used, based on output-input job market way. They include: the first method was based on employees statistics in economic portion. It consists of shift-share with location-quotient method. The second method input-output is based on production value added, that was used in three main parts such as economy, agriculture, service and industry to evaluate attraction or export of work forces in every town. The research findings show that employment share in agricultural part from 2006 to 2015 encountered 0.1% reduction and from 2016 to 2025 it would face 0.1% amplification. Employment share in industry part increased up to 0.3% and then to 1404 it would encounter 5% reduction. Service sector share in 2006 to 2015 was nearly stable (it decreased to 0.2%). And then from 2015 up to 2025 it continues its increase procedure and reached to 5% growth. Most employment variation is related to the share of service sector. Most location-quotient using employment model is related to Tehran city in service sector and least amount related to Tehran city is in agricultural and industrial part.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>Tehran province, economic parts, shift share model, location quotient model, output-input model</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>استان تهران, بخش‌های اقتصادی, مدل تغییر سهم, مدل ضریب مکانی, مدل داده- ستانده</keyword>
	<start_page>63</start_page>
	<end_page>78</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-158-64&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Nasrollah</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Maghsoudi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Management and Accounting, Islamic Azad University Islamshahr Branch, Islamshahr, Iran</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>نصراله</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مقصودی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>dr_n_maghsoudi@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846003509</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846003509</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد اسلامشهر، اسلامشهر، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>عوامل مؤثر بر آموزش شهروندی با تأکید بر توسعه پایدار شهری (مورد مطالعه: شهرداری زنجان)</title_fa>
	<title>Effective Factors on Citizenship Education Emphasizing on Urban Sustainable Development (Case: Zanjan Municipality)</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>آموزش شهروندی، از ارکان اساسی زندگی اجتماعی عصر حاضر است و در جوامع پیشرفته، از طریق برنامه&#8204;ریزی&#8204;های متنوع، به آموزش مهارت&#8204;های شهروندی، پرداخته می&#8206;شود؛ با توجه به این شرایط، پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر آموزش شهروندی از دیدگاه کارکنان شهرداری شهر زنجان انجام شده است. روش پژوهش از لحاظ هدف، کاربردی و از لحاظ چگونگی جمع&#8204;آوری اطلاعات، در زمره پژوهش&#8204;های توصیفی- پیمایشی است. جامعه آماری، شامل کلیه کارکنان شهرداری شهر زنجان بوده و با 204 نفر به&#8204;عنوان نمونه پژوهش، انتخاب شدند و روش نمونه&#8204;گیری، خوشه&#8204;ای چندمرحله&#8204;ای بوده است. ابزار پژوهش، پرسشنامه محقق&#8204;ساخته مبتنی بر طیف پنج ارزشی لیکرت بوده که روایی صوری آن توسط خبرگان دانشگاهی، تأیید شد و پایایی آن با استفاده از ضریب آلفای کرونباخ برابر با 93/0 به&#8204;دست آمد. همچنین جهت تحلیل داده&#8204;ها، از آزمون T تک&#8204;نمونه&#8204;ای و آزمون رتبه&#8204;بندی فریدمن استفاده شده است. مهم&#8204;ترین یافته&#8204;ها حکایت از آن داشتند که همه عوامل مؤثر بر آموزش شهروندی (رفتارهای مبتنی بر کنش&#8204;های اجتماعی/سیاسی، قانون&#8204;پذیری و قانون&#8204;گرایی، رفتارهای مبتنی بر آموزه&#8204;های دینی و ملی و رفتارهای مبتنی بر حفظ محیط&#8204;زیست و توسعه پایدار) در سطح 05/0، معنادار هستند و نتایج آزمون فریدمن نشان دادند که کارکنان شهرداری شهر زنجان، به ترتیب رفتارهای مبتنی بر آموزه&#8204;های دینی و ملی، قانون&#8204;پذیری و قانون&#8204;گرایی، رفتارهای مبتنی بر کنش&#8204;های اجتماعی/سیاسی و رفتارهای مبتنی بر حفظ محیط&#8204;زیست و توسعه پایدار در سطح 05/0 را به&#8204;عنوان عوامل مؤثر بر آموزش شهروندی، اولویت&#8204;بندی کرده&#8204;اند.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Citizenship education is one of the main pillars of social life in the current era. Skills of citizenship education are addressed through various planning in advanced societies. Given such conditions, this research aims to investigate effective factors on citizenship education from perspective of municipal employees in the city of Zanjan. In terms of purpose, this research is applied, and in terms of data collection, it is descriptive-survey. Statistical population includes all municipality employees of Zanjan city and 240 of them were selected as sample by using multi-stage cluster sampling. Research tool was researcher-made questionnaire based on five-point Likert scale. Its face validity was confirmed by academic experts and its reliability was calculated using by Cronbach&#8217;s alpha coefficient equal to 0.93. However, in order to analyze data, one-sample T-test and Friedman ranking test were used. The most important findings indicated that all effective factors on citizenship education including behaviors based on socio-political actions, law-abiding and law-orientation, behaviors based on religious and national commands, and those based on protecting environment and sustainable development are at significance level of 0.05. The results of Freidman test indicated that municipal employees in the city of Zanjan prioritized behaviors based on religious and national commands, law-abiding and law-orientation, those based on socio-political actions, and those based on protecting environment and sustainable development as effective factors on citizenship education&#160; respectively at the level of 0.05.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>citizenship education, citizenship training, municipal employees</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>آموزش شهروندی, تربیت شهروندی, کارکنان شهرداری, توسعه پایدار شهر</keyword>
	<start_page>79</start_page>
	<end_page>95</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-158-65&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Kaveh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Teymournejad</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Management, Islamic Azad University, Central Tehran Branch, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>کاوه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>تیمورنژاد</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>kaveh_teymournejad@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846003510</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846003510</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Alireza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Youzbashi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Psychology and Education, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>علیرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>یوزباشی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>0031947532846003511</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846003511</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Majid</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ebrahimi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Sadra Institute of Higher Education, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>مجید</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>ابراهیمی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>0031947532846003512</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846003512</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>مؤسسه آموزش عالی غیرانتفاعی صدرالمتألهین (صدرا)، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>نقش انگیزش شغلی در یادگیری سازمانی و توانمندسازی روان‌شناختی در راستای بهبود عملکرد اقتصادی کارکنان شهرداری</title_fa>
	<title>The Role of Job Motivation on Organizational Learning and Empowerment of Municipal Staffs to Increase Economic Performance of Municipal Employees</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>امروزه مدیریت منابع انسانی، یکی از مهم&#8204;ترین وظایف مدیران سازمانی است و انگیزش شغلی، یادگیری سازمانی و توانمندسازی روان&#8204;شناختی، از مباحثی هستند که مدیران با آن&#8204;ها مواجه هستند. از این رو پژوهش حاضر، با هدف بررسی تأثیر انگیزش شغلی بر یادگیری سازمانی و توانمندسازی روان&#8204;شناختی کارکنان شهرداری شهر یاسوج انجام شده است. روش پژوهش از لحاظ هدف، کاربردی و از نظر چگونگی جمع&#8204;آوری اطلاعات، در زمره پژوهش&#8204;های توصیفی- همبستگی است. جامعه آماری، شامل کلیه کارکنان شهرداری شهر یاسوج است که با استفاده از فرمول کوکران، 146 نفر به &#8204;عنوان نمونه پژوهش، انتخاب شدند و روش نمونه&#8204;گیری، تصادفی ساده است. ابزار پژوهش؛ شامل سه پرسشنامه استاندارد انگیزش شغلی هرزبرگ (1984)، یادگیری سازمانی نیفه (2001) و توانمندسازی روان&#8204;شناختی اسپریتزر (1995) است که روایی و پایایی آن&#8204;ها، تأیید شده است. برای تجزیه&#8204;وتحلیل داده&#8204;ها، از آزمون رگرسیون هم&#8204;زمان استفاده شده است. مهم&#8204;ترین یافته&#8204;ها، بیانگر آن بودند که انگیزش شغلی، 039/0 از واریانس یادگیری سازمانی و 122/0 از واریانس توانمندسازی روان&#8204;شناختی کارکنان را تبیین کرده و انگیزش شغلی، توانایی پیش&#8204;بینی تغییرات مربوط به یادگیری سازمانی و توانمندسازی روان&#8204;شناختی را دارد؛ پس انگیزش شغلی، بر یادگیری سازمانی و توانمندسازی روان&#8204;شناختی کارکنان شهرداری تأثیر معناداری دارد.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Today, human resources management is one of the most important duties of organizational managers. They confront with issues such as job motivation, organizational learning and psychological empowerment. This study was conducted to investigate the impact of job motivation on organizational learning and psychological empowerment of municipal employees of Yasooj. In terms of purpose, research method is applied and it is descriptive &#8211;correlative in terms of data collection. The statistical population included all of Yasuj municipal employees among them 146 people were selected as a sample by using Cochran formula and simple random sampling method. The research tools consisted of three questionnaires: Herzberg Professional Motivation (1984), Neife&#8217;s Organizational Learning (2001) and Spreader&#8217;s Psychological Empowerment (1995). Their validity and reliability were confirmed. Regression test was used for data analysis. The most important findings show that job motivation illustrates 0.039 of organizational learning variance and 0.122 of the variance of psychological empowerment of employees, which indicates that job motivation has the ability to predict changes in organizational learning and psychological empowerment. Therefore, job motivation has significant impact on organizational learning and psychological empowerment of municipal employees.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>job motivation, organizational learning, psychological empowerment, economic performance, municipal employees</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>انگیزش شغلی, یادگیری سازمانی, توانمندسازی روان‌شناختی, کارکنان شهرداری, عملکرد اقتصادی</keyword>
	<start_page>97</start_page>
	<end_page>111</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-158-66&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Abasalt</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Khorasani</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Education and Psychology, Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>اباصلت</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>خراسانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>0031947532846003513</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846003513</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Hamed</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Zamanimanesh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Humanities, Shahid Rajaee Teacher Training University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>حامد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>زمانی‌منش</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Hzm64@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846003514</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846003514</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت دبیر شهید رجائی، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>نقش نهاد شورای اسلامی شهر در اعتلای حقوق شهروندی (مورد مطالعه: شورای اسلامی شهر تهران)</title_fa>
	<title>The Role of Islamic City Council in the Promotion of Citizenship Rights (Case: Islamic City Council of Tehran)</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>امروزه شهر و هر محیط زندگی مدنی و اجتماعی، با شهروندان، معنی پیدا می&#8206;کند. رابطه شهروندی با مدیریت شهری از جمله مسائل و موضوعات مهمی است که در حوزه مدیریت شهری در جهان مورد توجه قرار گرفته است. یکی از عواملی که می&#8204;تواند به تحقق و پایداری نظام مردم&#8207;سالاری در جامعه از طریق اجتماعات مردمی بیانجامد، توجه به حقوق شهروندی است که می&#8206;توان دستیابی به این هدف را از سوی شوراها دنبال کرد. در یک نگاه جامع شوراها در بطن خود، کلیدواژه حقوق شهروندی، را دارا می&#8206;باشند؛ زیرا فلسفه وجودی خود شوراها بندهایی از تحقق معیارها و مؤلفه&#8207;های حقوق شهروندی است. به عبارت دیگر، شوراها تبلور تحقق حقوق شهروندی می&#8207;باشند. در این راستا پژوهش حاضر، به بررسی و تحلیل عملکرد شورای شهر تهران در تحقق حقوق شهروندی می&#8204;پردازد. نوع پژوهش، کاربردی و از لحاظ روش، پیمایشی- توصیفی است. گردآوری اطلاعات به دو صورت کتابخانه&#8204;ای- اسنادی و پیمایشی- میدانی و با روش پرسشنامه انجام گرفته است. نمونه در دسترس پژوهش، 150 نفر از کارمندان شورای اسلامی و 384 نفر از شهروندان شهر تهران در سال 1395 است. برای تجزیه&#8204;و&#8204;تحلیل داده&#8204;های جمع&#8204;آوری شده، از نرم&#8204;افزار SPSS و آزمون&#8204;های T، ضریب همبستگی پیرسون و رگرسیون استفاده شده&#8204; است. نتایج پژوهش نشان دادند که شهروندان شهر تهران میزان عملکرد شورای شهر را به دلیل نداشتن سازوکار مناسبی جهت نظارت بر امور شهری و تحقق حقوق شهروندی، کمتر از حد متوسط می&#8204;دانند. همچنین بین عملکرد شورای اسلامی شهر تهران (نظارت بر مدیریت شهری، انتخاب شهردار و تصویب امور شهرداری) با میزان تحقق حقوق شهروندی، همبستگی مثبت و معناداری وجود دارد. همچنین نتایج رگرسیون، حاکی از آن بودند که از میان ابعاد عملکرد شورای اسلامی شهر تهران، به&#8204;ترتیب متغیرهای انتخاب شهردار، نظارت بر مدیریت شهری و تصویب امور شهرداری، پیش&#8204;بینی&#8204;کننده میزان تحقق حقوق شهروندی هستند؛ لذا فراهم آوردن سازوکارهای مناسب جهت تحقق بهتر معیارهای بیان شده در شورای اسلامی شهر تهران، کمک شایانی به ایفای نقش هرچه بهتر این نهاد در تحقق حقوق شهروندی در راستای افزایش کیفیت زندگی شهروندان تهرانی خواهد کرد.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Today, the city and every environment of civil and social life become meaningful to the citizens. The relationship between citizenship and urban management is one of the important issues that have been considered in the field of urban management in the world. One of the factors that can lead to the realization and sustainability of the democratic system in society through public gatherings is the attention to citizens&#8217; rights that can be achieved by the councils to achieve this goal. In a comprehensive glance, the councils have the keyword of civil rights in itself since the philosophy of the council itself is a part of the realization of the criteria and components of the citizenship rights. In other words, the councils are the realization of citizenship rights. In this regard, the present study examines the performance of Tehran City Council in the realization of citizenship rights. This research is applied and survey-descriptive in terms of method. Data collection was carried out in two ways: library-documentary and survey-field with questionnaires. The available sample is 150 employees of the Islamic Council and 384 citizens of Tehran in 2016. To analyze the collected data, SPSS software, T-test, Pearson correlation coefficient and regression were used. The results of this study showed that citizens of Tehran have less than average performance of city council due to lack of proper mechanism for monitoring city affairs and realization of citizenship rights. In addition, there is a positive and significant correlation between the performance of Islamic City Council of Tehran (supervision of urban management, electing mayor and approval of municipal affairs) with the extent of realization of citizenship rights. Moreover, the results of regression test indicates that among the dimensions of the Islamic City Council of Tehran, the variables of electing mayor, the supervision of urban management and approval of municipal affairs predict respectively the extent of realization of citizenship rights. Therefore, providing appropriate mechanisms to better realization of these criteria in the Islamic City Council of Tehran will help to play the best role of this institution in realizing citizenship rights in order to increase Tehran citizens&#8217; quality of life.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>citizenship, citizenship rights, urban management, Islamic City Council, city of Tehran</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>شهروندی, حقوق شهروندی, مدیریت شهری, شورای اسلامی شهر, شهر تهران</keyword>
	<start_page>113</start_page>
	<end_page>131</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-158-67&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Salari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Edalat University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>محمد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سالاری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>0031947532846003515</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846003515</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه عدالت، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Maryam</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Safavi Soha</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Art and Architecture, Islamic Azad University, South Tehran Branch, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>مریم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>صفوی سهی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Maryamsafavii20@gmail.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846003516</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846003516</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی تهران جنوب، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
