<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <ArticleSet>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2345-2870</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-6398</EISSN>
			<Volume>6</Volume>
			<Issue>23</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2018</Year>
				<Month>9</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>An Assessment of the Logical Value of Comprehensive Urban Development Plans of Tehran</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>13</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Alireza</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Javid</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Faculty of Architecture and Urban Development, University of Science and Technology, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>A_r_javid@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mostafa</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Behzadfar</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Faculty of Architecture and Urban Development, University of Science and Technology, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI>10.29252/iueam.6.23.1</DOI>
	<Abstract>Integration of assessment with planning process is one of the distinctive features of modern urban planning. In response to the need for comprehensive and integrated thinking, to evaluate and analyze complex and changing urban issues, assessment has become a basic issue in urban planning process aiming to explain the value of urban programs in terms of influencing urban development, formulate the program and implement social interventions, and improve management. Despite significant advances in theoretical approaches and evaluation methods, scientific evaluation of the status of comprehensive urban development plans has not yet been carried out in our country. It is also difficult to deal with the environmental requirements based on the recognition of the problem and to find appropriate problem solving techniques. The purpose of this research is to provide a conceptual model and to assess of comprehensive urban development plans developed for Tehran, and to explore the bases that make the evaluation of comprehensive urban planning fragile. Therefore, the available sources and theoretical literature were reviewed and the evaluation approach, criteria and sub-criteria were identified to define the evaluation framework of the stated programs. The criteria and sub-criteria were determined by analytical-comparative methodology, with library studies and expert opinions. Then it was localized and adapted to meet the ground conditions of Iran through deep interviews with experts. Finally, the significance and application of each criteria and sub-criteria was evaluated using the questionnaire by the main custodians of comprehensive urban development programs in Tehran. The results of the evaluation in this research are based on the fact that the comprehensive urban development plans prepared for Tehran have a low logical value. In addition, the answer to the complexity problem is the main problem and the most important evaluation problem.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>assessment, Logical Value, Comprehensive Urban Development Plans, City of Tehran </Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iueam.ir/article-1-956-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iueam.ir/article-1-956-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2345-2870</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-6398</EISSN>
			<Volume>6</Volume>
			<Issue>23</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2018</Year>
				<Month>9</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>An Assessment of the Causal Model of Effective Metrics on Urban Competitiveness Using a Fuzzy DEMATEL Approach</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>15</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>33</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Firouz</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Jamali</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Faculty of Planning and Environmental Sciences, University of Tabriz, Tabriz, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Shahrivar</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Rosteai</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Department of Geography and Urban Planning, Faculty of Planning and Environmental Sciences, University of Tabriz, Tabriz, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammad</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Yapang Gharavi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Faculty of Planning and Environmental Sciences, University of Tabriz, Tabriz, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>gharavi65@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI>10.29252/iueam.6.23.15</DOI>
	<Abstract>At the beginning of the 21st century, globalization and innovation in the field of information technology and, consequently, the formation of the flow of space, have made cities, in national spaces, like multinational corporations, increasingly compete gain economic benefits. In the past, competition was associated with companies and manufacturing institutions, but as globalization and networking of the global economy began to emerge, cities have always enjoyed a special status as a node in network economy, and it is believed that the competition is at the same level with national competition. Today, perhaps one of the most successful ways to transform a city into a city with a successful economy is to use the concept of a competitive city. Competitiveness of cities has a crucial role in urban development, and in this way, it will provide sustainable revenues for urban managers in these urban areas. Therefore, this research has been conducted with the aim of explaining the causal model of effective measures on the competitiveness of the city. The present research is applied in terms of purpose, and descriptive-causal based on method. The statistical sample of the study consisted of 30 experts related to urban economics. In order to achieve the aim of the study, fuzzy DEMATEL technique was used. The research findings indicated that based on D-R values, among the four criteria of urban competitiveness, the economic criterion with the value of 0.833 is the most influential and the environmental criteria with the value of 0.689 has been influenced the most of urban competitiveness. In addition, based on D+R-values, the economic criterion with the value of (2.671) was identified as the most important criterion for urban competitiveness.&#160;</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Assessment, Urban Competitiveness, City Economy, Fuzzy Dematel </Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iueam.ir/article-1-957-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iueam.ir/article-1-957-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2345-2870</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-6398</EISSN>
			<Volume>6</Volume>
			<Issue>23</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2018</Year>
				<Month>9</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>An extraction and Analysis of the Return Risk of Real Estate Industry, (Based on Value at Risk Based on Markov Approach)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>35</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>54</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mahdi</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Zolfaghari</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Department of Economics, Tarbiyat Modarres University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>M.zolfaghari@modares.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Fatemeh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Faghihiyan</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Central Tehran Branch, Islamic Azad University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI>10.29252/iueam.6.23.35</DOI>
	<Abstract>Today, any attempt to invest in any economic activity, requires the knowledge and access to some components of its activities. One of the important components of investment is knowledge about investment risk according to the expected return in that activity. One of the main areas of investment in the country is investment on housing, which could take place directly or indirectly (through financial markets). In this regard, the importance of awareness of the risk in indirect investment on the housing sector considering to the nature of the financial markets is more necessary. But despite the importance of knowledge about risk, quantification methods developed for the past few years have not had much development. Therefore in this research we proposed a new model for measuring the share return risk of companies in real estate industry. This model is not only able to cover much of the shortcomings of current methods, but also able to extract the risk of stock returns in different states. The present model has been designed based on the &#34;value at risk&#34; and using the Markov process on parametric methods. This mechanism, in addition to taking into account the risk regime transfers is designed based on a set of models that they have got a variety of normal and abnormal distribution functions based on symmetric and asymmetric behavior. The results showed that the return of the company&#8217;s stock in housing sector follows form regime transfers and has got the GED distribution based on asymmetrical models.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>GARCH family risk, Markov chain process, real estate industry</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iueam.ir/article-1-958-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iueam.ir/article-1-958-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2345-2870</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-6398</EISSN>
			<Volume>6</Volume>
			<Issue>23</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2018</Year>
				<Month>9</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Expanding Higher Education Centers on the Use of Its Surrounding Areas in Tabriz Metropolis</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>55</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>65</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Nader</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Zali</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Department of Urban Development, Faculty of Art and Architecture, University of Gilan, Gilan, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>n.zali54@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mahdi</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Moradi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Faculty of Environmental Sciences and Architecture, University of Tabriz, Tabriz, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI>10.29252/iueam.6.23.55</DOI>
	<Abstract>The development of university centers is one of the causes of the modern physical alteration of cities and has a major impact on the development process of the city. This research studies the impact of university centers on changing and developing the use of spaces around Tabriz Metropolis. The research tools included observation and direct field studies, reviewing the maps of in 1968, 1996 and 2011 and using the base map in 2006 and changes made in the courses have been reviewed. GIS and SPSS software were used to analyze the maps. The statistical sample of this research is 480 uses around five universities (Tabriz State University, Medical Sciences, Payam Noor, Arts and Islamic Azad University of Tabriz). The research findings show the impact of university centers on changing land use patterns and urban development, especially the development of service and business spaces around these centers. Estimating the socioeconomic and cultural effects of academic centers on the surrounding uses has doubled the importance of changing the approach in the preparation of urban plans, the proper prediction of the effects of shaping factors and favorable landscape for the future of the city and the quantitative and qualitative development.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Higher Education Centers, Metropolis of Tabriz, Use of Surrounding Spaces</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iueam.ir/article-1-959-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iueam.ir/article-1-959-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2345-2870</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-6398</EISSN>
			<Volume>6</Volume>
			<Issue>23</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2018</Year>
				<Month>9</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Organizational productivity with the maintenance of human resources talents: providing a model (A Study on National Iranian Gas Company)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>67</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>80</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Azadeh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Ghamari</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Faculty of Management, Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>HassanReza</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Zeinabadi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Department of Educational Administration, Faculty of Management, Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>Zeinabadi_hr@khu.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hamidreza</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Arasteh</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Department of Educational Administration, Faculty of Management, Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammadreza</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Behrangi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Department of Educational Administration, Faculty of Management, Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Targeted maintaining and keeping employees is a cost-effective effort that leads to organizational productivity. In this regard, the present study uses a qualitative method to deal with the mechanisms of maintaining human resource talents at National Iranian Gas Company (NIGC). For this purpose, purposefully and snowball semi-structured deep interviews were conducted with 10 senior managers, deputies, experts of NIGC, and 6 faculty members. Interpretative analysis was used to analyze the data from the interviews. The validity of the findings of the qualitative section was verified through review by members (interviewees) and multi-sensory data sources. Test- retest reliability method was used to test the reliability or compatibility of the encodings. The results indicated that, according to the senior managers, experts and talents of NIGC, the mechanisms of human resource talents maintanance at NIGC include nine components; performance-based payment, providing self-actualization needs, providing material needs, merit-based reward system, delegation of authority, special service compensation system, the quality and desirability of working life, clear career path, and job security.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Model, Human Resource Mainatance, National Iranian Gas Company, Organizational Productivity</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iueam.ir/article-1-960-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iueam.ir/article-1-960-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2345-2870</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-6398</EISSN>
			<Volume>6</Volume>
			<Issue>23</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2018</Year>
				<Month>9</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Determining the Optimal Structure of Tehran Municipality Income Basis Based on Risk and Returns</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>81</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>95</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ali Akbar</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Gholizadeh</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Department of Economics, Faculty of Economics and Social Sciences, Bu-Ali Sina University, Hamedan, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>z_aliak@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mahdi</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Aminirad</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Faculty of Economics and Social Sciences, Bu-Ali Sina University, Hamedan, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The financial health of municipal budgets is of great importance, and its feedback is the ability of the municipality to provide optimal and continuous services to citizens. In recent decades, due to the lack of financial resources of municipalities, the key problem in the development of the cities of the country was the non-compliance of municipal expenditures and income from the structure of the city economy. The metropolitan municipality, unlike the state that is dependent on oil revenues, has no source of income but urban economy (sales of congestion, dues, etc.) Moreover, the survival of the organization and its services depend on the dynamism and reliability of its economy. Given the importance of municipal revenue structure, in this study, the income and expenditure structure of Tehran Municipality was compared with selected municipalities, then, using Tehran Municipality data during the period of 2001-2015 and Markowitz&#8217;s model, the share of each income code based on minimizing risk, maximizing expected returns, and Sharp&#8217;s benchmark in the income portfolio of Tehran Municipality was estimated. The results showed that Tehran Municipality&#8217;s revenue structure is not suitable and has a significant difference with estimated weights based on the maximization criteria of expected returns, risk minimization and Sharp&#8217;s benchmark.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Budget Optimization, Local Government, Income Portfolio, Risk and Returns, Tehran Municipality</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iueam.ir/article-1-961-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iueam.ir/article-1-961-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2345-2870</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-6398</EISSN>
			<Volume>6</Volume>
			<Issue>23</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2018</Year>
				<Month>9</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Resisting Urban Economy by Optimizing Efficient Urban Population</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>97</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>110</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Nasser</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Yarmohammadian</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Department of Economics and Entrepreneurship, Art University of Isfahan, Isfahan, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>n.yarmohamadian@aui.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Resistance economy is a term come across in literature of Iran economy that include lots of paper in this topic. Cities in national economy are a basis of production. Primer cities and metropolises are economy engines that cover major of goods and services production, and they are most important market for the goods and services produced in these cities, so that if these regions were not existed or the population was distributed sporadically or evenly, such a mass production and market volume were not formed. Given the importance of the metropolitan scale in the economy, based on urban economic theories, it is possible to determine efficient population of cities toward resistive urban economy. In this paper, resisting cities is analyzed by determining efficient population of cities. For calculating efficient population of city, urban social welfare function is specified and estimated. Results show Tehran population exceed efficient population level and bringing the efficient size to the actual size or vice versa by controlling urban population can resist urban economy, and consequently the national economy. Control policy is not enough for resisting urban economy but urban development and urban infrastructure development policies are recommended to increase the capacity of the city.&#160;</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Efficient Scale, Urban Economics, Resistance Economy, Resisting Cities</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iueam.ir/article-1-962-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iueam.ir/article-1-962-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2345-2870</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-6398</EISSN>
			<Volume>6</Volume>
			<Issue>23</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2018</Year>
				<Month>9</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The Role of Public Spaces in the Realization of City Prosperity and Sustainable Development</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>111</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>124</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Sajjad Mohammad</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Yarzadeh</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Department of Management, Faculty of Management, West Tehran Branch, Islamic Azad University, Tehran, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>ayarzadeh@yamil.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Behnoosh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Shamsollahi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Malaysia University of Science, Penang, Malaysia</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Public spaces are those that embrace a wide range of citizens from child to old, woman and man, and with every religion and race; therefore, public spaces have the potential to strengthen social cohesion, economic development, and the improvement of the quality of collective life. The realization of these issues requires the consideration of the design and visual quality of public spaces so that these spaces are able to significantly reduce environmental stimuli and increase the vitality of the society. Correct management of public spaces can informally increase the collective knowledge and individual and social skills of urban residents. This is achieved in the light of people&#8217;s participation in the economic, political and administrative affairs of the city as well as the increase in the level of their social interactions. Of course, the role of environmental-physical elements, such as symbols and signs, should not be ignored in raising awareness and citizens&#8217; visual perception. Accordingly, public spaces should be considered as a platform for encouraging citizens to participate and accept social responsibilities in order to transfer knowledge and awareness to improve citizens&#8217; quality of life. Therefore, in this research, it has been attempted to study the issues that need attention to urban public spaces management while studying the literature of city prosperity and sustainable development. In terms of method, this research is descriptive-analytic. The results indicated that development and attention to public spaces lead to economic development of city, improvement of citizens&#8217; health and education, and rebuilding the local identities of the city.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>public spaces, city prosperity, sustainable development</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iueam.ir/article-1-963-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iueam.ir/article-1-963-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
 </ArticleSet>
 
  
  
  
  
 