<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title> Journal of Urban Economics and Management </title>
<link>http://www.iueam.ir</link>
<description>Journal of Urban Economics and Management - Journal articles for year 2015, Volume 3, Number 11</description>
<generator>Yektaweb Collection - https://yektaweb.com</generator>
<language>en</language>
<pubDate>2015/9/10</pubDate>

					<item>
						<title>Evaluation of Tourism Sidewalks Recreation Potentials from the Perspective of Urban Sustainable Development (The case of 15 Khordad Avenue - Tehran) </title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=193&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0.0001pt; text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;Tourism sidewalks are the main interface and link among urban dynamic spaces and tourists, they can be counted as a basic factor of urban tourism development and active presence of tourists in addition to economic and social role.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 12pt line-height: 115% font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif&quot;&gt;&lt;!--stripped--&gt;&lt;!--stripped--&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0.0001pt; text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;Tehran, particularly the main range of urban central context in Tehran (Tehran Grand Bazaar) and 15 Khordad Avenue with tourism capacities and people excessive use of it (merchants and local people), does not have welfare facilities special for urban tourism. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 12pt line-height: 115% font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif&quot;&gt;&lt;!--stripped--&gt;&lt;!--stripped--&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;The main purpose of this research is investigating international successful experiences and comparing urban sidewalks routes and identifying these capabilities via accomplished recreation in physical space of Tehran 15 Khordad Avenue sidewalk. Therefore, it is appropriate that in addition to review of accomplished recreation in the route of 15 Khordad Avenue&amp;rsquo;s sidewalk, in terms of cases such as space and geographic perspective, route distance, using tourism signs, recreational facilities, suitable attractions and health facilities along the path, can be used as a desirable solution in redefining this route and similar places. It is tried that weaknesses and strengths of the above route would be identified by using SWOT analysis model from tourism perspective and to achieve this important matter, scientific and practical strategies were presented parallel with tourism development.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0.0001pt text-align: justify&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
						<author>Nasser Aminian</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Optimal Allocation of Construction Budget in Isfahan Municipality (Goal Programming Approach) </title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=195&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;With the complexity advent of cities and increase of their problems, municipalities manage the problems of cities by employing strategies such as City Development Strategy (CDS). This research has a descriptive &amp;ndash; analytic essence, which it sets to the application of Goal Programming model for optimal allocation of construction budget of Isfahan Municipality. It has been tried to identify the most important construction budget&amp;rsquo;s constraints, Non-priority sectors in the allocation of construction budget, model goals and the impact of subsections of construction budget in achieving the objectives of CDS and checking out the achievement of CDS objectives with current budget management method. The target society includes all the staffs of Isfahan Municipality and 11 of them have been selected for the sample size in non&amp;ndash;random manner. In order to analyze the values in years 2011 to 2014, Goal Programming model was used. Some of the required data were collected by using the questionnaire and some of them were extracted from the Municipality documents. According to the model stipulated in three forms, the results of the most complete model indicated that because of the lack of appropriate models for planning the credits and relying on the bargaining power, the allocation of the construction budget was not optimal in any years and the given values to variables do not achieve the goals mentioned in the CDS, and the credits in some subsections were considered more or less than enough, and goal programming model will be a useful tool in determining the optimal values in future years.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
						<author>Seyyedeh Mahboobeh Hosseini</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Clarification the Role of Intellectual Capital in Tendency to Organizational Citizenship Behavior of Bank Shahr Staffs</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=196&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;In the recent decade, intellectual capital has become increasingly important, with the introducing of knowledge-based economy in the organizations. The purpose of this research is clarification the role of intellectual capital in tendency to organizational citizenship behavior of Bank Shahr staffs. The method of this research is descriptive- correlational, and its target society is all the 2204 staffs of Bank Shahr-Tehran City. 327 people were selected randomly as a research sample by using Cochran sampling formula. Two standard questionnaires of Bonti&amp;rsquo;s intellectual capital and Podsakoff&amp;rsquo;s organizational citizenship behavior were used for data collection. In order to statistical analysis of data, &amp;ldquo;r&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;R&amp;rdquo; were used respectively for the coefficient of Pearson correlation and stepwise regression. The results showed that there is a positive and significant correlation between intellectual capital and its dimensions (human capital, customer capital/relational, structural capital) with tendency to organizational citizenship behavior of Bank Shahr staffs. furthermore, the results of stepwise regression indicated that among intellectual capital dimensions (predictor variables): structural capital predictor variables and relational capital are the predictors of tendency to organizational citizenship behavior of Bank Shahr staffs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
						<author>Seyyed Mohammadtaqi Taqavifard</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Spatial Analysis of Prosperity Levels in Tehran Metropolis From the Perspective of Urban Economics </title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=197&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;Currently, one of the urban management challenges is balanced spatial distribution of services and economic and social indicators in response to citizens. One of the factors of the formation of inequalities in Tehran districts is the physical growth and development of Tehran Metropolis and lack of proportional and coordinate distribution of facilities and urban services with it. The purpose of this research is evaluation and analysis of prosperity levels of Tehran Metropolis districts in terms of having economic, social, physical, cultural, servicing and recreational. For the spatial analysis of justice status in Tehran Metropolis, at first research indicators were loaded into four factors: economic, social, physical and servicing-recreational, with &amp;ldquo;R&amp;rdquo; factor analysis model and then, each of the indicators of 22 districts of Tehran Metropolis were graded by using the hybrid model of human development&amp;nbsp;and cluster analysis according to rating factor. The results show that among 22 districts of Tehran Metropolis, district 6 has the highest development degree at a rate of 0/95, and districts 3, 1, 2 and 7 are half-prosperous ones. Generally, in terms of prosperity of consolidated indicators, 4.55 of Tehran Metropolis districts are prosperous, 18.18 of them are half-prosperous and 77.27 of them are non-prosperous .&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
						<author>sajjad ahmadi</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Developing an Effective Model of Learning Transfer in order to Return on Investment in the Development of Human Resources Emphasising on Urban Management</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=198&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;Organizations invest high amounts annually in order to improve the staff&amp;rsquo;s performance in the field of training and learning. Despite the great deal of attention to training and its programs, accomplished studies suggest that many of these programs do not have required effectiveness in terms of learning transfer and transmission of learned skills to the workplace, as an important effective indicators of training programs, have done very little and the rate of the obtained capital return on investment is very low for them. So, awareness of predisposing or obstacle factors of learning transfer to the workplace and consequently investment return in human resources for organizations are of great importance specially for banks and municipalities. Therefore, models and current studies regarding the learning transfer were investigated in this research and an effective model of learning transfer was presented parallel with return on investment in human resources development&amp;nbsp;emphasising on urban management. The results showed that major factors of learning transfer from training environment to the workplace include individual and organizational factors. Individual ones are those influencing on the knowledge use and acquired skill from training environment in workplace and include motivation, attitude, self-efficacy and personality characteristics. Organizational factors are those related to the workplace and they influence on learning transfer and its use of whatsoever learned during training courses and they include support, responsiveness, job career, organizational climate and individual results.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
						<author>Alireza Youzbashi</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Sustainable Financing Strategies of Tehran Municipality in the Five-Year Plan, Emphasizing Issued Resistive Economy Policies</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=199&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;Financing is one of the most important responsibilities of public institutions such as municipalities. Financial sources of municipalities are receivable in different ways, but all of them do not have feature of sustainable revenues. It needs that firstly these items have relative continuity and secondly access to these revenues should not threaten and destroy the qualitative conditions of the city. The purpose of this research is presentation of sustainable financing strategies of Tehran Municipality in five-year plan emphasizing resistive economy policies by using descriptive-analytic method. To achieve this goal, at first provisions of sustainable revenue sources in the second five-year plan of Tehran Municipality were extracted and then sustainable and unsustainable revenues of Tehran Municipality were studied and identified and finally sustainable financing strategies in Tehran Municipality was presented. The results show that major part of the main revenues of municipalities is not compatible with concepts of sustainability and do not have continuity and desirability. So this necessity arises that it is better municipalities should have new strategies for sustainable and continuous revenue financing by studying the revenue structure so as to present optimal service to citizens.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
						<author>Nemat Hosseinzadeh</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>A Measurement of Passengers’ Satisfaction Rate from Bus Rapid Transit (BRT) System in Tabriz Metropolis Emphasizing on Predictive Models</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=200&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;With rising demand of urban travels, one of the main strategies to manage cities&amp;rsquo; transport is enhancement the share of urban public transport. To increase the desirability of the use of public transport, various systems were designed and utilized. One of them is BRT. Immediate action was carried out in Tabriz Metropolis to use this system in the main street of the city leaded to disrupt the urban communications network and different problems. This research evaluated the goals and strategies of BRT system and the degree of users&amp;rsquo; satisfaction of it in Tabriz by using field studies and statistical analysis. It has a descriptive-survey essence and data were collected by the researcher made questionnaire. Target society includes the passengers using BRT. The method of sampling is clustering and the designed questionnaire was reviewed via pre-test, its stability was verified by Cronbach alpha of 0.727 and its validity confirmed by presenting to experts and specialists. To prove statistical assumption, Kendall statistics, Summer&amp;rsquo;s Day, Chi-square, Pearson&amp;rsquo;s correlation and ordinal regression were used. The results show that there is an inverse and significant correlation among education and satisfaction rate of BRT system. It means that with increasing levels of education, the satisfaction decreases.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
						<author>Nader Zaali</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Designing Interactive Model of Perceived Security and Citizen Trust and Their Impacts on the Acceptance of Internet Banking (The Case of Khoy City)</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=201&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;Nowadays, learning to use internet provides an opportunity for financial institutes and banks to benefit from it in their own favor in such turbulent competitive environment. In this regard, this research studies simultaneous role of perceived security, citizens&amp;rsquo; trust and satisfaction on the acceptance of internet banking services. Statistical population of the research is customers of Bank Melli in the city of Khoy. Sample size was 392 according to Cochran's formula. Samples were chosen by using single- stage cluster sampling. In order to measure validity of the questionnaire, Confirmatory Factor Analysis (CFA) was used in first and second orders and Cronbach alpha was used for the test reliability. Research hypothesis were studied with the help of structural equation model i.e. path analysis. The results of the analysis indicated that the perceived security both directly and through trust and citizens&amp;rsquo; satisfaction, has a significant and positive effect on the acceptance of internet banking from citizens&amp;rsquo; attitude.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
						<author>Morteza Akbarzadeh Safavi</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>The Effective Factors on Private Sector Cooperation as an Approach to Finance Sustainable Recourses of Municipality Projects</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=202&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;Absorbing finances from the private and foreign sectors for implementation of municipalities&amp;rsquo; projects are counted as valid methods of providing financial resources in urban management field. Currently, one of the main approaches in urban and rural management fields in the country is reducing dependencies on governmental aids and dues and moving toward identifying T stable earnings and new instruments of providing financial resources such as: attracting domestic and foreign investors.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 12pt line-height: 115% font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif letter-spacing: -0.3pt &quot;&gt;&lt;!--stripped--&gt;&lt;!--stripped--&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;The main goal of this research is studying the effective factors on the participation of private sector providing stable financial recourses for municipality projects. According to the collected data, part of the potential investors do not participate in urban projects, therefore, using usual econometric methods have incompatible results. In order to estimate the parameters of this function, Logit and Probit method based on the maximum likelihood function is used. It is necessary to mention that for estimating function, Stata software is used. The statistical population is Tabriz city and its municipality. Required data were collected via survey method and the instruments of data collection were questionnaire and field findings. In this study, random sampling method was used and for determining the required sample size Cochran formula and Morgan table were used. The findings of this research show that factors such as improving business environment and efficient laws which guarantee the profit of private functionary make private sector increase the implementation of urban projects, and the presence of bureaucracy and lack of suitable capacity building delay the process mutually.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
						<author>Seyyed Kamal Sadeqi</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
	</channel>
</rss>
