<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title> Journal of Urban Economics and Management </title>
<link>http://www.iueam.ir</link>
<description>Journal of Urban Economics and Management - Journal articles for year 2018, Volume 6, Number 22</description>
<generator>Yektaweb Collection - https://yektaweb.com</generator>
<language>en</language>
<pubDate>2018/6/11</pubDate>

					<item>
						<title>Sustainable Technology Assessment Model in Tehran’s Urban Transportation</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=902&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px;&quot;&gt;Considering the current problems in the field of transportation in Tehran, this paper attempts to develop a sustainable technology assessment model in Tehran&amp;rsquo;s urban transport sector. The research was carried out in a mixed method. In the qualitative phase, using the principles of the data theory of the foundation, identifying the important components in the technology evaluation and compiling the paradigm model, was performed and in the quantitative phase, using the confirmatory factor analysis, the developed model was tested. The results of the study indicated that the topic of assessment of sustainable technology in the urban transport sector of Tehran is related to the use of urban transportation technologies. Due to population growth and consequently the increasing demand for urban travel, the expansion of marginalization and migration around Tehran and limited natural and ecological resources, and energy resources are created. Strategies such as strategic and prospective planning in the urban transport sector of Tehran, capacity of transportation in proportion to the demand for urban travel, assessment of compliance with requirements, national and international regulations, assessment of the economic justification of sustainable technology in the field of transportation and the possibility of creating the necessary investment with the resistance economy approach, evaluation of qualitative and technical functional considerations in the field of urban transport, assessment and monitoring of environmental impacts and life cycle analysis of transportation technologies, the use of clean and low carbon energy in transportation equipment, and so on are suggested. The strategies are influenced by the values and culture of society, the level of knowledge and public understanding of society from the risks of unsustainable technologies in the field of transportation, urbanization culture and observance of laws and regulations in the field of transportation by people and characteristics of Tehran in terms of climatic, demographic, geographical, political, infrastructure, and engineering aspects. It is expected that the implementation of the mentioned strategies could lead to events and consequences such as promoting the status of Iran in international rankings, promoting physical and mental health, vitality and welfare of the society, and labor force productivity, optimal utilization of urban infrastructure and facilities, promoting the level of knowledge and attitudes towards the use of sustainable technologies in transport, sustainable economic growth, entrepreneurship and employment, efficiency and positive performance in the field of urban transport and the environmentally sound and productive urban environment.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
						<author>Alireza Minoo</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>A Comparative Study of Islamic Contracts and Islamic Banking Support Contracts (A Study on Bank Shahr)</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=903&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;Islam emphasizes all social issues, especially healthy economic relations. What has led to the need to examine and address the issues of contracts in Islam and the contracts of support in Islamic banking, is the existence of various contracts in the society. In this research, it is tried to examine the compatibility of the contracts of support in Islamic banking with the contractual and religious principles recommended in Islam, after defining and clarifying the contracts and principles in the verses of the Holy Quran and explaining its nature. Identifying types of contracts, examining the foundations of legitimacy and clarifying their pillars and effects in support contracts in Islamic banking, and observing all aspects of it in current affairs of the bank have been done. The main question of the present research is to what extent Bank Shahr support contracts comply with the provisions of the recommendations and orders in Islamic contracts. In this regard, five types of contracts used to support Bank Shahr have been investigated in order to comply with the recommended conditions in the Quranic verses of the Holy Quran. The research method in this study is integrated content analysis. The research findings showed that in three types of banking contracts -purchase of items, design, procurement and commissioning of equipment, service and maintenance of equipment-, up to 82% of compliance and in two types of contracts - assignment of interests and the right to exploit land and lease property-, there is up to 91% compliance with Islamic conditions and recommendations for contracting.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
						<author>Mohammadreza Javid</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>An Explanation of City Branding Model in order to Promote City Competitiveness and Economic Growth by Using of F'ANP Model</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=905&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px;&quot;&gt;In recent decades, cities are seeking for new ways to promote themselves and economic growth; hence, in order to attract capital and enter to competition arena, city managers increasingly pay attention to optimal use of urban assets. In these competitive conditions, governments have focused on strengthening marketing activities and city branding for improving competitiveness. In this regard, this research tries to investigate the concepts and views on city branding, competitiveness and urban economic growth to extract the indicators of each, and then, by prioritizing extracted indices, will present a conceptual model of urban branding in line with competitiveness and the growth of urban economy. The research method based on purpose is applied and based on data collection is a library- survey research. Data collection instrument is questionnaire. In order to data analysis, F'ANP model is used in order to use the inherent advantages of the factor analysis method, the subject first analyze the dimensions of the constituent and then using the ANP method, these dimensions, elements and the relationship between the elements and the cluster to be investigated. The statistical sample consisted of professors and Ph.D. students of urbanization of Islamic Azad University, Science and Research and Shahr Qods branches, and simple random sampling was used. Factor analysis was performed using 21 indicators and using SPSS software. The results of the research indicated the importance and necessity of considering the principles of urban branding, such as creating urban attractions, creating distinct advantages of the place, increasing participation and productivity, connecting and communicating cities, improving the location, developing creativity, preserving and developing urban assets in the field of improving competitiveness and as a result the growth of the urban economy. Finally, strategies and suggestions for branding of cities are also being proposed to promote competitiveness and urban economic growth.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
						<author>Zahra Sadat  Saeideh Zarabadi</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>An Analysis of Spatial Distribution Pattern of Knowledge-Based Activities in Tehran</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=906&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;World urban economy accompanied with knowledge and information economy, so metropolitan areas drastically compete for attracting, developing knowledge-based and information activities, and promoting their competitive advantages. This research tries to identify the effective criteria on location selection of activities by explaining the spatial distribution pattern of knowledge-based activities in Tehran. The research method is mixed and the population of the study includes 560 knowledge-based companies in Tehran. Purposefully, 50 managers of Tehran&amp;rsquo;s knowledge-based companies were interviewed to identify and prioritize the criteria for choosing the locations of companies, using Delphi techniques. Linear regression analysis was used in GIS software to analyze the data quantitatively and to find out the relationship between the location of activities and the criteria for locating. The findings of this study showed that access criteria to main arteries, access to fast transportation lines and access to the subway have the most explanatory power. Contrary to traditional theories of location, there is no significant relationship between the cost of ownership or lease and the location of knowledge-based activities in Tehran. Statistical analysis complementary to regression analysis identified university decisions to locate knowledge-based growth centers, as an effective unknown factor on current spatial distribution pattern. The results of this research provide a suitable tool for urban planners to revive the spatial arrangement of knowledge-based activities in Tehran with the aim of improving performance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
						<author>Mohammadreza Poorjafar</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Spatial Analysis and Prioritization of the Intra-Regional Housing Gap Using the Techniques of Planning (A Study on the Cities of Ilam Province)</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=907&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;Housing has always been the most important thing is human life. Having a safe, secure and comfortable shelter is one of the long-term desires of every human being, but this need is also related to other human needs. On the other hand, today this reality is added to other realities that every phenomenon at any moment is a manifestation of the constant analysis and combination of variables that have regular, continuous, and multiplicative correlations; therefore, in investigating the phenomenon of housing, what is important is the relation and influence of its various aspects. The purpose of this study was to investigate the regional indexes affecting housing in Ilam province using TOPSIS technique. The research method is descriptive-analytical and development-applied, and GIS, GRAFER and EXCEL software have been used. The results of the study showed that the density index in the residential unit in the Ilam province between 1996 and 2006, except in 1997 and 1998, has slightly increased, the trend has improved since 1999and has approached the ideal&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; The average number of households in the residential unit showed that the construction of residential units in the province had been increasing but could not fully compensate for housing shortages. In contrast, the average household in the residential unit in the province had an upward trend. Finally, the TOPSIS model showed that CL was the highest and lowest in the following areas Ilam (0.99), Dehloran (0.13), Ivan (0.09), Mehran (0.08), Abdanan (0.05), Darreshahr (0.04) and Shirvan (0.00).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
						<author>Saeid Maleki</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Determining the Optimal Use of Urban Underground Space (Selected Streets of Isfahan City)</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=908&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;The use of underground spaces can lead to increased land productivity in cities. This paper addresses the issue of which of the four commercial, warehouse, public parking and passageways (two-floor streets) are optimal if we want to use the spaces below the streets of the city. Therefore, the selected 21 main street of districts 5 and 6 of Isfahan were selected as problem options. Using 2013 data and linear programming method, the objective function was designed for optimal user allocation. In the following, based on the two-stage hierarchical analysis method in the GIS software environment, the optimization problem was investigated. In order to investigate in the first stage, the type of use was selected as the main criteria of the problem including parking, warehouse, business center and passage use, and then, for the second step, the sub-criteria of landing price, traffic flow, area of green space and surface were selected. The results from the first phase survey showed which street is more important for which user. In addition, the results from the second phase survey showed which sub-criteria are more relevant in choosing a type of land use. Based on this, it is possible to decide which street is needed and what the priority of which street is to use for underground space. For the use of parking and passage, Shahid Hemmat Highway has the highest score and HezarJarib Street account for the commercial use and warehouse with the highest score.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
						<author>Reza NasrEsfahani</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>The Relationship between Branding of Economic Newspapers and Customers’ Satisfaction in Metropolitan Countries</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=909&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;In this research, the branding of newspapers in metropolises was investigated. The newspapers use different methods to attract their audience, and thus branding can play a significant role for newspapers in attracting customers. Branding leads to better communication between customers and the press. Providing correct information and branding have led to brand associations. In this research, customer satisfaction has also been used to branding. The research method is descriptive-correlational, and the statistical population is the customers of the economic newspapers. 318 people were selected as the sample. A researcher-made questionnaire was used to collect data. To analyze the data, Pearson correlation coefficient and linear regression were used. The results showed that there was a positive and significant correlation between brand awareness, brand loyalty and perceived quality of brand with customer satisfaction, but there was not a significant relationship between the association of the brand of economic newspapers and customer satisfaction. Linear regression results also showed that brand loyalty had a larger share in predicting customer satisfaction.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
						<author>Ali Akbar Farhangi</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Structural Modeling of Effective Factors on Women’s Satisfaction of Public Transport System (Case study: City of Kashan)</title>
						<link>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_id=910&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;Women form half the population and many spaces in cities are used more by them. Women, as a large and active group, use the most possible of the system in cities due to their time constraints. Therefore, the special survey of their traffic patterns in urban public spaces and in particular, the public transportation and bus network of the city have a significant role in increasing the prosperity of urban spaces. The purpose of this paper is to investigate the factors affecting women&amp;rsquo;s satisfaction from urban transportation system. Research method of in this study is descriptive-analytic. The data used in this study were collected through questionnaires and interviews. Then, using SPSS and AMOS software, the existing factors and structural modeling of these factors were investigated. The results showed that among the various indicators such as: services, equipment, seat quality, visual beauty, safety, social factors, security and behavior of the driver, the only factor of visual beauty, had a significant effect on women&amp;rsquo;s satisfaction with the inter-city bus system and other factors with P value greater than 0.05, did not have a significant impact on women&amp;rsquo;s satisfaction.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
						<author>Rasool Heydari Soorshejani</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
	</channel>
</rss>
