<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</title>
<title_fa>فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری</title_fa>
<short_title>IUESA</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iueam.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2345-2870</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-6398</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/iueam</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>en</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1392</year>
	<month>1</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2013</year>
	<month>4</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>1</volume>
<number>2</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تحلیلی بر عوامل عدم تحقق مدیریت واحد شهری از دیدگاه قوانین موجود</title_fa>
	<title>An Analysis of the Factors Preventing the Realization of an Urban Integrated Management through the Lens of Existing Laws</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; dir=&quot;rtl&quot; style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:yekanyw;&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;FA&quot;&gt;در سال&#8204;های اخیر پیچیدگی&#8204;های شهرنشینی در ایران و طرح مباحثی چون توسعه پایدار شهری، توسعه انسانی، تقویت اقتصاد شهر، تأکید بر عدالت اجتماعی، حفظ محیط&#8204;زیست و غیره، مقوله مدیریت شهری را بیش از پیش با مباحث پیچیده و نظام&#8204;مند مواجه نموده است. در نتیجه با توجه به گستره امور، نیاز به رویکردی تازه در مدیریت شهری از سویی و راهبردهای دولت و ایجاد تحول در ساختار اداری و مدیریتی کشور از سوی دیگر، لزوم توجه به شهرداری&#8204;ها و واگذاری وظایف جدید را توجیه کرده است. اما امروزه با تمام تأکیدها و تلاش&#8204;هایی که به ظاهر و در عمل صورت می&#8204;گیرد، سیستم واحد و مناسبی در نظام مدیریت شهری کشور تحقق نیافته است. در نبود مدیریت یکپارچه شهری، نابسامانی، ناهماهنگی، اتلاف منابع اعم از انسانی و مادی و بالاخره نارضایتی فزاینده شهروندان گریزناپذیر خواهد بود. بر همین اساس، طرح موضوع مدیریت یکپارچه شهری و تحلیل سیستم مدیریت شهری موجود در کشور، جهت رفع موانع و کاستی&#8204;ها، می&#8204;تواند حائز اهمیت فراوان باشد. در این راستا، روش این پژوهش کتابخانه&#8204;ای و توصیفی- تحلیلی بیان شده است. همچنین هدف از آن بررسی و تبیین مدیریت واحد شهری در قوانین کشور و شناسایی مشکلات و معضلات قانونی آن می&#8204;باشد. در پایان، با استفاده از نتایج به دست آمده، راهکارهایی جهت حل این مشکلات و بهبود یافتن وضعیت موجود مدیریت شهری در کشور پیشنهاد گردید.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;FA&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 12pt line-height: 115% font-family: 'B Nazanin'&quot;&gt;&lt;!--stripped--&gt;&lt;!--stripped--&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;In recent years, the complexities of urbanization in Iran and raising such issues as urban sustainable development, human development, city economy reinforcement, emphasis on social justice, environment preservation, etc. all in all, have made urban management a more complex and sophisticated issue. As a result, with regard to the extent of variables, a need for a new approach to urban management, on the one hand, and the government strategies and making a reform in the administrative and managerial structure of country, on the other hand, has justified the necessity of focusing on municipalities and of assigning new responsibilities to them. However, nowadays, despite all the emphases and efforts, no integrated system has been established in urban management system of the nation. In the absence of an urban integrated management, disorganization, disharmony, waste of resources, both human and financial, and, eventually, the citizens&amp;rsquo; ever-increasing dissatisfaction are inevitable. Thus, the plan for an urban integrated management and the analysis of the current urban management system of the nation are of great importance as they pave the way for removing obstacles and easing the shortcomings. In this regard, the research method has been reported to be descriptive-analytic and library-based. Moreover, the research aims at investigating and clarifying integrated urban management in the nation&amp;rsquo;s rules and regulations and in identifying problems and legal barriers. The research concludes with offering solutions for such problems and improving the status quo in the nation&amp;rsquo;s urban management via obtained results.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;rtl&quot; lang=&quot;FA&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 12pt line-height: 115% font-family: 'B Nazanin'&quot;&gt;&lt;!--stripped--&gt;&lt;!--stripped--&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>قوانین شهری, مدیریت واحد شهری, موانع و راهکارها, شهرداری, شهر</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>urban laws, urban integrated management, obstacles and solutions, municipality, city</keyword>
	<start_page>31</start_page>
	<end_page>50</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1-10&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Ahmad </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Pourahmad</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>احمد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>پوراحمد</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002070</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002070</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Masoumeh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Mahdian Bahnamiri</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>معصومه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مهدیان بهنمیری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002071</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002071</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Golestan University, Golestan, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه گلستان و مدرس دانشگاه پیام نور واحد هادی شهر</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ali </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mahdi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مهدی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002072</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002072</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
