<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>2018</YEAR>
<VOL>6</VOL>
<NO>23</NO>
<MOSALSAL>0</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>124</PAGE_NO>


<ARTICLES>

	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>ارزیابی ارزش منطقی برنامه‌های جامع توسعه شهری تهران</TitleF>
		<TitleE>An Assessment of the Logical Value of Comprehensive Urban Development Plans of Tehran</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>ادغام ارزیابی با فرایند برنامه&#8204;ریزی، یکی از ویژگی&#8204;های متمایز الگوهای نوین شهرسازی است. در پاسخ به ضرورت تفکر جامع و یکپارچه، برای تشخیص و تحلیل ساخت&#8204;مایه پیچیده و متغیر مسائل شهری، ارزیابی به مبحثی پایه در فرایند برنامه&#8204;ریزی شهری تبدیل شده است که هدف اصلی آن، تبیین میزان ارزش برنامه&#8204;های شهر از لحاظ تأثیرگذاری بر توسعه شهری، شکل&#8204;دهی برنامه و اجرای مداخلات اجتماعی و بهبود مدیریت است. علی&#8204;رغم پیشرفت&#8204;های قابل&#8204;توجه در رویکردهای نظری و روش&#8204;های ارزیابی، در کشور ما تاکنون ارزیابی علمی از وضعیت برنامه&#8204;های جامع توسعه شهری انجام نشده و همچنان پرداختن به الزامات محیطی بر مبنای شناخت مسئله و یافتن تکنیک&#8204;های ویژه حل مسئله متناسب با آن، با مشکل مواجه است. هدف این تحقیق، ارائه مدل مفهومی و ارزیابی برنامه&#8204;های جامع توسعه شهری تدوین&#8204;شده برای شهر تهران و شناخت تدقیقی زمینه&#8204;هایی است که شرایط ارزیابی برنامه&#8204;های جامع شهرسازی را شکننده می&#8204;سازد. از این رو منابع و متون نظری موجود بررسی گردید و برای تعریف چارچوب ارزیابی برنامه&#8204;های بیان شده، رویکرد ارزیابی، معیارها و زیرمعیارها شناسایی شدند. معیارها و زیرمعیارها از طریق روش تحلیلی- تطبیقی، با مطالعات کتابخانه&#8204;ای و نظریات متخصصان، تعیین شدند و سپس برای انطباق با شرایط زمینه&#8204;ای ایران از طریق مصاحبه عمیق با صاحب&#8204;نظران، بومی&#8204;سازی و تدقیق گردید. در نهایت اهمیت و کاربست هر معیار و زیرمعیار با به&#8204;کارگیری پرسشنامه توسط متولیان اصلی برنامه&#8204;های جامع توسعه شهری در تهران ارزیابی شد. نتایج ارزیابی در این پژوهش مبتنی بر آن است که برنامه&#8204;های جامع توسعه شهری تهیه شده برای شهر تهران، از ارزش منطقی کمی برخوردارند و پاسخ به مسئله پیچیدگی، اصلی&#8204;ترین مسئله و مهم&#8204;ترین معضل در ارزیابی می&#8204;باشد.&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Integration of assessment with planning process is one of the distinctive features of modern urban planning. In response to the need for comprehensive and integrated thinking, to evaluate and analyze complex and changing urban issues, assessment has become a basic issue in urban planning process aiming to explain the value of urban programs in terms of influencing urban development, formulate the program and implement social interventions, and improve management. Despite significant advances in theoretical approaches and evaluation methods, scientific evaluation of the status of comprehensive urban development plans has not yet been carried out in our country. It is also difficult to deal with the environmental requirements based on the recognition of the problem and to find appropriate problem solving techniques. The purpose of this research is to provide a conceptual model and to assess of comprehensive urban development plans developed for Tehran, and to explore the bases that make the evaluation of comprehensive urban planning fragile. Therefore, the available sources and theoretical literature were reviewed and the evaluation approach, criteria and sub-criteria were identified to define the evaluation framework of the stated programs. The criteria and sub-criteria were determined by analytical-comparative methodology, with library studies and expert opinions. Then it was localized and adapted to meet the ground conditions of Iran through deep interviews with experts. Finally, the significance and application of each criteria and sub-criteria was evaluated using the questionnaire by the main custodians of comprehensive urban development programs in Tehran. The results of the evaluation in this research are based on the fact that the comprehensive urban development plans prepared for Tehran have a low logical value. In addition, the answer to the complexity problem is the main problem and the most important evaluation problem.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>13</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی رضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>جاوید</Family>
				<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Javid</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Architecture and Urban Development, University of Science and Technology, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده معماری و شهرسازی، دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>A_r_javid@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مصطفی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>بهزاد‌فر</Family>
				<NameE>Mostafa</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Behzadfar</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Architecture and Urban Development, University of Science and Technology, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده معماری و شهرسازی، دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>assessment</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Logical Value</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Comprehensive Urban Development Plans</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>City of Tehran</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ارزیابی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ارزش منطقی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>برنامه‌های جامع توسعه شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شهر تهران</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##شریعت، سید محمود؛ منوری، سید مسعود. (1375). مقدمه‌ای بر ارزیابی زیست‌محیطی. تهران: انتشارات سازمان حفاظت محیط‌زیست.##غمامی، مجید. (1371). بررسی و نقد اجمالی طرح‌های جامع شهری. نشریه آبادی، 2(7)، 31-24.##فریور صدری، بهرام. (1393). تحولات طرح‌ریزی شهری ایران در دوران معاصر. تهران: انتشارات آذرخش.##ماجدی، حمید. (1395). نظریه طرح‌های ساختاری- راهبردی شهری و ناحیه‌ای. تهران: دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات.##منصوری، امیر. (1395). نقد و بررسی طرح جامع تهران، 86. تهران: پژوهشکده نظر.##هادی زنوز، بهروز. (1395). ارزیابی تحقق‌پذیری طرح‌های شهری در تهران. مجله هفت شهر، شماره‌های 54-53، 34-8.##Alexander, E. R. (2006). Evolution and status. Where is planning evaluation today and how did it get here. Evaluation in planning: Evolution and prospects, 3-16.##Alexander, E. R. (2006). Problems and prospects: dilemmas in evaluation and directions for the future. Evaluation in planning: Evolution and prospects, 267-76.##Alexander, E. R. (2016). Evaluation in planning: evolution and prospects. Routledge.## Alexander, E. R., &amp; Faludi, A. (1989). Planning and plan implementation: notes on evaluation criteria. Environment and Planning B: Planning and Design, 16(2), 127-140.##Baer, W. C. (1997). General plan evaluation criteria: An approach to making better plans. Journal of the American Planning Association, 63(3), 329-344.## Barbanente, A., &amp; Khakee, A. (2005). Scenarios as an exploratory evaluation approach. Some experiences from southern mediterranean. Beyond benefit cost analysis. Accounting for non-market values in planning evaluation, 225-247.##Berke, P., Backhurst, M., Day, M., Ericksen, N., Laurian, L., Crawford, J., &amp; Dixon, J. (2006). What makes plan implementation successful? An evaluation of local plans and implementation practices in New Zealand. Environment and Planning B: Planning and Design, 33(4), 581-600.##Faludi, A., &amp; Voogd, H. (1985). Evaluation of complex policy problems.##Khakee, A. (1998). Evaluation and planning: inseparable concepts. Town Planning Review, 69(4), 359.## Khakee, A. (2003). The emerging gap between evaluation research and practice. Evaluation, 9(3), 340-352.##Knieling, J., &amp; Othengrafen, F. (2015). Planning Culture—A Concept to Explain the Evolution of Planning Policies and Processes in Europe?. European Planning Studies, 23(11), 2133-2147.##Lichfield, N., Kettle, P., &amp; Whitbread, M. (2016). Evaluation in the Planning Process: The Urban and Regional Planning Series(Vol. 10). Elsevier.      ##Manaugh, K., Badami, M. G., &amp; El-Geneidy, A. M. (2015). Integrating social equity into urban transportation planning: A critical evaluation of equity objectives and measures in transportation plans in North America. Transport policy, 37, 167-176.##Mathur, H. M. (2011). Social impact assessment: a tool for planning better resettlement. Social Change, 41(1), 97-120.## Moroni, S. (2006). Planning, Evaluation and the Public Interest, Ur Alexander, ER (2006) Evaluation in Planning: Evolution and Prospects, Brookfield, VT.## Nijkamp, P., Rietveld, P., &amp; Voogd, H. (2013). Multicriteria evaluation in physical planning (Vol. 185). Elsevier.## Norton, R. K. (2005). More and better local planning: State-mandated local planning in coastal North Carolina. Journal of the American Planning Association, 71(1), 55-71.##Ofek, Y. (2017). Evaluating social exclusion interventions in university-community partnerships. Evaluation and program planning, 60, 46-55.##Oliveira, V., &amp; Pinho, P. (2010). Evaluation in urban planning: Advances and prospects. Journal of Planning Literature, 24(4), 343-361.##Oliveira, V., &amp; Pinho, P. (2010). Measuring success in planning: Developing and testing a methodology for planning evaluation. Town Planning Review, 81(3), 307-332.##Oliveira, V., &amp; Pinho, P. (2011). Bridging the gap between planning evaluation and programme evaluation: The contribution of the PPR methodology. Evaluation, 17(3), 293-307.## Othengrafen, F. (2014). The concept of planning culture: Analysing how planners construct practical judgements in a culturised context. International Journal of E-Planning Research (IJEPR), 3(2), 1-17.##Othengrafen, F. (2016). Uncovering the unconscious dimensions of planning: using culture as a tool to analyse spatial planning practices. Routledge.##Rinaldi, E., Paneghetti, C., Hedorfer, M., De Polignol, E., Cossettini, P., &amp; Patassini, D. (2017). Contextual Knowledge Generated by a Decision Support System for Brownfield Development—The Case of Porto Marghera (Venice, Italy). In Beyond Benefit Cost Analysis (pp. 89-114). Routledge.##Rossi, P. H., Lipsey, M. W., &amp; Freeman, H. E. (2003). Evaluation: A systematic approach. Sage publications.##Rossi, P. H., Schuerman, J., &amp; Budde, S. (1999). Understanding decisions about child maltreatment. Evaluation Review, 23(6), 579-598.##Saalman, H. (1971). Haussmann: Paris Transformed (New York: George Braziller). ##Sakieh, Y., Amiri, B. J., Danekar, A., Feghhi, J., &amp; Dezhkam, S. (2015). Scenario-based evaluation of urban development sustainability: an integrative modeling approach to compromise between urbanization suitability index and landscape pattern. Environment, Development and Sustainability, 17(6), 1343-1365.##Spilková, J., &amp; Vágner, J. (2016). The loss of land devoted to allotment gardening: The context of the contrasting pressures of urban planning, public and private interests in Prague, Czechia. Land Use Policy, 52, 232-239.##Voogd, H. (2017). Evaluation of visitability of public urban places. In Beyond Benefit Cost Analysis (pp. 15-24). Routledge. ## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>ارزیابی الگوی علّی معیارهای مؤثر بر رقابت‌پذیری شهری با رویکرد دیمتل فازی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>An Assessment of the Causal Model of Effective Metrics on Urban Competitiveness Using a Fuzzy DEMATEL Approach</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>در آغاز قرن بیست&#8206;ویکم، جهانی&#8204;شدن و نوآوری در عرصه&#8204;های فناوری اطلاعاتی و به&#8204;تبع آن شکل&#8204;گیری فضای جریان&#8204;ها، سبب شده تا شهرها نیز در فضاهای ملی مانند شرکت&#8204;های چندملیتی، رقابت روزافزونی را برای کسب منافع اقتصادی با یکدیگر داشته باشند. در گذشته رقابت به شرکت&#8204;ها و نهادهای تولیدی مربوط می&#8204;شد ولی با شکل&#8204;گیری جهانی&#8204;شدن و شبکه&#8204;ای شدن اقتصاد جهانی، شهرها همواره به عنوان گره&#8204;های اقتصاد شبکه&#8204;ای، جایگاه ویژه&#8204;ای یافتند و اعتقاد بر این است که این رقابت هم&#8206;سطح با رقابت ملی می&#8204;باشد. امروزه رقابت&#8204;پذیری شهرها نقش اساسی در توسعه شهرها دارد و در این راستا درآمدزایی پایدار را برای مدیران شهری این نواحی شهری فراهم خواهد کرد. از این &#8204;رو این پژوهش با هدف ارزیابی الگوی علّی معیارهای مؤثر بر رقابت&#8204;پذیری شهری انجام&#8204; شده است. تحقیق حاضر با توجه به هدف آن، کاربردی و براساس روش، توصیفی- علّی است. نمونه آماری پژوهش را ۳۰ نفر از کارشناسان و متخصصان مرتبط با اقتصاد شهری تشکیل داده&#8204;اند. به منظور دستیابی به هدف پژوهش، از تکنیک دیمتل فازی استفاده شد. نتایج تحقیق نشان دادند که براساس مقادیر D-R، از بین معیارهای چهارگانه رقابت&#8204;پذیری شهر، معیار اقتصادی با مقدار ۰/۸۳۳، تأثیرگذارترین و معیار محیطی با مقدار ۰/۶۸۹-، تأثیرپذیرترین معیار رقابت&#8204;پذیری شهر بودند. همچنین براساس مقادیر D+R، معیار اقتصادی با مقدار ۲/۶۷۱ به عنوان بااهمیت&#8204;ترین معیار رقابت&#8204;پذیری شهر شناسایی شد.&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>At the beginning of the 21st century, globalization and innovation in the field of information technology and, consequently, the formation of the flow of space, have made cities, in national spaces, like multinational corporations, increasingly compete gain economic benefits. In the past, competition was associated with companies and manufacturing institutions, but as globalization and networking of the global economy began to emerge, cities have always enjoyed a special status as a node in network economy, and it is believed that the competition is at the same level with national competition. Today, perhaps one of the most successful ways to transform a city into a city with a successful economy is to use the concept of a competitive city. Competitiveness of cities has a crucial role in urban development, and in this way, it will provide sustainable revenues for urban managers in these urban areas. Therefore, this research has been conducted with the aim of explaining the causal model of effective measures on the competitiveness of the city. The present research is applied in terms of purpose, and descriptive-causal based on method. The statistical sample of the study consisted of 30 experts related to urban economics. In order to achieve the aim of the study, fuzzy DEMATEL technique was used. The research findings indicated that based on D-R values, among the four criteria of urban competitiveness, the economic criterion with the value of 0.833 is the most influential and the environmental criteria with the value of 0.689 has been influenced the most of urban competitiveness. In addition, based on D+R-values, the economic criterion with the value of (2.671) was identified as the most important criterion for urban competitiveness.&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>15</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>33</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>فیروز</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>جمالی</Family>
				<NameE>Firouz</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Jamali</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Planning and Environmental Sciences, University of Tabriz, Tabriz, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده برنامه‎ریزی و علوم محیطی، دانشگاه تبریز، تبریز، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>شهریور</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>روستایی</Family>
				<NameE>Shahrivar</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rosteai</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Geography and Urban Planning, Faculty of Planning and Environmental Sciences, University of Tabriz, Tabriz, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده برنامه‎ریزی و علوم محیطی، دانشگاه تبریز، تبریز، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>یاپنگ غراوی</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Yapang Gharavi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Planning and Environmental Sciences, University of Tabriz, Tabriz, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده برنامه‎ریزی و علوم محیطی، دانشگاه تبریز، تبریز، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>gharavi65@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Assessment</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Urban Competitiveness</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>City Economy</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Fuzzy Dematel</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ارزیابی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>رقابت‌پذیری شهر</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اقتصاد شهر</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دیمتل فازی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##آقایی، رضا؛ آقایی، اصغر؛ محمدحسینی ناجی‌زاده، رامین. (1394). شناسایی و رتبه‎بندی شاخص‌های کلیدی موثر بر نگهداری و تعمیرات چابک با استفاده از رویکرد دلفی فازی و دیمتل فازی. فصلنامه مدیریت صنعتی، 7(4)، 672-641.##پژویان، جمشید؛ فقیه‎نصیری، مرجان. (1388). اثر رقابت‎مندی بر رشد اقتصادی با رویکرد الگوی رشد درون‌زا. فصلنامه پژوهش‌های اقتصادی ایران، شماره 38، 133-98.##داداش‌پور،‌هاشم؛ احمدی، فرانک. (1389). رقابت‌پذیری منطقه‌ای به مثابه رویکردی نوین در توسعه منطقه‌ای. فصلنامه راهبرد یاس، شماره22، 80-49.##ساسان‌پور، فرزانه؛ حاتمی، افشار. (1396). تحلیل فضایی رقابت‌پذیری آموزشی استان‌های کشور. فصلنامه اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری، 5(19)، 61-45.##سامانی‎کارگری، امیر. (1393). طراحی مدل رقابت‎پذیری شهری با تکیه ‌بر شاخص‌های حکمرانی خوب شهری در بستر فرایند جهانی‌شدن. رساله دکتری دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس.##ضیایی، محمود؛ محمودزاده، سیدمجتبی؛ شاهی، طاهره. (1396). اولویت‌بندی عوامل مؤثر بر پیاده‌سازی مدیریت زنجیره تأمین سبز در صنعت گردشگری. فصلنامه جغرافیا و توسعه، 15(46)، 34-19.##مروتی شریف‌آبادی، علی؛ عزیزی، فاطمه؛ جمشیدی، زینت. (1395). تحلیل عوامل مؤثر بر رضایت گردشگران داخلی استان یزد با استفاده از مدل دیمتل فازی. فصلنامه مطالعات مدیریت گردشگری، 11(33)، 104-85.##نجاتی‌حسینی، سید محمود. (1391). سیاست شهری و دیپلماسی شهری (از نظریه تا تجربه). فصلنامه جامعه‌شناسی تاریخی، 3(2)، 142-117.##نظم‎فر، حسین؛ عشقی چهاربرج، علی؛ علوی، سعیده. (1397). بررسی وضعیت رقابت‎پذیری اقتصادی شهرهای ایران. فصلنامه اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری، 6(22)، 38-23.##وارث، سید حامد؛ محمدی، شاپور؛ پروندی، یحیی. (1391). تأثیر رقابت‌پذیری جهانی (GCI) بر کامیابی اقتصادی کشورها: ارائه مدلی برای ارتقای رقابت‌پذیری ملی ایران. فصلنامه علوم مدیریت ایران، 7(26)، 48-25.##BaykasoğLu, A., KaplanoğLu, V., DurmuşOğLu, Z. D., &amp; ŞAhin, C. (2013). Integrating fuzzy DEMATEL and fuzzy hierarchical TOPSIS methods for truck selection. Expert Systems with Applications, 40(3), 899-907##Boddy, M., &amp; Parkinson, M. (Eds.). (2004). City matters: Competitiveness, cohesion and urban governance. Policy Press.##Borozan, D.) 2009(. Enhancing regional competitivenesst hroughthe entrepreneurship development. Interdisciplinary Management Research, 5,731-747.##Budd, L. &amp; A. Hirmis. (2004). Conceptual framework for regional competitiveness. Regional Studies, 38, 1015-1028.##Camagni, R. (2002). On the concept of territorial competitiveness: Sound ormisleading? Urban Studies, 39(13), 2395–2411.##Cochrane, A. (2007). Competitiveness, the market, and urban entrepreneurialism, Understanding Urban Policy: A Critical Approach.##Herrschel, T. (2013). Competitiveness and sustainability: can ‘smart city regionalism’square the circle?. Urban Studies, 50(11), 2332-2348. ##Jiang, Y., &amp; Shen, J. (2010). Measuring the urban competitiveness of Chinese cities in 2000. Cities, 27(5), 307-314.##Kamal-Chaoui, L., &amp; Robert, A. (2009). Competitive cities and climate change. OECD Regional Development Working Papers, 2009(2), 1.##Lin, G. C. (2002). The growth and structural change of Chinese cities: a contextual and geographic analysis. Cities, 19(5), 299-316.##Malecki, E. J. (2002). Hard and soft networks for urban competitiveness. Urban studies, 39(5-6), 929-945.##Man, T. W., Lau, T., &amp; Chan, K. F. (2002). The competitiveness of small and medium enterprises: A conceptualization with focus on entrepreneurial competencies. Journal of business venturing, 17(2), 123-142.##Martin, R., &amp; Simmie, J. (2008). The theoretical bases of urban competitiveness: does proximity matter?. Revue d’Économie Régionale &amp; Urbaine, (3), 333-351.##Mascareño, A. Sassen. S.(2001) The Global City: New York, London, Tokyo, Princeton University.##Molotch, H., Freudenburg, W., &amp; Paulsen, K. E. (2000). History repeats itself, but how? City character, urban tradition, and the accomplishment of place. American Sociological Review, 791-823##Musterd, S., &amp; Murie, A. (Eds.). (2011). Making competitive cities. John Wiley &amp; Sons.##Pamučar, D., Mihajlović, M., Obradović, R., &amp; Atanasković, P. (2017). Novel approach to group multi-criteria decision making based on interval rough numbers: Hybrid DEMATEL-ANP-MAIRCA model. Expert Systems with Applications, 88, 58-80.##Papa, R., Gargiulo, C.,  Franco, S., Russo, L. (2014). The Evolution of Urban Competitiveness in Italy. The 2nd international virtual Scientific Conference.##Pengfei, N, Kresl, P.K.) 2011( The Global Urban Competitiveness Report:. Edward Elgar Publishing Limited.##Pengfei, N., &amp; Qinghu, H. (2006). Comparative research on the global urban competitiveness. Beijing, China: Chinese Academy for Social Sciences.##Porter, M. E. (2004). Building the Microeconomic Foundations of Prosperity: Findings from the Business Competitiveness Index [interaktyvus]. Geneva: WEF [žiūrėta 2009 m. spalio 25 d.]. Prieiga per internetą:&lt; http://www. weforum. org/pdf/Gcr/GCR_2003_2004/BCI_Chapter. pdf.##Rogerson, R. J. (1999). Quality of life and city competitiveness. Urban studies, 36(5-6), 969-985.##Sáez, L., &amp; Periáñez, I. (2015). Benchmarking urban competitiveness in Europe to attract investment. Cities, 48, 76-85.##Shen, J. (2004). Urban competitiveness and urban governance in the globalizing world. Asian geographer, 23(1-2), 19-36.##Singhal, S., McGreal, S., &amp; Berry, J. (2013). An evaluative model for city competitiveness: Application to UK cities. Land Use Policy, 30(1), 214-222.##Sinkiene, J. (2009). Competitiveness factors of cities in Lithuania. Viesoji politika ir administravimas, (29).##So, M. S., &amp; Shen, J. (2004). Measuring urban competitiveness in China. Asian geographer, 23(1-2), 71-91.##Song, W., &amp; Cao, J. (2017). A rough DEMATEL- based approach for evaluating interaction between requirements of product-service system. Computers &amp; Industrial Engineering, 110, 353-363.##Turok, I. (2004). Cities, regions and competitiveness. Regional Studies, 38(9),1069–1083.##Van Kempen, R., &amp; Murie, A. (2009). The new divided city: Changing patterns in European cities. Tijdschrift voor economische en sociale geografie, 100(4), 377-398.##Wang, G. &amp; J. Shen.( 2002). Research on comprehensive competitiveness of theperpectual-level Chinese cities. Fudan Journal (Social Sciences), 3, 69-78.##Xu, J., &amp; Yeh, A. G. (2005). City repositioning and competitiveness building in regional development: New development strategies in Guangzhou, China. International Journal of Urban and Regional Research, 29(2), 283-308.##Zhao, Q., Xu, H., Wall, R. S., &amp; Stavropoulos, S. (2017). Building a bridge between port and city: Improving the urban competitiveness of port cities. Journal of Transport Geography, 59, 120-133.## ## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>استخراج و تحلیل ریسک بازدهی صنعت انبوه‌سازی، املاک و مستغلات (براساس روش ارزش در معرض ریسک مبتنی بر رهیافت مارکوف) </TitleF>
		<TitleE>An extraction and Analysis of the Return Risk of Real Estate Industry, (Based on Value at Risk Based on Markov Approach)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>امروزه هر اقدامی جهت سرمایه&#8204;گذاری در فعالیت&#8206;های اقتصادی، نیازمند آگاهی و دسترسی به برخی مؤلفه&#8204;های مربوط به آن فعالیت می&#8204;باشد. یکی از مؤلفه&#8204;های مهم در سرمایه&#8204;گذاری، آگاهی از میزان ریسک بازدهی سرمایه&#8204;گذاری با توجه به بازدهی انتظاری در آن فعالیت می&#8204;باشد. یکی از مهم&#8204;ترین حوزه&#8204;های سرمایه&#8204;گذاری در کشور، سرمایه&#8204;گذاری در بخش مسکن می&#8204;باشد که می&#8204;تواند به&#8204;صورت مستقیم یا غیرمستقیم (از طریق بازارهای مالی) صورت گیرد. در این رابطه اهمیت آگاهی از میزان ریسک در سرمایه&#8204;گذاری غیرمستقیم در بخش مسکن با توجه به ماهیت بازارهای مالی بیش&#8204;از پیش ضروری می&#8204;باشد. علی&#8204;رغم اهمیت آگاهی از میزان ریسک، در سال&#8204;های گذشته، روش&#8204;های ارائه شده برای اندازه&#8204;گیری کمی آن توسعه چندانی نداشته است؛ ازاین&#8207;رو در این پژوهش تلاش شده الگوی جدیدی برای اندازه&#8204;گیری ریسک بازدهی سهام شرکت&#8204;های فعال در صنعت انبوه&#8204;سازی، املاک و مستغلات ارائه گردد که نه تنها قادر است بخش عمده&#8204;ای از نواقص روش&#8204;های جاری را پوشش دهد، بلکه می&#8204;تواند ریسک بازدهی سهام شرکت&#8204;ها را در حالت&#8204;های مختلف به&#8204;صورت کمی استخراج کند. الگوی حاضر براساس روش ارزش در معرض ریسک و با بهره&#8204;گیری از فرایند رژیمی مارکوف بر اساس روش&#8204;های پارامتریک طراحی شده است. این سازوکار علاوه&#8204;بر در نظر گرفتن انتقالات رژیمی ریسک، براساس مجموعه&#8204;ای از مدل&#8204;ها طراحی شده است که انواع مختلفی از توابع توزیع نرمال و غیرنرمال را بر پایه رفتارهای متقارن و نامتقارن درنظر می&#8204;گیرد. نتایج تحقیق نشان دادند که بازدهی سهام شرکت&#8204;های فعال در حوزه مسکن از انتقالات رژیمی تبعیت می&#8204;کنند و از توزیع GED بر پایه مدل&#8204;های نامتقارنی برخوردار است.&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Today, any attempt to invest in any economic activity, requires the knowledge and access to some components of its activities. One of the important components of investment is knowledge about investment risk according to the expected return in that activity. One of the main areas of investment in the country is investment on housing, which could take place directly or indirectly (through financial markets). In this regard, the importance of awareness of the risk in indirect investment on the housing sector considering to the nature of the financial markets is more necessary. But despite the importance of knowledge about risk, quantification methods developed for the past few years have not had much development. Therefore in this research we proposed a new model for measuring the share return risk of companies in real estate industry. This model is not only able to cover much of the shortcomings of current methods, but also able to extract the risk of stock returns in different states. The present model has been designed based on the &#34;value at risk&#34; and using the Markov process on parametric methods. This mechanism, in addition to taking into account the risk regime transfers is designed based on a set of models that they have got a variety of normal and abnormal distribution functions based on symmetric and asymmetric behavior. The results showed that the return of the company&#8217;s stock in housing sector follows form regime transfers and has got the GED distribution based on asymmetrical models.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>35</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>54</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهدی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>ذوالفقاری</Family>
				<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Zolfaghari</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Economics, Tarbiyat Modarres University, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>M.zolfaghari@modares.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>فاطمه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>فقیهیان</Family>
				<NameE>Fatemeh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Faghihiyan</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Central Tehran Branch, Islamic Azad University, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>GARCH family risk</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Markov chain process</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>real estate industry</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ریسک</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>خانواده GARCH</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>فرایند زنجیره مارکوف</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>صنعت انبوه‌سازی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>املاک و مستغلات</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##ابراهیمی، علیرضا. (1385). مدل‌های ARCH و GARCH و کاربردهای آنها در تحلیل داده‌های اقتصادی. پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد آمار، دانشگاه اصفهان.##اصغرپور، حسین؛ فلاحی، فیروز؛ صنوبر؛ ناصر، رضازاده، علی. (1392). مقایسه پرتفوی بهینه سهام شرکت‎های صنایع غذایی بورس تهران با استفاده از رویکردهای پارامتریک و ناپارامتریک. مجله تحقیقات اقتصاد کشاورزی، 5(4)، 130-107.##بیات، علی؛ اسدی، لیدا. (1396). بهینه‎سازی پرتفوی سهام: سودمندی الگوریتم پرندگان و مدل مارکویتز. فصلنامه مهندسی مالی و مدیریت اوراق‎بهادار، 8(32)، 85-63.##ذوالفقاری، مهدی. (1392). بررسی انواع ریسک مالی و شیوه‌های مدیریت آن در بازارهای مالی: مبانی تئوریکی و مرور تجربیات کشورها. دفتر مطالعات اقتصادی وزارت صنعت، معدن و تجارت.##ذوالفقاری، مهدی. (1394). بررسی و تحلیل ریسک نوسانات نرخ ارز با استفاده از فرایند مارکوف و ارائه الگوی مالی-اسلامی جهت مدیریت ریسک آن. رساله دکتری، دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس.##سارنج، علی‌رضا. (1393). ارائه مدلی برای تبیین رفتار انتقالات رژیمی در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران با استفاده از فرایند سوئیچینگ مارکوف. رساله دکتری، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران.##سحابی، بهرام؛ صادقی سقدل، حسین؛ خورسندی طاسکوه؛ ولی‎اله. (1394). بررسی و محاسبه ارزش در معرض ریسک بازده سهام دو صنعت کانه‌های فلزی و صنایع دارو با استفاده از آنالیز موجک و مدل‌های سری زمانی. فصلنامه پژوهش‌های اقتصادی، 1(15)، 122-105.##شاهمرادی، اصغر؛ زنگنه، محمد. (1386). محاسبه ارزش در معرض خطر برای شاخص‌های عمده بورس اوراق بهادار تهران با استفاده از روش پارامتریک. تحقیقات اقتصادی، شماره 86، 149-121.##شیخ، عباسعلی. (1394). تحلیل ریسک و بازده سرمایه‌گذاری و نگاهی به مدل‎های قیمت‎گذاری دارایی. مجله پژوهش‌های جدید در مدیریت و حسابداری. شماره 1، 62-33.##کشاورز حداد، غلامرضا؛ صمدی، باقر. (1389). برآورد و پیش‎بینی تلاطم بازدهی در بازار سهام تهران و مقایسه دقت روش‌ها در تخمین ارزش در معرض خطر: کاربردی از مدل‎های خانواده FIGARCH. مجله تحقیقات اقتصادی، 44(10)، 235-195.##Andreou, E., &amp; Ghysels, E. (2006). Monitoring disruptions in financial markets. Journal of Econometrics, 135(1-2), 77-124.##Ardia, d., Hoogerheid, l. (2014). GARCH Models for Daily Stock Returns: Impact of Estimation Frequency on Value-at-Risk and Expected Shortfall Forecasts. Economics Letters, 123(2), 187-190.##Assaf, A. (2015). Value-at-Risk analysis in the MENA equity markets: Fat tails and conditional asymmetries in return distributions. Journal of Multinational Financial Management, 29, 30-45.## Barzegar, M. (2014). A Critical on single-regim models in Iranian financial markets and review of regim behaviors on selected industries. Master's Degree in Engineering Engineering, Stevens School of Business, USA.##Beaubrun-Diant, K. E., &amp; Maury, T. P. (2016). Home tenure, stock market participation, and composition of the household portfolio. Journal of Housing Economics, 32, 1-17.##Benavides, G. (2007). GARCH Processes and Value at Risk: An empirical analysis for Mexican interest rate futures.##Binay Kumar, R. (2003). A Study of the Temporal Aggregation of GARCH Model. Indira Gandhi Institute of Development Research (IGIDR) - Development Research##Faghihian, F. (2015). The regime transitions in Iran's financial markets in the food industry. PhD in Financial Management, Izmir University, Turkey.##Giot, P., &amp; Laurent, S. (2003). Value‐at‐risk for long and short trading positions. Journal of Applied Econometrics, 18(6), 641-663.##Hamilton, J. D. (1989). A new approach to the economic analysis of nonstationary time series and the business cycle. Econometrica: Journal of the Econometric Society, 357-384.##Jung-Bin, S. (2015). alue-at-risk estimates of the stock indices in developed and emerging markets including the spillover effects of currency market. Economic Modelling Volume 46, Pages 204–224.##Kevin, E, Diant, B., Maury, T.P. (2016). Home tenure, stock market participation, and composition of the household portfolio. Journal of Housing Economics, 32, 1-17.##Markowitz, H. (1959). Portfolio selection efficient diversification of investments. New Yourk: Wiley &amp; Sonns.##Marty, W. (2015). Portfolio analytics: an introduction to return and risk measurement. Springer Texts in Business and Economics.##Seong-Min, Y., Hoon Kang, S. (2009). A Skewed Student-t Value-at-Risk Approach for Long Memory Volatility Processes in Japanese Financial Markets. Journal of International Economic Studies, Vol. 11, pp. 211-242.##Walid, C., Chaker, A., Masood, O., &amp; Fry, J. (2011). Stock market volatility and exchange rates in emerging countries: A Markov-state switching approach. Emerging Markets Review, 12(3), 272-292.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر گسترش مراکز آموزش عالی بر کاربری‌ فضاهای پیرامون آن در کلان‎شهر تبریز</TitleF>
		<TitleE>The Effect of Expanding Higher Education Centers on the Use of Its Surrounding Areas in Tabriz Metropolis</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>توسعه مراکز دانشگاهی؛ از جمله عوامل دگرگونی کالبدی امروزی شهرها بوده و تأثیر زیادی بر فرایند تحولات توسعه شهر دارد. این تحقیق، تأثیر مراکز دانشگاهی در تغییر و توسعه کاربری فضاهای پیرامون کلان&#8204;شهر تبریز را بررسی می&#8204;کند. ابزار تحقیق، شامل مشاهده و مطالعات میدانی مستقیم، بررسی نقشه&#8204;های سال&#8204;های (۱۳۴۷، ۱۳۷۵ و۱۳۹۰) و بهره&#8204;گیری از نقشه پایه سال ۱۳۸۵ بود که تغییرات انجام گرفته در دوره&#8204;های بیان شده مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. به منظور تحلیل نقشه&#8204;ها از نرم&#8204;افزار GIS و SPSS استفاده شده است. نمونه آماری این تحقیق، ۴۸۰ کاربری اطراف پنج دانشگاه&#8204; (دولتی تبریز، علوم پزشکی، پیام&#8206;نور، هنر و آزاد اسلامی تبریز) می&#8204;باشد. یافته&#8204;های پژوهش، تأثیر مراکز دانشگاهی در تغییر الگوهای کاربری زمین و توسعه شهر به&#8204;خصوص توسعه فضاهای خدماتی و تجاری در اطراف این مراکز را نشان می&#8204;دهد. تخمین میزان اثرات اجتماعی، اقتصادی و فرهنگی مراکز دانشگاهی بر کاربری&#8204;های اطراف، اهمیت تغییر رویکرد در تهیه طرح&#8204;های شهری، پیش&#8207;بینی صحیح تأثیرات عوامل شکل&#8206;دهنده و چشم&#8206;اندار مطلوب برای آینده شهر و توسعه کمی و کیفی را دو چندان کرده است.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The development of university centers is one of the causes of the modern physical alteration of cities and has a major impact on the development process of the city. This research studies the impact of university centers on changing and developing the use of spaces around Tabriz Metropolis. The research tools included observation and direct field studies, reviewing the maps of in 1968, 1996 and 2011 and using the base map in 2006 and changes made in the courses have been reviewed. GIS and SPSS software were used to analyze the maps. The statistical sample of this research is 480 uses around five universities (Tabriz State University, Medical Sciences, Payam Noor, Arts and Islamic Azad University of Tabriz). The research findings show the impact of university centers on changing land use patterns and urban development, especially the development of service and business spaces around these centers. Estimating the socioeconomic and cultural effects of academic centers on the surrounding uses has doubled the importance of changing the approach in the preparation of urban plans, the proper prediction of the effects of shaping factors and favorable landscape for the future of the city and the quantitative and qualitative development.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>55</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>65</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>نادر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>زالی</Family>
				<NameE>Nader</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Zali</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Urban Development, Faculty of Art and Architecture, University of Gilan, Gilan, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده معماری و هنر، دانشگاه گیلان، گیلان، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>n.zali54@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهدی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>مرادی اطمینان</Family>
				<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Moradi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Environmental Sciences and Architecture, University of Tabriz, Tabriz, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده علوم محیطی و معماری، دانشگاه تبریز، تبریز، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Higher Education Centers</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Metropolis of Tabriz</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Use of Surrounding Spaces</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مراکز آموزش عالی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>کلان‎شهر تبریز</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>کاربری فضاهای پیرامون</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>توسعه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##آراسته، حمیدرضا؛ سبحانی‎نژاد، مهدی؛ همایی، رضا. (1387). وضعیت دانشگاه‌های شهر تهران در عصر جهانی‌شدن. فصلنامه پژوهش و برنامه‎ریزی در آموزش عالی، 14(4)، 66-47.##اسفندیاری مهنی، حمیده؛ آقایی‌زاده، اسماعیل؛‌هادیانی، زهره. (1396). مطالعه نقش مؤسسات آموزش عالی در توسعه فیزیکی شهرها با استفاده از مدل WASPAS (نمونه موردی: شهر زاهدان). فصلنامه مطالعات ساختار و کارکرد شهری، 4(13)، 109-86.##اشرفی، یوسف. (1387). ارزیابی قابلیت‎های توسعه شهری با توجه به عملکرد و تأثیر دانشگاه در چارچوب رویکرد استراتژیک (نمونه موردمطالعه: شهر مراغه). پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه تهران. ##پوراحمد، احمد؛ سیف‎الدینی، فرانک؛ پرنون، زیبا. (1390). مهاجرت و تغییر کاربری اراضی در شهر اسلامشهر. نشریه مطالعات جغرافیایی مناطق خشک، 2(5)، 152-131.##پورمحمدی، محمدرضا؛ جام کسری، محمد. (1390). تحلیلی بر الگوی توسعه ناموزون تبریز. نشریه تحقیقات جغرافیایی، 26(1(پیاپی100))، 54-31.##تیموری، اصغر؛ ربیعی‎فر، ولی‎الله؛‌هادوی، فرامرز؛‌هادوی، محمدرضا. (1392). ارزیابی و پیش‎بینی گسترش افقی شهر قزوین با تأکید بر تغییرات کاربری اراضی، طی دوره (2011-1986). فصلنامه اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری، 2(5)، 27-15.##رضایی، محمدرضا؛ رحیمی، اسمعیل. (1392). بررسی علل تغییر کاربری اراضی در طرح‎های تفصیلی شهری و تأثیر آن بر خدمات شهری شهر مرودشت. نشریه پژوهش و برنامه‎ریزی شهری، 4(13)، 96-77.##رهایی، امید؛ قائم‌مقامی، پروین. (1390). اثرات کالبدی ساختمان‎های صنعتی بر گسترش شهری در ایران نمونه موردی: پالایشگاه تهران و منطقه مسکونی باقرشهر. نشریه باغ نظر، 16(8)، 53-43.##روستا، زهرا؛ منوری، سید مسعود؛ درویشی، مهدی؛ فلاحتی، فاطمه؛ مروتی، مریم. (1392). ارزیابی روند توسعه فیزیکی شهر شیراز و تأثیر شرایط فیزیوگرافیک بر روی روند تغییرات کاربری اراضی. نشریه جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی محیطی 24(1(پیاپی 49)،200-183.##عظیمی، نورالدین؛ پویان، صالح. (1393). بررسی تغییرات کاربری زمین شهری از طریق مصوبات کمیسیون ماده پنج (مطالعه موردی شهر رشت). نشریه جغرافیا و برنامه‎ریزی، 18(47)، 195-171.##فرید، یدالله. (1384). جغرافیا و شهرشناسی. تبریز: انتشارات دانشگاه تبریز.##قربانی، مهدی؛ مهرابی، علی‎اکبر؛ ثروتی، محمدرضا؛ نظری سامانی، علی‎اکبر. (1389). بررسی تغییرات جمعیتی و اثرگذاری‌های آن بر تغییرات کاربری اراضی (مطالعه موردی: منطقه بالا طالقان). نشریه مرتع و آبخیزداری (منابع طبیعی ایران)، 63(1)، 88-75.##متولی، صدرالدین؛ چرم‌زاده، جاسم. (1390). بررسی نقش دانشگاه‌ها و مؤسسات آموزش عالی در توسعه شهری (مطالعه موردی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد بابل). نخستین همایش ملی آرمان‌شهر ایران. دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد نور.##مرکز آمار ایران. (1385). سرشماری عمومی نفوس و مسکن.##موسی‌کاظمی، سید مهدی؛ رهنمایی، محمدتقی؛ گلپایگانی، محسن. (1392). بررسی عملکرد فضایی مراکز آموزش عالی در توسعه پایدار فرهنگ شهری کلان‌شهر تهران (نمونه موردی: مناطق 3 و 19). فصلنامه مطالعات برنامه‌ریزی شهری، 1(2)، 27-11.##واحدیان بیکی، لیلا؛ پوراحمد، احمد؛ سیف‎الدینی، رها. (1390). اثر توسعه فیزیکی شهر تهران بر تغییر کاربری اراضی منطقه5. نشریه نگرش‎های نو در جغرافیای انسانی (جغرافیای انسانی)، 4(1)، 46-29.##Andersson, R., Quigley, J. M., &amp; Wilhelmsson, M. (2009). Urbanization, productivity, and innovation: Evidence from investment in higher education. Journal of Urban Economics, 66(1), 2-15.##Hampton, G., &amp; Higham, D. (1999). The Impact of an Urban University on Community Development.##Ningal, T., Hartemink, A. E., &amp; Bregt, A. K. (2008). Land use change and population growth in the Morobe Province of Papua New Guinea between 1975 and 2000. Journal of Environmental Management, 87(1), 117-124.##Wiewel, W., &amp; Perry, D. C. (2015). Global universities and urban development: Case studies and analysis. Routledge.##Reveshty, M. A. (2011). The assessment and predicting of land use changes to urban area using multi-temporal satellite imagery and GIS: A case study on Zanjan, IRAN (1984-2011). Journal of Geographic Information System, 3(04), 298.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بهره‌وری سازمانی با نگه‌داشت استعدادهای نیروی انسانی: ارائه الگو (مورد مطالعه: شرکت ملی گاز ایران)</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Organizational productivity with the maintenance of human resources talents: providing a model (A Study on National Iranian Gas Company)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>نگه&#8204;داشت و حفظ هدفمند کارکنان مستعد، یک تلاش اثربخش هزینه- سودمندی است که به بهره&#8204;وری سازمان می&#8204;انجامد. در این راستا پژوهش حاضر با استفاده از روش کیفی، به مطالعه سازوکارهای نگه&#8204;داشت استعدادهای نیروی انسانی در شرکت ملی گاز ایران پرداخته است. به همین منظور، با ۱۰ نفر از مدیران، معاونان و کارشناسان ارشد شرکت ملی گاز ایران و ۶ نفر از اعضای هیئت علمی دانشگاه، به صورت هدفمند و گلوله برفی، مصاحبه&#8204;های عمیق نیمه&#8204;ساختاریافته به&#8204;عمل آمد. برای تحلیل داده&#8204;های حاصل از مصاحبه&#8204;ها، از تحلیل تفسیری استفاده شد. روایی یافته&#8204;های بخش کیفی از طریق بررسی توسط اعضا (مصاحبه&#8204;شوندگان) و چندسویه&#8204;نگری منابع داده&#8204;ها، تأیید گردید و برای محاسبه قابلیت اطمینان یا سازگاری کدگذاری&#8204;های انجام&#8204;شده، از روش پایایی بازآزمون استفاده شد. نتایج پژوهش نشان داد که به نظر مدیران، کارشناسان ارشد و استعدادهای شرکت ملی گاز ایران، سازوکارهای نگه&#8204;داشت استعدادهای نیروی انسانی در شرکت گاز ایران شامل ۹ مؤلفه؛ پرداخت مبتنی بر عملکرد، تأمین نیازهای خودشکوفایی، تأمین نیازهای مادی، سیستم پاداش مبتنی بر شایستگی، تفویض اختیار، سیستم جبران خدمات ویژه، کیفیت و مطلوبیت زندگی کاری، مشخص بودن مسیر پیشرفت شغلی و امنیت شغلی می&#8204;باشند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Targeted maintaining and keeping employees is a cost-effective effort that leads to organizational productivity. In this regard, the present study uses a qualitative method to deal with the mechanisms of maintaining human resource talents at National Iranian Gas Company (NIGC). For this purpose, purposefully and snowball semi-structured deep interviews were conducted with 10 senior managers, deputies, experts of NIGC, and 6 faculty members. Interpretative analysis was used to analyze the data from the interviews. The validity of the findings of the qualitative section was verified through review by members (interviewees) and multi-sensory data sources. Test- retest reliability method was used to test the reliability or compatibility of the encodings. The results indicated that, according to the senior managers, experts and talents of NIGC, the mechanisms of human resource talents maintanance at NIGC include nine components; performance-based payment, providing self-actualization needs, providing material needs, merit-based reward system, delegation of authority, special service compensation system, the quality and desirability of working life, clear career path, and job security.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>67</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>80</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>آزاده</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>قمری</Family>
				<NameE>Azadeh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ghamari</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Management, Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه خوارزمی، دانشکده مدیریت، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسن رضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>زین آبادی</Family>
				<NameE>HassanReza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Zeinabadi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Educational Administration, Faculty of Management, Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Zeinabadi_hr@khu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حمیدرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>آراسته</Family>
				<NameE>Hamidreza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Arasteh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Educational Administration, Faculty of Management, Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>بهرنگی</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammadreza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Behrangi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Educational Administration, Faculty of Management, Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Model</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Human Resource Mainatance</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>National Iranian Gas Company</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Organizational Productivity</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>الگو</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نگه‌داشت استعدادهای نیروی انسانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شرکت ملی گاز ایران</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بهره‌وری سازمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##ابیلی، خدایار. (1387). میزگرد : جابجایی مدیران؛ آثار و کارکردها. ماهنامه تدبیر، 85، 19-8.##ابیلی، خدایار. (1394). مدیریت منابع انسانی (با تأکید بر رویکردهای نوین). چاپ دوم، تهران: سازمان مدیریت صنعتی.##حاجی کریمی، عباسعلی؛ سلطانی، مرتضی. (1390). بررسی و تحلیل عوامل سنجش مدیریت استعداد (مطالعه موردی صنعت ماشین‌آلات و تجهیزات صنعتی ایران). فصلنامه مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی، 9(23)، 95-116.##رسولی، بهروز؛ نقشینه، نادر؛ فهیم‌نیا، فاطمه. (1393). مطالعه کیفیت زندگی کاری کتابداران کتابخانه‌های عمومی شهر تهران. تحقیقات اطلاع‌رسانی و کتابخانه‌های عمومی، 20 (2)، 331-317.##شاطری، کریم؛ ابیلی، خدایار؛ رضاییان، علی؛ قلی‌پور، آرین؛ مرادفام، شعله. (1394). عوامل اثرگذار بر حفظ استعدادها و نخبگان سازمانی صعنت برق ایران در راستای تحقق سیاست‌های کلی علم و فناوری. فصلنامه سیاست‌های راهبردی و کلان، 3(12)، 51-78.##طهماسبی، رضا. (1391). طراحی و تدوین سیستم مدیریت استعداد در سازمان با تمرکز بر بازار سرمایه. رساله دکتری، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران.##طهماسبی، رضا؛ قلی‌پور، آرین؛ جواهری‌زاده، ابراهیم. (1391). مدیریت استعدادها: شناسایی و رتبه‌بندی عوامل مؤثر بر جذب و نگهداشت استعدادهای علمی. پژوهش‌های مدیریت عمومی، 5(17)، 5-26.##محمدپور زرندی، حسین؛ طباطبایی مزدآبادی، سید محسن. (1396). مدیریت آموزش سازمانی (با تأکید بر توسعه سرمایه شهری). چاپ سوم، تهران: نشر گسترش فرهنگ کتاب.##محمدی، مرضیه؛ پورکیانی، مسعود. (1393). تأثیر ابعاد سیاست‌های کلی نظام اداری در حوزه منابع انسانی بر نگهداشت کارکنان دانش‌محور در بدنه نظام آموزش عالی ایران. فصلنامه رسالت مدیریت دولتی، 5(13)، 30-23.##میرسپاسی، ناصر؛ غلام‌زاده، داریوش؛ رشیدی، محمدمهدی؛ صنعتی‌گر، هدا. (1389). آسیب‌شناسی طرح جذب و نگهداری نخبگان (مورد مطالعه: شرکت ملی نفت ایران). فصلنامه مدیریت و منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، 4(11)، 40-7.##میرکمالی، سیدمحمد؛ حاج خزیمه، مجتبی؛ ابراهیمی، صلاح‌الدین. (1394). شناسایی ملاک‌های جذب و نگهداشت منابع انسانی و ارائه راهکارهای مناسب (مورد مطالعه: کارکنان دانشکده‌های پردیس فنی دانشگاه تهران). مجله مدیریت توسعه و تحول، 2(22)، 18-9.##Areiqat, A. Y., Abdelhadi, T., &amp; Al-Tarawneh, H. A. (2010). Talent management as a strategic practice of human resources management to improve human performance. Interdisciplinary Journal of Contemporary Research in Business, 2(2), 329.##Armstrong, M. (2006). Strategic human resource management. Kogan Page Ltd.##Asongu, S. A. (2017). Knowledge economy gaps, policy syndromes, and catch-up strategies: Fresh South Korean lessons to Africa. Journal of the Knowledge Economy, 8(1), 211-253.##Bhatnagar, J. (2007). Talent management strategy of employee engagement in Indian ITES employees: key to retention. Employee relations, 29(6), 640-663.##Birt, M., Wallis, T., &amp; Winternitz, G. (2004). Talent retention in a changing workplace. South African Journal of Business Management, 35(2).##Choudhary, S. (2016). A study on retention management: how to keep your top talent. International Journal of Advanced Research in Management and Social Sciences, 5(3), 17-31.##Corbin, J. M., &amp; Strauss, A. (1990). Grounded theory research: Procedures, canons, and evaluative criteria. Qualitative sociology, 13(1), 3-21.##Dries, N. (2013). The psychology of talent management: A review and research agenda. Human Resource Management Review, 23(4), 272-285.##Duttagupta, R. (2005). Identifying and managing your assets: Talent management. PricewaterhouseCoopers, London.##Garavan, T. N., Carbery, R., &amp; Rock, A. (2012). Mapping talent development: definition, scope and architecture. European Journal of Training and Development, 36(1), 5-24.##Govaerts, N., Kyndt, E., Dochy, F., &amp; Baert, H. (2011). Influence of learning and working climate on the retention of talented employees. Journal of Workplace Learning, 23(1), 35-55.##Manne, H. G. (2011). Entrepreneurship, compensation, and the corporation.##Milkovich, G. T., Newman, J. M., &amp; Milkovich, C. (2002). Compensation (Vol. 8). New York: McGraw-Hill.##Nikandrou, I., Brinia, V., &amp; Bereri, E. (2009). Trainee perceptions of training transfer: An empirical analysis. Journal of European Industrial Training, 33(3), 255-270.##Phillips, D. R., &amp; Roper, K. O. (2009). A framework for talent management in real estate. Journal of Corporate Real Estate, 11(1), 7-16.##Scott, D., McMullen, T., &amp; Royal, M. (2012). Retention of key talent and the role of rewards. WorldatWork Journal, 21(4), 58-70.##Shanbhag, M., Dutt, M. L., &amp; Bagwe, S. (2016). Strategic Talent Management: A Conceptual Analysis of BCG Model. Imperial Journal of Interdisciplinary Research, 2(7).##Sharer, E., Jones, C. J., Morris, A., Harpel, A., Miesle, A., &amp; Dixon, J. (2016). Recruiting and Maintaining Millennial Talent for The JM Smucker Company.##Silverman, D. (Ed.). (2016). Qualitative research. Sage.##Sleiderink, D. E. M. (2012). Talent management in health care: identifying and retaining talent at Medisch Spectrum Twente.##Sweem, S. L. (2009). Leveraging employee engagement through a talent management strategy: optimizing human capital through human resources and organization development strategy in a field study. Benedictine University.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تعیین ساختار بهینه پایه‌های درآمدی شهرداری تهران براساس ریسک و بازدهی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Determining the Optimal Structure of Tehran Municipality Income Basis Based on Risk and Returns</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>سلامت مالی بودجه شهرداری&#8204;ها از اهمیت بالایی برخوردار است که بازخورد آن، توانایی شهرداری در تأمین خدمات بهینه و مداوم برای شهروندان است. در دهه&#8204;های اخیر، همراه با عدم&#8204;کفایت منابع مالی شهرداری&#8204;ها، مشکل کلیدی در توسعه شهرهای کشور، عدم&#8204;تطابق و متابعت هزینه&#8204;ها و درآمدهای شهرداری از ساختار اقتصاد شهر بوده است. شهرداری کلان&#8204;شهرها، منبـع درآمدی جز اقتصاد شهری (فروش تراکم و عوارض و ...) ندارد و بقای سازمان و خدمات آن، وابسـته بـه پویایی و پایایی اقتصاد آن است. با توجه به اهمیت ساختار درآمد شهرداری&#8204;ها، در این پژوهش ابتدا ساختار درآمدی و هزینه&#8204;ای شهرداری تهران با چند شهرداری منتخب، مقایسه و سپس با استفاده از داده&#8204;های بودجه&#8204;ای شهرداری تهران طی دوره ۱۳۹۴-۱۳۸۰ و الگوی مارکویتز، اقدام به برآورد سهم هر یک از کدهای درآمدی براساس حداقل کردن ریسک، حداکثر&#8204;سازی بازدهی انتظاری و معیار شارپ در پرتفوی درآمدی شهرداری تهران شده است. نتایج نشان دادند که ساختار درآمد شهرداری تهران، مناسب نمی&#8204;باشد و با وزن&#8204;های برآوردی براساس معیارهای حداکثرسازی بازده انتظاری، حداقل&#8206;سازی ریسک و معیار شارپ، تفاوت اساسی دارد.&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The financial health of municipal budgets is of great importance, and its feedback is the ability of the municipality to provide optimal and continuous services to citizens. In recent decades, due to the lack of financial resources of municipalities, the key problem in the development of the cities of the country was the non-compliance of municipal expenditures and income from the structure of the city economy. The metropolitan municipality, unlike the state that is dependent on oil revenues, has no source of income but urban economy (sales of congestion, dues, etc.) Moreover, the survival of the organization and its services depend on the dynamism and reliability of its economy. Given the importance of municipal revenue structure, in this study, the income and expenditure structure of Tehran Municipality was compared with selected municipalities, then, using Tehran Municipality data during the period of 2001-2015 and Markowitz&#8217;s model, the share of each income code based on minimizing risk, maximizing expected returns, and Sharp&#8217;s benchmark in the income portfolio of Tehran Municipality was estimated. The results showed that Tehran Municipality&#8217;s revenue structure is not suitable and has a significant difference with estimated weights based on the maximization criteria of expected returns, risk minimization and Sharp&#8217;s benchmark.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>81</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>95</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی اکبر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>قلی‌زاده</Family>
				<NameE>Ali Akbar</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Gholizadeh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Economics, Faculty of Economics and Social Sciences, Bu-Ali Sina University, Hamedan, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده اقتصاد و علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، همدان، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>z_aliak@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهدی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>امینی‌راد</Family>
				<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Aminirad</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Faculty of Economics and Social Sciences, Bu-Ali Sina University, Hamedan, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده اقتصاد و علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه بوعلی‌ سینا، همدان، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Budget Optimization</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Local Government</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Income Portfolio</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Risk and Returns</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Tehran Municipality</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بهینه‌سازی بودجه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دولت محلی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سبد درآمدی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ریسک و بازدهی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شهرداری تهران</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##آخوندی، عباس؛‌هادی زنوز، بهروز. (1384). بازنگری ساختاری نظام درآمدی کلان‌شهر تهران؛ شرکت خدمات مدیریت ایرانیان. به پیشنهاد مرکز مطالعات و برنامه‌ریزی شهرداری تهران.##جدیدی میاندشتی، مهدی. (1383). گزارش اقتصاد شهری و شهرداری‌ها. چاپ اول، تهران: انتشارات سازمان شهرداری‌های کشور. ##حسن‌زاده، علی؛ خسروشاهی، پرویز. (1388). الگوی تأمین مالی کارآمد برای شهرداری‌های کلان‌شهرها (مطالعه موردی شهرداری تهران). اولین همایش مالیه شهرداری، مشکلات و راهکارها، تهران.##حسین‌زاده، نعمت؛ نثاری، رضا؛ منتظری، رسول. (1394). راهبردهای تأمین مالی پایدار شهرداری تهران در برنامه پنج‌ساله با تأکید بر سیاست‌های ابلاغی اقتصاد مقاومتی. فصلنامه اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری، 3(11)، 116-99. ##دانش‌جعفری، داود؛ باباجانی، جعفر؛ کریمی اسبوئی، سمانه. (1392). ارزیابی پایداری منابع مالی و درآمدی شهرداری تهران. فصلنامه اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری، 2(7)، 34-15.##رهنمای رودپشتی، فریدون؛ نیکومرام،‌هاشم؛ طلوعی اشلقی، عباس؛ حسین‎زاده لطفی، فرهاد؛ بیات، مرضیه. (1394). بررسی کارایی بهینه‎سازی پرتفوی براساس مدل پایدار با بهینه‎سازی کلاسیک در پیش‎بینی ریسک و بازده پرتفوی. مجله مهندسی مالی و مدیریت اوراق‎بهاردار، 6(22)، 60-29.##زیاری، کرامت‌اله؛ مهدی، علی؛ مهدیان بهنمیری، معصومه. (1392). مطالعه و شناخت منابع مالی و ارائه راهکارهایی برای بهبود پایداری درآمد شهرداری‌ها؛ مورد پژوهش؛ شهرداری شهر مهاباد. نشریه مدیریت شهری، 11(31)، 124- 107.  ##سعیدنیا، احمد. (1382). کتاب سبز شهرداری‌ها. دوره نهم، چاپ سوم،  انتشارات سازمان شهرداری‌های کشور. تهران.##شرزه‌ای، غلامرضا؛ مجتهد، احمد. (1385). پروژه اصلاح و تأمین منابع درآمدی شهرداری‌های کشور. پژوهشکده پولی و بانکی بانک مرکزی جمهوری اسلامی، به پیشنهاد سازمان شهرداری‌های کشور.##صادقی، محمدرضا؛ فرزانه، الهام. (1391). تحلیل حساسیت مسئله انتخاب سبد سهام. سومین کنفرانس ریاضیات مالی و کاربردها، سمنان.##قربانی، رسول؛ عظیمی، میترا. (1393). بررسی تأثیر ساختار درآمدی شهرداری بر روند توسعه شهری با استفاده از تکنیک ضریب همبستگی و تحلیل عاملی؛ مطالعه موردی مشهد. مجله پژوهش و برنامه‌ریزی شهری، 5(18)، 132-115.##محمودی، محمود؛ زمردیان، غلامرضا؛ آقایی، مرتضی. (1390). بررسی عوامل مربوط به درآمدهای پایدار شهر تهران و اولویت‌بندی آن‌ها. نشریه مدیریت شهری. دوره نهم. شماره ویژه‌. 259-275.##مظفری، غلامحسین؛ پاپلی یزدی، محمدحسین؛ وثوقی، فاطمه؛ حاتمی‌نژاد، حسین. (1395). ارائه الگوی پایدارسازی نظام درآمدی و تأمین منابع مالی شهرداری‌ها (مطالعه موردی: شهرداری تهران). فصلنامه تحقیقات جغرافیایی، سال سی و یکم، شماره چهارم. 24-44.##میره‌ای، محمد؛ حاجی‌لو، مهران؛ پیله‌ور، مهدی.(1396). بررسی منابع درآمدهای پایدار شهرداری‌ها (مورد مطالعه: شهر شبستر استان آذربایجان شرقی). فصلنامه علمی- پژوهشی اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری، دوره پنجم، شماره 20، 1-22.##هادی زنوز، بهروز. (1381). برنامه‌ریزی راهبردی شهر تهران. طرح مطالعاتی اصلاح نظام درآمدی شهرداری تهران. معاونت هماهنگی و برنامه‌ریزی شهرداری تهران.##Brock C. (2008). Introductory econometrics for finance. Cambridge University Press. ##Di Napoli, T. P. (2014). Planning and Financing New York State’s Capital Investments. Office of Budget and Policy Analysis. This report is available through the Comptroller’s website at: www.osc.state.ny.us.##Dirie, I. (2005). Municipal finance: Innovative resourcing for municipal infrastructure and service provision. CLG International LLC, Washington, DC.‌##Dye, R. F. (2008). The dynamic between municipal revenue sources and the state-local relationship in New England. FRB of Boston Public Policy Discussion Paper, (08-1).##Garrett, T. A. (2009). Evaluating state tax revenue variability: a portfolio approach. Applied Economics Letters, 16(3), 243-246.##Garvin, C. F. (1996). Financial Toolbox. For Use with MATLAB.##Lee, H. S., Cheng, F. F., &amp; Chong, S. C. (2016). Markowitz portfolio theory and capital asset pricing model for Kuala Lumpur stock exchange: A case revisited. International Journal of Economics and Financial Issues, 6(3S).##Lintner, J. (1965). The valuation of risk assets and the selection of risky investments in stock portfolios and capital budgets. The Review of Economics and Statistics, 47(1), 13-37.##Markowitz, H. (1959). Portfolio Selection: Efficient Diversification of Investments. John Wiley &amp; Sons, New York.##Martin, P. (1997). Third Millennium Management, Bathos Press, University of South Australia. ##Maudos, J. (2017). Income structure, profitability and risk in the European banking sector: The impact of the crisis. Research in International Business and Finance, 39, 85-101.##Mossin, J. (1966). Equilibrium in a capital asset market. Econometrica: Journal of the econometric society, 768-783.##Sharpe, W. F. (1994). The Sharpe ratio. The journal of portfolio management, 21(1), 49-58.##Sproats, K. (2003). Local government in Asia and the Pacific: a comparative analysis of fifteen countries. UN. Economic and social commission for Asia and the Pacific (ESCA).‌##Tjia, J. (2009). Building financial models. McGraw Hill Professional.##Tole, T.M (1992). You cannot diversify without Diversifying .Journal of portfolio management. 8, 2, winter: 5-11.##Treynor, J. L. (1962). Toward a theory of market value of risky assets, unpublished manuscript. A fial version was published in 1999. In: Korajczyk, R.A., editor. Asset Pricing and Portfolio Performance: Models, Strategy and Performance Metrics. London: Risk Books.p15-22.##Yan, W. (2012). The impact of revenue diversification and economic base on state revenue stability. Journal of Public Budgeting, Accounting &amp; Financial Management, 24(1), 58.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>مقاوم‌سازی اقتصاد شهری از طریق دستیابی به جمعیت کارای شهری</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Resisting Urban Economy by Optimizing Efficient Urban Population</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>اقتصاد مقاومتی، اصطلاحی است که در ادبیات اقتصادی ایران وارد شده و حول آن، نظریات متعددی شکل گرفته است. شهرها در اقتصاد ملی، رکن اصلی و اولیه تولید هستند. نخست&#8204;شهرها و کلان&#8204;شهرها، موتور محرک اقتصاد هستند که بخش زیادی از تولید کالا و خدمات در محدوده آنها صورت می&#8204;گیرد و همچنین عمده بازار محصولات تولید شده در این شهرها هستند؛ به&#8204;طوری که اگر این شهرها نبودند و این جمعیت به&#8204;طور پراکنده یا یکنواخت توزیع می&#8204;شدند، این میزان از تولید و این بازار شکل نمی&#8204;گرفت. با وجود اهمیت مقیاس کلان&#8204;شهرها در اقتصاد، مطابق با نظریات اقتصاد شهری، می&#8204;توان اندازه کارایی برای شهرها تصور کرد که با تعیین آن، می&#8204;توان به سوی مقاوم&#8204;سازی اقتصاد شهری و اقتصاد مقاومتی حرکت کرد. در این مقاله، مقاوم&#8206;سازی شهرها از طریق تعیین اندازه کارا شهر، بررسی و تحلیل شده است. برای محاسبه اندازه کارا شهر، تابع رفاه اجتماعی شهر، تصریح و برآورد شده است. یافته&#8204;ها نشان&#8204;دهنده این هستند که جمعیت شهر تهران، از سطح کارای خود عبور کرده و نزدیک کردن اندازه کارا به اندازه واقعی یا نزدیک کردن اندازه واقعی به اندازه کارا با کنترل جمعیت شهر می&#8204;تواند اقتصاد شهر و در نتیجه، اقتصاد ملی را مقاوم&#8206;ترکند. تنها سیاست&#8204;های کنترلی برای مقاوم&#8204;سازی اقتصاد شهر، جوابگو نیستند و سیاست&#8206;های توسعه ارائه خدمات شهری و زیرساخت شهری برای افزایش ظرفیت گنجایش شهر، توصیه می&#8204;شوند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Resistance economy is a term come across in literature of Iran economy that include lots of paper in this topic. Cities in national economy are a basis of production. Primer cities and metropolises are economy engines that cover major of goods and services production, and they are most important market for the goods and services produced in these cities, so that if these regions were not existed or the population was distributed sporadically or evenly, such a mass production and market volume were not formed. Given the importance of the metropolitan scale in the economy, based on urban economic theories, it is possible to determine efficient population of cities toward resistive urban economy. In this paper, resisting cities is analyzed by determining efficient population of cities. For calculating efficient population of city, urban social welfare function is specified and estimated. Results show Tehran population exceed efficient population level and bringing the efficient size to the actual size or vice versa by controlling urban population can resist urban economy, and consequently the national economy. Control policy is not enough for resisting urban economy but urban development and urban infrastructure development policies are recommended to increase the capacity of the city.&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>97</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>110</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>ناصر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>یارمحمدیان</Family>
				<NameE>Nasser</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Yarmohammadian</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Economics and Entrepreneurship, Art University of Isfahan, Isfahan, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشکده پژوهش‎های عالی هنر و کارآفرینی، دانشگاه هنر اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>n.yarmohamadian@aui.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Efficient Scale</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Urban Economics</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Resistance Economy</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Resisting Cities</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مقیاس کارا</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اقتصاد شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اقتصاد مقاومتی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مقاوم‌سازی شهرها</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##اکبری، نعمت‌الله، عسگری، علی؛ فرهمند، شکوفه. (1385). تحلیل توزیع اندازه شهرها در سیستم شهری ایران، فصلنامه پژوهش‌های اقتصادی، 6(4).##برخورداری، سجاد؛ جعفری، محمد. (1394). اقتصاد مقاومتی در اقتصاد ایران. تهران: مؤسسه تحقیقاتی تدبیر اقتصاد.##پایگاه اطلاع‌رسانی دفتر حفظ و نشر آثار حضرت آیت‌الله العظمی.##شاطریان، محسن؛ اشنوایی، امیر؛ زارعی فرشاد، حمید. (1390). تحلیل و مقایسه توزیع اندازه شهرها در سیستم شهری ایران و کشورهای همسایه. پژوهش‎های جغرافیای انسانی، 43(78)، 99-85.##عابدین درکوش، سعید؛ نصیری، حسین. (1389). بررسی درآمد اندازه بهینه شهر‌های ایران به روش تابع مازاد. فصلنامه اقتصاد شهر، 2(7)، 85-71.##عبدالملکی، حجت‎الله. (1393). اقتصاد مقاومتی: درآمدی بر مبانی، سیاست‌ها و برنامه عمل. تهران: انتشارات سدید.##مرکز پژوهش‌های مجلس شورای اسلامی. (1393). درباره سیاست‌های کلی اقتصاد مقاومتی. مروری بر ادبیات جهانی درباره تاب‌آوری ملی، دفتر اقتصادی. ##نظام بهرامی، کمیل؛ فدایی، احسان؛ راعی، مجتبی. (1396). تجربه اقتصاد مقاومتی در جهان و ایران. تهران: پژوهشگاه فرهنگ، هنر و ارتباطات وزارت فرهنگ و ارشاد اسلامی.##Arnott, R. (2004). Does the Henry George Theorem provide a practical guide to optimal city size?. American Journal of Economics and Sociology, 63(5), 1057-1090.##Au, C. C., &amp; Henderson, J. V. (2006). Are Chinese cities too small?. The Review of Economic Studies, 73(3), 549-576.##Behrens, K., &amp; Murata, Y. (2009). City size and the Henry George theorem under monopolistic competition. Journal of Urban Economics, 65(2), 228-235.##Camagni, R., Capello, R., &amp; Caragliu, A. (2013). One or infinite optimal city sizes? In search of an equilibrium size for cities. The Annals of Regional Science, 51(2), 309-341. ##Capello, R., &amp; Camagni, R. (2000). Beyond optimal city size: an evaluation of alternative urban growth patterns. Urban Studies, 37(9), 1479-1496.##Gaigne, c., Zenou. Y. (2013). Agglomeration, city size and crime. European Economic Review, 2015, vol. 80, issue C, 62-82.##Geography, R. E. (2009). World development report. The World Bank, Washington DC.##Kim, E., Hewings, G., &amp; Nam, K. M. (2014). Optimal urban population size: national vs local economic efficiency. Urban Studies, 51(2), 428-445.##Mizutani, F., Tanaka, T., &amp; Nakayama, N. (2015). Estimation of optimal metropolitan size in Japan with consideration of social costs. Empirical Economics, 48(4), 1713-1730.##Percoco, M. (2013). Geography, institutions and urban development: Italian cities, 1300- 1861. Annals of Regional Science, 50(1), 135-152.##Singell, L. D. (1974). Optimum city size: Some thoughts on theory and policy. Land Economics, 50(3), 207-212.##Storper, M. (2013). Keys to the city: How economics, institutions, social interaction, and politics shape development. Princeton University Press.##Yarmohammadian, N., Akbari, N., Asgary, A., &amp; Movahedinia, N. (2014). Optimal and Sustainable City Size by Estimating Surplus Function for Metropolitans of Iran.##Zheng, X. P. (2007). Measurement of optimal city sizes in Japan: a surplus function approach. Urban Studies, 44(5-6), 939-951.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>نقش فضاهای عمومی در تحقق شکوفایی شهری و توسعه پایدار </TitleF>
		<TitleE>The Role of Public Spaces in the Realization of City Prosperity and Sustainable Development</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>فضاهای عمومی، فضاهایی هستند که روزانه پذیرای قشر و گروه وسیعی از شهروندان از کودک تا پیر، زن و مرد و با هر دین و نژادی هستند؛ بنابراین فضاهای عمومی از پتانسیل کافی جهت تقویت انسجام اجتماعی، توسعه اقتصادی و ارتقای کیفیت زندگی جمعی برخوردار می&#8204;باشند. تحقق مسائل مذکور، لزوم توجه به نوع طراحی و کیفیت بصری فضاهای عمومی را می&#8204;طلبد تا این فضاها قادر باشند تا حد چشم&#8204;گیری از محرک&#8204;های محیطی کاسته و سبب افزایش سرزندگی و نشاط در جامعه شوند. مدیریت صحیح فضاهای عمومی می&#8204;تواند به شکل غیررسمی سبب افزایش دانش جمعی و مهارت&#8204;های فردی و اجتماعی ساکنان شهرها شود که این امر در سایه مشارکت مردم در امور اقتصادی، سیاسی و مدیریتی شهر و نیز افزایش سطح تعاملات اجتماعی آنها محقق می&#8204;گردد. البته نباید نقش عناصر فیزیکی محیطی را چون نمادها و نشانه&#8204;ها در افزایش آگاهی و درک بصری شهروندان نادیده گرفت. بر این اساس باید به فضاهای عمومی به عنوان بستری برای تشویق شهروندان به امر مشارکت و پذیرش مسئولیت&#8204;های اجتماعی و نیز آموزشگاهی برای انتقال دانش و آگاهی&#8204;های لازم برای بهبود کیفیت زندگی شهروندان نگریست. از این&#8204;رو در این پژوهش، تلاش شده است ضمن مطالعه و بررسی ادبیات شکوفایی شهری و توسعه پایدار، به بررسی مسائلی که ضرورت توجه به مدیریت فضاهای عمومی شهری را می&#8204;طلبد، پرداخته شود. این پژوهش از لحاظ روش تحقیق، توصیفی- تحلیلی است. نتایج پژوهش نشان دادند که توسعه و توجه به فضاهای عمومی، سبب توسعه اقتصادی شهر، ارتقای سلامت شهروندان، بهبود وضعیت آموزش شهروندان و باززنده&#8204;سازی هویت&#8204;های محلی شهر می&#8204;شود.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Public spaces are those that embrace a wide range of citizens from child to old, woman and man, and with every religion and race; therefore, public spaces have the potential to strengthen social cohesion, economic development, and the improvement of the quality of collective life. The realization of these issues requires the consideration of the design and visual quality of public spaces so that these spaces are able to significantly reduce environmental stimuli and increase the vitality of the society. Correct management of public spaces can informally increase the collective knowledge and individual and social skills of urban residents. This is achieved in the light of people&#8217;s participation in the economic, political and administrative affairs of the city as well as the increase in the level of their social interactions. Of course, the role of environmental-physical elements, such as symbols and signs, should not be ignored in raising awareness and citizens&#8217; visual perception. Accordingly, public spaces should be considered as a platform for encouraging citizens to participate and accept social responsibilities in order to transfer knowledge and awareness to improve citizens&#8217; quality of life. Therefore, in this research, it has been attempted to study the issues that need attention to urban public spaces management while studying the literature of city prosperity and sustainable development. In terms of method, this research is descriptive-analytic. The results indicated that development and attention to public spaces lead to economic development of city, improvement of citizens&#8217; health and education, and rebuilding the local identities of the city.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>111</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>124</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سجاد محمد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>یارزاده</Family>
				<NameE>Sajjad Mohammad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Yarzadeh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Department of Management, Faculty of Management, West Tehran Branch, Islamic Azad University, Tehran, Iran</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران غرب، تهران، ایران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>ayarzadeh@yamil.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>بهنوش</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شمس الهی</Family>
				<NameE>Behnoosh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Shamsollahi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>Malaysia University of Science, Penang, Malaysia</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه علوم مالزی، پیننگ، مالزی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>public spaces</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>city prosperity</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>sustainable development</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>فضاهای عمومی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شکوفایی شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>توسعه پایدار</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اقتصاد شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>##ابراهیم‌نیا سماکوش، سعید؛ خاکساری، علی؛ لطیفی، غلامرضا؛ دامادی، محمد. (1392). ارزیابی نقش گردشگری شهری در توسعه اقتصادی محیطی شهر بابلسر. فصلنامه اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری، 1(3)، 31-17.##امجدی ملایی، علیرضا؛ فیضی، محمدجواد؛ حداد لاریجانی، آنالی. (1392). نقش و اهمیت ساماندهی و زیباسازی فضاهای عمومی در توسعه گردشگری شهری. اولین همایش ملی مدیریت گردشگری، طبیعت‎گردی و جغرافیا، همدان. ##انصاری، معصومه. (1393). ارزیابی نقش و جایگاه کالبدی- کارکردی فضاهای عمومی در ارتقای کیفیت زندگی شهری. پایان‌نامه کارشناسی‌ارشد، تهران، دانشگاه پیام نور.##ایزدی، محمدسعید؛ حقی، محمدرضا. (1394). ارتقای احساس امنیت در فضاهای عمومی با بهره‌گیری از طراحی شهری (نمونه مطالعه: میدان امام شهر همدان). نشریه علمی- پژوهشی هنرهای زیبا- معماری و شهرسازی، 20(2)، 12-5. ##باقری، محمد؛ عظمتی، حمیدرضا. (1388). ارتقای سلامت جسمی روانی شهروندان با طراحی محیط و منظر شهر. نشریه انسان و محیط‌زیست، 7(19)، 95-88.##بحرینی، سیدحسین. (1374). پروژه (شهرهای سالم) سازمان بهداشت جهانی و لزوم اجرای جدی آن در جمهوری اسلامی ایران. محیط‌شناسی، شماره 17، 15-4.##پاپلی یزدی، محمد حسین؛ رجبی سناجردی، حسین. (1392). نظریه‎های شهر و پیرامون. تهران: انتشارات سمت. ##پاکزاد، جهانشاه؛ فرید طهرانی، سایه. (1390). ترس در فضای شهری. تهران: انتشارات آرمان‌شهر. ##تولایی، نوین. (1382). فضای شهری و روابط اجتماعی و فرهنگی. فصلنامه نامه پژوهش فرهنگی، شماره 5، 140-109.##تیبالدز، فرانسیس. (1396). شهرسازی شهروندگرا: ارتقای عرصه‌های همگانی و محیط‌های شهری. ترجمه محمد احمدی‌نژاد. چاپ چهارم، اصفهان: انتشارات خاک.  ##حاتمی‌نژاد، حسین؛ شریفی، امیر. (1394). بررسی نقش گسترش گردشگری شهری بر توسعه پایدار شهری. نشریه گردشگری شهری، 2(1)، 74-61. ##دانش‌پور، سیدعبدالهادی؛ چرخیان، مریم. (1386). فضاهای عمومی و عوامل مؤثر بر حیات جمعی. نشریه باغ نظر، 4(7)، 28-19.##رفیعیان، مجتبی؛ تقوایی، علی اکبر؛ خادمی، مسعود؛ علی‌پور، روجا. (1391). بررسی تطبیقی رویکردهای سنجش کیفیت در طراحی فضاهای عمومی شهری. نشریه علمی- پژوهشی انجمن علمی معماری و شهرسازی ایران، شماره 4، 43-35. ##رفیعیان، مجتبی؛ خدایی، زهرا. (1388). بررسی شاخص‎ها و معیارهای مؤثر بر رضایت‌مندی شهروندان از فضاهای عمومی شهری. نشریه راهبرد، 18(53)، 248-227. ##رفیعیان، مجتبی؛ سیفایی، مهسا. (1384). فضاهای عمومی شهری، بازنگری و ارزیابی کیفی. نشریه هنرهای زیبا، شماره 23، 42-35. ##رهنمایی، محمد تقی؛ اشرفی، یوسف. (1388). فضاهای عمومی شهر و نقش آن در شکل‌گیری جامعه مدنی از دیدگاه برنامه‌ریزی شهری. فصلنامه انجمن جغرافیای ایران، شماره‌های 14 – 15، 46-23. ##طبیبیان، منوچهر. (1376). ارزیابی پروژه شهر سالم در ایران (کوی سیزده آبان). محیط‌شناسی، 20(0)، 74-61.##عامری، حمیدرضا؛ زند، صابر. (1390). درآمدی بر شهرشناسی. تهران: دانشگاه پیام نور. ##فکوهی، ناصر؛ اوحدی، یاسمن. (1391). هویت و فضای عمومی در شهر. فصلنامه مطالعات اجتماعی ایران، 6(1)، 78-58.##کریمیان، حسن. (1389). نمادهای فرهنگی در مناظر شهری: بیان معنا، حس هویت و آرامش روحی. پژوهش‌های جغرافیای انسانی، 42(74)، 132-119. ##لینچ، کوین. (1390). تئوری شکل شهر. ترجمه سیدحسین بحرینی. تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه تهران.##محتشمی، نگار؛ مهدوی‌نژاد، محمدجواد؛ بمانیان، محمدرضا. (1395). عوامل رشد و موانع بازدارنده شکوفایی شهری. دومین کنفرانس بین‌المللی دستاوردهای نوین پژوهشی در عمران معماری و مدیریت شهری، تهران، دانشگاه جامع علمی و کاربردی.##محمدپور زرندی، حسین؛ طباطبایی مزدآبادی، سیدمحسن. (1391). تأثیر جذب سرمایه‌گذاران داخلی و خارجی و مشارکت‌های مردمی بر توسعه پایدار شهر. فصلنامه اقتصاد شهر، 4(15)، 24-12.##محمدپور زرندی، حسین؛ طباطبایی مزدآبادی، سیدمحسن. (1395). مدیریت آموزش سازمانی (با رویکرد بر توسعه سرمایه شهری). چاپ سوم، تهران: انتشارات گسترش فرهنگ کتاب. ##مرصوصی، نفیسه؛ عظیمی، سارینا. (1396). نقش عوامل محیطی و کالبدی در ارتقای امنیت فضاهای شهری. نشریه جغرافیا، 15(52)، 154-137.##مطیعی‌لنگرودی، سید حسن؛ رضائیه‌آزادی، مریم. (1392). ارزیابی اثرات گردشگری از دیدگاه جامعه میزبان در تفرجگاه بند ارومیه. فصلنامه اقتصاد فضا و توسعه روستایی، 2(2)، 91-75.##نوری، هدایت‌الله؛ خراسانی، زینب. (1391). تحلیلی بر اثرات اقتصادی، اجتماعی، و زیست‌محیطی توسعه گردشگری در شهرستان ساری. فصلنامه برنامه‌ریزی فضای جغرافیا، 1(4)، 18-1.##Asadi, R. (2011). Strategies for Development of Iran Urban Tourism. Australian Journal of Basic and Applied Sciences, 5(9), 1933-1943.##Atkinson, R. (2003). Domestication by cappuccino or a revenge on urban space? Control and empowerment in the management of public spaces. Urban studies, 40(9), 1829-1843.##Carmona, M., De Magalhaes, C., &amp; Hammond, L. (2008). Public space: the management dimension. Routledge.##Carr, S., Francis, M., Rivlin, L. G., &amp; Stone, A. M. (1992). Public space. Cambridge University Press. ##Duhl, L. J., &amp; Hancock, T. (1988). Promoting health in the urban context. WHO Healthy Cities Project Office.##Ejikeme, P. O. (2014). Education for Sustainable Development. IOSR Journal of Research &amp; Method in Education.(IOSR-JRME), 4(3), 12-15. ##Habitat, U. N. (2013). Streets as public spaces and drivers of urban prosperity. Nairobi: UN Habitat.##Hajer, M. A. (2001). In Search of New Public Domain-Analysis and Strategy.##Joss, S. (2015). Sustainable cities: Governing for urban innovation. Macmillan International Higher Education.##Kates, R. W., Parris, T. M., &amp; Leiserowitz, A. A. (2005). What is sustainable development? Goals, indicators, values, and practice. Environment(Washington DC), 47(3), 8-21. ##Maclean, P. (2008). Education for Peace Building and Sustainable Development: Delusion, Illusion or Reality?. Available from:&lt; fromhttp://www. daneprairie. com.##Nasution, A. D., &amp; Zahrah, W. (2017). Public Open Space’s Contribution to Quality of Life: Does privatisation matters?. Asian Journal of Environment-Behaviour Studies, 2(5), 71-83.##United Nations Human Settlements Programme. (2013). State of the World's Cities 2012-2013: Prosperity of Cities. Routledge for United Nations Human Settlements Programme (UN-Habitat). ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>

</ARTICLES>

</JOURNAL>
</XML>
