<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <ArticleSet>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2345-2870</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-6398</EISSN>
			<Volume>3</Volume>
			<Issue>10</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2015</Year>
				<Month>4</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Offering an Annual Tax Calculation Model for Private Vehicles with the Approach of Increasing Incomes of Sustainable Urban Management</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>19</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>kamran</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>rahimi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Islamic Azad University (Sciences and Researches Branch)</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>pooria</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Zangaaneh Ranjbar</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Islamic Azad University (Sciences and Researches Branch)</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>hooman</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Alenoori Forushani</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Imam Khomaini International University of Qazvin</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>saeed</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>SherafatiPur</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Tarbiat Modarres University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>In addition to have some benefits for the users, private vehicles as a one of urban transportation systems, impose different costs and effects on environment and citizens who are not among users of private cars. Currently, only a small share of car prices is received as the annual tax of car ownership by the municipality, therefore it is necessary to review the process and the external car costs generated by vehicles, has been internalized. In this research, after the study of determining trends of the tax in other countries, and identification the affecting factors in determination the car use tax using factor analysis, we tried to provide a model to internalize the external costs, in order to increase sustainable revenues for urban management and optimize urban economy trends. Finally we tried to use know factors in a mathematical functions to calculate a proportional amount to the external costs generated by vehicles in a way that this proposed amount could be able to increase sustainable revenues for urban management and persuade citizens to use low-pollutant vehicles. The main suggestion of this research is to begin the process of increasing the dependence of urban economy and management of metropolitans Municipalities to unsustainable income resources such as building density and replacing them with scientific and sustainable incomes.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>private vehicles, tax, sustainable incomes of urban management, urban economy, external costs</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iueam.ir/article-1-144-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iueam.ir/article-1-144-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2345-2870</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-6398</EISSN>
			<Volume>3</Volume>
			<Issue>10</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2015</Year>
				<Month>4</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The Economic Valuation of Urban Entertainment Services (the Case of: Estimates of the Amusement Value of Mellat Park in Holly Mashhad)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>21</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>35</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>sadegh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Bafandeh Imandoust</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Payame Noor University, Mashhad Center</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>mohammd</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>lashkari</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Payame Noor University, Mashhad Center</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>fatemeh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Moghtadaei</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Payame Noor University, Mashhad Center</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>because of having many attractions, Mellat park in holly Mashhad is a major tourist site therefore, the study of its recreational value could be effective to Estimate the deficiencies, needs and tourism development in this park. The study was carried out to determine the leisure value of Mellat Park in holy Mashhad, and to estimate the amount of visitors willing to pay the park using contingent valuation method and the and dichotomous choice questionnaire. Target population of this study is the visitors of Mellat Park. The sample size is about 222 people that were selected by available sampling method. To investigate the effect of explanatory variables on visitors willing to pay, Logit model was used and based on the maximum reliability method, the parameters of the model was estimated. The results showed that 74.78% of those surveyed were willing to pay for recreational use of the park are people willing to pay an average visitors to the amusement park, 9849.48 rials have been obtained for each visit. The annual recreational value of it, is estimated about 2.46237 &#215; 1010 IRR. The variables of proposed rate payment and any transportation costs, have negative effect and the variables of park quality, marital status, duration of study per week, environmental orientation and gender, have a positive effect on the willingness to pay. The results indicate that people are aware about the importance of urban parks and have a willingness to pay a substantial charge in the planning and management of the park that can be helped.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>urban economy, recreational value, willingness to pay, contingent valuation, Mellat park</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iueam.ir/article-1-145-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iueam.ir/article-1-145-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2345-2870</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-6398</EISSN>
			<Volume>3</Volume>
			<Issue>10</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2015</Year>
				<Month>4</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Evaluation the Qualitative and Quantitative Indicators Affecting on Urban Green Space Planning (The Case of Miyaneh City)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>37</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>57</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>majid</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>yaripour</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Isfahan University of Arts</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>sadegh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Hadizadeh Zargar</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Isfahan University of Arts</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Increase in urban population and, the growth and spread of physical and social dimensions of cities has a significant impact on urban life, so that nowadays the concept of cities without regarding green spaces and its various forms is unthinkable. Hence the main objective of this research is to improve the quality of green space in the city of Miyaneh. This Research In terms of the target is an applied research and In terms of method is a descriptive-analytical research. After identifying the components effective and factors on the planning of urban green space, these indicators in four areas were evaluated in the Miyaneh. The target population of this research is all the users of parks and green spaces in the city center, in the months of August, September and October 1391. Then by Using Cochran formula, 383 questionnaires with regard to the scale and reach within the park were distributed randomly. Data was gathered by using the study of literature, documentary method and interview with 10 experts who were familiar to the research subject. Using hierarchical analysis process (AHP), the relative importance of each of these indexes has been set the existing. Parks and green spaces, due to the factors considered were evaluated and through identifying shortcomings, deficiencies and required levels for planning the green spaces in the Miyaneh, some optimal solutions were provided. Based on the results, the physical component, has the largest relative importance among other factors and also environmental, social and economic components are in secondary grade. As well as 3 urban areas have the most difficult situation in green space, so it should be a priority in the planning and construction of urban green spaces</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Green space planning, urban green space, Analytical Hierarchy process, Miyaneh city</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iueam.ir/article-1-146-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iueam.ir/article-1-146-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2345-2870</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-6398</EISSN>
			<Volume>3</Volume>
			<Issue>10</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2015</Year>
				<Month>4</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Privatization on the Performance of the Tehran Bus Lines (With Emphasis on the BRT System)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>59</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>76</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Sedigheh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Atrkar Roshan</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Alzahra University, Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Shamsollah</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Shirinbakhsh</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Alzahra University, Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>maryam</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>esfandyar</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Alzahra University, Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hossein</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Doroudian</LastName>
	<Affiliation>University of Tehran, Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Bus transportation has a significant stand in facing urban transports, especially in Metropolitans. One of the steps taken in the area of bus services in Tehran in recent years, is the transference many services of lines to the private sector. This study seek to determine the effects of privatization on providing bus services in Tehran metropolitan. The importance of Extremist bus lines in mobility and better access to information systems, led this experimental study to carry out within these lines. To a experimental study, we compared the performance of lines 1 and 2 (state lines) and line 7 (private line), during the years 1389 to 1391 using the quarterly data. The most widely used method in this type of study, is data envelopment analysis. The results showed that the relative deficiency of line 7 in comparison to the state lines that from the point of kind of managerial deficiency and scale deficiency which scale deficiency was more intensive. Also the deficiency of private line in the output of passengers' transportation was further than output of travelled kilometres. Therefore, based on the research findings, it seems to entrance the private motivations into bus transit services in ways followed, have negative results.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>privatization, bus services, BRT, Data Envelopment Analysis (DEA), technical efficiency</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iueam.ir/article-1-147-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iueam.ir/article-1-147-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2345-2870</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-6398</EISSN>
			<Volume>3</Volume>
			<Issue>10</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2015</Year>
				<Month>4</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The Impact of Socioeconomic Conditions and Traffic Management on the Number of Intercity Trips in Tehran (the Cases of: Shykhhady, Qeytarieh and Qezelqale Neighborhoods)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>77</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>93</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>ahmad</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Purahmad</LastName>
	<Affiliation>University of Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammadtaghi</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Rahnamaei</LastName>
	<Affiliation>University of Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Rahmatollah</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Farhudi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>University of Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Fatemeh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Salarvandian</LastName>
	<Affiliation>University of Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Martin</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Dijst</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Utrecht University, Utrecht, Netherland</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Today, with the increasing use of cars and intense traffic and pollution in cities, sustainable urban transport has become one of the main concerns of managers and urban planners. So identification the patterns of travel is one of requirements to achieve the sustainable transport management. One aspect of travel is the number of daily trips and identification of the factors affecting it. The main objective of this study was to identify factors affecting the number of intercity trips in Tehran. In order to achieve the desired goal, the Multivariate Method and Poisson regression models were used. in order to present the traffic policies and socio-economic factors affecting on the number of intercity trips, first 2 neighborhood that located in the odd and even traffic plan were chosen and then were compared to a third neighborhood (Qeytarieh) that was located on the outside of those neighborhood 450 questionnaires were distributed in this areas according to Cochran formula and Morgan table. The results show that: Socio-economic variables (gender, age, education, income, owning a car in the household, type of household, type of job and having a child under 12 years), had the greatest impact on the number of business trips, While in excursions and trips to shopping, the variable of Location relative to the traffic patterns, was more effective.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>number of trips, socioeconomic variables, traffic management, poisson regression model</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iueam.ir/article-1-149-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iueam.ir/article-1-149-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2345-2870</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-6398</EISSN>
			<Volume>3</Volume>
			<Issue>10</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2015</Year>
				<Month>4</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Determination The Factors Affecting the Choice of Residential Units Location, by Using the Discrete Choice Model (the Case of Tabriz)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>95</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>110</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Parviz</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Mohammadzadeh</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Tabriz University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Abolfazl</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Ghanbari</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Islamic Azad University, Tabriz Branch</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Roghieh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Nazemfar</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Islamic Azad University, Tabriz Branch</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Appropriate decision making about site selection for Residential Units by managers of cities, Housing construction companies, and recreational and educational centers, is required to understand the preferences of households in the area. The purpose of this paper is to investigate the factors influencing the choice of residential location and measuring the impacts of these factors on probability of the choice. For this purpose, the multinomial logit model was used, and different city areas were classified based on the value of real estate transactions. Then, we sampled from categories randomly based on residential density. Totally 383 households were sampled. The results showed that the household economic factors included income, price, Rent housing units, household, being House or apartment, access to recreational and educational centers, time and costs of transportation are the main determining factors. The results of this study proved that. the behavior and preferences of families in different neighborhoods is not the same. for example, the increase in prices and rents in neighborhoods with low trading value, have a negative effect on the selections, but in neighborhoods with higher trading value, it means the improvement of the quality of housing, and increased the probability if choices. Also The tendency to apartment units in neighborhoods with high trading value, is higher than low-cost areas. Due to differences in the behavior of households in selecting housing units in different neighborhoods by stahttp://iueam.ir/files/0allsites/wysiwyg_en.gifkeholders, influential and relevants, is very important.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>location residential units, household characteristics, the multinomial logit model</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iueam.ir/article-1-150-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iueam.ir/article-1-150-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2345-2870</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-6398</EISSN>
			<Volume>3</Volume>
			<Issue>10</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2015</Year>
				<Month>4</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Training in Sustainable Urban Development</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>111</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>125</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hossein</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Mohammadpour Zarandi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Iranian Urban Economics Scientific Association</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Sustainability is a pattern for thinking about the future in which environmental, social and economic considerations, are in a balanced state with each other, in order to improve the quality of life. Sustainable city is a city in which due to economic use of resources, avoid to producing too much waste and recycling them as much as possible and adopt effective policies, is able to maintain its existence. Training is a helper factor for achieving to sustainability paradigm, especially in the cities, and it is necessary to being consistent to functional assumptions of sustainable development. Training should be changed in structure and in terms of content. This paper aims to identify and understand the role of education in sustainable development, in particular sustainable urban development, and analytic studies relying on documents, including international declarations, to check the status of education in sustainable development, within the framework of international treaties and agreements, conceptual and epistemological aspects that have been investigated. The results show that the concept formulation of the education for sustainable development, by organizations like UNESCO, has properly done. But at the end of the decade of &#8220;education for sustainable development&#8221;, some problems have been remained, particularly in developing countries, therefore The future international efforts in this regard should be directed towards developing countries and cities</Abstract>
	<Keywords>training, sustainable urban development, sustainable city, human resource, economic development</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iueam.ir/article-1-151-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iueam.ir/article-1-151-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2345-2870</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-6398</EISSN>
			<Volume>3</Volume>
			<Issue>10</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2015</Year>
				<Month>4</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Measuring the Development Degree of Ardabil Province Cities, Using the Hierarchical and Numerical Taxonomy Analysis Models</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>127</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>138</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mirnaser</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Mirbagheri</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Payame Noor University, Ardabil Center</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>delavar</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Ma'sumi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Payame Noor University, Rasht Center</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>behrooz</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>navid</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Islamic Azad University, Tehran Centeral Branch</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Seyyed Rashed</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Safavi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Payame Noor University, Khalkhal Center</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Inequality in the world has been growing in a number of indicators. This is more tangible in the third world countries and because of growing cities and the slow backwardness of some regions. The process of development and social justice in human settlements is one of subjects in this context. Measuring the development of Ardabil province cities using by synthetic indexes of infrastructure, social, economic, health and health care affairs is the main purpose of this study. Results of the hierarchical and numerical taxonomy analysis models showed that there is an inequality among the cities of the province in terms of level of development, So that the city of Ardabil is more enjoyment, and there is a huge gap between it and other cities in this province.

According to analysis the numerical taxonomy and AHP models, Meshkin Shahr after Ardabil, is at the first level of development (degree of development models, respectively, 0.19 and 18.2 percent) and Khalkhal is on the second level of development (degree of development models, respectively, 0.17 and 13.8 percent).</Abstract>
	<Keywords>development, numerical taxonomy analysis, AHP model, ardabil province </Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iueam.ir/article-1-152-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iueam.ir/article-1-152-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2345-2870</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-6398</EISSN>
			<Volume>3</Volume>
			<Issue>10</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2015</Year>
				<Month>4</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Measuring Tourists\' Satisfaction of the Mahabad City with an Emphasis on Shopping Tourism</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>139</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>155</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mansour</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Soleimani</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran,</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Mohammadnejad</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>parvin</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>khodadadi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>University of Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>vahid</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Ataei</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Payame Noor University, Ray Center, Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Nowadays, about 70 percent of tourist spending, is allocated to shopping and the satisfaction of shopping is a main reason for return them to the tourists destinations. The city of Mahabad has been become one of tourism centers and border markets in Iran because of its location that is close to the border and spheres of influence for good business. In this Regard, the purpose of this research is to evaluate the satisfaction rate of tourists coming to the city of Mahabad, based on shopping tourism. Hence, the method of this Research is descriptive- analytical and other methods such as documentary and survey methods are also used. The target population of the study includes 58,000 tourists who entered to Mahabad in the New Year ceremonies of 1393. Data, were collected based on 120 questionnaires that were distributed among the tourists who stayed in Mahabad, and analyzed by SPSS and Factor analysis model. In the questionnaire, respondents were asked to comment and rate 46 variables about the quality and the consent of a trip to the city of Mahabad and its attractions, using Likert Scale. The results showed that 2 factors of the host community behavior and the quality of accommodation and the quality of the environment and its attractions, have more than 56% of the total variance. Also the explained variables have the greatest impact on the satisfaction of tourists who entered the city. Finally, with regard to the relationship between satisfaction and return tourists for shopping, we have presented suggestions to increase the amount of tourists satisfaction.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>shopping tourism, boarder areas, tourists satisfaction, factor analysis, Mahabad city</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iueam.ir/article-1-153-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iueam.ir/article-1-153-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
 </ArticleSet>
 
  
  
  
  
 