<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</title>
<title_fa>فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری</title_fa>
<short_title>IUESA</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iueam.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2345-2870</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-6398</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/iueam</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>en</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1392</year>
	<month>10</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>1</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>2</volume>
<number>5</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تأثیر سطوح ارزیابی بر بهبود کیفیت دوره‌های آموزشی شهرداری تهران با رویکرد ارتقای عملکرد اقتصادی</title_fa>
	<title>The Effect of Evaluation Levels on Improving the Quality of Training Courses by Tehran Municipality with an Approach to Promoting Economic Function</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; dir=&quot;rtl&quot; style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:yekanyw;&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;AR-SA&quot;&gt;برگزاری دوره&#8204;های آموزشی در هر سازمانی، از جمله مسائل مهم مرتبط با سرمایه انسانی است که بر ابعاد مختلف عملکرد؛ از جمله عملکرد اقتصادی، تأثیرگذار می&#8204;باشد. نظام آموزش هر سازمان نیاز به بازخورد و بررسی دارد تا نواقص آن برطرف گردد و بهره&#8204;وری دوره&#8204;های برگزار شده بالاتر رفته و توجیه و صرفه اقتصادی داشته باشد. در این راستا ارزیابی دوره&#8204;های آموزشی می&#8204;تواند کمک شایانی نماید. هدف از این تحقیق، بررسی تأثیر سطوح ارزیابی بر بهبود کیفیت دوره&#8204;های آموزشی برگزار شده برای کارشناسان مالی شهرداری تهران می&#8204;باشد. جامعه آماری این تحقیق را کلیه کارشناسان مالی شهرداری تهران تشکیل می&#8204;دهند که تعداد 143 نفر به عنوان حجم نمونه و به صورت تصادفی انتخاب شده&#8204;اند. ابزار گردآوری اطلاعات در این تحقیق، پرسشنامه می&#8204;باشد که با استفاده از روش&#8204;های استاندارد، پایایی و روایی آن، مورد تأیید قرار گرفته است. جهت تجزیه و تحلیل داده&#8204;ها از آزمون &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;student&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span lang=&quot;AR-SA&quot;&gt;و برای رتبه&#8204;بندی، از آزمون فریدمن استفاده شده است. نهایتاً مشخص گردید هر پنج سطح ارزیابی آموزش بر روی بهبود کیفیت دوره&#8204;های آموزشی، اثرگذار می&#8204;باشد. همچنین نتایج به دست آمده از آزمون فریدمن نشان داده&#8204;اند که سه سطح ارزیابی تغییرات رفتاری در شغل، شناسایی نتایج کلیدی آموزش و محاسبه بازگشت سرمایه (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;ROI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;AR-SA&quot;&gt;)، اولویت اول تا سوم را به خود اختصاص می&#8204;دهند؛ به عبارتی، نتایج به دست آمده از این سه نوع ارزیابی، بیانگر تأثیر بیشتر دوره&#8204;های آموزشی برگزار شده می&#8204;باشد.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;AR-SA&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 12pt line-height: 150% font-family: 'B Nazanin'&quot;&gt;&lt;!--stripped--&gt;&lt;!--stripped--&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;Organizing training courses in each organization is among the important issues related to human capital which has effects on different aspects of function such as economic function. Training system of each organization requires feedback and investigation so that the drawbacks whereof could be resolved and the efficiency of the very courses increases and they become much more economical. Hence, to this end, evaluation of training courses can play a vital role. The current research aims at investigating the effect of evaluation levels on improving the quality of training courses for the staff at finance department of Tehran municipality. The population was all the staff at finance department of Tehran municipality from among whom 143 participants were randomly selected. The data was collected by means of a questionnaire the reliability and validity of which were estimated to be significant. To analyze the collected data and for ranking, Student&amp;rsquo;s T-test and Friedman Test was utilized, respectively. The results indicate that all the five levels of evaluation of training courses have significant effects on improving the quality whereof. Besides, the results obtained from Friedman test indicate that the three levels of evaluating behavioral changes at work, identifying key results of training, and estimating Return on Investment (ROI) were ranked one to three, respectively in other words, the results obtained from such three levels of evaluation bear witness to the significant effect of the very courses.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>ارزیابی, آموزش, سطوح ارزیابی آموزش, کیفیت آموزش, شهرداری تهران, عملکرد اقتصادی</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>evaluation, training, levels of evaluating training, training quality, Tehran municipality, economic function </keyword>
	<start_page>29</start_page>
	<end_page>38</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1-35&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Hossein</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Mohammadpour Zarandi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حسین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>محمدپور زرندی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002147</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002147</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Science and Culture University and the Head of Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association </affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه علم و فرهنگ و رئیس انجمن علمی اقتصاد شهری ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Davoud</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Danesh Jafari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>داود</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>دانش‌جعفری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002148</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002148</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Allameh Tabataba’i University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Goshtasb</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Mozaffari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>گشتاسب</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مظفری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002149</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002149</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Education and Psychology, Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده علوم تربیتی و روانشناسی، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Seyyed Mohsen </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Tabatabaei Mozdabadi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سید محسن</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>طباطبایی مزدآبادی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002150</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002150</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Allameh Tabataba’i University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
