
	<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"	xmlns:cr_unixml="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2020-07-27T16:25:18+04:30</responseDate>
	<request metadataPrefix="cr_unixml" verb="ListRecords" set="10.1002">http://iueam.ir/browse.php?mag_id=19&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</request>
	<ListRecords>
		
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>19-662</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>5</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>18</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Proposing a Conceptual Framework of Urban Regeneration Interaction and Entrepreneur City in Achieving Place Marketing</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Mojtaba</given_name>
					<surname>Rafieiyan</surname>
					<email>rafiei_m@modares.ac.ir</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Fatemeh</given_name>
					<surname>Mohammadi Aydaghmish</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Along with development of planning relationship and urban development market affected by globalization processes and urban competition, urban regeneration policies have taken a new form. However, in practice, urban regeneration processes are influenced by physical policies and up-to-down managerial approach in our country and less attention has been paid to transnational scale and entrepreneur approaches to facilitate these processes. Thus, this research tries to propose a conceptual framework for place marketing in urba

n regeneration affected by entrepreneur city approaches with qualitative-inductive method and using qualitative content analysis and comparative analysis of the world examples. For this purpose, eight samples of global experiences were compared (with maximum diversity sampling method). The results indicated that changes made in line with urban regeneration with entrepreneur city approach from change in managerial systems, and using corporate governance in line with market motivation and building capacity have initiated new types of participation. All these changes in all aspects were made aiming to improve infrastructures and increase quality of life. Protection of local identity and attention to global scales as well are accentuated in the process of attracting capital in place marketing. The results indicated that the use of such process in our country requires considering cultural, institutional, and legal aspects. In this regard, improving environment quality, promoting mental image of place, tourism development, facilitator rules and regulations, attention to local creativity, and efficient and transparent management are of great importance.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>place marketing</keyword>
	<keyword>urban regeneration</keyword>
	<keyword>entrepreneur city</keyword>
	<keyword>corporate governance</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>6</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>1</first_page>
								  <last_page>20</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-662-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>19-663</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>5</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>18</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Urban Regeneration by Emphasizing on Identification and Analysis of Cultural Creative Clusters (Case Study: Shiraz Historical-Cultural Fabric)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Pegah</given_name>
					<surname>Izadi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Zohreh</given_name>
					<surname>Hadiyani</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Ali</given_name>
					<surname>Hajinejad</surname>
					<email>ahajinejad@gep.usb.ac.ir</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name>Jafar</given_name>
					<surname>Qaderi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Different strategies and theories have been proposed to solve problems of urban decline phenomenon and its different economic, social, physical, and environmental aspects summarized in urban regeneration approach. Based on the production of culture as a new regeneration approach, regeneration supports creative industries and uses cluster development of these industries as a centerpiece of regeneration. With descriptive-analytical method, this research tries to evaluate the position of Shiraz historical-cultural fabric in relation with creative city indicators, to investigate cluster development of cultural industries in this area, and realize possibilities of regeneration based on cultural production in the studied area. The findings indicate that Shiraz historical-cultural fabric (municipality-district8) with coefficient of 0.58 is ranked in partially prosperous in terms of creative city indicators in the city of Shiraz. Yet, studies related to cluster development of cultural industries and businesses indicate despite geographical and cluster concentration of domestic and handicraft industries, and publishing industry, lack of cooperation network and effective links between related entities with each category have helped not to fulfill cluster development of creative industries. Other known cultural categories including museums and cultural institutes do not have cluster geographical distribution and they enjoy low level of density link in their institutional network.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Creative industries</keyword>
	<keyword>cluster development</keyword>
	<keyword>creative city</keyword>
	<keyword>regeneration</keyword>
	<keyword>city of Shiraz</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>6</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>21</first_page>
								  <last_page>40</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-663-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>19-664</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>5</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>18</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Investigating Micro-System Management Establishment of Peri-Urban Areas (Case Study: Tehran Metropolis- District 22)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Gholamreza</given_name>
					<surname>Kazemian Shirvan</surname>
					<email>Kazemian1344@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mahmoud</given_name>
					<surname>Ziyaei</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Maghasood</given_name>
					<surname>Amiri</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name>Hossein</given_name>
					<surname>Moradi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Population overflow or attraction, metropolis activity around its surrounding, role and performance changes of centers adjacent to metropolis have positive and negative consequences and dealing with them separately is not possible, efficient and equitable. Since administering one city is an attempt to manage a spontaneous phenomenon, emerging cities and their evolution and growth are because of many decision that people make to determine place of living, work, establishing a company, financing resources, recreation, and education and so on. Each of these decisions has mutual impact on each other directly or indirectly in a complicated network of mutual exchange and cooperation. Peri-urban areas are one of the problematic ones in metropolis management, but political divisions is a concept that some consider it as the most basic issue facing management and governance of these areas. Political division is due to the expansion of metropolis areas beyond the confines of a single state territory such as municipality. Tehran Metropolis progress and urban-rural development in its per-urban environment, if land speculation is not controlled and there are no tool and mechanism to guide it systematically at different levels, will results in environmental, social, economic, quality of life, and ecological decline in the area. Thus, it has been tried in this research to study management literature of metropolis areas in addition to investigate issues that demand attention to management of peri-urban areas as well. One of the main goals of this research is to present policies in management system of peri-urban areas to improve inter-organization, intra-organization, and institutional interaction and integration. In terms of method, this research is descriptive-analytical. Given the research results, since Tehran district 22 is affected and formed by different factors and forces and it has been expanded in spatial territory of Metropolis surrounding, more attention and accuracy should be paid to its structural-functional management.&#160;
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>city management</keyword>
	<keyword>peri-urban areas</keyword>
	<keyword>Tehran Metropolis</keyword>
	<keyword>micro-system management</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>6</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>41</first_page>
								  <last_page>56</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-664-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>19-665</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>5</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>18</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Energy Consumption Optimization in Urban Rail Transport (Case Study: Tehran Subway)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Amir Masoud</given_name>
					<surname>Nikookar</surname>
					<email>Nikookar.amir@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Tahmineh</given_name>
					<surname>Nategh</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Jalil</given_name>
					<surname>Gharibi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Necessity and importance of energy in state economic, social, and political structure and stability of and terminable fossil resources have been centerpiece of attention to energy issue in last few years. Urban railway, as one of the main pillars of urban economy, has increased the importance of this sector based on mass transit with advantages such as economic savings in fuel consumption, preventing air pollution, reaching environmental standards, and creating social culture and discipline, and it has been followed by continuation and development of rail transport sector in the country. In this research, optimization of energy consumption in urban rail transport has been investigated and some strategies have been presented in this regard. For this purpose, 160 metro experts, who had direct relation with establishment and implementation of energy management system in Tehran Metro Operation Company, were considered as population. By using Morgan table, 113 of them were selected as sample by simple random sampling. To collect data, library ad field studies, interview with related experts, and researcher-made questionnaire containing 22 questions were used. To analyze data, SPSS software, exploratory factor analysis, and Freidman test were used. In order to identify current situation in energy management (based on ISO 50001 standard), general measures Tehran Metro Operation Company in current situation, including contract demands of electricity consumption were detected. However, by using factor analysis, 11 factors were identified and ranked in the field of energy consumption optimization. Appropriate information ranked the highest and encouraging suggested pland ranked the least.&#160;
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>optimization</keyword>
	<keyword>consumption</keyword>
	<keyword>energy</keyword>
	<keyword>rail transport</keyword>
	<keyword>city of Tehran</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>6</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>57</first_page>
								  <last_page>75</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-665-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>19-666</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>5</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>18</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Structural Equation Modeling of Effective Economic and Cultural Components on Energy Consumption Behavior in Urban Societies</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Esfandiyar</given_name>
					<surname>Mohammadi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mahdiyeh</given_name>
					<surname>Mokhtarifar</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Ardeshir</given_name>
					<surname>Shiri</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Energy consumption efficiency is one of the most important concerns in urban communities allotted more than 70 percent of Iran&#8217;s population to itself. Since energy efficiency index that is one of the targeted components in resistance economy policies has been reduces, it is necessary to design and adopt comprehensive, efficient, and integrated policies in order to improve efficiency and productivity of energy consumption in Iran. Energy consumption optimization in urban communities is affected by different factors and components. One of influential components is socio-cultural factors. This is because of an element named consumption attitude and behavior among any household&#8217;s member that has socio-cultural roots, and consequently only socio-cultural tools are effective on its change and reform, but this type of factors has been less considered by researchers in analysis of consumption behavior. In this research, energy consumption behavior in urban community has been analyzed with socio-economic approach and by using data based on experts&#8217; view in this area, factor analysis technique, and LISREL Structural Equation Modeling (SEM), it was analyzed exactly and scientifically. According to the results from the mentioned model, economic policies, whether price ones or non-price ones, do not have acceptable impact to improve and reform energy consumption behavior in urban community. There is a poor relationship between this type of components and energy consumption behavior in urban households. On the contrary, social and national beliefs and norms have significant impact on consumption behavior. Currently, they are main source of forming and directing energy consumption model in Iran&#8217;s urban communities. However, the potential impact of religious and moral values on social and national beliefs and norms has been proved. Given direct impact of this type of socio-cultural components on energy consumption behavior in urban society, high capacity can be regarded for religious-ethical views and values to improve consumption behavior in urban community.&#160;
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>energy consumption</keyword>
	<keyword>energy consumption behavior</keyword>
	<keyword>economic policies</keyword>
	<keyword>structural equation modeling</keyword>
	<keyword>socio-cultural components</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>6</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>77</first_page>
								  <last_page>92</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-666-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>19-669</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>5</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>18</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Structural Equation Modeling of Effective Economic and Cultural Components on Energy Consumption Behavior in Urban Societies</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Mahdi</given_name>
					<surname>Sadeghi Shahdani</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mahdi</given_name>
					<surname>Khoshkhooy</surname>
					<email>khoshkhooy@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Energy consumption efficiency is one of the most important concerns in urban communities allotted more than 70 percent of Iran&#8217;s population to itself. Since energy efficiency index that is one of the targeted components in resistance economy policies has been reduces, it is necessary to design and adopt comprehensive, efficient, and integrated policies in order to improve efficiency and productivity of energy consumption in Iran. Energy consumption optimization in urban communities is affected by different factors and components. One of influential components is socio-cultural factors. This is because of an element named consumption attitude and behavior among any household&#8217;s member that has socio-cultural roots, and consequently only socio-cultural tools are effective on its change and reform, but this type of factors has been less considered by researchers in analysis of consumption behavior. In this research, energy consumption behavior in urban community has been analyzed with socio-economic approach and by using data based on experts&#8217; view in this area, factor analysis technique, and LISREL Structural Equation Modeling (SEM), it was analyzed exactly and scientifically. According to the results from the mentioned model, economic policies, whether price ones or non-price ones, do not have acceptable impact to improve and reform energy consumption behavior in urban community. There is a poor relationship between this type of components and energy consumption behavior in urban households. On the contrary, social and national beliefs and norms have significant impact on consumption behavior. Currently, they are main source of forming and directing energy consumption model in Iran&#8217;s urban communities. However, the potential impact of religious and moral values on social and national beliefs and norms has been proved. Given direct impact of this type of socio-cultural components on energy consumption behavior in urban society, high capacity can be regarded for religious-ethical views and values to improve consumption behavior in urban community.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>energy consumption</keyword>
	<keyword>energy consumption behavior</keyword>
	<keyword>economic policies</keyword>
	<keyword>structural equation modeling</keyword>
	<keyword>socio-cultural components</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>6</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>93</first_page>
								  <last_page>112</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-669-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>19-668</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>5</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>18</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>The Role of Organizational Change on Improving Organizations Financial and Economic Performance (Case Study: Bank Shahr)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Hossein</given_name>
					<surname>Mohammadpour Zarandi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Alireza</given_name>
					<surname>Amirkabiri</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Hamidreza</given_name>
					<surname>Azimi</surname>
					<email>Pr.azimi7@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			The present research investigates the impact of organizational change on improving Bank Shahr financial and economic performance. For this purpose, the impact of organizational change components on Bank Shahr financial and economic performance have been studied based on Weisbord Six-Box Model. Research method is descriptive-correlation. Population includes 150 staff managers and experts of Bank Shahr central office. 108 of them were selected as sample based on Cochran formula. Data collection tool is a questionnaire including 38 items in two organizational change and financial-economic performance sectors. After measuring its validity and reliability, the questionnaires were distributed among managers and experts with simple random sampling method. Collected data were analyzed based on structural equation analysis. The results indicated that 1. The model has a good fitness. 2. Organizational change has a significant impact on financial-economic performance of Bank Shahr. 3. The components of organizational change i.e. goals, structure, leadership, communication, reward, and ways to help have significant impact on financial-economic performance of Bank Shahr. 4. The prioritization of organizational change components are ranked in terms of degree of impact on financial-economic performance of Bank Shahr, leadership, ways to help, goals, communication, structure, and reward respectively.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Organizational change</keyword>
	<keyword>Weisbord model</keyword>
	<keyword>financial-economic performance</keyword>
	<keyword>Bank Shahr</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>6</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>113</first_page>
								  <last_page>125</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-668-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>19-670</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>5</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>18</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Assessing the Indicators of Good Governance in Development of Urban Tourism (Case Study: City of Tehran)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Naser</given_name>
					<surname>Aminian</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>MirAli</given_name>
					<surname>Seyyed Naghavi</surname>
					<email>asnagavi@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Manoochehr</given_name>
					<surname>Jahaniyan</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name>Seyyed Mohsen</given_name>
					<surname>Emami</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Urban tourism is proposed as one of the influential and stimulus factor in urban economy. Tourism and policy-making style in tourism development planning require the utilization of new techniques in urban governance. Municipalities, as main custodians of urban management, play an important role in preparing the ground for participatory space in urban tourism arena as well as empowering citizens in urban areas. Thus, by assessing the indicators of good governance in urban tourism management, the ground can be prepared to implement these 10 indicators i.e. marketing, collaborative partnership, responsiveness, efficiency and effectiveness, justice-orientation, law-orientation, accountability, investment safety, integrated management in policy-making, and financial transparency in Tehran Metropolis. In terms of data collection, this research is descriptive-correlation, and it is applied in terms of purpose, by using documentary and field studies. Data were collected by questionnaire distributed in two population samples including authorities and professors of Iranian Tourism Scientific Association during summer 2016. They were 240 people and 148 of them were selected randomly by using Morgan table. To collect data, a researcher-made questionnaire including 96 items was used. The reliability was 0.97. Survey data via structured questionnaire were distributed electronically among population. Data were analyzed by using Friedman test and SPSS software. The results indicated that among 10 intended indicators, marketing was identified as the most important index of good governance in urban tourism according to the respondents.&#160;
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>good governance</keyword>
	<keyword>indicators of good governance</keyword>
	<keyword>urban tourism</keyword>
	<keyword>city of Tehran</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>6</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>127</first_page>
								  <last_page>139</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-670-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
			
		</ListRecords>
		</OAI-PMH>
		 
  
  
  
  
 