<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <records>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>2345-2870</issn>
	<eissn>2588-6398</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2015-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>3</volume>
	<issue>12</issue>
	<startPage>1</startPage>
	<endPage>20</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">An Assessment of Effective Factors on Economic Empowerment (Case Study: Vulnerable Women in Tehran)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mehrdad Navabakhsh</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mostafa Azkiya</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mansour Vosouqi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Zahra sadat Moshir Estekhareh</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
             Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
             Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
             Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
             Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Empowerment is a process in which an individual will be aware of his needs, internal demands, and capabilities, and acquire necessary abilities aiming to achieve requests. Native notion of socio-economic empowerment, effective factors on growth and its barriers were studied by two qualitative (grounded theory) and quantitative (correlation analysis) in this research. Depth interview techniques, and focus group discussions, and participatory and direct observation were used for qualitative data collection, and Scott and GYF questionnaire was used for 111 samples for quantitative data collection in order to examine the obstacles of women&#8217;s empowerment based on three factors: attitude and the amount of experience, training, and women&#8217;s socio-economic status (employment) in the form of 33 items. The qualitative results show that employment, balancing income and expenses, savings and entrepreneurship have influential and determining role in continuation and sustainability of people&#8217;s economic empowerment. The overall results of qualitative research show that some relatives who live together, family-orientation, social capital, cooperation, social correlation, and supporting each other are some effective factors on empowerment growth. Also, the results of quantitative research indicate that two factors: training and employment are the most important effective factors on vulnerable women&#8217;s empowerment in empowerment staff of Tehran Municipality.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-255-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>empowerment</keyword>
	<keyword>vulnerable women</keyword>
	<keyword>grounded theory</keyword>
	<keyword>empowerment staff of Tehran Municipality</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>2345-2870</issn>
	<eissn>2588-6398</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2015-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>3</volume>
	<issue>12</issue>
	<startPage>21</startPage>
	<endPage>40</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">The Necessities of Qualitative Development of Training for Urban Economy and Financial Experts in Tehran Municipality</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Hamid Rahimiyan</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Kaveh Teymournejad</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Morteza Taheri</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
             Allameh Tabatabaei University, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
             Islamic Azad University, Central Tehran Branch, Tehran Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
             Allameh Tabatabaei University, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Human capital is one of the most important resources of an organization. If they are trained correctly and become capable, they can promote the organization and enhance its performance. Therefore, this research investigates the pathology of training courses aiming to present qualitative development strategies for urban economy and financial experts in Tehran Municipality. The research method is mixed exploratory. 13 financial and urban economy experts and the members of management and training center of Tehran Municipality were selected by purposive sampling and snowball methods in the qualitative section. Data collection tool was in semi-structured interview form. The result of qualitative section has been identified the existing damages in training courses of financial and urban economy experts in Tehran Municipality in seven aspects of educational need assessment, educational goals, educational content, educators, organizing education, assessment system, and motivational mechanisms. A research-made questionnaire including 40 items in seven aspects which was detected in the qualitative section was used for data collection in the quantitative section. For determining the validity and reliability of the questionnaire face validity and Cronbach&#8217;s alpha were used respectively that the amount was equal to 0.84. The population was all of the financial and urban economy experts, 227 people, in Tehran Municipality. 143 people of them were selected by using Cochran sampling formula with simple random sampling method. Descriptive and inferential statistical methods were used in order to analyze the data. Training requirements for quality development and the degree of their importance were studied. Finally, some strategies were suggested for qualitative development of training in need assessment, design, implementation, and assessment of training courses steps.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-256-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>qualitative development of training</keyword>
	<keyword>financial and urban economy experts</keyword>
	<keyword>Tehran Municipality</keyword>
	<keyword>human capital</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>2345-2870</issn>
	<eissn>2588-6398</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2015-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>3</volume>
	<issue>12</issue>
	<startPage>41</startPage>
	<endPage>57</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Applying New Approach to Develop a Strategy in Gold Industry (Case Study: Isfahan Urban Economy)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Majid Ebrahimi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Ali Fattahzadeh</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Javad Maali</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
             Sadra Institute of Higher Education, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
             Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
             Islamic Azad University, Central Tehran Branch, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The production of gold ornaments and artifacts is a local and national industry. Isfahan is one of the major metropolises which it has the first rank of gold industry, jewelry and silver in Iran. Obtained value added in this industry is not in a good position than other industries in Isfahan, however. Thus, more attention to this valuable industry will result in more development and growth and economic progress in Isfahan as well. Hence, the researcher tried to present an integrated framework in order to develop appropriate strategies in this metropolis which will help the growth and survival of the industry. For presenting a comprehensive framework strategy, SWOT has been used for determining the factors in this study. Major factors have been selected by using fuzzy linguistic variables and multi criteria decision making method. Using these factors, necessary conditions for enhancing value added obtained from this industry may be enhanced and more share of global markets will be gained.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-257-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>gold artifacts</keyword>
	<keyword>SWOT</keyword>
	<keyword>Isfahan urban economy</keyword>
	<keyword>MCDM</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>2345-2870</issn>
	<eissn>2588-6398</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2015-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>3</volume>
	<issue>12</issue>
	<startPage>59</startPage>
	<endPage>75</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">The Anticipation of Changes in Housing Prices in Urban Distressed Areas after Implementation of Renovation Projects Using Grey Method (Case Study: Majd Project, Mashhad Municipality district 2)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Sahar Soltani</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Maryam Hasannejad</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Morteza Bastam</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
             Member of Tourism Economy Department of Tourism Research Center, Mashhad, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
             Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Member of Tourism Economy Department in University of Jihad, Mashhad, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
             Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Mashhad, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Mutual connection between the structure of cities and economic factors often leads to economic feedbacks which caused by structural intervention. This intervention usually affects people, private and public sectors&#8217; decisions in urban land use through reducing or increasing economic costs or benefits of urban activities. The purpose of this study is prediction the changes in housing prices after implementation of distressed areas&#8217; rehabilitation projects in (Majd project) (one of the rehabilitation projects of distressed areas in Mashhad) by using Grey Theory to predict the future price of real estates. The results showed that the prediction of economic and structural developments in studied area may result in the changes of real estate nominal prices, which can be explained by the Adaptive Expectations Theory in economics. Even though the structural effects are the first and more visible impacts of distressed areas rehabilitation projects, the subsequent economic effects would appear with some delays (4 years for this study). The real estate prices in two study areas - out of four &#8211; have been affected more than others. In 2013, the implementation of Majd project caused 27 to 54 percent increase in real prices of housing in that area. The results of the Grey Theory represented that current increasing trend in real estate prices will continue in future in a way that until to the project completion time, the nominal prices of real estate in that area would increase by 30 percent in comparison to 2013. Eventually, some recommendations such as reforming local prices offered to exploit the economic benefits of increased prices of real estate.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-258-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Urban Economics</keyword>
	<keyword>urban distresed areas</keyword>
	<keyword>real estate prices</keyword>
	<keyword>Majd Project</keyword>
	<keyword>Grey Theory</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>2345-2870</issn>
	<eissn>2588-6398</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2015-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>3</volume>
	<issue>12</issue>
	<startPage>77</startPage>
	<endPage>97</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">The Impact of Organizational Learning on Economic and Social Accountability of Tehran Municipality (Case Study: Tehran Municipality Districts 1, 6, 8, 19, and 22)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Ali Akbar Qahramani</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Azamosadat Mostafavi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
             Islamic Azad University, Qazvin Branch, Qazvin, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
             Islamic Azad University, Qazvin Branch, Qazvin, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Today, most people expect social demands from organizations. They move toward social expectations in line with accountability. Many social experts have emphasized on the importance of learning in organizations. The aim of this research is studying the impact of organizational learning on economic and social accountability of Tehran Municipality. Case study is Tehran Municipality districts 1, 6, 8, 19, and 22 and 255 high-ranked and average managers are the population of this research. The reliability of data collection tool was assessed by Cronbach&#8217;s alpha and estimated 0.98. Kolmogorov-Smirnov test, Pearson correlation coefficient, sample T test, T statistics in SPSS and LISREL were used for data collection. Confirmatory Factor analysis and Structural Equation Modeling were used for studying construct validity of the questionnaire and testing the hypothesis and model fitting concept respectively. According to the obtained results, there is a positive and significant relationship between organizational learning and social accountability. Multiple coefficient of determination (R2) shows that the variable of organizational learning could predict 0.69 percent of social accountability.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-259-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>urban management</keyword>
	<keyword>economic accountability</keyword>
	<keyword>organizational learning</keyword>
	<keyword>social responsibility</keyword>
	<keyword>Municipality of Tehran districts</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>2345-2870</issn>
	<eissn>2588-6398</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2015-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>3</volume>
	<issue>12</issue>
	<startPage>99</startPage>
	<endPage>118</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Structural Analysis, Measurement of Spatial Distribution Model and Classification the Construction of Urban Areas Based on Benefit from Urban Services (Case Study: Five Districts of Zahedan)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Behrouz Darvish</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Rahim Sarvar</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Fereshteh Sheybani Moghaddam</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
             Islamic Azad University, Science and Research branch, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
             Islamic Azad University, Shahr Rey branch, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
             Islamic Azad University, Science and Research branch, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Heterogeneity of distribution system of urban services is one of the most important consequences of the rapid growth of urbanization and physical development of cities in the country in the past decades. It has paved the way for social injustice and having urban services land uses in the regions and neighborhoods of a city. This research has been developed in order to measure access level of residents in urban areas of Zahedan for required facilities and services. Initially, per capita of status quo of each individual from service uses of city&#8217;s status quo was extracted by using data and information of Zahedan comprehensive urban plan and then the extent and distribution of land uses in five districts of Zahedan were&#160; examined by utilizing Williamson and entropy models. Finally, each district was evaluated and ranked in terms of having facilities and services. The results of Williamson and entropy models show unbalanced distribution and lack of services in district 4 due to large and increasing population. Balanced distribution of services is seen in district 5 and studying results of having urban services and facilities due to TOPSIS model shows that there is a big difference among urban areas in terms of accessibility and urban services so that the highest amount of TOPSIS for district 5 is 0.894 and the lowest amounts are 0.058 and 0.178 for districts 2 and 4 respectively.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-260-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>urban services</keyword>
	<keyword>spatial distribution</keyword>
	<keyword>Williamson model</keyword>
	<keyword>entropy model</keyword>
	<keyword>TOPSIS technique</keyword>
	<keyword>Zahedan</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>2345-2870</issn>
	<eissn>2588-6398</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2015-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>3</volume>
	<issue>12</issue>
	<startPage>119</startPage>
	<endPage>135</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Spatial Ranking of Public Services and their Shortage in Cities (Case Study: Noorabad Mamsani City)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Ali Shamsoddini</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Reza Amiri Fahlyiani</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
             , Islamic Azad University, Marvdasht Branch, Marvdasht, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
             Shahid Chamran University, Ahwaz, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">One of the criteria of social justice and urban sustainable development is considering balanced distribution of infrastructures and urban facilities therefore, the distribution of the services should be in such a way that not only it creates spatial justice in the areas, but it also prepare the ground for urban development. This research has descriptive-analytical approach and tries to recognize and rank the rate of existing services in 13 neighborhoods of Noorabad Mamsani City in Fars Province using education, health, and cultur, sport, office, green space, and facility indexes. For this purpose, initially the prosperity of services in these areas was examined by using models of the coefficient of variation and statistical techniques and then, the rate of prosperity of urban services in these neighborhoods was evaluated and analyzed by using multiple criteria decision making (MCDM) model based on TOPSIS approach. The results show that there are significant discrepancies regarding the rate of prosperity of services among 13 neighborhoods of Noorabad so that central areas of the city i.e. neighborhoods 1 and 2 in district 2, are prosperous and nomadic areas are prosper less. Eventually, there is imbalance and inequality among different areas in this city regarding concentration of population and access in terms of spatial distribution of services.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-261-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>urban services</keyword>
	<keyword>urban sustainable development</keyword>
	<keyword>urban management</keyword>
	<keyword>TOPSIS model</keyword>
	<keyword>Noorabad Mamsani</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>2345-2870</issn>
	<eissn>2588-6398</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2015-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>3</volume>
	<issue>12</issue>
	<startPage>137</startPage>
	<endPage>154</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">The Modeling of Locating Method in Regenerating Urban Distressed Areas (Case Study: Zeynabiyeh Area in Isfahan)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Masoud Shafiei Dastjerdi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Peyman Moradiyan Borujeni</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
             Dolat Abad branch, Islamic Azad University, Isfahan, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
             Tarbiyat Modarres University, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Urban regeneration is a comprehensive plan preparing the ground for sustainable improvement in economic, physical, social, and environmental condition in a city. Locating urban regeneration projects is one of the most important steps of the plan. The result of the negligence is failure in the implementation of projects or the imposition of financial, social, and cultural damages to cities. The current study intends to verify the hypothesis that following complex, multi-dimensions, and particularly presented models in this paper are considerably more effective on locating projects through presenting an exact locating model and measuring its accuracy in the case study. 13 criteria and 32 sub-criteria of economic, social, physical, environmental, and administrative information have been simultaneously used in locating process in the proposed model. Compatibility Coefficient for the importance of options in AHP model has been calculated and verified by utilizing GIS instrument. Data were collected from the case study by field method to locate the projects. The results show that there is a direct and significant relation between the place of projects and socio-economic variables in the environment.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-262-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>decay</keyword>
	<keyword>regeneration</keyword>
	<keyword>prioritization</keyword>
	<keyword>AHP</keyword>
	<keyword>Zeynabiyeh area in Isfahan</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
 </records>
 
  
  
  
  
 