<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <records>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>2345-2870</issn>
	<eissn>2588-6398</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2016-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>4</volume>
	<issue>14</issue>
	<startPage>1</startPage>
	<endPage>17</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Prioritization of Management Indexes of Municipal Solid Waste in Line with Sustainable Development (Case Study: City of Bokan)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Hossein Saraei</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Zahra Jamshidi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Navid Ahangari</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
             University of Yazd, Yazd, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
             University of Yazd, Yazd, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
             Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Non-systematic management of municipal solid waste prepares the ground for the creation of human and environmental problems in long run. Therefore, sustainable and effective municipal waste management strategy is needed to balance the development, quality of life and environment. This paper has been developed to evaluate the management indicators of municipal solid waste in accordance with sustainable development in Bukan by using TOPIS technique. Research method is survy (questionnaire and field study) and describtive- analytical data analysis was used. The statistical population was the city&#8217;s population of 171,773 people with the sample of 384 people. It was reduced to 330 due to the limitations of the study. Findings show that 150 tons of waste are produced daily on average in the city of Bukan and the waste per capita is 0.740 kg per day. The most amount of produced solid waste is related to organic materials with 75.82 and the least amount is related to wood with 0.65 percent. The final obtained ranking of satisfaction rate of sustainable development indexes of solid waste management by TOPSIS method has indicated that the factor of tip request was in the first rank and the factor of advertisement attractiveness was in the 20th rank that is the least important one.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-392-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Municipal solid waste management</keyword>
	<keyword>sustainable development</keyword>
	<keyword>TOPSIS technique</keyword>
	<keyword>city of Bukan</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>2345-2870</issn>
	<eissn>2588-6398</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2016-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>4</volume>
	<issue>14</issue>
	<startPage>19</startPage>
	<endPage>38</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Factors Affecting Land and Housing Market Changes (Case Study: Padideh Tourism Compony-Shandiz City in 2009-2014)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Zahra Anabestani</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Rahim Sarvar</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Masoud Mahdavi Hajilouei</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
             Islamic Azad university, Science and Research Branch, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
             Islamic Azad university, Science and Research Branch, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
             Islamic Azad university, Science and Research Branch, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">When the large urban projects (Mega Project) to be loaded on a national scale in a small town, you can see dramatic changes in the market for land and housing in urban settlements. This paper attempts to study the impact of presence and activity of Padideh Shandiz Tourism Company on land and housing market changes examined in 2009 to 2014 from the perspective of citizens. Regarding purpose, this research is applied. Data were collected via library, field study (questionnaire), and descriptive method was used for data analysis (mean, standard deviation) and inferential statistics (factor analysis and one-sample t-test) were performed. The statistical population community, including families living in Shandiz City on the basis of the 2011 census, with a 10,428 population of 3056 households and is required sample size of 160 households was based on Cochran formula. The findings indicate that the direct effects caused by the presence and activities of Padideh Shandiz Tourism Company in the time interval studied, the statistic 43.6% of the biggest impacts on the land and housing market changes have had on the town. Also based on one sample t-test showed a significant difference between the mean and median of the theoretical (3) Shandiz City from the perspective of citizens that are substantially influence of these factors on land and housing market changes. According to the findings, strategies including attention to urban managements of land and housing market changes in the future, due to the low-income indigenous housing, prevention of social conflicts, provision of infrastructure, etc. have been proposed.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-393-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Padideh Tourism Company</keyword>
	<keyword>environmental factors</keyword>
	<keyword>urban management</keyword>
	<keyword>urban housing</keyword>
	<keyword>Shandiz City</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>2345-2870</issn>
	<eissn>2588-6398</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2016-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>4</volume>
	<issue>14</issue>
	<startPage>39</startPage>
	<endPage>62</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Strategic Planning for the Organizing of Urban Old Textures (Case Study: Shahidgah-Sheikh Safi Neighborhood in Ardabil City)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Nader Zaali</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Majid Zareie</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Saman Ebizadeh</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Farshid Hashemzadeh Ghalehjogh</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
             University of Gilan, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
             Imam Khomeini International University, Qazvin, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
             Islamic Art University of Tabriz, Tabriz, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
             University of Gilan, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Currently, old textures are one of the main problems in many cities and even villages in our country. The specific feature of these textures makes it necessary to be considered from different aspects. This study is trying to find strategies to improve and organize old texture in the Shahidgah neighborhood of Ardabil. It also aims to plan and design in accordance with the existing status and consistent with strategic priorities. In this regard, using review of documents and field surveys, existing status of the neighborhood were evaluated using SWOT analysis and planning strategies. Continuing with the quantitative models used, organizing strategies are prioritized. Finally, five design alternatives presented in accordance with texture requirements. Findings indicate that the organizing of the studied area should adopt a systematic approach for 4 dimensions of physical, economic, social and environmental interventions to deal with. The preferred alternative has tried to organize and remove the ruined buildings in the middle of the area, a closeness be created and the central space is used to create a neighborhood center.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-394-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Organizing</keyword>
	<keyword>old texture</keyword>
	<keyword>Strategic Planning</keyword>
	<keyword>SWOT</keyword>
	<keyword>Shahidgah neighborhood</keyword>
	<keyword>Ardabil</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>2345-2870</issn>
	<eissn>2588-6398</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2016-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>4</volume>
	<issue>14</issue>
	<startPage>63</startPage>
	<endPage>76</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">An Analysis of Socio-Economic Impacts of National Carpet Museum of Tabriz</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Kasra Rahbaripoor</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Hassan Sattari Sarebangholi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Rasool Darskhan</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
             Islamic Azad University, Tabriz branch, Tabriz, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
             Islamic Azad University, Tabriz branch, Tabriz, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
             Islamic Azad University, Tabriz branch, Tabriz, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">This research has been done to identify the impacts of implementing the project of carpet museum of Tabriz from different aspects particularly economic and social dimensions on various groups of citizens and local society. It has been tried to study intrinsic, instrumental, and institutional values of this museum in the form of social and economic impacts. Combined approach of participatory and technocratic has been used and the results of both methods have been listed in research findings, conclusion, and management of consequences. Survey method has been used. 142 people are sample including inhabitants, salespersons, passengers, and experts in the field of carpet and urban management. Respondents were selected both randomly and purposefully so that inhabitants and passengers were selected randomly and salespersons and experts were chosen purposefully. The results indicate relative agreement between people&#8217;s ideas and experts&#8217; about social, economic, and human impacts of the project. The findings show that building this museum may have positive impacts including employment, preparing the ground for investment, economic boom of the area, and socially positive results such as development of social interactions of ordinary people and experts together, and increasing people&#8217;s knowledge about carpet industry. Crowd, traffic, discomfort for residents, and disruption of the social homogeneous texture of the neighborhood can be noted as negative impacts.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-395-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>museum</keyword>
	<keyword>assessment of social impact</keyword>
	<keyword>intrinsic value</keyword>
	<keyword>instrumental value</keyword>
	<keyword>institutional value</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>2345-2870</issn>
	<eissn>2588-6398</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2016-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>4</volume>
	<issue>14</issue>
	<startPage>77</startPage>
	<endPage>99</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">An Analysis on the Price of Urban Land in Iran’s Provinces during 2001 to 2011</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Ghanbari</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Ajza Shokuhi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Rahim Rahnama</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Omid Ali Kharazmi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
             Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Mashhad, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
             Ferdowsi University of Mashhad    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
             Ferdowsi University of Mashhad    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
             Ferdowsi University of Mashhad    
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Attention to land, as one of the principal and renewable sources in urban sustainable development, is a necessary task since it is considered as one of the main sources of urban sustainable development. The purpose of this research is an analysis on the price of urban land in different provinces of Iran during 2001 to 2011. The research method is documentary and library techinque was used for data collection. PASW, GeoDa, and GIS soft wares were used for data analysis. Research findings indicate random distribution of urban land price during 2001 to 2011 in different provinces. According to Enter regression test, it was specified that there is no significant relationship between the variables of urbanization percentage and the average of land area of urban buildings with the price of urban land in 2001, but there was a significant relationship between these variables in 2006 and 2011. However, there is a significant relationship between development level of provinces and the price of urban land in 2011 in some provinces at the level of 95 percent. After studying the changes in the average price of urban land of Iran&#8217;s provinces during 2001 to 2011, it was specified that the average coefficient of variation of urban land price was equal to 827.73 and Bushehr, Khorasan Razavi, and Hamedan provinces had the highest coefficient of variation and Kordestan, Hormozgan, and Khuzestan provinces had the least.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-397-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>price of urban land</keyword>
	<keyword>urbanization</keyword>
	<keyword>province</keyword>
	<keyword>area</keyword>
	<keyword>Iran</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>2345-2870</issn>
	<eissn>2588-6398</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2016-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>4</volume>
	<issue>14</issue>
	<startPage>101</startPage>
	<endPage>113</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Determining Non-Linear Causality between Urban and Non-Urban Ground Transport and Economic Growth Using Wavelet Neural Network (Case Study: Iran)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Ali Hosein Samadi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Jafar Qaderi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Zahoor Nejadhalafi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
             Faculty of Economics, University of Shiraz, Shiraz, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
             Faculty of Economics, University of shiraz, shiraz, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
             Faculty of Economics, University of shiraz, shiraz, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">In the last few decades, the relationship between economic infrastructures, particularly transport sector, and economic growth has been the subject of many reserachers in different economies. Iran has many advantages considering particular geographic situation in terms of transport facilities as it connects many countries. In this study, the relationship among ground transport, economic growth, capital formation , and work force was examined by using quarterly data during 1992 to 2012. Required data were extracted from the statistics of Centeral Bank of Islamic Republic of Iran and yearbooks of Statistical Center of Iran. The most important difference of this study compared to other previous studies is using wavelet neural network method and non-linear approach in explaining the relationship among discussed variables. The results of causal relationship test between variables imply the existence of causality from ground transport to economic growth.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-398-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>economic growth</keyword>
	<keyword>transport</keyword>
	<keyword>neural network</keyword>
	<keyword>causality</keyword>
	<keyword>Iran</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>2345-2870</issn>
	<eissn>2588-6398</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2016-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>4</volume>
	<issue>14</issue>
	<startPage>115</startPage>
	<endPage>136</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Effective Factors on Urban Brand and Their Prioritization from Perspective of International Tourists (Case Study: Tehran’s Milad Tower)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Naser Aminian</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Ali Hassani</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
             University of Science and Culture, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
             University of Science and Culture, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Urban tourism is a part of international tourism market having the most development potential in the recent years. In 2015, tourists&#8217; willingness to visit Iran and its historical and cultural attractions and symbols has been increased. Tehran, as the capital, is the most suitable alternative of urban tourism destination for international tourists. Its urban attractive symbols have had important role in this regard; therefore, the main purpose of this research is to identify and determine prioritization of Tehran Milad Tower brand aspects from perspective of international tourists. This research is descriptive-survey, with applied purpose, by using documentary and field studies. To collect data, questionnaire was used; it was distributed among international visitors of Tehran Milad Tower during September to November 2015. At first, primary questionnaire was distributed as pilot among a group of 30 international visitors of Milad Tower, and its validity and reliability were confirmed. Then, revised questionnaires, including 20 items, were distributed among 240 people as sample based on available sampling. Data were analyzed by using Friedman test and SPSS software. The results indicated that popularity of brand name, with the ranking average of 4.98, as the most important priority in choosing a visiting place, was identified from perspective of tourists.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-401-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>urban brand</keyword>
	<keyword>aspects of urban brand</keyword>
	<keyword>urban tourist</keyword>
	<keyword>Tehran Milad Tower</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>2345-2870</issn>
	<eissn>2588-6398</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2016-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>4</volume>
	<issue>14</issue>
	<startPage>137</startPage>
	<endPage>157</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">The Role of Informal Jobs in Relieving Informal Settlement (Case Study: Hesaramir of Pakdasht)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Fatemeh Salarvandiyan</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Seyyed Ali Hosseini</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Leyla Habibi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Maryam Jafari Mehrabadi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
             Faculty of Geography, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
             Faculty of Geography, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
             Handicrafts and Tourism, University of Mazandaran, Mazandaran, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
             Department of Geography, university of Gilan, Gilan, Iran    
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">New theories in empowerment have been focused on the role of spontaneous solutions of suburbanites in the recent years. One of the scientific strategies that inhabitants of informal settlements use for solving the problems of marginalization is to choose informal economy and spontaneous jobs. This research has descriptive-analytical approach emphasizing on questionnaire in order to study the role of such occupations as a solution arisen from these societies in order to relieve the issue of informal settlement among informal habitats of Hesaramir in Pakdasht. Cochran Formula was used to determine sample size. 25303 people of total population of Hesaramir were considered as a statistical population; therefore, 378 people were selected. SWOT technique indicated that development of spontaneous jobs in the informal settlements of Hesaramir of Pakdasht has very high strengths (3.33 scores in terms of internal factors and 3.34 scores in terms of external factors). One sample t tests and chi-square were used to analyze the questionnaires. Chi-square test results showed that there is a significant relationship between the gender of the studied people and tendency to spontaneous jobs with the probability of 95%. T and Kolmogorov-Smirnov tests were used to show the impact of spontaneous jobs on economic recovery. The results of Kolmogorov-Smirnov test indicate that tendency to such jobs has leaded to the improvement of economic situation. T-test indicates the significance level less than 0.05 showing the impact of these jobs on the improvement of economic situation.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-399-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>informal settlement</keyword>
	<keyword>spontaneous jobs</keyword>
	<keyword>informal economy of the city</keyword>
	<keyword>SWOT</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
 </records>
 
  
  
  
  
 