@article{ 
author = {Mohammadi, Mahmood and Shahivandi, Ahmad and MoradiChadgani, Dariush and Rastghalam, Niloofar},  
title = {Assessing the Impact of Competitiveness on Urban Network Transformation Using Social Network Analysis (Case: Isfahan City-Region)}, 
abstract ={Abstract: The urban network is a collection of large and small cities, each of which, in terms of size and performance, affects the evolutionary process of the area. This study uses the two concepts of competitiveness and urban network to investigate the effective factors in the occurrence and intensification of inequalities in the urban network of Esfahan. In this regard, the changes and transformations of Esfahan urban network during three periods of 1375, 1385 and 1395 with regard to competitiveness indices and considering the distance between cities (based on flow analysis method) and creation of competitiveness matrix, using urban network mapping In the social network analysis (Gephi) software is measured. In this way, for each concept at any given time, a separate network is plotted and analyzed. The results indicate that in the mentioned periods distribution of competitive ability as a stream of capital, labor, and information in the city-region of Esfahan has been unfair. As far as the metropolis of Esfahan with much difference, the gap in the urban hierarchy of city-regions Based on the concept of competitiveness. The second place in comparison with this view belongs to Najafabad and the third place belongs to Falavarjan. In addition, except for a few exceptions, the process of changing cities' competitiveness has been consistent with the process of changing the hierarchy of cities in the same time frame. Therefore, it can be said that the urban hierarchy pattern in the Esfahan urban network follows a competitive ranking.},  
Keywords = {Competitiveness, Urban Network, Esfahan City-Region, Social Network Analysis},
volume = {7},
Number = {25}, 
pages = {1-15}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1072-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1072-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {JafarzadehNajar, Morteza and Hooshmand, Mahmood and Lotfalipour, Mohammad Reza and Behname, Mahdi},  
title = {Investigating the Possibility of Using Waqf and Interest-Free Bonds to Finance Public Spaces in the Surrounding Texture of Holy Shrine of Imam Reza}, 
abstract ={Abstract: One of the most important and vital tissues in the country is the context around the Holy Shrine of Imam Reza. The main problem about this context is the lack of funding for public spaces. In the present study, the willingness of people to participate in the improvement of the worn out texture surrounding the Shrine of Imam Reza is estimated by purchasing waqf bonds and interest-free bonds, using the conditional valuation method. For this purpose, 240 pilgrims and adjacent persons were interviewed. In order to distinguish the factors influencing the decision on participation and the level of participation, two-stage method of Heckman and Tobit model were used. By eliminating incomplete answers, 57% of the people were willing to buy waqf bonds and, 48% of the people were willing to buy interest-free bonds. The results of the Hackit Model showed that the variables of &#8220;trust in local institutions&#8221; and &#8220;social awareness&#8221; influence significantly on respondents&#8217; decision to buy bonds. In addition, the &#8220;sense of belonging to the city&#8221; affects the degree of willingness to participate. In the case of interest-free bonds, the variable of social awareness has a significant effect on the decision of the respondents to participate in it. The variables of sense of belonging to the city and the neighborhood and the household&#8217;s economic situation have an impact on the degree of willingness to participate. While the belief in interest-free bonds and the variables of trust in local institutions, both in the first stage (decision to pay) and in the second stage (willingness to pay), have a significant effect on respondents. The average willingness to participate was estimated at 7,450,000 Rials for interest-free bonds and it was 1,660,000 for waqf bonds.},  
Keywords = {Waqf bonds, Interest-free bonds, Financing, Renovation and Improvement, Texture around the Holy Shrine, Public Spaces},
volume = {7},
Number = {25}, 
pages = {17-33}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1073-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1073-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {MajnoonyToutakhane, Ali and Soleymani, Alirez},  
title = {Planning for Strengthening the City’s Economic Infrastructure with an Emphasis on Sustainable Tourism (Case: Ardebil City)}, 
abstract ={Abstract: In the present era, the tourism industry was introduced as one of the pillars of sustainable development and as a powerful tool for economic, social and environmental impacts which, while attracting the participation of the local community in the development of the national economy, has the potential of preserving and protecting natural resources, making environmental sustainability. Today, sustainable development policy is a public approach that governments have been considering to make ecologically sustainable tourism a promising local community in the long run. In this regard, the present study was conducted with the aim of planning sustainable development in the city of Ardebil. The research method is a descriptive-analytic type with an applied purpose. The data used in the research is documentary and field research. In order to achieve the most urgent and deterrent forces in the development of sustainable urban tourism, through the completion of a questionnaire and interview with 40 experts from urban tourism, effective strategies encouraging and inhibiting the development of sustainable tourism were formulated. Then, they were weighed and prioritized, using the network analysis (ANP) model. Finally, based on the most important adversary and deterrent forces, the most sustainable strategies for sustainable tourism development in Ardebil were extracted. The results of the research show that among the forces that encourage sustainable development of the city (creation of employment) the highest priority and among the inhibitory forces of sustainable development of the city (lack of sustainable management in the urban tourism sector) have the highest priority. Seven strategies were also identified and developed for the most important adversary and deterrent forces of city tourism development. Among the strategies proposed, the strategy (optimal and targeted utilization of increased incentives for travel among people to exploit the attractions and products of tourism in order to create employment and income for the people of Ardabil city) was selected as the best strategy. Moreover, in this research, the spatial pattern of the elemental inhabitants of Ardabil city was examined using the geographic information system (GIS) and it was determined that the tourism space of Ardabil city is influenced by the historical space of the city (old texture) and covers the central part of the city (area 1).},  
Keywords = {Planning, City Economic Development, Sustainable Tourism, Network Analysis, Ardebil},
volume = {7},
Number = {25}, 
pages = {35-50}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1074-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1074-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {FallahTafti, Hamed and HeydariKooshaknoo, Majid and AlmasiSarvestani, Raziyeh},  
title = {Understanding of Smart Citizen Components in Urban Environment with Technological Learning Approach (Case: Yazd City)}, 
abstract ={Abstract: Smart citizenship component has been forgotten in the light of the theory of smart growth and urban excellence. In this theory, most urban planners and planners only study the indicators of the economy and exceptional services in cities, and the lifestyle and culture of citizens and its impact. They are less concerned with urban development. In this regard, in this research, Yazd city has been selected as the study to evaluate the indicators of smart citizens and its components in urban development and excellence. A survey from a sample of citizens, appropriate data was collected through a multi-criteria questionnaire with desirable validity and reliability. Using SPSS software, exploratory factor analysis was used to determine the validity and reliability of independent and dependent variables and then the named components were named. In the next step, using the confirmatory factor analysis in AMOS software, the validity of the research structures was tested. The statistical relation between the variables and their indices was confirmed. In the final model, using the fittest tests, the relationships between the variables and the effect of independent and dependent variables were confirmed. Findings of the research indicate that the significance of the law-governed factor is 31.579 percent of the variance explained more than other factors and citizens consider the role of law-governed in the characteristics of the smart citizen more critical. From the perspective of citizens, the optimal use of information and communication technology and the formation of the smart city have a positive effect on the various economic, social, and environmental dimensions of Yazd city. So while recognizing the need for training with new ways and content, they see the role of ICT in better life experience.},  
Keywords = {Smart Citizen, Smart City, Yazd City, Urban Environment, Technological Learning},
volume = {7},
Number = {25}, 
pages = {51-62}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1075-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1075-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {MehmandoostGhamsari, Zahra Sadat and FathiVajargah, Koorosh and Khorasani, Abasalt and SafayiMovahed, Saei},  
title = {Identification and Validation of Effective Factors on the Establishment of Workplace Curriculum Model Emphasizing on Economic Development Consequences}, 
abstract ={Abstract: The work environment curriculum is one of the emerging disciplines of the curriculum seeking to apply the findings of this study in the work environment. This study aims to investigate the effective factors on the establishment of a work environment curriculum-model in related documents and to identify its economic consequences. For this purpose, the relevant documents have been examined from the beginning. The research population includes all published works in this field from 1993 to 2017 in eight valid databases. The content of the documents was to categorize and organize the effective factors on the deployment of the work environment curriculum using the MAXQDA18 software. Then Delphi technique was used to validate these factors. The most important factors identified are individual, background, and occupational ones. Finally, the economic growth and development consequences of the establishment of curriculum in organizations were investigated that included individual factors (improving the learning process, improving relationships with colleagues, increasing work engagement and career progression), and organizational factors (organizational learning, process improvement, product improvement, lower cost, human capital development).},  
Keywords = {Validation, Work Environment Curriculum, Economic Growth, Organization},
volume = {7},
Number = {25}, 
pages = {63-79}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1076-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1076-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {JaliliKamjo, Parviz and Nademi, Younes},  
title = {Oil Price Shocks and Housing Business Cycles in Iran: Markov Regime-Switching GARCH Model}, 
abstract ={Abstract: The housing market is one of the most important subsectors of capital markets that have the most backward and forward linkages with other sectors. Because of the high dependence of Iranian economy to oil revenues, oil price shocks can be affect the housing market. The aim of this study is to analyze the business cycle of the housing market, with emphasis on the impact of oil shocks on the return of housing. According to APM model, regardless of portfolio selected, several factors affect the return of housing assets that in this study, the risk and shocks of macroeconomic factors including money supply, private sector investment, housing facilities allocated by special Maskan Bank and oil export revenues, have been analyzed on the housing return by a Markov regime-switching GARCH model during the period 1982 -2016. The results have shown that the return of housing in the Iranian economy has three high, moderate and low return regimes. So that the volatility of the housing return is different in each of the three regimes. Housing returns volatility at the low return regime is more than volatility of returns at the moderate and high return regimes. Therewith in the 35 years of the research period, housing market has been 13 years in the moderate return regime, 20 years in the low return regime and only 2 years in the high return regime. The results also showed that based on Dutch disease hypothesis oil shocks, liquidity and private investment have a significant positive impact on the return of housing but the housing facilities of Maskan Bank have a significant negative impact on the return of housing.},  
Keywords = {Oil Price Shocks, Business Cycles, Markov Switching GARCH Approach, Iranian Housing Market},
volume = {7},
Number = {25}, 
pages = {81-98}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1077-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1077-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Hosseini, Abbas and Mojibi, Tooraj and MahdizadehAshrafi, Ali and Vazifehdoost, Hossei},  
title = {Designing a Policy Model for the Development of Small and Medium Enterprises (SMEs) Emphasizing on Innovation (Case: Ministry of Cooperatives, Labor and Social Welfare)}, 
abstract ={Abstract: Employment and the achievement of people in the desired job are considered as one of the most basic needs of the society, and the elimination of unemployment as a social, economic and cultural destructive phenomenon is one of the most important concerns of policy makers and planners in different countries. In addition it is and one of the main indicators of development of societies. In most countries, the solution to achieve this is through the provision of the infrastructure needed to set up and run small and medium-sized enterprises. Given the importance of small and medium enterprises in the process of economic and social development of countries and the special attention of planners and development policymakers to this important issue, policy makers need to adopt a policy suitable for the growth and development of small and medium-sized enterprises. However, the policy-making of the aforementioned businesses, from a theoretical perspective, requires an accurate basis to help create an entrepreneurial economy with more entrepreneurs and achieve the goals set by the country. Accordingly, this research aims at designing a policy framework for the development of small and medium-sized enterprises, with an emphasis on innovation and making use of domestic and international knowledge and experience to improve the policy process of small and medium-sized enterprises development and its numerous valuable results, especially in terms of employment assistance and unemployment reduction. In this paper, an attempt has been made to construct a proper framework for conducting research based on previous research and documentary studies. Then, based on the initial framework, a deep study and a case study were analyzed using the interviewing tool and study documents to extract the conceptual model. To analyze the extracted data from interviews, open source and axial coding was used. Finally, the resulting pattern in four dimensions was drawn from the effective factors on business development, development policies, policy-making bodies, and the performance of small and medium businesses.},  
Keywords = {Policy Model, Development of Small and Medium Enterprises (SMEs), Innovation},
volume = {7},
Number = {25}, 
pages = {99-115}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1078-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1078-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {},  
title = {}, 
abstract ={},  
Keywords = {},
volume = {7},
Number = {25}, 
pages = {117-133}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1079-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1079-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {BaghersadRanani, Mansour and Varesi, Hamidreza and Taghvaei, Masou},  
title = {An Evaluation of Large-Scale Commercial Buildings Architectural Space Indicators with an Approach to Urban Threats and Risks}, 
abstract ={Abstract: Achieving to technical criteria that by applying them in architectural design stage of large commercial buildings, considered as one of the most important uses in urban planning, can increase the level of citizens&#8217; security against all kinds of natural hazards and threats, and reduce vulnerability and it can provide continuation of the services and activities of these buildings. The present study has a developmental-applied nature. By descriptive-survey method, the issue is investigated in large-scale commercial buildings. In this research, to assess the architectural space of large-scale commercial buildings, five criteria including continuity of activities in emergencies, costs, facilitating emergency exit, reducing the impact of explosions and earthquakes are considered. In this research, using Swara and Smart methods, the subject matter and the proposed model for evaluating the vulnerability of the architectural space are discussed. The results of the evaluation of the criteria and indicators of the architectural space indicate that the criteria for reducing the effect of the explosion, facilitating emergency exit, the continuity of activities in crisis, earthquake and cost with the weights of 0.3056, 0.2778, 0.2315, 1852.0 and 0.1543 are ranked first to fifth. Using the proposed model, the architecture of large-scale commercial buildings can be evaluated against urban threats and vulnerabilities, as well as the vulnerability and weaknesses of these buildings in each indicator and criterion.},  
Keywords = {Architectural space, threats, compatibility, vulnerability, passive defense, large-scale commercial building},
volume = {7},
Number = {26}, 
pages = {1-14}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1188-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1188-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Rezaeian, Sajad and Asgari, Heshmatolah and Darvishi, Bagher},  
title = {The Study of Determinants of Rent Housing in Ilam City Based on Hedonic Spatial Econometrics}, 
abstract ={Abstract: Housing unit is heterogeneous and multidimensional commodity; therefore, to determine effective factors on rent, hedonic pricing model is used. To explain the factors, four properties are used for housing, which are physical variables of residential units, access variables, environmental variables (neighborhood), and economic and social characteristics. The variables related to the spatial property are used by spatial hedonics to bind the lease function to the location. Spatial hedonic technique is able to determine the effective factors on the rental of housing, also the impact of renting housing from other properties of adjacent ones. In this paper, using linear, semi-logarithmic, logarithmic and box-cox models, the effect of each of the properties of leased residential units on their rental prices has been investigated using simple and spatial hedonic function. The results indicate that the best model is the linear model. Moreover, among the residential apartments in Ilam, physical and socioeconomic factors affect the rental of residential units more than neighborhoods and access variables, as well as the effect of spatial dependent variable in spatial hedonic model on rentals is quite significant and positive. The estimated model of spatial econometric method is well fitted; the percentage of coefficients and the explanation of the effect of the variables in the model are more efficient and better than conventional econometric methods.},  
Keywords = {Rent, Hedonic, Spatial Econometric, Spatial Dependence, Spatial Heterogeneity},
volume = {7},
Number = {26}, 
pages = {15-27}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1189-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1189-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Mortezavi, Morteza and Sheykh, Rez},  
title = {Optimization of Urban Budget Allocation Based on Spatial Justice Indicators (Case: Mashhad Metropolis)}, 
abstract ={Abstract: One of the main responsibilities of urban managers is to create justice in the area of fair and equal access of citizens to urban services. By objective realization of spatial justice concept, while providing the citizens with the appropriate services, the ground of reducing urban problems is prepared. Spatial justice is one of the main concepts of sustainable urban development. This can be achieved by making the right decision about the allocation of the city budget. Recognizing prosperous and non-prosperous areas fair and informed allocation of financial resources among urban areas require the use of a technique that takes into account different and sometimes conflicting criteria for decision making. In this research, using PROMETHEE V-C technique, it has been tried to examine Mashhad metropolitan financial resources to thirteen areas, taking into account the criteria of spatial justice, in the form of a case study. The results indicate that the holy city of Mashhad is not in desirable position in terms of spatial justice indicators. Samen area is recognized as the most prosperous and district 3 as the most deprived area in the city of Mashhad. The high ability of the proposed technique to allocate budget equitably with multiple indicators has been shown in this study; therefore, this technique can be used as an effective tool for urban decision-making.},  
Keywords = {Spatial Justice, Resource Allocation, Urban Facilities, Multi-Criteria Decision-Making Techniques, PROMETHEE V-C},
volume = {7},
Number = {26}, 
pages = {29-44}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1190-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1190-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Ghorbanizadeh, Vajhollah and Roodsaz, Habib and Sharifzadeh, Fatah and Sadeghi, Mohamm},  
title = {The Effect of Individual Knowledge Management on Organizational Performance of Tehran Municipality}, 
abstract ={Abstract: Today&#8217;s multidimensional and challenging environment has created dynamic and complex conditions for many organizations. Therefore, the development of many of the knowledge workers&#8217; skills and abilities is necessary in order to improve organizational performance. One of the key skills of individuals for organizational success is individual knowledge management. This paper examines the effects of individual knowledge management factors on organizational performance in Tehran municipality. This research is applied and a descriptive survey in terms of purpose. The statistical population of this research is managers, consultants, and technical experts of Tehran Municipality in the highest organizational occupation (three categories) in terms of career 15-16 14-16 including 2467 people. The statistical sample suitable for the present study is equal to 332 people based on the sampling method of limited communities at the error level of 0.05. In this research, a questionnaire was used to collect data. Structural Equation Modeling and LISREL software were used to study the final model of the research. The findings of the study confirmed the effect of components of self-learning evaluation, self-learning management, information literacy, knowledge consciousness, creative skills, participatory skills and collaborative network on organizational performance.},  
Keywords = {Individual Knowledge Management, Collaboration Network, Learning Management, Knowledge Intelligence, Organizational Performance},
volume = {7},
Number = {26}, 
pages = {45-58}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1191-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1191-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Zebardast, Esfandiyar and Ghanooni, Hossei},  
title = {An Analysis of Urban Sprawl Using Factor Analysis Technique (Case: Qazvin City Districts)}, 
abstract ={Abstract: Urban sprawl is an issue in many cities throughout the world, which has affected many aspects of urban life negatively. Urban sprawl, which is generally attributed to horizontal and leapfrogged extension of city boundaries caused by citizen&#8217;s will to leave central urban areas and live in urban countryside. The first step for tackling this problem is the identification of sprawled places and the influential factors on sprawl in urban land. Therefore, this article analyses urban sprawl phenomenon in Qazvin city districts. Relying on relevant theoretical texts, 13 indicators are chosen among others in literature for measuring urban sprawl in Qazvin districts. These indices are localized according to the conditions of Iran and the data associated with each of them are extracted using census statistics and Geographic Information System (GIS). Then, factor analysis technique is implemented by SPSS software and the indicators are attributed to four factors. By assessing the contributing indicators to each factor, they are named density, configuration, land-use and accessibility respectively. The results of factor analysis are very consistent with literature. These factors explain the variance of urban sprawl by 27.8, 21.6, 11.3 and 9.5 percent respectively. It is shown that &#34;shape index&#34; and &#34;fractal dimension&#34; as new indicators for measuring urban sprawl are significantly effective on this phenomenon. Results show that districts 4, 5, 7, 11 and 12 are the most sprawled and districts 17, 28, 38 and 39 are the least sprawled districts in Qazvin. These two new indexes in Iranian urban literature can be used in other sprawl studies in the country. In addition, the results of this study can guide Qazvin municipality to make important decisions about the direction of city development.},  
Keywords = {Urban Sprawl, Factor Analysis, Configuration, Qazvin},
volume = {7},
Number = {26}, 
pages = {59-78}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1192-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1192-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {GhaemiAsl, Mahdi and Manzoor, Davoud and MousaviBarrodi, Mahdi},  
title = {On-Grid Simulation of Distributed Generation (DG) of Renewable Electricity in Urban Lighting in the Context of Sustainable Urban Management (Case: Mashhad)}, 
abstract ={Abstract: Lighting passages is done for citizens&#8217; welfare simultaneously with the peak of the consumption of the network, from sunset to sunrise. The present study aimed at designing a model of sustainable urban management in the field of lighting, with simulation of the use of photovoltaic LEDs instead of sodium and halogen lamps. Accordingly, in a system simulation of the network, the scenarios for adjusting the input of various photovoltaic capacities to the electricity supply system of the city of Mashhad have been investigated. The results of on-grid analysis by using this decentralized production pattern shows, taking into account the 200 watts capacity and the 20% utilization factor for each photovoltaic LEDs and installing a photovoltaic LED instead of sodium and halogen lamps, all the power needed to lighting of city streets is provided by photovoltaic solar technology. Moreover, by reducing the potential between fossil and renewable production, emissions of pollutants are reduced by 104,000 tons. Therefore, this method can be used to manage clean and sustainable energy in urban scale consumption, and, while helping the environment and reducing air pollution, it prevents losses caused by the transfer of electrical energy from the plant to the place of consumption.},  
Keywords = {On-Grid Simulation, Sustainable Urban Management, Photovoltaic Technology},
volume = {7},
Number = {26}, 
pages = {79-92}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1193-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1193-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Moradi, Mohammad Ali},  
title = {Designing a Model for Improving Business Environment in the City of Tehran}, 
abstract ={Abstract: Improving the environment in which businesses operate is important to business success. In particular, improving the environment reduces transaction costs and improves the competitiveness of businesses. The business environment of the city has unique characteristics that need to be understood and analyzed in various aspects. This research aims to design a model for improving the business environment in the city of Tehran using exploratory approach to identify the components and dimensions of the model. For this purpose, firstly explicit knowledge exists in the literature is reviewed and then a qualitative research methodology is employed to explore the implicit knowledge of experts obtained through interviews with 22 experts. After documenting the data obtained from the interviews, a three stage coding method is used to analyze&#160; the collected information and data using Atlas Ti. In the end, by combining the findings from the literature and the findings from the analysis of the interviews, a model is designed for improving the business environment in Tehran. It is worth noting that this model has identified and classified environment factors affecting the improvement of the business environment at the four levels of organizational, micro, macro, and international. Urban environment components include physical infrastructure, non-physical infrastructure, laws and regulations, institutions, local-participatory governance, policy for citizenship, institutional co-operation, urban-level competition development, private-public partnerships, organising businesses in the interior and exterior of the city, identification and development of opportunities, implication of new knowledge and technology, sustainable income for urban development, urban spatial development, transaction costs and tax support. The components of the micro-environment include suppliers, the labor market, credit market, the media and the customer. The components of the macroeconomic environment are demographic (immigration management), environmental, legal, political, technological, economic and social factors, and ultimately the components of the international environment include cultural, political, technological, and innovation components and law factors.},  
Keywords = {Improvement of Business Environment, Designing Model, Qualitative Method, Coding approach, City of Tehran.},
volume = {7},
Number = {26}, 
pages = {93-113}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1194-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1194-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Tamizi, Alirez},  
title = {Economic and Environmental Factors Determining the Amount of Carbon Dioxide Emissions in the MENA Countries}, 
abstract ={Abstract: The gradual warming of the earth and its negative environmental and economic impacts contributed to pay attention to sustainable development considerably. Since climate change is a major cause of greenhouse gas emissions, including CO2, countries are seeking to prevent the rapid growth of emissions to reduce global climate change. Accordingly, and considering the importance of the subject, the present study examines the effects of variables such as per capita income, population, energy consumption structure, energy intensity, degree of trade openness, industry share of GDP on carbon dioxide emissions in MENA countries, during 1993-2015 based on the regression model of population stochastic effects, Stochastic Impacts by Regression on Population, Affluence and Technology (STRIPAT) and Spatial Durbin Panel Data Model (SDPDM). The results of this study indicate that the logarithm of GDP, population, energy structure and energy intensity have a positive and significant effect on carbon dioxide emissions, and the degree of trade openness has a negative and significant effect on carbon emissions. In addition, the positive and significant effect of the intermittent spatial variable indicates that carbon emissions are highly relevant among different regions. In general, the results of model estimation show that attention is more important to spatial correlation, heterogeneity and external effects in policymaking.},  
Keywords = {Carbon Dioxide Emission, Spatial Durbin Panel Data Model, STIRPAT},
volume = {7},
Number = {26}, 
pages = {115-130}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1195-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1195-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Ayini, Mohammad and Zabihi, Hossein and SaeidehZarabadi, Zahra Sadat},  
title = {A Study of the Challenges of Urban Management System in New Iranian Cities}, 
abstract ={Due to the goals of new towns, new towns are considered among the most important settlements in the country. These new towns face challenges in urban management system. Due to the necessity of identifying these challenges, the goal of this article is to identify the challenges of urban management system in new towns of Iran. In this research, data collection tool was focus group discussion technique and the qualitative content analysis method was applied to analyze the comments of meeting members for classification and categorization and reaching general and specific concepts. The members of meeting consisted of 33 experts and specialists related to new towns, who were selected by a goal or criterion-oriented sampling method. Eight factors were extracted in the context of the challenges of urban management in new Iranian towns; after analyzing the interviews of the participants. They are: institutional-administrative, facilities and services, Planning and policy making, environmental, socio-cultural, urbanism and architecture, financing and budgeting, legal and juridical. The participants of focus group discussion meetings emphasized on the necessity of explaining a coherent urban management system based on the characteristics of new towns in Iran. The results of this research can help programmers and policy makers to review and reform the structure of urban management system in new towns.},  
Keywords = {New Towns of Iran, Urban Management Challenges, Focal Group, Urban Management of New Cities.},
volume = {7},
Number = {27}, 
pages = {1-15}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1242-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1242-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Azmoodeh, Mohammad and Haghighi, FarshidRez},  
title = {The Influence of Access-Based Indices on House Prices (Case: Tehran District 6)}, 
abstract ={The purpose of this study was to examine the relationship between the variables dependent on the location of a residential block in an urban area based on the concept of accessibility and the price. For this purpose, based on the researches, 11 effective variables and their calculation method were identified and according to the experts&#8217; opinions of the transportation and urban planning field, the weight of each parameter was determined by the method of the pairwise comparison matrix analysis of the Analytic Hierarchy Process (AHP). In the next step, with the overlapping of ArcGIS software analysis and the factors&#8217; weights, the impact of each factor and the overall set of parameters in a metropolitan area was evaluated which blocks were classified into three categories of good, moderate, and poor accessibility. In this study, District 6 of Tehran metropolitan was selected as the case study. The results show that, based on the analysis of variables, the trend of rising housing prices in the region and the value of block accessibility act unlike each other, which by moving toward the north of the region, despite the decrease in the level of accessibility, we will face a rise in housing prices. Meanwhile, among the variables, the &#34;affordability level&#34; of the neighborhoods, which after the &#8220;Topography&#8221; of the region has the lowest weight among the indices, has the highest correlation with the trend of price change, which indicates the dependence of the price on other market variables.},  
Keywords = {Housing Price, Accessibility, Spatial Analysis, GIS, Tehran},
volume = {7},
Number = {27}, 
pages = {16-30}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1243-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1243-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {VeysiNab, Borhan and BabaeiAghdam, Fereidoon and Ghorbani, Rasoul},  
title = {An Analysis of Effective Economic Factors on Urban Livability (Case: Tabriz Metropolis)}, 
abstract ={One of the basic preconditions for planning to improve the quality of life and increase the level of sustainability in different societies is identifying the factors and elements that influence urban biodiversity. The economic dimension of livability is one of the most important dimensions affecting the quality of urban life and its promotion. Therefore, the present study is based on descriptive-analytical approach following two main aims: A- Identification and study of the status of economic indicators affecting the livability of the Tabriz Metropolis, B- Leveling economic indicators affecting the livability Tabriz Metropolis and providing appropriate model with livability of Tabriz Metropolis. In this research, the indices related to the economic dimension of livability in 12 indicators were identified by studying relevant research literature and interviews with experts, then structural-interpretive modeling technique and MICMAC software were used to express the relationships and type of indicators. Finally, to evaluate the status of economic livability of Tabriz Metropolis, one-sample t-test was used. The results of the study show the indicators of job security; enough income; proper employment opportunities; appropriate employment and opportunity to earn money were the most effective indicators on improving the livability of Tabriz Metropolis. In addition, the economic livability of the Tabriz Metropolis is low and unacceptable; among the 12 variables of research, only two variables, the ability to provide goods and services, and having a suitable job with the score of 3.10 and 3.07 are in a good condition and other variables are below the average. Therefore, exploiting a strong market economy is recommended in order to create a good job and invest in the region.},  
Keywords = {Urban Livability, Economic Dimension, Sustainable Development, Quality of Life, Tabriz Metropolis},
volume = {7},
Number = {27}, 
pages = {31-45}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1244-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1244-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Iranmanesh, Saeid and Shakibayi, Alireza and NazariRobati, Fatemeh},  
title = {Ranking Challenges Facing Construction Investors in Vanished Texture of Kerman}, 
abstract ={With the expansion of urban societies and urbanization, the emergence of worn-out texture of the old fabric and the margin of cities is inevitable. Given their geographical and climatic characteristics, these areas are of great importance for urban space. The city of Kerman is similar to other Iranian regions with the emergence of worn-out texture. Since the exhaustion of these contexts causes many social, economic and human problems, efforts to improve and renovate worn tissues are important. The purpose of this paper is to rank the main challenges faced by construction investors in the worn-out texture of Kerman. In this regard, using library-field method and using a questionnaire, sample views of 10 investors in the worn-out texture of Kerman city have been collected. In order to analyze the data, the fuzzy hierarchy analysis method has been used in MATLAB software space. The results showed that the main challenges faced by investors in the worn out texture of Kerman city are the economic and technical challenges of engineering.},  
Keywords = {Worn Texture, Investment, Challenge ranking, Fuzzy Hierarchy Analysis, City of Kerman},
volume = {7},
Number = {27}, 
pages = {46-55}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1245-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1245-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Qaderi, Jafar and Rastegar, Ebrahim and Ghahri, Moslem},  
title = {Identification and Analysis of Effective Factors on the Economic, Social, and Physical Dimensions of Quality Of Life in Urban Neighborhood (Case: Tehran Municipality District 7)}, 
abstract ={Today, quality of urban life is one of the most important areas of urban studies in different countries, which has multiple social, environmental, economic and biological approaches. This research is aimed at identifying the factors affecting the quality of life in urban neighborhoods in district 7 of Tehran. Due to its high density in the central Tehran area and the existence of various social and economic centers, this area has affected the quality of life of citizens and residents in the neighborhoods of this region. This research is applied - development and method of study in the form of documentary, survey and analytical. Data collection is through document review (index identification) and scrolling (questionnaire). The population of this study consists of residents of the 7th district of Tehran municipality based on the census of 2016, which is equal to 312194. 321 people were selected as the sample by simple random sampling. Data were collected through documentary survey (index identification) and survey (questionnaire). Measurement of quality of life in urban neighborhoods was done through Kruskal-Wallis test and factor analysis using SPSS software. The results of the research indicate that there is a significant difference in the quality of life between the fourteen neighborhoods of the research area. According to the five components of security and social services; physical and service quality; economic quality, environmental quality and quality of public health, Niloofar Shahid Ghandi and Bagh Saba Sohrevardi neighborhoods with an average of 148 and 127.20, respectively had the highest rank in quality of life. Nezam Abad and Armeneh with 38.27 and 25.50 respectively had the lowest level of quality of life from the viewpoint of respondents. Among the measured components, the most significant difference was observed in physical and environmental dimensions. In the end, in order to know more precisely the effective factors, out of a total of 80 variables examined in the 5 components assessed by factor analysis, 10 factors influencing the quality of life of the residents of the neighborhoods of the 7th district of the municipality were identified.},  
Keywords = {Quality of Life, Urban Neighborhoods, Effectiveness, Tehran Municipality},
volume = {7},
Number = {27}, 
pages = {51-65}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1246-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1246-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Shoul, Abbas and Hakimi, Im},  
title = {Identifying and Classifying the Causes of Delay in Construction Projects (Case: City of Sirjan)}, 
abstract ={Successful implementation of construction projects is one of the key factors for economic development of every country. Construction projects are often criticized for overrunning time and budgets. Thus, analyzing the factors causing delay is essential with the aim of omitting them. Several researches have been conducted to identify the reasons and causes of delays in different countries. In this paper, various researches investigated different factors affecting construction projects delays have been analyzed and 24 effective factors on construction projects have been identified and extracted. Data were collected from experts of contracting companies, employers, head of the workshop, and observers of construction projects in Sirjan city. To analyze the data and prioritize contributing factors affecting construction projects delays, two techniques of soft and hard operational research methods including ISM and BWM were used. The results indicated inadequate experience and knowledge, inadequate modern equipment, financial problems, difficulties in obtaining construction materials, the conflict among contractor, consultant and owner, and improper planning are the most important effective factors on construction projects delays.},  
Keywords = {Project Management, Construction Projects, Delay, ISM, BWM, City of Sirjan},
volume = {7},
Number = {27}, 
pages = {61-75}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1247-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1247-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Monavariyan, Abbas and Nargesiyan, Abbas and HosseiniMakarem, Atefeh},  
title = {Designing a Network Governance Model in Tehran Municipality}, 
abstract ={The present study deals with designing a network governance model in Tehran municipality. This research is developmental in terms of purpose and descriptive-exploratory in terms of method. Interview tools were used to collect qualitative data. Participants in this study are managers and authorities of Tehran municipality, contractors and faculty members of universities with a history of working in the municipality. In order to design a network governance model in Tehran municipality, data-based theorization with Strauss and Corbin&#8217;s approach has been used. According to the results of open and pivotal coding, the causal factors influencing network governance include the culture of participation, political powers, upstream laws, and popular organizations. In addition, effective contextual factors on network governance include cultural infrastructure, legal infrastructure, trust building, government support, behavioral training, team capacity, and networking infrastructure. Interfering factors include management barriers, cultural and social barriers, and organizational barriers, strategic and legal dilemmas. Network governance strategies include developing information channels and environmental scanning, strengthening research and development infrastructures, developing collaborative networks for evaluating and selecting projects, outsourcing and developing citizen participation in decision making. The implications of network governance include economic efficiency, strategic development of urban services, and organizational effectiveness.},  
Keywords = {Governance, Network Governance, Tehran Municipality, Data Theory, Economic Efficiency},
volume = {7},
Number = {27}, 
pages = {76-85}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1248-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1248-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Salamat, Shadi and Mirsepassi, Nasser and Reshadatjoo, Hamideh},  
title = {Designing Human Resources Performance Management System to Improve Economic Productivity (Case: Ayandeh Bank)}, 
abstract ={The purpose of this study is designing human resources performance management system to improve productivity of Ayandeh Bank. In the process of doing this research, qualitative and quantitative methods have been used. In the framework of the qualitative method, a number of experts in banking field were identified and, after conducting Delphi interviews with them, some of the most important bank performance indicators were identified. After designing a performance management model based on the desired indicators, a quantitative research process began. The population of quantitative section was All Ayandeh Bank employees with over 5 years of experience, nearly 2500 people, 333 were selected as multi-stage sampling. The research instrument for measuring individual, team and organizational performance and improving productivity is researcher-made questionnaire. Validity was determined by content validity and reliability was determined using Cronbach&#8217;s alpha by internal consistency. The results indicate team performance management with a coefficient of 0.68 has a more effective effect on improving productivity than individual performance with a coefficient of 0.61 and organizational performance with a coefficient of 0.52. Square multiple correlation coefficient, variable of improving productivity (0.87), indicates that the independent variables of individual, group and organizational performance management (87%) explain the variance of this variable. The results showed that based on model fit indices, the designed model is the most effective and successful model for deploying HRM model to improve Ayandeh Bank productivity.},  
Keywords = {Performance Management, Human Resources, Improving Economic Productivity, Ayandeh Bank},
volume = {7},
Number = {27}, 
pages = {86-100}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1249-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1249-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {},  
title = {}, 
abstract ={},  
Keywords = {},
volume = {7},
Number = {28}, 
pages = {1-20}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1301-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1301-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {},  
title = {}, 
abstract ={},  
Keywords = {},
volume = {7},
Number = {28}, 
pages = {21-40}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1302-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1302-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {},  
title = {}, 
abstract ={},  
Keywords = {},
volume = {7},
Number = {28}, 
pages = {41-60}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1303-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1303-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {},  
title = {}, 
abstract ={},  
Keywords = {},
volume = {7},
Number = {28}, 
pages = {61-80}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1304-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1304-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {},  
title = {}, 
abstract ={},  
Keywords = {},
volume = {7},
Number = {28}, 
pages = {81-100}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1305-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1305-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {},  
title = {}, 
abstract ={},  
Keywords = {},
volume = {7},
Number = {28}, 
pages = {101-120}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1306-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1306-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {},  
title = {}, 
abstract ={},  
Keywords = {},
volume = {7},
Number = {28}, 
pages = {121-140}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1307-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1307-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {},  
title = {}, 
abstract ={},  
Keywords = {},
volume = {7},
Number = {28}, 
pages = {141-160}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1308-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1308-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2019}  
}

