
	<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"	xmlns:cr_unixml="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2020-07-27T16:26:49+04:30</responseDate>
	<request metadataPrefix="cr_unixml" verb="ListRecords" set="10.1002">http://iueam.ir/browse.php?mag_id=8&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</request>
	<ListRecords>
		
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>8-82</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2014</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>2</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>8</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Calculation the Return on Investment Rate (ROI) of the Specialized Courses of Tehran Municipality</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Hossein</given_name>
					<surname>Mohammadpour Zarandi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Seyyed Mohammadtaghi</given_name>
					<surname>Taghavifard</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Sustainable development is based on knowledge and education is the key of knowledge and consciousness development. So it could be noted that: education is the key of development. Here it is necessary to denote the efficiency of educational courses to achieve goals of the organization. Therefore the main Purpose of research is addressing the Return on Investment (ROI) of education in urban development area in Tehran municipality. In this study, special trainings of Tehran municipality urban development and its ROI was investigated. In this process AHP teaching and expert Choice software was about 559.37 percent. This Rate is a well ROI rate and shows the logic holding of these courses. Also it shows that investing in education in Tehran municipality will have a positive effect on its total productivity, in long term.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>return on investment (ROI)</keyword>
	<keyword>educational costs and benefits</keyword>
	<keyword>to educate and improve</keyword>
	<keyword>human resources</keyword>
	<keyword>Tehran municipality.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2014</year>
								  <month>12</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>1</first_page>
								  <last_page>16</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-82-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>8-83</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2014</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>2</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>8</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Sustainability Assessment of Urban Transport Systems (The Case of Rasht)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Reza</given_name>
					<surname>Esmaeilpur Ashka</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mohammadrahim</given_name>
					<surname>Ramezanian</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Sareh</given_name>
					<surname>Nabizadeh</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Today, the occurrence or aggravation of harmful effects in urban transportation, such as air pollution and increased traffic accidents, reveals the necessity of sustainable transportation. In Rasht Metropolis with an annual growth rate of 1/9 percent in population, traffic is very severe. To better planning in the context of sustainable transport, first it is necessary to investigate the condition of stability or instability of the existing or planned transportation system. So the main purpose of this article is assessment the sustainability of urban transportation systems in Rasht. Therefore The 20 important criteria of sustainability - through interview with experts and review the previous researches - and 5 urban transportation systems - between the existing and future planned systems for the Rasht- were selected. After distributing the questionnaire among experts and using Fuzzy TOPSIS, subway and then bike, were determined as the most stable systems of urban transportation. Finally, to demonstrate the impacts of weight-criteria on decision-making process, a sensitivity analysis was performed, which confirmed the above results. Thus, the need for being faster in development of urban rail as the best public transport system as well as the necessity of addressing to bicycle as a clean non-powered vehicle in urban planning of Rasht is very important, especially for the urban short routes.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>sustainable transportation</keyword>
	<keyword>urban transportation systems</keyword>
	<keyword>sustainability criteria</keyword>
	<keyword>Multi Criteria Decision making</keyword>
	<keyword>Rasht city</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2014</year>
								  <month>12</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>17</first_page>
								  <last_page>30</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-83-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>8-84</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2014</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>2</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>8</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Estimation the Housing Price in Holy City of Mashhad Using the Kaplan Meier Model (Survival Curve)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Mohammadrahim</given_name>
					<surname>Rahnama</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Amir</given_name>
					<surname>Asadi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Mojtaba</given_name>
					<surname>Rusta</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Regarding the importance of housing in life, the investigation of various aspects of this issue such as housing price Estimation, identifying its affective factors and combination of price and its changes over the time is necessary. To achieve these goals, housing price in Mashhad has been estimated by using Kaplan Meier model both in apartment and in the villas. To meet this objective, 1000 examples of Housing and apartment&#8217;s price during 2010 and 2011 were extracted from khorasan newspaper ads. Data was scattered on the map, by Geographic information system (GIS) and its results was analyzed by SPSS software and Kaplan Meier model. The results of Kaplan Meier model showed that the difference in prices of villas and apartments based on the number of every house rooms is significant and the probability of villas prices are less than apartment prices according to the number of rooms, was confirmed. In addition of the 3 variables which entered in the equation, the variable of ''infrastructure level'' is the highest coefficient Equal to 1/196.Subsequently, the variable of &#34;old building&#34; has a coefficient equal to 0.973.After that, the variable of &#34;land extent&#34; with a coefficient equal to 0.996 is located in the second stage. Then the variable of &#34;Age of Building&#34; with a coefficient equal to .973 stands in the third stage. Also the spatial distribution of apartment and villa prices in the city of Mashhad indicated that the most expensive areas are mainly developed Regions or areas with high access (to holy shrine).
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Estimation of Price</keyword>
	<keyword>housing price</keyword>
	<keyword>Kaplan Meier model</keyword>
	<keyword>villa and apartment housing</keyword>
	<keyword>Mashhad city.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2014</year>
								  <month>12</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>31</first_page>
								  <last_page>46</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-84-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>8-85</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2014</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>2</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>8</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>The Impact of Cultural Capital (Institutional Dimension) on Socio-Environmental Behaviors with the Sustainable Urban Development Approach (The Case of Shiraz City)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Elham</given_name>
					<surname>Vaghefi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mansoor</given_name>
					<surname>Haghighatian</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			In the present age, almost the half of the world&#8217;s population live in the urban areas. In this condition, the role of cities and urban areas directly and urban development and construction indirectly, and their contribution in current instability have attracted the Serious attention of Scientific circles and policy makers. It is recommended that cities should be viewed as a Locus to solve global problems and achieve sustainable development, should be considered and used.

The main purpose of this study is to assess the socio-environmental behaviors and cognition the impacts of social capital and its dimensions on the socio-environmental behaviors in sustainable urban development.

This article has been conducted with a quantitative approach and using the survey method. Through a structured questionnaire, survey data was collected and analyzed by SPSS software. The theoretical framework of this research comes from the theory of Bourdieu and new environmental paradigm.In this survey, environmental and social behaviors, has been measured in four parts of: features and circumstances, knowledge, attitudes and ecological behaviors.The results showed that between gender, socio-economic bases, marital status, and socio-environmental behaviors, there is a significant relationship. also the relation between cultural capital (Institutionalized dimension) and socio-environmental behaviors was confirmed.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>cultural capital</keyword>
	<keyword>socio-environmental behaviors</keyword>
	<keyword>sustainable environmental development</keyword>
	<keyword>Shiraz city</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2014</year>
								  <month>12</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>47</first_page>
								  <last_page>65</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-85-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>8-86</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2014</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>2</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>8</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Gap Analysis and Need Assessment of General and Specialized Skills of Urban Economy and Financial Experts of Tehran Municipality</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Hamid</given_name>
					<surname>Rahimian</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Seyyed Mohsen</given_name>
					<surname>Tabatabaei Mozdabadi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Education in every country is an investment for next generation, whose purpose is human resources development. In this way, institutional and organizational growth and development is depend on promotion of education, insight and human resource skills. Hence, the main purpose of this research is the gap analysis of general and specialized skills of financial and urban economy experts in Tehran municipality. This is a Descriptive survey. The statistical society of this survey are all financial and urban economy experts of Tehran municipality equal to 227 persons. The sample size was 143 persons that was calculated by using Cochran sampling formula.A researcher made questionnaire has been used to collect data. To determine the validity, it was used the content validity method and to determine reliability it was used Cronbach&#8217; alpha. The amount of Alpha was 0.82. Also quantitative and qualitative statistics method were used to statistical data analysis. The results of the research show that: 1- the present situation of educational needs was at average level and the preferred situation of it was evaluated at the upper limit. 2- There was a significant difference between the present and preferred situation of educational needs (both general and Professional needs). 3- The general skills Prioritization of economic and financial experts of municipality are: statistics, writing grammar, communications, management, planning and computer sciences. 4- The specialized skills Prioritization of the economic and financial experts are: Accounting, corporate finance and financing.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>educational needs assessment</keyword>
	<keyword>Gap analysis</keyword>
	<keyword>common skills</keyword>
	<keyword>specialized skills</keyword>
	<keyword>economic and financial experts</keyword>
	<keyword>Tehran municipality</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2014</year>
								  <month>12</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>67</first_page>
								  <last_page>78</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-86-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>8-87</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2014</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>2</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>8</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Development of Urbanization Dimensions with Social Marketing School Approach</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Hossein</given_name>
					<surname>Hataminejad</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Ahmad</given_name>
					<surname>Purahmad</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Mohammadbagher</given_name>
					<surname>Ghalibaf</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name>Mohammadtaghi</given_name>
					<surname>Rahnamaei</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="5">
					<given_name>Seyyed Ali</given_name>
					<surname>Hosseini</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Urbanization as the dominate mode of living is raising and subsequently, its problems are increasing. Social marketing approach is one of the new approaches to solve this problem that its Concepts could be used for Promoting of beliefs, attitudes and optimal human behavior in the community. The goal of this survey is explanation of social marketing in relation with urban planning and urbanization problems in Iran. It tries to propose some solutions for urban challenges by using the focus on the offering of the proper behaviors and social ideas to citizens and urban communities as costumers. This research is a descriptive-analytical research and some tools such as interviews with experts, and library and documentary methods are used. Research findings show that many of the problems of urbanization in Iran Rooted in the beliefs and false norms of citizens towards their living environment and how to deal with their urban management. Also, the development model of urbanization with Social Marketing Approach which consists of five consecutive steps is extracted. The research result shows that by Using Social Marketing School and Its solutions based on the focusing on the offering the appropriate behavior to citizens, it could be prepare the basis for urbanization to pass through from chaotic situation to favorable ways in whole aspects. And by this method we can transition to desirable urbanization and prevailed on challenges such as civic culture, stable income, citizen participation, traffic, informal settlements, air pollution, and social disorders.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Development</keyword>
	<keyword>Urbanization</keyword>
	<keyword>Social marketing</keyword>
	<keyword>Social changes.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2014</year>
								  <month>12</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>79</first_page>
								  <last_page>96</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-87-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>8-88</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2014</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>2</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>8</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>The Relationship Between Perceived Organizational Protection of Urban Management with Social Responsibility and Municipal Employees’ Job Performance of Hamadan</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Fakhrossadat</given_name>
					<surname>Nasiri Valik bani</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Complexity of urban issues and need to information related to organizational features and job characteristics of employees for managing and correct urban programming and diversity of these information, are the important issues in urban management Efficiency and Effectiveness. With respect to this topic, the purpose of this research was study the relationship between Perceived Organizational protestation of Urban Management with Social Responsibility and employees&#8217; job performance of General Department of the Hamadan Municipality. The Statistical population of the research was included all Municipal employees. Then 140 people were selected as the sample size by using Stratified-relative random sampling method. Also to analysis the research data, inferential statistics Methods such as Pearson correlation coefficient, T test, and multivariate regression analysis were used. The Results showed that: The Status of perceived organizational protect, social responsibility and employee&#8217;s job performance was above the average and there was a significant positive correlation between organizational protections with social responsibility and employee&#8217;s job performance in Municipal General Department of Hamadan.&#160;
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>urban management</keyword>
	<keyword>Perceived Organizational protestation</keyword>
	<keyword>social responsibility</keyword>
	<keyword>job performance</keyword>
	<keyword></keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2014</year>
								  <month>12</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>97</first_page>
								  <last_page>108</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-88-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>8-89</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2014</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>2</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>8</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Public-Private Sectors Partnership in Renovation of Distressed Areas in 9th Region of Tehran Municipality</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Kaveh</given_name>
					<surname>Mohammadi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mohammadtaghi</given_name>
					<surname>Razavian</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Mozafar</given_name>
					<surname>Sarrafi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name>Esmail</given_name>
					<surname>Gholamhoseini</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Nowadays, partnership of Public and Private sectors is one of the most common ways to renovation of Distressed areas due to the high total of construction costs and Lack of economic power of owners. The purpose of this survey is Evaluation the influences of Public and Private sectors partnership on renovation of distress areas in 9th Region of Tehran Municipality and provide solutions for reinforce and extension of this type of partnerships. This survey is an applied and developmental research that collects data through documentary and field methods and processes them by descriptive-analytical methods. Statistical society of this research includes 1162 residential Plaque of Distressed areas that have been renovated in recent years. 235 samples were selected by Cochran formula and the data was analyzed by GIS and SPSS softwares. The results show that the partnership of Public-Private sectors in 9th region is the cause of renovation about the 9000 Residential Units. Also according to the results of this research, it could be hoped to success this partnership if these conditions will be established: the legal infrastructures for Public-Private partnership, conformity of the Distressed areas with overall goals of renovation urban textures, enough facilities and persuasive packages, Coordinating and partnership of owners, increasing the supervision of related organizations of partnership and finally using the experts, wealthy and native investors.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>public-private partnership</keyword>
	<keyword>Distressed areas</keyword>
	<keyword>9th Region of Tehran Municipality</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2014</year>
								  <month>12</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>109</first_page>
								  <last_page>127</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-89-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
			
		</ListRecords>
		</OAI-PMH>
		 
  
  
  
  
 