@article{ 
author = {Hadavinejad, Mostafa and Ahmadi, Safoor},  
title = {A Diagnosis on City Councils and Municipalities Interactions: (A Study on the Cities of Lorestan Province)}, 
abstract ={Dysfunctional interaction between municipality and city council can significantly undermine the performance of both institutions and thus the quality of urban management. This significant effect highlights the necessity of local studies on the pathologies of this relationship. The present research aimed to identify and rank the pathologies of the interactions between municipalities and city councils in one province of Iran. The research was carried out by the use of exploratory mixed methods in the framework of taxonomy development model. In the first phase of research, 51 council members and mayors in the studied province, who were selected by typical sampling, were interviewed. The findings revealed 31 pathologies in 6 major categories. Then, a questionnaire prepared for pairwise comparison of found pathologies was distributed among 64 mayors and councils members in the studied province. The results of the AHP technique showed that among the major pathologies in the municipality-city council interactions, insufficient institutionalization of municipalities and councils and legal gaps are the most prominent. Among the miner pathologies, deficiency of council and municipality laws, deficient expertise and experience of some council members and mayors, and absence of a coherent training program for council members in relation to their duties were found to be the most important factors undermining the interactions of city councils with municipalities in the studied realm.},  
Keywords = {municipality, city council, pathology, municipal-city council interactions, cities of Lorestan Province},
volume = {6},
Number = {21}, 
pages = {1-14}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.21.1},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-848-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-848-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Darskhan, Rasoul and JafariPaybandi, Seyed MohammadHosei},  
title = {An Analysis of Islamic-Political Economy Impact on Sustainable Urban Development (Case: City of Zanjan)}, 
abstract ={In Islamic-political economy, urban sustainable development seeks to balance economic growth, ecological reconstruction, environmental protection and social progress. With descriptive-analytical method, this research investigates the impact of Islamic-political economy on the indicators of urban sustainable development. Data were collected by field studies and library method. Statistical population includes 386851 people living in the city of Zanjan. 384 of them were selected as sample by using Morgan Table sampling method. Data were analyzed by one-sample t-test, path analysis, and structural equation modeling with SPSS and LISREL software. According to the results, the indicators of sustainable development in the city of Zanjan are desirable with t-statistic of 57.846 and the components of Islamic-political economy with t-statistic of 53.70&#160; . According to the path analysis, the effect of the total component of Islamic political economy is 0.306; therefore, the impact of Islamic political economy on sustainable development of Zanjan is desirable and significant. Thus, in order to improve the sustainable development of the city of Zanjan, it is necessary to respect citizenship rights, attempt to protect the environment, prevent renting and land use change and to increase knowledge and awareness of the people and insights of the authorities.},  
Keywords = {sustainable development, political economy, justice, Islamic city, Zanjan},
volume = {6},
Number = {21}, 
pages = {15-31}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.21.15},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-849-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-849-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Akbari, Nematollah and Moayedfar, Rozita and MirzaieKhondabi, Farzaneh},  
title = {Analyzing Livability in the Distressed Areas of Isfahan City with an Emphasis on City Development Strategy}, 
abstract ={Adoption of inefficient policies in the field of distressed areas and low quality of livability, there is the need for new approaches in preparing and implementing renovation and improvement plans; so, city development strategy can be an appropriate plan to replace current plans. The purpose of the study is to evaluate the livability of distressed areas in Isfahan city as one of the elements of urban development strategy to use the approach in renovation and improvement. Moreover, its innovation is in addressing livability situation of independent distressed areas of the city to provide urban development strategy plan.&#160; The research method is descriptive-analytical and regarding the purpose, the study is applied. The data were collected using questionnaires. They were distributed and filled out in August and September of 2015. In this research, SPSS, EXCEL and Arc Gis software were used. The study sample included 385 residents of distress areas who were selected by stratified random sampling. According to the results, the distressed area of Isfahan, with an average of 2.49 and t statistics, -38.07 is not livable and the residents have evaluated the index of urban development strategy and its status undesirable. Moreover, the other three dimensions of economic, social and environmental state are unfavorable and the social dimension has had a more critical situation. Livability state is not the same in all parts of the area. There is also a significant difference between the distressed areas regarding livability. In the meantime, the distressed area of district 9 rather than districts four and eleven and the distressed area of district 3 rather than district eleven had more livability.},  
Keywords = {livability, distressed area, city development strategy, renovation and improvement, city of Isfahan},
volume = {6},
Number = {21}, 
pages = {33-50}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.21.33},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-850-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-850-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Mohammadifar, Yousef and Rousta, Ahmad and Gharehche, Manizhe and Hamidizadeh, Mohammadrez},  
title = {The Necessities and Consequences of City Branding and Emphasizing the Economy of Urban Tourism}, 
abstract ={Today, city branding is important in urban spatial, cultural, social and economic structures for sustainable development, but this has been less used for several reasons. This paper discusses the identification of the causal circumstances of city branding and the analysis of its consequences and impacts in two qualitative and quantitative phases. The extracted model is based on the qualitative research method of data theory, using theoretical sampling method, and in the quantitative phase, city branding outcomes were investigated based on correlation method. The results of this study showed that, on the one hand, city branding is influential as a predictor variable for creating an ideal image and also on the level of satisfaction of residents living as criterion variables, and on the other hand, it has a direct and significant impact on audience satisfaction level including tourists.},  
Keywords = {city branding, urban tourism, city image, citizens’ satisfaction},
volume = {6},
Number = {21}, 
pages = {51-65}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.21.51},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-851-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-851-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {MohammadianMosammam, Hassan and Ahmadi, Leyla and Razavian, Mohammad Taghi},  
title = {AN Investigation on the Phenomenon of Women Vendors in Tehran’s Metro}, 
abstract ={One of the major challenges facing managers and urban planners in the third millennium is increasingly development of informal economy. Tehran Metropolis is not an exception and it has witnessed a growing expansion of the informal economy, especially vendors in the subway over the last few decades. Accordingly, this paper aimed to review the theories and approaches about the phenomenon of street vending and then analyzed the passengers&#8217; attitudes towards women vendors as well as the characteristics and reasons for its spread in subway cars using a survey based on semi-structured interview. The statistical population includes of two groups of traveler women and street vendors of Tehran metro line 1 and the sample size is 75 and 82 respectively. The results revealed that passengers are more willing to buy from Metro vendors. The major group age of metro&#8217;s vendors are young, educated, often immigrants, married and heads of households. The most important reason for this activity is inadequate capital and lack of jobs in the formal sector. The respond of managers and city officials is often based on legalistic approach, prohibiting, and preventing their activities. Finally, in order to organize vendors in metro, solutions including efficient and comprehensive spatial planning throughout the country, facilitating self-employment, development of special places for vendors, monitoring and controlling the quality of products, training and empowering, licensing activities in specific places and renting metro stalls to vendors have been presented.},  
Keywords = {informal economy, street jobs, women vendors, Tehran Metro Line 1},
volume = {6},
Number = {21}, 
pages = {67-81}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.21.67},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-853-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-853-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Sobhaniyan, Seyyed Mohammad Hadi and AghajaniMemar, Ehsan and TootoonchiMaleki, Saei},  
title = {Tax on Capital Gains of Housing Estate; a Sustainable Source of Income for Municipalities and an Appropriate Tool to Control Speculation in the Housing Market}, 
abstract ={By expanding the scope and dimensions of urban life, municipalities, as the main charge of planning system and urban management, have great responsibility and commitment toward society and citizens. It is obvious that performing tasks and duties pertaining to municipalities requires financial resources and appropriate facilities. In our country, unsustainability of municipal revenues has been changed into as one of the main features of cities&#8217; finance. Thus, introducing sustainable source of income for municipalities can help remarkably functional independence and their continuity of servicing. One of the other problems of urban system in Iran is price volatility in the housing sector. This has resulted in deviation of capital toward housing speculation as well as disorders of other investment markets in the country because of structural problems of economy and inefficiencies of the government&#8217;s policies resulting in reducing investment in economic productive sectors, particularly in some years. Therefore, it is necessary to adopt practical strategies to control speculation activities and fluctuations in housing prices by policy-makers. A tax base entitled &#8220;tax on capital gains of housing estate&#8221; has been introduced by using descriptive-analytical method. It can follow two purposes in urban management and planning system simultaneously. The first goal is to create sustainable revenues for municipalities by using the capacity of transactions and exchanges in housing estate market. The second purpose is to create an efficient and effective tool in management and policy-making of housing estate market aiming to avoid speculative trading in this market. Moreover, this policy is in accordance with paragraph 17 of general policies of resistance economy referring to increase in the share of tax revenues.},  
Keywords = {tax on capital gains, sustainable revenue, speculation, housing estate},
volume = {6},
Number = {21}, 
pages = {83-96}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.21.83},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-854-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-854-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Motaghi, Samir},  
title = {Strategic Management of Tourism Economy (A Study on Chaharmahal and Bakhtiyari Province)}, 
abstract ={Optimal tourism management, particularly in less-prosperous areas, is of great importance in absorbing capital from this industry. Chaharmahal and Bakhtiyari Province is one of the natural tourism areas in Iran. Despite having proper natural and environmental potentials to take advantage of tourism benefits, it has remained unknown and less prosperous; therefore, one of the approaches that can help to improve profitable managerial styles and attitudes. The present research is descriptive-analytical in terms of purpose, using David&#8217;s Comprehensive Strategic Management Model and SWOT technique to develop strategies and QSPM to prioritize selected strategies. The research data was compiled from 120 tourism experts, officials and managers of Chaharmahal and Bakhtiari using Delphi technique. The results identified and determined mission, vision, qualitative and quantitative goals, and presented a strategy to develop tourism industry of the province. The results of evaluating the internal and external factors of tourism industry of the province indicated that the tourism industry of this province is weak and had no proper reaction to external factors. However, after identifying and prioritizing the strategies with QSPM matrix, it was specified that launching Internet sites for marketing tourist attractions in the province has the highest priority among selected strategies.},  
Keywords = {tourism economy, QSPM, SWOT, strategic management, Chaharmahal and Bakhtiyari},
volume = {6},
Number = {21}, 
pages = {97-110}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.21.97},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-855-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-855-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {SadeghiDarvazeh, Saeid and Ghasemi, Ahmadreza and Tilenoei, Neda Rasouli and Shoul, Abbas},  
title = {Locating Mechanized Parking in Qom with Sustainable Development Approach (A study on the city of Qom)}, 
abstract ={Population growth and urbanization, increase in number of private vehicles, low-width&#8217;s streets and lack of marginal parking spaces, especially in central parts of cities, have brought numerous problems for big and populated cities. Locating mechanized parking lots, which with occupying less area have a high parking capacity, is of the necessities of urban and traffic planning in large cities. The present study aims to identify, to weight and to prioritize effective criteria in locating of mechanized parking with sustainable development approach, and ultimately to prioritize potential sites for the construction of mechanized parking lots in central part of Qom. Therefore, first with regard to principles and components of sustainable development and applicable planning of urban land and transport and traffic planning and also with regard to characteristics of Qom city, three criteria and 16 sub criteria to locate mechanized parking lots have been chosen. The method used in this research for weighting and prioritization of locating criteria and sub criteria is Analytic Network Process (ANP) and fuzzy PROMETHEE. Therefore, after gathering the required data from the paired comparison questionnaire and calculate the total weight of the criteria, priority was given as followed: &#8220;environmental&#8221; criterion with weight of 0.429 in top priority, &#8220;economic&#8221; criterion with weight of 0.347 in second priority and &#8220;social&#8221; criteria with weight of 0.251 was located in third priority. Moreover, the result of ranking potential sites to construct mechanized parking using fuzzy PROMETHEE were identifies as follow: location in Keivanfar street is the first place, location in Sedaqhat alley in the second place and location in ice making factory in the fourth place.},  
Keywords = {Locating, Mechanized Parking, Sustainable Development Approach, ANP, PROMETHEE},
volume = {6},
Number = {21}, 
pages = {111-127}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.21.111},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-856-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-856-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Dmitrichenko, Nikolay and Khrutba, Viktoriia and Spasichenko, Oksana and Khrutba, Yulii},  
title = {Ecological and Economic Principles to Improve the Route Network of Urban Transport}, 
abstract ={The transport system of many Ukrainian cities does not meet the EU standards and requirements. There is a need to improve urban transport networks, to use transport potential efficiently on the basis of environmental logistics and to improve environmental safety as one of the principles of sustainable transport development. The systems model to create an ecologically safe logistics system of public transport determines the relationship between input parameters (transport system indicators), output parameters (ecological and economic indicators of the route network) and controlling parameters, restrictions, uncontrolled parameters and environmental impact assessment. To model the route network, linear programming (a transport task) has been used as a method with the criteria for optimizing the indicators of economic, ecological and social assessment. A target function is an additive function indicating economic costs, environmental and social losses in passenger and / or freight transportation with weight ratios. It describes the cost of the logistics system. The weight ratios of the importance of economic and ecological indicators are chosen for each route depending on the specifics of transportation. It enables to choose the scheme of transportation by the integration index. (Optimal or compromise plan is suggested according to economic or ecological indicators). The developed approach has been applied to improve the route network of public transport in Kyiv based on ecological and economic principles. Network optimization of only three routes has enabled to increase the income and reduce expenses for passenger transportation. Meanwhile, harmful emissions -&#160;CO,&#160;CmHn,&#160;NOx,&#160;PM,&#160;СO2&#160;&#160;- have also decreased.},  
Keywords = {Ecologically-Oriented Logistics System, Ecological and Economic Assessment, Green Logistics, Transport System, Route Network, Optimization},
volume = {6},
Number = {21}, 
pages = {131-144}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.21.131},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-883-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-883-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Marjani, Taimoor and Pourabedi, Mohammadreza and Saaedi, Leila and Minoo, Alirez},  
title = {Sustainable Technology Assessment Model in Tehran’s Urban Transportation}, 
abstract ={Considering the current problems in the field of transportation in Tehran, this paper attempts to develop a sustainable technology assessment model in Tehran&#8217;s urban transport sector. The research was carried out in a mixed method. In the qualitative phase, using the principles of the data theory of the foundation, identifying the important components in the technology evaluation and compiling the paradigm model, was performed and in the quantitative phase, using the confirmatory factor analysis, the developed model was tested. The results of the study indicated that the topic of assessment of sustainable technology in the urban transport sector of Tehran is related to the use of urban transportation technologies. Due to population growth and consequently the increasing demand for urban travel, the expansion of marginalization and migration around Tehran and limited natural and ecological resources, and energy resources are created. Strategies such as strategic and prospective planning in the urban transport sector of Tehran, capacity of transportation in proportion to the demand for urban travel, assessment of compliance with requirements, national and international regulations, assessment of the economic justification of sustainable technology in the field of transportation and the possibility of creating the necessary investment with the resistance economy approach, evaluation of qualitative and technical functional considerations in the field of urban transport, assessment and monitoring of environmental impacts and life cycle analysis of transportation technologies, the use of clean and low carbon energy in transportation equipment, and so on are suggested. The strategies are influenced by the values and culture of society, the level of knowledge and public understanding of society from the risks of unsustainable technologies in the field of transportation, urbanization culture and observance of laws and regulations in the field of transportation by people and characteristics of Tehran in terms of climatic, demographic, geographical, political, infrastructure, and engineering aspects. It is expected that the implementation of the mentioned strategies could lead to events and consequences such as promoting the status of Iran in international rankings, promoting physical and mental health, vitality and welfare of the society, and labor force productivity, optimal utilization of urban infrastructure and facilities, promoting the level of knowledge and attitudes towards the use of sustainable technologies in transport, sustainable economic growth, entrepreneurship and employment, efficiency and positive performance in the field of urban transport and the environmentally sound and productive urban environment.&#160;},  
Keywords = {Technology, Sustainability, Urban Transport, Technological Evaluation, Environment, city of Tehran},
volume = {6},
Number = {22}, 
pages = {1-18}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.22.1},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-902-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-902-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Javid, Mohammadreza and RabeieMandajin, Mohammadrez},  
title = {A Comparative Study of Islamic Contracts and Islamic Banking Support Contracts (A Study on Bank Shahr)}, 
abstract ={Islam emphasizes all social issues, especially healthy economic relations. What has led to the need to examine and address the issues of contracts in Islam and the contracts of support in Islamic banking, is the existence of various contracts in the society. In this research, it is tried to examine the compatibility of the contracts of support in Islamic banking with the contractual and religious principles recommended in Islam, after defining and clarifying the contracts and principles in the verses of the Holy Quran and explaining its nature. Identifying types of contracts, examining the foundations of legitimacy and clarifying their pillars and effects in support contracts in Islamic banking, and observing all aspects of it in current affairs of the bank have been done. The main question of the present research is to what extent Bank Shahr support contracts comply with the provisions of the recommendations and orders in Islamic contracts. In this regard, five types of contracts used to support Bank Shahr have been investigated in order to comply with the recommended conditions in the Quranic verses of the Holy Quran. The research method in this study is integrated content analysis. The research findings showed that in three types of banking contracts -purchase of items, design, procurement and commissioning of equipment, service and maintenance of equipment-, up to 82% of compliance and in two types of contracts - assignment of interests and the right to exploit land and lease property-, there is up to 91% compliance with Islamic conditions and recommendations for contracting.&#160;},  
Keywords = {Contract, Islam, Islamic Banking, Islamic Contractual Terms, Bank Shahr},
volume = {6},
Number = {22}, 
pages = {19-31}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.22.19},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-903-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-903-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Moradi, Fatemeh and SaeidehZarabadi, Zahra Sadat and Majedi, Hami},  
title = {An Explanation of City Branding Model in order to Promote City Competitiveness and Economic Growth by Using of F\'ANP Model}, 
abstract ={In recent decades, cities are seeking for new ways to promote themselves and economic growth; hence, in order to attract capital and enter to competition arena, city managers increasingly pay attention to optimal use of urban assets. In these competitive conditions, governments have focused on strengthening marketing activities and city branding for improving competitiveness. In this regard, this research tries to investigate the concepts and views on city branding, competitiveness and urban economic growth to extract the indicators of each, and then, by prioritizing extracted indices, will present a conceptual model of urban branding in line with competitiveness and the growth of urban economy. The research method based on purpose is applied and based on data collection is a library- survey research. Data collection instrument is questionnaire. In order to data analysis, F'ANP model is used in order to use the inherent advantages of the factor analysis method, the subject first analyze the dimensions of the constituent and then using the ANP method, these dimensions, elements and the relationship between the elements and the cluster to be investigated. The statistical sample consisted of professors and Ph.D. students of urbanization of Islamic Azad University, Science and Research and Shahr Qods branches, and simple random sampling was used. Factor analysis was performed using 21 indicators and using SPSS software. The results of the research indicated the importance and necessity of considering the principles of urban branding, such as creating urban attractions, creating distinct advantages of the place, increasing participation and productivity, connecting and communicating cities, improving the location, developing creativity, preserving and developing urban assets in the field of improving competitiveness and as a result the growth of the urban economy. Finally, strategies and suggestions for branding of cities are also being proposed to promote competitiveness and urban economic growth.&#160;},  
Keywords = {City Branding, Urban Competitiveness, Economic Growth, F’ANP model},
volume = {6},
Number = {22}, 
pages = {33-56}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.22.33},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-905-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-905-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Homafar, Milad and Poorjafar, Mohammadreza and SaeidiRezvani, Navi},  
title = {An Analysis of Spatial Distribution Pattern of Knowledge-Based Activities in Tehran}, 
abstract ={World urban economy accompanied with knowledge and information economy, so metropolitan areas drastically compete for attracting, developing knowledge-based and information activities, and promoting their competitive advantages. This research tries to identify the effective criteria on location selection of activities by explaining the spatial distribution pattern of knowledge-based activities in Tehran. The research method is mixed and the population of the study includes 560 knowledge-based companies in Tehran. Purposefully, 50 managers of Tehran&#8217;s knowledge-based companies were interviewed to identify and prioritize the criteria for choosing the locations of companies, using Delphi techniques. Linear regression analysis was used in GIS software to analyze the data quantitatively and to find out the relationship between the location of activities and the criteria for locating. The findings of this study showed that access criteria to main arteries, access to fast transportation lines and access to the subway have the most explanatory power. Contrary to traditional theories of location, there is no significant relationship between the cost of ownership or lease and the location of knowledge-based activities in Tehran. Statistical analysis complementary to regression analysis identified university decisions to locate knowledge-based growth centers, as an effective unknown factor on current spatial distribution pattern. The results of this research provide a suitable tool for urban planners to revive the spatial arrangement of knowledge-based activities in Tehran with the aim of improving performance.},  
Keywords = {knowledge-based activity, spatial arrangement, site selection, linear regression, city of Tehran},
volume = {6},
Number = {22}, 
pages = {57-75}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.22.57},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-906-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-906-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Maleki, Saei},  
title = {Spatial Analysis and Prioritization of the Intra-Regional Housing Gap Using the Techniques of Planning (A Study on the Cities of Ilam Province)}, 
abstract ={Housing has always been the most important thing is human life. Having a safe, secure and comfortable shelter is one of the long-term desires of every human being, but this need is also related to other human needs. On the other hand, today this reality is added to other realities that every phenomenon at any moment is a manifestation of the constant analysis and combination of variables that have regular, continuous, and multiplicative correlations; therefore, in investigating the phenomenon of housing, what is important is the relation and influence of its various aspects. The purpose of this study was to investigate the regional indexes affecting housing in Ilam province using TOPSIS technique. The research method is descriptive-analytical and development-applied, and GIS, GRAFER and EXCEL software have been used. The results of the study showed that the density index in the residential unit in the Ilam province between 1996 and 2006, except in 1997 and 1998, has slightly increased, the trend has improved since 1999and has approached the ideal. The average number of households in the residential unit showed that the construction of residential units in the province had been increasing but could not fully compensate for housing shortages. In contrast, the average household in the residential unit in the province had an upward trend. Finally, the TOPSIS model showed that CL was the highest and lowest in the following areas Ilam (0.99), Dehloran (0.13), Ivan (0.09), Mehran (0.08), Abdanan (0.05), Darreshahr (0.04) and Shirvan (0.00).},  
Keywords = {Spatial Analysis, Intra-Regional Gap, Housing Inequality, Ilam Province},
volume = {6},
Number = {22}, 
pages = {77-93}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.22.77},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-907-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-907-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {NasrEsfahani, Reza and Safari, Babak and Bashiri, Maji},  
title = {Determining the Optimal Use of Urban Underground Space (Selected Streets of Isfahan City)}, 
abstract ={The use of underground spaces can lead to increased land productivity in cities. This paper addresses the issue of which of the four commercial, warehouse, public parking and passageways (two-floor streets) are optimal if we want to use the spaces below the streets of the city. Therefore, the selected 21 main street of districts 5 and 6 of Isfahan were selected as problem options. Using 2013 data and linear programming method, the objective function was designed for optimal user allocation. In the following, based on the two-stage hierarchical analysis method in the GIS software environment, the optimization problem was investigated. In order to investigate in the first stage, the type of use was selected as the main criteria of the problem including parking, warehouse, business center and passage use, and then, for the second step, the sub-criteria of landing price, traffic flow, area of green space and surface were selected. The results from the first phase survey showed which street is more important for which user. In addition, the results from the second phase survey showed which sub-criteria are more relevant in choosing a type of land use. Based on this, it is possible to decide which street is needed and what the priority of which street is to use for underground space. For the use of parking and passage, Shahid Hemmat Highway has the highest score and HezarJarib Street account for the commercial use and warehouse with the highest score.&#160;},  
Keywords = {optimal use, urban space, underground, two-stage hierarchy, city of Isfahan},
volume = {6},
Number = {22}, 
pages = {95-110}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.22.95},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-908-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-908-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {KarbalaeiHajioghli, Hassan and Farhangi, Ali Akbar and Soltanifar, Mohammad and Delavar, Ali and Geranmayehpour, Ali},  
title = {The Relationship between Branding of Economic Newspapers and Customers’ Satisfaction in Metropolitan Countries}, 
abstract ={In this research, the branding of newspapers in metropolises was investigated. The newspapers use different methods to attract their audience, and thus branding can play a significant role for newspapers in attracting customers. Branding leads to better communication between customers and the press. Providing correct information and branding have led to brand associations. In this research, customer satisfaction has also been used to branding. The research method is descriptive-correlational, and the statistical population is the customers of the economic newspapers. 318 people were selected as the sample. A researcher-made questionnaire was used to collect data. To analyze the data, Pearson correlation coefficient and linear regression were used. The results showed that there was a positive and significant correlation between brand awareness, brand loyalty and perceived quality of brand with customer satisfaction, but there was not a significant relationship between the association of the brand of economic newspapers and customer satisfaction. Linear regression results also showed that brand loyalty had a larger share in predicting customer satisfaction.&#160;},  
Keywords = {branding, customer satisfaction, economic newspapers, Country metropolises},
volume = {6},
Number = {22}, 
pages = {111-122}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.22.111},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-909-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-909-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {HeydariSoorshejani, Rasool},  
title = {Structural Modeling of Effective Factors on Women’s Satisfaction of Public Transport System (Case study: City of Kashan)}, 
abstract ={Women form half the population and many spaces in cities are used more by them. Women, as a large and active group, use the most possible of the system in cities due to their time constraints. Therefore, the special survey of their traffic patterns in urban public spaces and in particular, the public transportation and bus network of the city have a significant role in increasing the prosperity of urban spaces. The purpose of this paper is to investigate the factors affecting women&#8217;s satisfaction from urban transportation system. Research method of in this study is descriptive-analytic. The data used in this study were collected through questionnaires and interviews. Then, using SPSS and AMOS software, the existing factors and structural modeling of these factors were investigated. The results showed that among the various indicators such as: services, equipment, seat quality, visual beauty, safety, social factors, security and behavior of the driver, the only factor of visual beauty, had a significant effect on women&#8217;s satisfaction with the inter-city bus system and other factors with P value greater than 0.05, did not have a significant impact on women&#8217;s satisfaction.},  
Keywords = {Structural Modeling, Women’s Satisfaction, Public Transportation, Security, City of Kashan},
volume = {6},
Number = {22}, 
pages = {123-138}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.22.123},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-910-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-910-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Javid, Alireza and Behzadfar, Mostaf},  
title = {An Assessment of the Logical Value of Comprehensive Urban Development Plans of Tehran}, 
abstract ={Integration of assessment with planning process is one of the distinctive features of modern urban planning. In response to the need for comprehensive and integrated thinking, to evaluate and analyze complex and changing urban issues, assessment has become a basic issue in urban planning process aiming to explain the value of urban programs in terms of influencing urban development, formulate the program and implement social interventions, and improve management. Despite significant advances in theoretical approaches and evaluation methods, scientific evaluation of the status of comprehensive urban development plans has not yet been carried out in our country. It is also difficult to deal with the environmental requirements based on the recognition of the problem and to find appropriate problem solving techniques. The purpose of this research is to provide a conceptual model and to assess of comprehensive urban development plans developed for Tehran, and to explore the bases that make the evaluation of comprehensive urban planning fragile. Therefore, the available sources and theoretical literature were reviewed and the evaluation approach, criteria and sub-criteria were identified to define the evaluation framework of the stated programs. The criteria and sub-criteria were determined by analytical-comparative methodology, with library studies and expert opinions. Then it was localized and adapted to meet the ground conditions of Iran through deep interviews with experts. Finally, the significance and application of each criteria and sub-criteria was evaluated using the questionnaire by the main custodians of comprehensive urban development programs in Tehran. The results of the evaluation in this research are based on the fact that the comprehensive urban development plans prepared for Tehran have a low logical value. In addition, the answer to the complexity problem is the main problem and the most important evaluation problem.},  
Keywords = {assessment, Logical Value, Comprehensive Urban Development Plans, City of Tehran },
volume = {6},
Number = {23}, 
pages = {1-13}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.23.1},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-956-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-956-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Jamali, Firouz and Rosteai, Shahrivar and YapangGharavi, Mohamm},  
title = {An Assessment of the Causal Model of Effective Metrics on Urban Competitiveness Using a Fuzzy DEMATEL Approach}, 
abstract ={At the beginning of the 21st century, globalization and innovation in the field of information technology and, consequently, the formation of the flow of space, have made cities, in national spaces, like multinational corporations, increasingly compete gain economic benefits. In the past, competition was associated with companies and manufacturing institutions, but as globalization and networking of the global economy began to emerge, cities have always enjoyed a special status as a node in network economy, and it is believed that the competition is at the same level with national competition. Today, perhaps one of the most successful ways to transform a city into a city with a successful economy is to use the concept of a competitive city. Competitiveness of cities has a crucial role in urban development, and in this way, it will provide sustainable revenues for urban managers in these urban areas. Therefore, this research has been conducted with the aim of explaining the causal model of effective measures on the competitiveness of the city. The present research is applied in terms of purpose, and descriptive-causal based on method. The statistical sample of the study consisted of 30 experts related to urban economics. In order to achieve the aim of the study, fuzzy DEMATEL technique was used. The research findings indicated that based on D-R values, among the four criteria of urban competitiveness, the economic criterion with the value of 0.833 is the most influential and the environmental criteria with the value of 0.689 has been influenced the most of urban competitiveness. In addition, based on D+R-values, the economic criterion with the value of (2.671) was identified as the most important criterion for urban competitiveness.&#160;},  
Keywords = {Assessment, Urban Competitiveness, City Economy, Fuzzy Dematel },
volume = {6},
Number = {23}, 
pages = {15-33}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.23.15},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-957-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-957-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Zolfaghari, Mahdi and Faghihiyan, Fatemeh},  
title = {An extraction and Analysis of the Return Risk of Real Estate Industry, (Based on Value at Risk Based on Markov Approach)}, 
abstract ={Today, any attempt to invest in any economic activity, requires the knowledge and access to some components of its activities. One of the important components of investment is knowledge about investment risk according to the expected return in that activity. One of the main areas of investment in the country is investment on housing, which could take place directly or indirectly (through financial markets). In this regard, the importance of awareness of the risk in indirect investment on the housing sector considering to the nature of the financial markets is more necessary. But despite the importance of knowledge about risk, quantification methods developed for the past few years have not had much development. Therefore in this research we proposed a new model for measuring the share return risk of companies in real estate industry. This model is not only able to cover much of the shortcomings of current methods, but also able to extract the risk of stock returns in different states. The present model has been designed based on the &#34;value at risk&#34; and using the Markov process on parametric methods. This mechanism, in addition to taking into account the risk regime transfers is designed based on a set of models that they have got a variety of normal and abnormal distribution functions based on symmetric and asymmetric behavior. The results showed that the return of the company&#8217;s stock in housing sector follows form regime transfers and has got the GED distribution based on asymmetrical models.},  
Keywords = {GARCH family risk, Markov chain process, real estate industry},
volume = {6},
Number = {23}, 
pages = {35-54}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.23.35},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-958-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-958-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Zali, Nader and Moradi, Mahdi},  
title = {The Effect of Expanding Higher Education Centers on the Use of Its Surrounding Areas in Tabriz Metropolis}, 
abstract ={The development of university centers is one of the causes of the modern physical alteration of cities and has a major impact on the development process of the city. This research studies the impact of university centers on changing and developing the use of spaces around Tabriz Metropolis. The research tools included observation and direct field studies, reviewing the maps of in 1968, 1996 and 2011 and using the base map in 2006 and changes made in the courses have been reviewed. GIS and SPSS software were used to analyze the maps. The statistical sample of this research is 480 uses around five universities (Tabriz State University, Medical Sciences, Payam Noor, Arts and Islamic Azad University of Tabriz). The research findings show the impact of university centers on changing land use patterns and urban development, especially the development of service and business spaces around these centers. Estimating the socioeconomic and cultural effects of academic centers on the surrounding uses has doubled the importance of changing the approach in the preparation of urban plans, the proper prediction of the effects of shaping factors and favorable landscape for the future of the city and the quantitative and qualitative development.},  
Keywords = {Higher Education Centers, Metropolis of Tabriz, Use of Surrounding Spaces},
volume = {6},
Number = {23}, 
pages = {55-65}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},

doi = {10.29252/iueam.6.23.55},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-959-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-959-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Ghamari, Azadeh and Zeinabadi, HassanReza and Arasteh, Hamidreza and Behrangi, Mohammadrez},  
title = {Organizational productivity with the maintenance of human resources talents: providing a model (A Study on National Iranian Gas Company)}, 
abstract ={Targeted maintaining and keeping employees is a cost-effective effort that leads to organizational productivity. In this regard, the present study uses a qualitative method to deal with the mechanisms of maintaining human resource talents at National Iranian Gas Company (NIGC). For this purpose, purposefully and snowball semi-structured deep interviews were conducted with 10 senior managers, deputies, experts of NIGC, and 6 faculty members. Interpretative analysis was used to analyze the data from the interviews. The validity of the findings of the qualitative section was verified through review by members (interviewees) and multi-sensory data sources. Test- retest reliability method was used to test the reliability or compatibility of the encodings. The results indicated that, according to the senior managers, experts and talents of NIGC, the mechanisms of human resource talents maintanance at NIGC include nine components; performance-based payment, providing self-actualization needs, providing material needs, merit-based reward system, delegation of authority, special service compensation system, the quality and desirability of working life, clear career path, and job security.},  
Keywords = {Model, Human Resource Mainatance, National Iranian Gas Company, Organizational Productivity},
volume = {6},
Number = {23}, 
pages = {67-80}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-960-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-960-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Gholizadeh, Ali Akbar and Aminirad, Mahdi},  
title = {Determining the Optimal Structure of Tehran Municipality Income Basis Based on Risk and Returns}, 
abstract ={The financial health of municipal budgets is of great importance, and its feedback is the ability of the municipality to provide optimal and continuous services to citizens. In recent decades, due to the lack of financial resources of municipalities, the key problem in the development of the cities of the country was the non-compliance of municipal expenditures and income from the structure of the city economy. The metropolitan municipality, unlike the state that is dependent on oil revenues, has no source of income but urban economy (sales of congestion, dues, etc.) Moreover, the survival of the organization and its services depend on the dynamism and reliability of its economy. Given the importance of municipal revenue structure, in this study, the income and expenditure structure of Tehran Municipality was compared with selected municipalities, then, using Tehran Municipality data during the period of 2001-2015 and Markowitz&#8217;s model, the share of each income code based on minimizing risk, maximizing expected returns, and Sharp&#8217;s benchmark in the income portfolio of Tehran Municipality was estimated. The results showed that Tehran Municipality&#8217;s revenue structure is not suitable and has a significant difference with estimated weights based on the maximization criteria of expected returns, risk minimization and Sharp&#8217;s benchmark.},  
Keywords = {Budget Optimization, Local Government, Income Portfolio, Risk and Returns, Tehran Municipality},
volume = {6},
Number = {23}, 
pages = {81-95}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-961-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-961-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Yarmohammadian, Nasser},  
title = {Resisting Urban Economy by Optimizing Efficient Urban Population}, 
abstract ={Resistance economy is a term come across in literature of Iran economy that include lots of paper in this topic. Cities in national economy are a basis of production. Primer cities and metropolises are economy engines that cover major of goods and services production, and they are most important market for the goods and services produced in these cities, so that if these regions were not existed or the population was distributed sporadically or evenly, such a mass production and market volume were not formed. Given the importance of the metropolitan scale in the economy, based on urban economic theories, it is possible to determine efficient population of cities toward resistive urban economy. In this paper, resisting cities is analyzed by determining efficient population of cities. For calculating efficient population of city, urban social welfare function is specified and estimated. Results show Tehran population exceed efficient population level and bringing the efficient size to the actual size or vice versa by controlling urban population can resist urban economy, and consequently the national economy. Control policy is not enough for resisting urban economy but urban development and urban infrastructure development policies are recommended to increase the capacity of the city.&#160;},  
Keywords = {Efficient Scale, Urban Economics, Resistance Economy, Resisting Cities},
volume = {6},
Number = {23}, 
pages = {97-110}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-962-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-962-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Yarzadeh, Sajjad Mohammad and Shamsollahi, Behnoosh},  
title = {The Role of Public Spaces in the Realization of City Prosperity and Sustainable Development}, 
abstract ={Public spaces are those that embrace a wide range of citizens from child to old, woman and man, and with every religion and race; therefore, public spaces have the potential to strengthen social cohesion, economic development, and the improvement of the quality of collective life. The realization of these issues requires the consideration of the design and visual quality of public spaces so that these spaces are able to significantly reduce environmental stimuli and increase the vitality of the society. Correct management of public spaces can informally increase the collective knowledge and individual and social skills of urban residents. This is achieved in the light of people&#8217;s participation in the economic, political and administrative affairs of the city as well as the increase in the level of their social interactions. Of course, the role of environmental-physical elements, such as symbols and signs, should not be ignored in raising awareness and citizens&#8217; visual perception. Accordingly, public spaces should be considered as a platform for encouraging citizens to participate and accept social responsibilities in order to transfer knowledge and awareness to improve citizens&#8217; quality of life. Therefore, in this research, it has been attempted to study the issues that need attention to urban public spaces management while studying the literature of city prosperity and sustainable development. In terms of method, this research is descriptive-analytic. The results indicated that development and attention to public spaces lead to economic development of city, improvement of citizens&#8217; health and education, and rebuilding the local identities of the city.},  
Keywords = {public spaces, city prosperity, sustainable development},
volume = {6},
Number = {23}, 
pages = {111-124}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-963-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-963-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Estiri, Mehrdad and Rayej, Hamzeh and HosseiniTooli, Farshi},  
title = {Developing a Model to Measure Shopping Center Attractiveness in Tourism Regions (Case: Kish Island)}, 
abstract ={The importance of commercial centers as a major driver of tourism has been widely acknowledged in theoretical studies of tourism marketing. This study combines quantitative and qualitative approaches to determine the effective measures on the attractiveness of commercial centers as one of the effective dimensions on the attractiveness of tourism areas and the research data have been collected and analyzed in two main phases. The first phase by conducting qualitative exploratory research through semi-structured interviews with active managers in the urban planning and tourism area of Kish Island and analyzing the content of the responses presented confirmed that the attractiveness of commercial marketing could be considered as one of the criteria determining the attractiveness of the tourist areas. In the second phase of the study, in two separate studies, with the participation of tourists from Kish Island, with the aim of identifying the criteria affecting the attractiveness of commercial shopping centers in terms of buyers based on confirmatory and exploratory factor analysis methods as well as structural equation modeling (SEM), a five-dimensional model tangible factors, store space, product, sellers, and convenience shopping is designed.},  
Keywords = {Place Marketing, Shopping centers, tourism marketing, customer satisfaction, Kish Island},
volume = {6},
Number = {24}, 
pages = {1-15}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-974-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-974-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Bagheri, Noushin and HaghshenasKashani, Farideh},  
title = {Credit Risk Assessment of Urban Cooperatives Using Neural Network Method}, 
abstract ={One of the most important issues for institutions that provide financial facilities to others is the issue of credit risk. One of the ways to quantify and measure credit risk and, consequently, its proper management, is to use a credit rating. Credit rating is a model for measuring the performance of facility recipients, which is based on quantitative criteria such as corporate financial information, in order to allow prospective clients to obtain a similar profile with facilities and customers with a proper and inappropriate credit position. To be identified. According to the mission of the organization, the Central :::::union::::: of Cooperative of Workers of Iran has numerous member cooperatives from across the country, which provides their products there. In this research, the effect of each of the factors involved in determining the risk of credit in this cooperative has been tested first. Then, using the self-organizing mapping algorithm, we will cluster the data to exclude clusters that are very remote and far-reaching. The credit risk of each of the cooperatives has been calculated through the algorithm of the multi-layer perceptron neural networks in MATLAB software and a model for predicting credit risk in the future. The main purpose of this research was to use this algorithm to classify cooperatives by calculating credit risk numbers and use it to predict the future credit risk of the future cooperatives. &#160;},  
Keywords = {Scoring, Neural Network Algorithm, Validation, Credit Risk},
volume = {6},
Number = {24}, 
pages = {17-33}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-967-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-967-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Rostamzadeh, Parviz and Mirghaderi, Seyed Hadi and Diyanatkhah, Seyed Navi},  
title = {Effective Factors on the Difference between the Amount of Initial Estimation and the Cost of Construction Projects (Case: Shiraz Municipality)}, 
abstract ={Actual (Final) price of construction projects are usually deviations compared to their initial estimates. At runtime, these projects face increasing in costs for various reasons and may lose their economic justification. Therefore, identifying factors affecting this price difference are one of the most important issues in this field. This study identifies the importance of the factors affecting the difference between the amount of initial estimation and the actual cost of five mega-projects of the Shiraz municipality as example. This research is descriptive-survey and data collection was done using questionnaire and interviewing tool. In order to determine the weight, priority and categories of factors, the best-worst method, gray TOPSIS and weight-quality matrix were used, respectively. The results of this study show that nine important price deviations are effective in five superstructures that fall into three broad categories: &#34;high quality and high weight&#34;, &#34;low quality, high weight or vice versa&#34;, &#34;low quality and weight&#34;. According to the research findings, the &#34;existence of adversaries&#34; is the most influential factor in the price deviation of Shiraz municipality's superstructures.},  
Keywords = {construction projects, price deviation factors, Gray TOPSIS, BWM, Shiraz Municipality},
volume = {6},
Number = {24}, 
pages = {35-50}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-968-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-968-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Abroodi, Seyed Mojtaba and Kashfi, Seyed Saeid and Hosseini, Seyed Teymoor},  
title = {The Effect of New Law on Traffic Violations on Deterrence and reducing Traffic Accidents and Violations (Case: City of Tehran)}, 
abstract ={Driving without observance of driving laws and regulations threatens the order and safety of any society and disrupts the comfort of the people of that society. According to the new law on defamation and 289 percent increase in violations in 2016 compared to 2010, the purpose of this study is to investigate the deterrent effect of the new law on the investigation of violations of accidents and offenses in Tehran. In terms of purpose, this research is applied and analytical-descriptive survey type in terms of method. To collect the research data, a researcher-made questionnaire with a main hypothesis and three sub-hypotheses with 43 items was used and distributed among the statistical community that is the same as the heads of the 26th districts of Tehran police corridor and after completing the questionnaire by SPSS software and PLS and the T-test and Friedman tests have been analyzed. The results indicate that there is a positive and significant effect on accidents and violations at 99% confidence level, between severity, prudence or certainty, and the speed of new law enforcement and deterrence. The results also show that immediate treatment and severe punishment such as record keeping, vehicle seizure and the use of additional penalties, social exclusion, dismissal of liability in specific cases, etc. have a positive and significant effect on deterrence of violations and accidents. Increasing smart systems for recording road violations affects preventing violations and accidents, and reducing violations. It was also found that equipping the police with the appropriate equipment to accelerate the handling of incident violations had a significant positive effect on the deterrence of violations and accidents. Declaring driving disqualifications by judicial authorities and controlling them by specific means is effective in deterring offenses.},  
Keywords = {},
volume = {6},
Number = {24}, 
pages = {51-62}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-969-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-969-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Shamai, Ali and YousofiBabadi, Saei},  
title = {An Analysis of Good Governance Role on Sustainable Tourism Revenues (Case: City of MasjedSeleyman)}, 
abstract ={Various strategies have been proposed to promote sustainable incomes through good urban governance. One of the good strategies for good urban governance is the development of sustainable tourism in order to achieve sustainable urban incomes. Tourism as the second industry plays an important role in the cycle of economic activity, employment development, currency and tax revenue, and compensation for the lack of credit for other sectors of the economy in small and medium-sized cities. The purpose of this research is to analyze the role of good urban governance in promoting sustainable urban tourism through tourism in Masjed Soleyman city. The method of this research is mixed-exploratory and according to the data, it is quantitative and qualitative research and data access method is documentary and survey. The population of the sample is 30 urban experts and the sampling method is selective and targeted. In order to analyze the data, inferential statistics (sample t-test) was used in SPSS software and also for weighting the variables considered by multi-criteria decision-making models ANP and Super Decision software were used. The findings indicate that among the good urban governance variables that have an impact on sustainable urban incomes, the indicators for equipping the infrastructure, and facilities for attracting private investment in tourism is the most important and the index of equality of all shareholders against the benefits and plans of tourism development, has taken the lowest weight. The analytical results of the study of good urban governance variables that could be effective in increasing sustainable urban tourism through tourism have not been considered. The reasons for this unsatisfactory state of tourism infrastructure are inadequate facilities for attracting private sector investment (with a score of 0.12), lack of incentives for private sector investors in tourism (0.98), weakness in integrated urban management, including tourism development policies and lack of sufficient supervision over the performance of urban management and local institutions (0.016).},  
Keywords = {good urban governance, sustainable revenue, tourism industry, Masjed Seoleyman},
volume = {6},
Number = {24}, 
pages = {63-79}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-970-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-970-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Poorahmad, Ahmad and Piri, Esmaeil and Mohammadi, Yadegar and Parsa, Shahram and Heydari, Sam},  
title = {Good Urban Governance in Urban Neighborhoods (Case: Marivan City)}, 
abstract ={Good urban governance is one of the concepts that it takes into consideration the general welfare of citizens and its policies and programs are within the framework of specific indicators. Therefore, the purpose of this study is to investigate good urban governance indicators in the central neighborhoods of Marivan city, (1, 2, 4, 14). The data and information of this research were collected in two ways, library and survey, that in the survey method, the questionnaire tool was used that validity and reliability were confirmed by experts in this field. The total sample size was estimated at 380 people using the Cochran formula, the sampling method is non-random and questionnaires were distributed randomly among citizens. SPSS and Excel software were used to analyze the data, and given the normality of the data, ANOVA test was used. Using Tukey&#8217;s test, the differences between each neighborhood were investigated. The results indicated that in the neighborhoods studied, good urban governance indexes are not in desirable condition. The first and 14th neighborhoods do not have a significant difference in terms of accountability, consistency orientation and justice, and in other indices, these two neighborhoods have significant differences with each other. This significant difference is not high due to the difference in the average of the indices studied in both neighborhoods, and it can be said that the status of urban governance indicators in these two neighborhoods, like the two and four neighborhoods, is not in a desirable situation, and all of them are on almost the same level.},  
Keywords = {Good Urban Governance, Urban Management, Neighborhood, Marivan},
volume = {6},
Number = {24}, 
pages = {81-98}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-971-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-971-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Ahangari, Navid and Mohammadi, Robab and Najafi, Hakimeh},  
title = {Identification and Prioritization Factors Affecting the Domestic Tourist’s Behavior (Case: Isfahan)}, 
abstract ={Relevant researches in connection with models and purchase behavior of tourists provide useful information for tourism planning and its promotion. To this end, this paper is aimed at identifying and prioritizing the factors that influence the purchase behavior of domestic tourists in Isfahan city. In terms of purpose, it is cognitive research and data analysis is descriptive- analytical and the data collection tool is survey. Data were collected by library and field studies. Data collection tools consisted of a researcher-made questionnaire and a survey of domestic tourists. The statistical population of this research is all domestic tourists who visited Isfahan city in 2013. Thus, the sample size was estimated by Cochran without N, 96, but to improve the validity of the instrument was increased to 200 cases. The findings show that most of items bought by tourists (37/5%) are food items and souvenirs. Most methods used in purchase, instantaneous choice and immediately of the market (39%) and the main purpose of purchase items are to buy souvenirs (33/5%). The highest score was allocated to the highest index (0.25) and the lowest score was allocated to the lowest index (0.03) of the total score of one. In the final ranking, the component of the variety of items available for purchase in priority and the high price of souvenirs on the volume of purchases, ranked 18th.},  
Keywords = {Prioritization, Effective Factors, Purchase Behavior of Tourists, Souvenir, Isfahan},
volume = {6},
Number = {24}, 
pages = {99-115}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-972-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-972-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Heydari, Ali and Amiri, Mojtaba and Jamour, Hossei},  
title = {The Role of Internal Organizational Factors in Implementing the Budgeting System Based on Performance: An Interpretative Structural Modeling Approach (Case: Tehran Municipality)}, 
abstract ={It is essential to create the context for the strategic change in the organization. One of the necessity of reforming the municipal economic structure, modifying the method of budgeting and distributing resources, from traditional budgeting to an advanced budgeting system. Performance-based budgeting (PBB) by assigning targeted credit to activities can provide operational monitoring and facilitate access to resource allocation results while clarifying the distribution of resources. Accordingly, in this research, while introducing the internal factors affecting the implementation of the PBB, it has been attempted to express the relation between factors in the form of a conceptual model according to the extent of the impact and the effectiveness of each of the factors. This research is qualitative-quantitative in nature and is an applied in target dimension. In the process of identifying the factors, the content analysis method is used and in the classification stage of the known factors, an interpretative structural modeling tool is used. Data collection was gathered through reviewing organizational documents and interviewing managers, advisors and deputies of the Directorate of Program and Budget of Tehran Municipality. The results of the research show that in general, 11 main internal organizations are effective in implementing PBB. The citizenry agent has the least impact on the integrated information systems and has the most impact. According to the results of MICMAC analysis, none of the factors in the self-management area and two factors in the dependent region and eight factors in the communication area and the only factor of &#34;integrated information systems&#34; in the independent region.},  
Keywords = {PBB, Intra-organizational factors, Interpretative structural modeling, Tehran Municipality},
volume = {6},
Number = {24}, 
pages = {117-133}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-973-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-973-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2018}  
}

