
	<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"	xmlns:cr_unixml="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2020-07-27T16:32:52+04:30</responseDate>
	<request metadataPrefix="cr_unixml" verb="ListRecords" set="10.1002">http://iueam.ir/browse.php?mag_id=26&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</request>
	<ListRecords>
		
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>26-1072</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2019</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>7</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>25</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Assessing the Impact of Competitiveness on Urban Network Transformation Using Social Network Analysis (Case: Isfahan City-Region)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Mahmood</given_name>
					<surname>Mohammadi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Ahmad</given_name>
					<surname>Shahivandi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Dariush</given_name>
					<surname>Moradi Chadgani</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name>Niloofar</given_name>
					<surname>Rastghalam</surname>
					<email>niloo.rgh@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Abstract: The urban network is a collection of large and small cities, each of which, in terms of size and performance, affects the evolutionary process of the area. This study uses the two concepts of competitiveness and urban network to investigate the effective factors in the occurrence and intensification of inequalities in the urban network of Esfahan. In this regard, the changes and transformations of Esfahan urban network during three periods of 1375, 1385 and 1395 with regard to competitiveness indices and considering the distance between cities (based on flow analysis method) and creation of competitiveness matrix, using urban network mapping In the social network analysis (Gephi) software is measured. In this way, for each concept at any given time, a separate network is plotted and analyzed. The results indicate that in the mentioned periods distribution of competitive ability as a stream of capital, labor, and information in the city-region of Esfahan has been unfair. As far as the metropolis of Esfahan with much difference, the gap in the urban hierarchy of city-regions Based on the concept of competitiveness. The second place in comparison with this view belongs to Najafabad and the third place belongs to Falavarjan. In addition, except for a few exceptions, the process of changing cities' competitiveness has been consistent with the process of changing the hierarchy of cities in the same time frame. Therefore, it can be said that the urban hierarchy pattern in the Esfahan urban network follows a competitive ranking.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Competitiveness</keyword>
	<keyword>Urban Network</keyword>
	<keyword>Esfahan City-Region</keyword>
	<keyword>Social Network Analysis</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2019</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>1</first_page>
								  <last_page>15</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-1072-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>26-1073</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2019</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>7</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>25</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Investigating the Possibility of Using Waqf and Interest-Free Bonds to Finance Public Spaces in the Surrounding Texture of Holy Shrine of Imam Reza</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Morteza</given_name>
					<surname>Jafarzadeh Najar</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mahmood</given_name>
					<surname>Hooshmand</surname>
					<email>m-hoshmand@um.ac.ir</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Mohammad Reza</given_name>
					<surname>Lotfalipour</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name>Mahdi</given_name>
					<surname>Behname</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Abstract: One of the most important and vital tissues in the country is the context around the Holy Shrine of Imam Reza. The main problem about this context is the lack of funding for public spaces. In the present study, the willingness of people to participate in the improvement of the worn out texture surrounding the Shrine of Imam Reza is estimated by purchasing waqf bonds and interest-free bonds, using the conditional valuation method. For this purpose, 240 pilgrims and adjacent persons were interviewed. In order to distinguish the factors influencing the decision on participation and the level of participation, two-stage method of Heckman and Tobit model were used. By eliminating incomplete answers, 57% of the people were willing to buy waqf bonds and, 48% of the people were willing to buy interest-free bonds. The results of the Hackit Model showed that the variables of &#8220;trust in local institutions&#8221; and &#8220;social awareness&#8221; influence significantly on respondents&#8217; decision to buy bonds. In addition, the &#8220;sense of belonging to the city&#8221; affects the degree of willingness to participate. In the case of interest-free bonds, the variable of social awareness has a significant effect on the decision of the respondents to participate in it. The variables of sense of belonging to the city and the neighborhood and the household&#8217;s economic situation have an impact on the degree of willingness to participate. While the belief in interest-free bonds and the variables of trust in local institutions, both in the first stage (decision to pay) and in the second stage (willingness to pay), have a significant effect on respondents. The average willingness to participate was estimated at 7,450,000 Rials for interest-free bonds and it was 1,660,000 for waqf bonds.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Waqf bonds</keyword>
	<keyword>Interest-free bonds</keyword>
	<keyword>Financing</keyword>
	<keyword>Renovation and Improvement</keyword>
	<keyword>Texture around the Holy Shrine</keyword>
	<keyword>Public Spaces</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2019</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>17</first_page>
								  <last_page>33</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-1073-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>26-1074</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2019</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>7</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>25</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Planning for Strengthening the City’s Economic Infrastructure with an Emphasis on Sustainable Tourism (Case: Ardebil City)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Ali</given_name>
					<surname>Majnoony Toutakhane</surname>
					<email>a.majnoony@bonabu.ac.ir</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Alireza</given_name>
					<surname>Soleymani</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Abstract: In the present era, the tourism industry was introduced as one of the pillars of sustainable development and as a powerful tool for economic, social and environmental impacts which, while attracting the participation of the local community in the development of the national economy, has the potential of preserving and protecting natural resources, making environmental sustainability. Today, sustainable development policy is a public approach that governments have been considering to make ecologically sustainable tourism a promising local community in the long run. In this regard, the present study was conducted with the aim of planning sustainable development in the city of Ardebil. The research method is a descriptive-analytic type with an applied purpose. The data used in the research is documentary and field research. In order to achieve the most urgent and deterrent forces in the development of sustainable urban tourism, through the completion of a questionnaire and interview with 40 experts from urban tourism, effective strategies encouraging and inhibiting the development of sustainable tourism were formulated. Then, they were weighed and prioritized, using the network analysis (ANP) model. Finally, based on the most important adversary and deterrent forces, the most sustainable strategies for sustainable tourism development in Ardebil were extracted. The results of the research show that among the forces that encourage sustainable development of the city (creation of employment) the highest priority and among the inhibitory forces of sustainable development of the city (lack of sustainable management in the urban tourism sector) have the highest priority. Seven strategies were also identified and developed for the most important adversary and deterrent forces of city tourism development. Among the strategies proposed, the strategy (optimal and targeted utilization of increased incentives for travel among people to exploit the attractions and products of tourism in order to create employment and income for the people of Ardabil city) was selected as the best strategy. Moreover, in this research, the spatial pattern of the elemental inhabitants of Ardabil city was examined using the geographic information system (GIS) and it was determined that the tourism space of Ardabil city is influenced by the historical space of the city (old texture) and covers the central part of the city (area 1).
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Planning</keyword>
	<keyword>City Economic Development</keyword>
	<keyword>Sustainable Tourism</keyword>
	<keyword>Network Analysis</keyword>
	<keyword>Ardebil</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2019</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>35</first_page>
								  <last_page>50</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-1074-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>26-1075</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2019</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>7</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>25</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Understanding of Smart Citizen Components in Urban Environment with Technological Learning Approach (Case: Yazd City)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Hamed</given_name>
					<surname>Fallah Tafti</surname>
					<email>h.fallah@sau.ac.ir</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Majid</given_name>
					<surname>Heydari Kooshaknoo</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Raziyeh</given_name>
					<surname>Almasi Sarvestani</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Abstract: Smart citizenship component has been forgotten in the light of the theory of smart growth and urban excellence. In this theory, most urban planners and planners only study the indicators of the economy and exceptional services in cities, and the lifestyle and culture of citizens and its impact. They are less concerned with urban development. In this regard, in this research, Yazd city has been selected as the study to evaluate the indicators of smart citizens and its components in urban development and excellence. A survey from a sample of citizens, appropriate data was collected through a multi-criteria questionnaire with desirable validity and reliability. Using SPSS software, exploratory factor analysis was used to determine the validity and reliability of independent and dependent variables and then the named components were named. In the next step, using the confirmatory factor analysis in AMOS software, the validity of the research structures was tested. The statistical relation between the variables and their indices was confirmed. In the final model, using the fittest tests, the relationships between the variables and the effect of independent and dependent variables were confirmed. Findings of the research indicate that the significance of the law-governed factor is 31.579 percent of the variance explained more than other factors and citizens consider the role of law-governed in the characteristics of the smart citizen more critical. From the perspective of citizens, the optimal use of information and communication technology and the formation of the smart city have a positive effect on the various economic, social, and environmental dimensions of Yazd city. So while recognizing the need for training with new ways and content, they see the role of ICT in better life experience.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Smart Citizen</keyword>
	<keyword>Smart City</keyword>
	<keyword>Yazd City</keyword>
	<keyword>Urban Environment</keyword>
	<keyword>Technological Learning</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2019</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>51</first_page>
								  <last_page>62</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-1075-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>26-1076</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2019</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>7</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>25</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Identification and Validation of Effective Factors on the Establishment of Workplace Curriculum Model Emphasizing on Economic Development Consequences</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Zahra Sadat</given_name>
					<surname>Mehmandoost Ghamsari</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Koorosh</given_name>
					<surname>Fathi Vajargah</surname>
					<email>kouroshfathi2@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Abasalt</given_name>
					<surname>Khorasani</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name>Saeid</given_name>
					<surname>Safayi Movahed</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Abstract: The work environment curriculum is one of the emerging disciplines of the curriculum seeking to apply the findings of this study in the work environment. This study aims to investigate the effective factors on the establishment of a work environment curriculum-model in related documents and to identify its economic consequences. For this purpose, the relevant documents have been examined from the beginning. The research population includes all published works in this field from 1993 to 2017 in eight valid databases. The content of the documents was to categorize and organize the effective factors on the deployment of the work environment curriculum using the MAXQDA18 software. Then Delphi technique was used to validate these factors. The most important factors identified are individual, background, and occupational ones. Finally, the economic growth and development consequences of the establishment of curriculum in organizations were investigated that included individual factors (improving the learning process, improving relationships with colleagues, increasing work engagement and career progression), and organizational factors (organizational learning, process improvement, product improvement, lower cost, human capital development).
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Validation</keyword>
	<keyword>Work Environment Curriculum</keyword>
	<keyword>Economic Growth</keyword>
	<keyword>Organization</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2019</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>63</first_page>
								  <last_page>79</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-1076-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>26-1077</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2019</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>7</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>25</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Oil Price Shocks and Housing Business Cycles in Iran: Markov Regime-Switching GARCH Model</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Parviz</given_name>
					<surname>Jalili Kamjo</surname>
					<email>Parviz.jalili@abru.ac.ir</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Younes</given_name>
					<surname>Nademi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Abstract: The housing market is one of the most important subsectors of capital markets that have the most backward and forward linkages with other sectors. Because of the high dependence of Iranian economy to oil revenues, oil price shocks can be affect the housing market. The aim of this study is to analyze the business cycle of the housing market, with emphasis on the impact of oil shocks on the return of housing. According to APM model, regardless of portfolio selected, several factors affect the return of housing assets that in this study, the risk and shocks of macroeconomic factors including money supply, private sector investment, housing facilities allocated by special Maskan Bank and oil export revenues, have been analyzed on the housing return by a Markov regime-switching GARCH model during the period 1982 -2016. The results have shown that the return of housing in the Iranian economy has three high, moderate and low return regimes. So that the volatility of the housing return is different in each of the three regimes. Housing returns volatility at the low return regime is more than volatility of returns at the moderate and high return regimes. Therewith in the 35 years of the research period, housing market has been 13 years in the moderate return regime, 20 years in the low return regime and only 2 years in the high return regime. The results also showed that based on Dutch disease hypothesis oil shocks, liquidity and private investment have a significant positive impact on the return of housing but the housing facilities of Maskan Bank have a significant negative impact on the return of housing.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Oil Price Shocks</keyword>
	<keyword>Business Cycles</keyword>
	<keyword>Markov Switching GARCH Approach</keyword>
	<keyword>Iranian Housing Market</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2019</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>81</first_page>
								  <last_page>98</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-1077-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>26-1078</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2019</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>7</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>25</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Designing a Policy Model for the Development of Small and Medium Enterprises (SMEs) Emphasizing on Innovation (Case: Ministry of Cooperatives, Labor and Social Welfare)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Abbas</given_name>
					<surname>Hosseini</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Tooraj</given_name>
					<surname>Mojibi</surname>
					<email>mojibi@iaufb.ac.ir</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Ali</given_name>
					<surname>Mahdizadeh Ashrafi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name>Hossein</given_name>
					<surname>Vazifehdoost</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Abstract: Employment and the achievement of people in the desired job are considered as one of the most basic needs of the society, and the elimination of unemployment as a social, economic and cultural destructive phenomenon is one of the most important concerns of policy makers and planners in different countries. In addition it is and one of the main indicators of development of societies. In most countries, the solution to achieve this is through the provision of the infrastructure needed to set up and run small and medium-sized enterprises. Given the importance of small and medium enterprises in the process of economic and social development of countries and the special attention of planners and development policymakers to this important issue, policy makers need to adopt a policy suitable for the growth and development of small and medium-sized enterprises. However, the policy-making of the aforementioned businesses, from a theoretical perspective, requires an accurate basis to help create an entrepreneurial economy with more entrepreneurs and achieve the goals set by the country. Accordingly, this research aims at designing a policy framework for the development of small and medium-sized enterprises, with an emphasis on innovation and making use of domestic and international knowledge and experience to improve the policy process of small and medium-sized enterprises development and its numerous valuable results, especially in terms of employment assistance and unemployment reduction. In this paper, an attempt has been made to construct a proper framework for conducting research based on previous research and documentary studies. Then, based on the initial framework, a deep study and a case study were analyzed using the interviewing tool and study documents to extract the conceptual model. To analyze the extracted data from interviews, open source and axial coding was used. Finally, the resulting pattern in four dimensions was drawn from the effective factors on business development, development policies, policy-making bodies, and the performance of small and medium businesses.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Policy Model</keyword>
	<keyword>Development of Small and Medium Enterprises (SMEs)</keyword>
	<keyword>Innovation</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2019</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>99</first_page>
								  <last_page>115</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-1078-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>26-1079</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2019</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>7</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>25</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title></title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email>abbpor@sharif.edu</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2019</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>117</first_page>
								  <last_page>133</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-1079-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
			
		</ListRecords>
		</OAI-PMH>
		 
  
  
  
  
 