<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</title>
<title_fa>فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری</title_fa>
<short_title>IUESA</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iueam.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2345-2870</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-6398</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/iueam</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>en</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>6</volume>
<number>24</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>نقش عوامل درون‌سازمانی در پیاده‌سازی نظام بودجه‌ریزی عملیاتی: رویکرد مدل‌سازی ساختاری تفسیری (مورد مطالعه: شهرداری تهران)</title_fa>
	<title>The Role of Internal Organizational Factors in Implementing the Budgeting System Based on Performance: An Interpretative Structural Modeling Approach (Case: Tehran Municipality)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:yekanyw;&quot;&gt;ایجاد زمینه و بستر برای تغییر استراتژیک در سازمان، امری ضروری است. از ضرورت&#8204;های اصلاح ساختار اقتصادی شهرداری&#8204;ها، اصلاح و تغییر روش بودجه&#8204;ریزی و توزیع منابع، از بودجه&#8204;ریزی سنتی به یک نظام بودجه&#8204;ریزی پیشرفته می&#8204;باشد. بودجه&#8204;ریزی عملیاتی با اختصاص هدف&amp;rlm;مند اعتبار به فعالیت&#8204;های شهرداری&#8204;ها می&#8204;تواند ضمن شفاف&#8204;سازی نحوه توزیع منابع، امکان پایش عملیاتی و تسهیل دسترسی به نتایج تخصیص منابع را فراهم سازد. بر این اساس، در این تحقیق ضمن معرفی عوامل درون سازمانی مؤثر بر اجرای نظام بودجه&#8204;ریزی عملیاتی، تلاش شده است با توجه به میزان اثرگذاری و اثرپذیری هر یک از عوامل، ارتباط بین عوامل در قالب یک مدل مفهومی بیان شود. این پژوهش از نظر ماهیت کیفی- کمی و از بعد هدف، کاربردی می&#8204;باشد. در مرحله شناسایی عوامل، از روش تحلیل محتوا و در مرحله دسته&#8204;بندی عوامل شناخته&#8204;شده، از ابزار مدل&#8204;سازی ساختاری تفسیری استفاده شده است. داده&#8204;ها از طریق بررسی مستندات سازمانی و مصاحبه با مدیران، مشاوران و معاونان اداره کل برنامه و بودجه شهرداری تهران جمع&#8204;آوری شده&amp;lrm;اند. نتایج تحقیق نشان می&#8204;دهد به طور کلی یازده عامل اصلی درون&amp;lrm;سازمانی، در اجرای بودجه&#8204;ریزی عملیاتی مؤثرند که عامل شهروندمداری، کمترین اثرگذاری و عامل سیستم&#8204;های اطلاعات یکپارچه، بیشترین اثرگذاری را دارد. با توجه به نتایج حاصل از تحلیل MICMAC، هیچ یک از عوامل در ناحیه خودگران قرار نگرفته و دو عامل در ناحیه وابسته، هشت عامل در ناحیه ارتباطی و تنها عامل سیستم&#8204;های یکپارچه اطلاعات در ناحیه مستقل قرارگرفته است.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;It is essential to create the context for the strategic change in the organization. One of the necessity of reforming the municipal economic structure, modifying the method of budgeting and distributing resources, from traditional budgeting to an advanced budgeting system. Performance-based budgeting (PBB) by assigning targeted credit to activities can provide operational monitoring and facilitate access to resource allocation results while clarifying the distribution of resources. Accordingly, in this research, while introducing the internal factors affecting the implementation of the PBB, it has been attempted to express the relation between factors in the form of a conceptual model according to the extent of the impact and the effectiveness of each of the factors. This research is qualitative-quantitative in nature and is an applied in target dimension. In the process of identifying the factors, the content analysis method is used and in the classification stage of the known factors, an interpretative structural modeling tool is used. Data collection was gathered through reviewing organizational documents and interviewing managers, advisors and deputies of the Directorate of Program and Budget of Tehran Municipality. The results of the research show that in general, 11 main internal organizations are effective in implementing PBB. The citizenry agent has the least impact on the integrated information systems and has the most impact. According to the results of MICMAC analysis, none of the factors in the self-management area and two factors in the dependent region and eight factors in the communication area and the only factor of &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;integrated information systems&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; in the independent region.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>بودجه‌ریزی عملیاتی, عوامل دورن‌سازمانی, مدل‌سازی ساختاری تفسیری, شهرداری تهران</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>PBB, Intra-organizational factors, Interpretative structural modeling, Tehran Municipality</keyword>
	<start_page>117</start_page>
	<end_page>133</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-158-109&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Ali </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Heydari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حیدری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846004754</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004754</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Department of MBA, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mojtaba </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Amiri</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مجتبی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>امیری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846004755</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004755</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Department of Public Administration, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Hossein </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Jamour</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حسین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>جمور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>hjamour@alumni.ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846004756</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004756</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
