@article{ 
author = {Faraji, Seyed Jalalaldin and Alikhani, Mohammad and JafariNozar, Marjan and TabatabaeiMozdabadi, Seyyed Mohse},  
title = {Provide the Necessary Strategies for Launching Intelligent Camera-based Parking}, 
abstract ={One of the most important and significant issues in urban transportation is the issue of mobile car parking in the city. The need to pay attention to this has led to the introduction of several strategies in recent decades to organize and manage the condition of car parks in urban areas. Meanwhile, attention to modern technologies and their role and position in the management of these spaces is increasing day by day. In this regard, perhaps one of the best intelligent parking lots in the world is camera-based parking lots, which has provided significant capacity for urban management, both in terms of urban transportation management and revenue generation. The aim of this study was to investigate the role and importance of intelligent camera-based parking lots, focusing on urban spaces and extracting the necessary grounds and strategies for the use of urban management in the better use of this type of parking. Therefore, interviews were conducted with 16 academic and executive experts in the fields of urban management and transportation, and then, using the thematic analysis method, six central codes were identified as the main areas for launching this type of parking. In the next step, using SWOT analysis method, the strengths, weaknesses, opportunities and threats related to using smart cameras in locating parking spaces in the city are analyzed and the most important strategies necessary for city managers to use camera-oriented parking lots are extracted. Finally, using the QSPM quantitative programming matrix, key strategies were selected and prioritized.},  
Keywords = {Smart City, Smart Transportation, Intelligent Parking, Intelligent Camera-based Parking},
volume = {8},
Number = {30}, 
pages = {1-22}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1410-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1410-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2020}  
}

@article{ 
author = {MohebbiHerdasht, Behnam and Chavoshi, Seyed Kazem and Jahangirnia, Hossein and GholamiJamkarani, Rez},  
title = {Investigating the Effect of Non-financial Indicators on Forecasting the Occurrence of Financial Distress  from the View of Urban Managers (Case Study: Bank Shahr)}, 
abstract ={The purpose of this study was to investigate the effect of non-financial indicators on forecasting The occurrence of financial distress in the Shahr Bank from the point of view of urban managers using the structural equation modeling approach. This research is an applied research in terms of purpose And in terms of method, it was a descriptive-survey study. The statistical population of the study consisted of 53 senior and middle managers of Tehran Municipality and Shahr Bank. gathering of information has been done in the library form and field study method (questionnaires) were used to collect information. The method of analyzing the research data was structural equations modeling in Smart PLS software. The results showed that from the perspective of urban managers, corporate governance indicators, management ability and competitiveness are indicators with a non-financial nature Which can be very effective in forecasting The occurrence of financial distress So that corporate governance 65%, management ability 47% and competitiveness index 56% directly determine the changes related to the variable of forecasting the occurrence of financial distress. Also, the final study results shows that there is a positive and significant correlation between non-financial indicators and forecasting the occurrence of financial distress.},  
Keywords = {Non-financial Indicators, Financial Distress, Corporate Governance, Management Ability, Competitiveness, City Managers, Bank Shahr},
volume = {8},
Number = {30}, 
pages = {23-38}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1411-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1411-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2020}  
}

@article{ 
author = {KarimiKhorami, Asghar and ZaraeSodani, Alireza and Aliahmadi, Saee},  
title = {Consequences of Economic Consequences Strategic Scheduling Announcing Management Profits}, 
abstract ={Corporates provide different dates for presenting information about financial status and future prospects of corporate to stockholders. Stockholders and stock market participants consider the information obtained from the corporate as good news or bad news and they react on this basis. In recent years, corporate programs have been considered by analysts and accounting researchers in order to maximize the positive reaction of the securities market to good performance of corporates and minimize inappropriate reaction to their negative performance. In this research, multivariate regression model was used to test the hypotheses. The statistical population was Tehran Stock Exchange corporates. After Sampling, 120 corporates were selected during the 2014-2017.According to the results, some managers change the timing to hide bad news. The obtained results showed that there is a direct relationship between the negative reports of earning prediction and its announcement time on holidays. This relationship is positive and significant statistically. Morever there is a direct relationship between the positive news reports of earning prediction and its announcement time on usual days (Exchange working days). Therefore, unusual accumulated profits have an economic consequence, and this shows that it can affect investors' decisions as a criterion.},  
Keywords = {Market Reaction, Good and Bad News, Earnings Announcement Time, Result Economic},
volume = {8},
Number = {30}, 
pages = {39-50}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1412-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1412-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2020}  
}

@article{ 
author = {KhooshegolGarusi, Mahsoomeh and Afshari, Zahr},  
title = {The Impact of Macroeconomic Shocks on Iran’s Housing Investment by Using BVAR}, 
abstract ={Residential investment is the main component of investment and has a crucial rule in output and employment. The residential investment is affected by macroeconomic shocks. This paper provides an empirical assessment of the pace at which housing investment has responded to different macroeconomics shocks in Ian in the 1978- 2017 period by using the BVAR method. Four macroeconomic shocks are introduced to the model i.e. exchange rate, monetary, fiscal, and oil income shocks. The Sims-Zha (Normal-Wishart) was recolonized the most appropriate prior function for our data set. The Impulse response functions reveal that one standard deviation positive shocks to exchange rate, interest rate, government expenditure, and oil income initially increased housing investment and then gradually returned to its steady-state value. Oil price and monetary shocks had the shortest and longest duration impact on residential investment.&#160; The highest volatility in residential investment created by the fiscal, monetary, exchange rate, and oil income shocks respectively. The results indicate that the policymaker should consider the difference in the amount and duration of the impacts of four macroeconomic shocks on residential investment in the policymaking.},  
Keywords = {Residential Investment, Monetary Shock, Fiscal Shock, Oil Price Shock, BVAR},
volume = {8},
Number = {30}, 
pages = {51-66}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1413-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1413-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2020}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Vala, Amirbehnam and Arghan, Abbas and KorkeAbadi, Zeynab},  
title = {Explaining Social-Economic Strategies of Urban Regeneration in Historical Contexts (Case Study: Semnan\'s Historical Context)}, 
abstract ={The historic core is part of the city's integrity that has not grown and worn out in the process of urban development in line with the needs of the day. In order to solve the problems caused by the phenomenon of urban burnout, several approaches have been proposed, none of which have been able to permanently eliminate or control this phenomenon. Meanwhile, the urban regeneration approach has been considered as a different approach with a comprehensive approach and a coherent and integrated approach to restore the trend of past economic growth, taking into account the sustainability dimension. The aim of this study is to explain the socio-economic strategies of urban regeneration in historical contexts. The research method is descriptive-analytical and library and survey methods have been used to collect data. The results of SWOT model showed that the final score of strengths and weaknesses is equal to 2.81, which is slightly higher than the desired average (2.5). The result is that the historical context of Semnan is strong in terms of internal factors; Therefore, it is possible to use the existing potential and actual power in order to adjust the threat points and weakness in order to revitalize. The results also showed that the total final score of opportunities and threats was 2.97, which is slightly higher than the average score (2.5) as the final score of strengths and weaknesses. As a result, the opportunities in the historical context are greater than the threats, and therefore, in order to revive the historical context, opportunities or situations can be exploited and the factors that cause the threat can be avoided. Analysis of internal and external factors showed that the offensive strategy (maximum-maximum) has been adopted as the most important strategy in urban regeneration policy in the historical context of Semnan.},  
Keywords = {Urban Regeneration, Worn-out Texture, Historical Texture, Strategy, Semnan City},
volume = {8},
Number = {30}, 
pages = {67-86}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1414-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1414-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2020}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Eskandar, Fatemeh and Radfar, Reza and ToloueeAshleghi, Abbas},  
title = {Identification and Ranking of Effective Indicators on Team Performance in Educational Enterprises (Case Study: Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch of Tehran, Faculty of Management and Economics)}, 
abstract ={In recent years, the importance of work teams in the field of organizational performance has been very much considered. In this regard, the identification and ranking of indicators affecting team performance in organizations should be considered. Azad University, as one of the educational enterprises, is not a part of this. The purpose of this research was to identify and rank the indexes and criteria affecting team performance at the Faculty of Management and Economics of Tehran Science and Research Branch. Qualitative research method. To this end, using field studies, identifiers that have an impact on team performance have been identified and made available to 20 experts in order to score points based on the realm of research. In the next step, based on the results obtained, 6 indicators and sub-criteria of each indicator are determined. In the further research, the indexes and criteria are ranked according to the method of Dimetal and Fuzzy Hierarchical Analysis (AHP). Paired comparisons are based on expert opinion. According to the results of the research, it appears that the team composition index in terms of experts has the greatest impact on teamwork at the faculty of management. Also, the active approach criterion will have the greatest impact on team performance.},  
Keywords = {Performance Indicator - Enterprise - Working Group - Fuzzy Dimetal Method - Fuzzy Hierarchy Process Analysis},
volume = {8},
Number = {30}, 
pages = {87-104}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1415-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1415-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2020}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Zebardast, Esfandiar and Mirzaei, Mohammad Rez},  
title = {Identifying and Rating Challenges of Urban Regeneration Management (Case Study: District Ten of Municipality of Tehran)}, 
abstract ={Distressed urban areas suffer from a wide range of economic, social and physical issues and urban regeneration can be a proper response to these unfavorable conditions. District ten of municipality of Tehran (DTMT) located in central area of Tehran and 55 percent of its area is covered with decayed texture. As a result of diversity of tasks of urban management, there are numerous stakeholders involved in the urban regeneration process. This paper is practical in term of the goal, analytical in term of nature and survey in term of data collection. This paper seeks to answer what are the main challenges in the way of urban regeneration management in the DTMT? To answer this questions; First, theoretical and experimental literature on urban regeneration management was studied and features of DTMT as our case study were assessed. Second, the challenges of urban regeneration management in distressed textures of this district were identified through interviewing and content analysis method. Then, by open coding method, the identified challenges were classified according to two domains: spatial territory and urban functions. Drawing up a network of relationships between identified challenges proved that there are dominant relationships between them. In the next step, by PESTEL analysis and Analytical Network Process (ANP), it was determined that the conflict of interests between Renovation Organization of Municipality of Tehran (ROMT) and municipality of Tehran district ten and also the lack of adequate funding in ROMT are the main challenges in the way of urban regeneration management in the DTMT.},  
Keywords = {Challenges of Urban Management System, Urban Regeneration, Decayed Textures, District Ten of Municipality of Tehran (DTMT), Analytic Network Process (ANP).},
volume = {8},
Number = {30}, 
pages = {105-128}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1416-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1416-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2020}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Talaei, Mahdi and Delangizan, Sohrab and Naderi, Nader},  
title = {Designing an Urban Business Model}, 
abstract ={Business model, how to production value, absorb customer, explain the structure of make money and cost, and all business on the way of this structure will be disparate and find identity. Now a day&#8217;s ،designing of the business model have known applicable in the four level: the product or services level, business unit level, company level and industry level. Whereas cities is the main center of economic activities, developing a business model is important. Add a new layer with name of the &#34;urban layer&#34; to the literature on the business model is the goal of this study. This research is of exploratory (qualitative) type and qualitative data were collected from the research method and with the method of data collection and documentary information as well as in-depth expert interviews. The nature of the research is inductive and the information obtained was analyzed by systematic review method, content analysis and logical analysis through MAXQDA software. The results show that the complex space of urban management, the need for economic policy and the facilitation of business affairs in the city, have necessitated the development of a business model for cities. In this study, after review and analysis, the dimensions of the extraction model and the relationships between them were explained, and finally the urban business model was designed.},  
Keywords = {Urban Business, Business Model, Urban Management, Urban Economy, Model Design, Qualitative Approach},
volume = {8},
Number = {30}, 
pages = {129-153}, 
publisher = {Iran Urban Economics Scientific Association},
url = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1417-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iueam.ir/article-1-1417-en.pdf},  
journal = {Journal of Urban Economics and Management},  
issn = {2345-2870}, 
eissn = {2588-6398}, 
year = {2020}  
}

