
	<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"	xmlns:cr_unixml="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2020-07-27T16:16:30+04:30</responseDate>
	<request metadataPrefix="cr_unixml" verb="ListRecords" set="10.1002">http://iueam.ir/browse.php?mag_id=16&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</request>
	<ListRecords>
		
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>16-459</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2016</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>4</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>15</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>A Comparative Analysis of Facility Level and Population Distribution in Urban Network of Yazd Province</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Mohammad</given_name>
					<surname>Rastegari</surname>
					<email>mrastegari1984@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mohammad Hossein</given_name>
					<surname>Saraei</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			During last three decades, because of rapid influx of population into the cities, many problems have been emerged for cities. Thus, it is necessary to plan and present models in order to regulate urban network to reduce and organize emerging problems. Finding factors resulting from these events, presenting solution in order to reduce unfavorably existing situation, and move toward balance in population and activity distribution are some of the most concerns of planners and city managers. In this research, the relationship between urban facilities and population distribution in urban network was studied by evaluating level of enjoying municipal facilities in urban areas of Yazd Province. In terms of research type, it is developmental-applied and in terms of method, it is descriptive-analytical. Data were collected by library studies, documents of Iran&#8217;s Statistical Center, statistical yearbook, and relevant documents. To analyze data and reach to practical results, numerical Taxonomy model and numerical analysis process were used. The results indicate that presented facilities and services in urban areas have fairly big influence on balanced distribution of population; therefore, deductive rank of Taxonomy analysis that indicates level of enjoying facilities in the areas is in line with the rank of population distribution. In this regard, indexes relevant with municipal facilities and services can considerably play effective role on absorbing population, avoiding immigration, and decentralization in different areas.&#160;
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>municipal facilities and services</keyword>
	<keyword>numerical Taxonomy</keyword>
	<keyword>city of Yazd</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2016</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>1</first_page>
								  <last_page>17</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-459-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>16-460</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2016</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>4</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>15</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Spatial Analysis of Urban Poverty in Tehran Metropolis</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Ali</given_name>
					<surname>Movahhed</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Saman</given_name>
					<surname>Vali Noori</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Hossein</given_name>
					<surname>Hataminejad</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name>Ahmad</given_name>
					<surname>Zanganeh</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="5">
					<given_name>Moosa</given_name>
					<surname>Kamanroodi Kajouri</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Urban poverty is one of the main concerns of the 21st century and fighting against it is at the top of the millennium development goals. This paper has been done aiming to identify and analyze spatially areas of urban poverty. It has been done with quantitative method and survey based on secondary analysis in Tehran Metropolis in a way that calculated items were categorized based on four main factors of housing including economic, social, cultural, and educational ones and 43 indexes. They were selected by using statistical blocks data of Tehran Metropolis based on population and housing census in 2011. The results indicated that four extracted factors determine 72.7 percent of distribution of the total variance including housing poverty (28.7 percent), economic poverty (18.4 percent), social poverty (14.1 percent), and educational-cultural poverty (11.5 percent) respectively. They also indicated that districts 17, 19, 18, and 16 had the highest ranks regarding all poverty factors including economic, social, cultural, and educational ones. It is recommended to prioritize poverty alleviation and empowerment in development measures. However, the results of fuzzy VIKOR showed that there were 2312 very poor blocks (38.5 percent), 2049 poor blocks (34.1 percent), 1068 average blocks (17.8 percent), 458 rich blocks (7.6 percent), and only 114 very rich blocks.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>spatial analysis</keyword>
	<keyword>urban poverty</keyword>
	<keyword>Tehran Metropolis</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2016</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>19</first_page>
								  <last_page>36</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-460-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>16-461</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2016</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>4</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>15</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Ranking Components of Household’s Residential Movement Model Emphasizing on Economic View of Housing  (Case Study: Seyyed Khandan Neighborhood-Tehran District 3)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Hossein</given_name>
					<surname>Mohammadpour Zarandi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mohammadreza</given_name>
					<surname>Daroudi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			One of the aspects of city dynamism is households&#8217; movement from one residential neighborhood to other ones inside the city. These movements that affect city structure have various reasons. Assessing the reasons of household&#8217;s residential movement is very complex task since it is due to the concept of residential satisfaction or dissatisfaction. However, this movement, depending on the type of ownership, can be done based on people&#8217;s indexes and factors. Therefore, this paper aims to analyze and prioritize importance of residential movement indexes emphasizing on the type of people and households&#8217; ownership in Seyyed Khandan neighborhood of Tehran. To determine sample size of the case study, Cochran formula was used and 175 questionnaires were distributed in the neighborhood. However, in order to prioritize residential indexes in two aspects of (owner/tenant), Entropy and qualitative method of SAW were used. This paper indicates that educated landowners have high tendency and jobless landowners have low tendency to move. This may be due to their fear of losing the ownership of their residential units because of fluctuations in the housing market. However, tenants who earn high income tend to have successive movements greatly and those who are unemployed or earn low revenue prefer to stay in their residential environment. Therefore, it is recommended that banking facilities and urban projects to be increased in line with providing houses for households in order to reduce their repetitive movements.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>residential movement</keyword>
	<keyword>prioritization</keyword>
	<keyword>type of ownership</keyword>
	<keyword>Seyyed Khandan neighborhood</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2016</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>37</first_page>
								  <last_page>53</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-461-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>16-462</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2016</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>4</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>15</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Identification of Effective Dimensions on Forecasting Urban Planning with Economic Approach (Case Study: Sustainable Development of Qazvin)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Hesam</given_name>
					<surname>Zand Hesami</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Shiva</given_name>
					<surname>Shahramfar</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			This paper aims to identify effective aspects of forecasting on city management in order to illustrate opportunities and discover the advantages of available tools with economic approach. In terms of purpose, this research is applied, and in terms of data collection, it is descriptive-survey. Sampling method is purposeful and 10 experts were considered as sample size. Consolidated questionnaire was used for data collection. In order to measure validity of the questionnaire, convergent validity test was used. To check reliability, Cronbach&#8217;s alpha coefficient was calculated as 0.793. KMO and Bartlett&#8217;s tests, developed mean-variance approach t-test were used. To perform statistical operations, PLS and SPSS 17 were used. In this research, the indexes were identified by using Delphi technique and eight major indexes including quality of life, environmental thinking, transport, compatibility of economic environment, economic infrastructures of the society, economic health of the society, housing, and energy were selected and all hypotheses were confirmed. Finally, three types of forecasting were proposed. This paper tries to present a model for participatory forecast based on urban economy in city management (case study: city of Qazvin). However, three scenarios were proposed considering economic conditions of Qazvin entitled continuation of status, rapid growth and interconnectedness with the global economy, and balanced growth and interconnectedness with the global economy. Therefore, according to these scenarios, practical suggestions were proposed in line with much dynamism of Qazvin urban economy.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>forecast</keyword>
	<keyword>urban planning</keyword>
	<keyword>sustainable development</keyword>
	<keyword>urban economy</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2016</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>55</first_page>
								  <last_page>73</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-462-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>16-463</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2016</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>4</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>15</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Identification of the Relationship between Tourism Industry Development and Economic Growth of Zanjan Province</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Esmael</given_name>
					<surname>Nasiri Hendeh Khaleh</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Faramarz</given_name>
					<surname>Hadavi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Mahdi</given_name>
					<surname>Zamani</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Today, tourism industry, as a dynamic industry, has devoted an important part of production activities in the world by its development-oriented features. Hence its development in a country requires factors such as an appropriate strategy, planning and efficient management. In this paper, the status of tourism industry in Zanjan Province has been evaluated using SWOT technique and Input-Output table. The use of expert judgment of &#8220;Delphi&#8221; is used so that the judgment of the expert group a list of internal factors (strengths and weaknesses) and external (opportunities and threats) influencing the approach taken and the quantification was carried out .Methods of data collection and data analysis are applied and descriptive-analytical. According to the research findings, Zanjan province can become one of the big tourism hubs in the country because of its special geographical location and being between two industrial hubs of Tehran and East. Azerbaijan Provinces. Its strategy is defensive one, and strategies were proposed based on QSPM matrix at the end. Based on research findings in Zanjan province, tourism industry and its related sectors, in terms of linking with other sectors of the economy, can be considered as leading sectors in the economy of Zanjan Province. Therefore, this industry can boost the whole economy of Zanjan by supplying tourism services, demand for enjoying them, and producing tourism goods in other sectors. With regard to these potentials, tourism should be placed on the priority of the province planners in order to exploit them in line with the economy of this province.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Tourism industry</keyword>
	<keyword>Economy development</keyword>
	<keyword>Zanjan province</keyword>
	<keyword>Input-Output table</keyword>
	<keyword>SWOT technique</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2016</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>75</first_page>
								  <last_page>94</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-463-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>16-464</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2016</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>4</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>15</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Transport and Urban Traffic Management in Tehran with Economic View</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Seyyed Teymoor</given_name>
					<surname>Hosseini</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mohammad</given_name>
					<surname>Ariyana</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Seyyed Mojtaba</given_name>
					<surname>Abroodi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			One of the management issues in the city of Tehran is urban traffic. In the city of Tehran, population increase and limited resources have resulted in confusion and disorganization in dealing with this matter. Identification of difficulties and effective factors on traffic and transport management of Tehran, particularly dealing with urban sectors, meets the need of city management in a relatively short time. Given the importance of this issue, identification of effective factors on traffic and transport management can have significant impacts on solving traffic problems and it can prepare the ground for application of optimal city management. Thus, the purpose of this research is to identify and prioritize effective components on traffic and transport management of Tehran with economic view and application of AHP method. Statistical population includes experts in different fields of servicing, economic, social, and military ones that is estimated about 100 people and 50 of them were selected by purposive quota sampling to for paired comparisons. In this regard, data were collected by questionnaire, and they were examined by AHP technique and Expert Choice software. The results indicated the component of access priority toward movement that results in reducing traffic and consequently costs, is the most important component in urban traffic and transport management in Tehran; therefore, it is recommended that movement at different levels and range of public transport, as major components in policy-making, should be included in the priority of urban plans in order to reduce costs.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>transport</keyword>
	<keyword>traffic management</keyword>
	<keyword>urban planning</keyword>
	<keyword>public arena</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2016</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>95</first_page>
								  <last_page>109</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-464-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>16-465</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2016</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>4</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>15</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Cost Management of Urban Green Space (Case Study: Tehran)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Jafar</given_name>
					<surname>Masoomzadeh</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Morteza</given_name>
					<surname>Rahmani</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Azozollah</given_name>
					<surname>Jafari</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Urban green space is one of the most important components in city management and cities&#8217; development given its social and environmental functions and financial and economic aspects. Different species of plants including trees, shrubs, cover crops and flowers or seasonal plants have specific features in terms of climate-compatible of Tehran and water demand. They also have different roles in meeting expected functions of urban green space, particularly prettification and reducing air pollution by producing oxygen. Thus, this paper tries to study selection criteria, assess plant species, and determine appropriate criterion for Tehran green space. Then, it determines relative weight of each one by surveying 35 experts&#8217; view in the form of group analytical hierarchy process (GAHP) method. The obtained weights are instruments for valuation of 60 Tehran&#8217;s main plant species done by simple valuation (linear) and TOPSIS methods.&#160; The results indicated that evergreen oak, elm, and silver cypress are the most valuable species. Ranking of plant species were obtained by two mentioned methods in each of four groups that they were almost matched with each other. Using these ranks has increased at least 33 percent of productivity cost of urban green space in replanting project of municipality districts as well as increasing citizens&#8217; satisfaction and life of plant species that is in line with resistance economy.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Analytical Hierarchy Process (AHP)</keyword>
	<keyword>urban green space</keyword>
	<keyword>cost management</keyword>
	<keyword>TOPSIS model</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2016</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>111</first_page>
								  <last_page>125</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-465-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>16-466</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-27</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>IUESA</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2345-2870</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-6398</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>10.29252/iueam</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2016</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>4</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>15</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Investigation of Educational Needs with Job Analysis Approach  (Case Study: Financial and Urban Economy Experts of Tehran Municipality)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Seyyed Mohsen</given_name>
					<surname>Tabatabaei Mozdabadi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Progress and development of organizations depend on improving the level of knowledge, insight, and skills of their human resources so that organizations can achieve to competitive advantage in line with their scientific and economic goals as well as innovation. The first step of educational planning in organizations is to determine educational needs and present educational plans for employees&#8217; growth and education. Educational needs are related to the knowledge, attitude or skills that human resources need them in order to carry out their job responsibilities optimally. Thus, this paper has been done aiming to investigate educational needs with the approach of job analysis. Research method is mixed exploratory. In qualitative part, research samples were 13 financial and urban economy experts selected by purposive sampling. Data were collected by semi-structured interview. In this part, required knowledge, skill, technology, and instrument for four jobs of accountant, auditor, document expert, and urban economy expert of Tehran Municipality were identified and four questionnaires were developed based on it. In quantitative part, 143 people were selected by simple random sampling method among financial and urban economy experts of Tehran Municipality including 62 urban economy experts, 49 accountants, 22 auditors, and 10 document experts. In order to analyze data statistically, Lee Hee and one sample t-tests were used. Finally, educational needs of four jobs including accountant, auditor, document expert, and financial and urban economy expert of Tehran Municipality were obtained. According to the priorities, for high priority needs, educational plan was proposed for the first year.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>: Educational needs</keyword>
	<keyword>job analysis</keyword>
	<keyword>financial and urban economy experts</keyword>
	<keyword>Tehran Municipality</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2016</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>127</first_page>
								  <last_page>146</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iueam.ir/article-1-466-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
			
		</ListRecords>
		</OAI-PMH>
		 
  
  
  
  
 