<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Journal of Urban Economics and Management</title>
<title_fa>فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی اقتصاد و مدیریت شهری</title_fa>
<short_title>IUESA</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iueam.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2345-2870</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-6398</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/iueam</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>en</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1395</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>5</volume>
<number>17</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>نقش سرمایه اجتماعی، تعهد و رفتار شهروندی سازمانی در بهبود عملکرد شغلی (مورد مطالعه: شهرداری شهرستان خوی)</title_fa>
	<title>The Role of Social Capital, Commitment, and Organizational Citizenship Behavior in Improving Job Performance
(Case Study: Khoy Municipality)
</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:yekanyw;&quot;&gt;امروزه، شهرداری به&amp;lrm;عنوان یکی از بزرگ&amp;lrm;ترین نهادهای اجتماعی محسوب می&amp;lrm;شود و اثربخشی این ارگان، مستلزم ساختار سازمانی مناسب و تعهد کارکنان به&#8204;منظور افزایش عملکرد است. مدیران به منظور کسب خدماتی با کیفیت بالاتر، باید بر نگرش و رفتار کارکنان خدماتی، از طریق پیشینه فرهنگی، الگو&#8204;های رفتاری و شیوه&#8204;&#8204;های مدیریتی، تمرکز کنند. از این&#8204; رو سرمایه اجتماعی، با خلق هنجار&#8204;ها و اعتماد متقابل، موجب تحقق اهداف اعضا می&#8204;شود و بستر مناسبی برای بهره&#8204;وری سرمایه انسانی، مالی و اقتصادی ایجاد می&#8204;کند. در این&#8204; راستا، تحقیق حاضر به بررسی تأثیر سرمایه اجتماعی بر عملکرد شغلی با در نظر گرفتن مواردی چون تعهد کارکنان و رفتارهای شهروندی سازمانی پرداخته است. جامعه آماری تحقیق، 140 نفر از کارکنان ستادی شهرداری شهرستان خوی است. این پژوهش از لحاظ روش، توصیفی از نوع همبستگی است و داده&amp;lrm;&#8204;ها از طریق پرسشنامه، جمع&amp;lrm;آوری شدند. به&#8204;منظور سنجش روایی پرسشنامه تحقیق، از تحلیل عاملی تأییدی مرتبه اول و دوم و جهت تعیین پایایی، از آلفای کرونباخ استفاده شد. داده&#8204;&#8204;ها نیز با استفاده از مدل معادلات ساختاری تحلیل شدند. نتایج تحقیق، حاکی از تأثیر مثبت سرمایه اجتماعی بر تعهد کارکنان، رفتارهای شهروندی سازمانی و عملکرد شغلی بودند. همچنین تأثیر مثبت تعهد کارکنان و بروز رفتارهای شهروندی سازمانی توسط آن&#8204;ها بر عملکرد شغلی نیز تأیید شد. در نتیجه می&#8204;&#8204;توان گفت بهبود فرایندهای مربوط به تعهد کارکنان و رفتارهای شهروندی سازمانی که متأثر از عواملی چون سرمایه اجتماعی است، منجر به ارتقای عملکرد شغلی کارکنان می&#8204;شود.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px;&quot;&gt;Today, municipality is counted as one of the largest social bodies. Its effectiveness requires appropriately organizational structure and employees&amp;rsquo; commitment to increase performance. Managers should concentrate on attitude and behavior of service staff through cultural background, behavioral patterns, and managerial styles in order to obtain higher quality services. Thus, social capital results in achievement of members&amp;rsquo; objectives by creating norms and mutual trust and it prepares a suitable ground for efficiency of human, financial, and economic capital. In this regard, this research investigates the impact of social capital on job performance by considering issues such as employees&amp;rsquo; commitment and organizational citizenship behaviors. Statistical population includes 140 headquarters staff of Khoy Municipality. This research method is descriptive and correlational. Data were collected by questionnaire. In order to measure validity, the first and second order confirmatory factor analysis was used. To determine reliability, Cronbach&amp;rsquo;s alpha was used. Data were analyzed by Structural Equation Modeling. The results indicated positive impact of social capital on employees&amp;rsquo; commitment, organizational citizenship behaviors, and job performance. However, the positive impact of employees&amp;rsquo; commitment and organizational citizenship behaviors on their job performance was confirmed. As a result, it can be stated that improvement of processes related to employees&amp;rsquo; commitment and organizational citizenship behaviors, affected by factors such as social capital, results in improvement of employees&amp;rsquo; job performance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>سرمایه اجتماعی, تعهد به کیفیت خدمات, تعهد به سازمان, رفتارهای شهروندی سازمانی, عملکرد شغلی</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Social capital, commitment to quality of services, commitment to organization, organizational citizenship behaviors, job performance</keyword>
	<start_page>115</start_page>
	<end_page>132</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iueam.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-158-51&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad Ali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Nemati</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمدعلی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نعمتی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846003163</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003163</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Psychology and Educational Sciences, Allameh Tabatabaei University Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده روان‌شناسی و علوم تربیتی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Morteza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Akbarzadeh Safooei</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مرتضی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>اکبرزاده صفوئی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>M.Akbarzadeh651@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846003164</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003164</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Economics, Management, and Administrative Sciences, Semnan University, Semnan, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده اقتصاد، مدیریت و علوم اداری دانشگاه سمنان، سمنان، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Somayyeh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Zangiyan</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سمیه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>زنگیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846003165</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003165</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Economics, Management, and Administrative Sciences, Semnan University, Semnan, Iran </affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده اقتصاد، مدیریت و علوم اداری دانشگاه سمنان، سمنان، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mansoor</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Baqersad Ranani</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>منصور</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>باقرصاد رنانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846003166</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003166</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Geographical Sciences and Planning, University of Isfahan, Isfahan, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده علوم جغرافیایی و برنامه‌ریزی، دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
