<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Factors Affecting Stock Return of Firms Listed in Tehran Stock Exchange: Meta-analysis Approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>عوامل مؤثر در بازده سهام شرکت‏های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران: رویکرد فراتحلیل</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>29</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>50</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">21193</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21193</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>باقر</FirstName>
					<LastName>عسگرنژاد نوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار مدیریت بازرگانی، گروه مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشکدۀ ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی، اردبیل، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>12</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study is to investigate the factors influencing firms &#039;stock return using meta-analysis approach. The study population consists of studies that had examined factors affecting stock returns of listed firms in Tehran Stock Exchange. Accordingly, a total of 89 different research are selected. Based on the literature review, the following factors are considered; liquidity ratios, leverage ratios, activity ratios, profitability ratios, multiple ratios cash flow ratios, risk indicators, earning management indicator, earning forecast, real investment and firm characteristics. The results show that the effect of liquidity ratios, leverage ratios, activity ratios, earning management indicator and firm characteristics on stock return are not significant. But the positive effect of profitability ratios consists of return on equity, profit and profit margin, market-based ratios consist of market return, cash flow ratios consist of cash flow based on operations, risk indicators including market risk premium, indices of earning forecast including the time horizon of profit forecasts and eventually real investment are confirmed.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف این پژوهش، بررسی عوامل مؤثر در بازده سهام شرکت‏ها با به‌کارگیری روش فراتحلیل است. جامعۀ آماری پژوهش شامل مطالعاتی است که عوامل مؤثر در بازده سهام شرکت را در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران  بررسی کرده است. براساس این، درمجموع، 89 پژوهش مختلف انتخاب شد. براساس پیشینۀ پژوهش، عوامل مؤثر شامل نسبت‏های نقدینگی، اهرمی، فعالیت، سودآوری، بازار، جریان‏های نقدی، شاخص‏های ریسک، مدیریت سود، پیش‌بینی سود، سرمایه‌گذاری واقعی و ویژگی‏های شرکت در نظر گرفته شد. نتایج نشان داد نسبت‏های نقدینگی، اهرمی، فعالیت، مدیریت سود و ویژگی‏های شرکت در بازده سهام شرکت‏ها تأثیر نداشته است؛ اما تأثیر مثبت سایر عوامل یعنی نسبت‏های سودآوری شامل نرخ بازده حقوق صاحبان سهام، میزان سود و حاشیۀ سود، نسبت‏های بازار شامل بازده بازار، نسبت‏های جریان‏های نقدی شامل جریان‏های نقدی ناشی از عملیات، شاخص‏های ریسک شامل صرف ریسک، شاخص‏های پیش‌بینی سود شامل افق زمانی پیش‌بینی سود و در‌نهایت، سرمایه‌گذاری واقعی در بازده سهام تأیید شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازده سهام</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش فراتحلیل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه‏گذاری مالی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21193_188ee8d19c7238afbc14f22e44cca47d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
