<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1394</YEAR>
<VOL>3</VOL>
<NO>3</NO>
<MOSALSAL>3</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>0</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</TitleF>
				<TitleE></TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT></CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>-</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>0</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>0</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر فعالیت‌های سرمایه‌گذاری نقدی و غیر نقدی در تبیین قیمت سهام و عملکرد آتی شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Investigation Effect of Investments (including cash and non-cash) in Explaining Future Performance of the Listed Companies in Tehran Stock Exchange</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در این پژوهش نقش جریان‌های نقدی حاصل از فعالیت‌های سرمایه‌گذاری و اطلاعات مربوط به سرمایه‌گذاری‌های غیرنقدی در ارزیابی قیمت سهام و عملکرد آتی شرکت‌ها بررسی و مطالعه شده است. در راستای دستیابی به هدف مذکور فرضیه‌های پژوهش با استفاده از داده‌های تلفیقی 90 شرکت پذیرفته شده در بازار بورس اوراق بهادار تهران که اطلاعات مورد نیاز پژوهش برای دوره یازده ساله پژوهش (1391-1380) در خصوص آنها قابل دسترسی بود، مورد بررسی و آزمون قرار گرفت. نتایج این پژوهش، نشان دهنده دو واقعیت است؛ اول این که، جریان‌های نقدی سرمایه‌گذاری اطلاعات ارزشمندی در خصوص سرمایه‌گذاری‌های شرکت به منظور کمک به استفاده کنندگان از صورت‌های مالی در ارزیابی قیمت سهام و عملکرد آتی شرکت‌ فراهم می‌کند و دوم این که، اطلاعات مربوط به سرمایه‌گذاری‌های غیرنقدی شرکت نیز اگر چه در متن صورت‌های مالی منعکس نمی‌شوند، لیکن برای مقاصد ارزیابی وضعیت آتی شرکت اطلاعات سودمند و مربوطی هستند. افزون بر این، نتایج آزمون تأثیرضرایب در مدل‌های تفکیکی اجزای جریان‌های نقدی سرمایه‌گذاری نیز حاکی از تفاوت معناداری بین ضرایب مورد استفاده برای هر یک از عناصر مزبور است، به این معنی که محتوای اطلاعاتی هر یک از اجزای جریان‌های نقدی سرمایه‌گذاری شرکت‌ها متفاوت از یکدیگر است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Investors to invest in stocks when the optimal selection requires the evaluation of information, such as liquidity, ability to pay the debts of the business unit and profitability are. Many studies examined significance of the financial statement items in explaining the company&#039;s future performance, up now in this paper we will investigates whether financial statements, particularly the cash flow statement, provide users with usefulness information on investment transactions. To investigate this issue, tested the 97 companies listed in Tehran stock exchange during the period 1380 to 1390. In this study, the adjusted R2 is used to test the hypotheses. Highest adjusted R2 indicates that the model has the highest explanatory power of future performance company. By taking all the information and results obtained from the CFO and stock prices, evidence shows that investment sector cash flow statement provides information on the Future performance. In addition, results show that non-cash investing provide addition to information CFI</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>20</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بهار مقدم</Family>
						<NameE>mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Baharmoghadam</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.bahar330@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سیده سحر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>داودی</Family>
						<NameE>seyedeh sahar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Davoody</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه پیام نور مرکز رامهرمز</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه پیام نور مرکز رامهرمز</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sahar_davoody@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نسرین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>یوسف زاده</Family>
						<NameE>nasrin</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Yousef zadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه ولیعصر (عج) رفسنجان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه ولیعصر (عج) رفسنجان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>n.yousefzadeh@vru.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>زینب</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>اعظمی</Family>
						<NameE>Zeinab</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Aazami</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ze.aazami@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جریان‌های نقدی حاصل از فعالیت‌های سرمایه‌گذاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایه‌گذاری‌های غیرنقدی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قیمت سهام</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عملکرد آتی شرکت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1]   بهرامفر، نقی؛ مهرانی،کاوه. (1383).رابطهبینسودهرسهم،سودتقسیمیوسرمایهگذاریدر شرکت‌هایپذیرفتهشدهدربورساوراقبهادارتهران،فصلنامهحسابداریوحسابرسی، سال یازدهم،شماره36، ص46 -27.##[2]   پور حیدری، امید؛ افلاطونی، عباس؛ نیکبخت، زهرا.(1389). بررسی توانایی وجوه نقد حاصل از فعالیت‌های عملیاتی در پیش­بینی وجوه نقد آتی. فصلنامه مطالعات حسابداری، شماره 26، ص 45-29.##[3]   دستگیر، محسن؛ خدابنده، رامین. (1382). بررسی ارتباط بین محتوای اطلاعاتی اجزای اصلی صورت جریان وجه نقد با بازده سهام. مجله علوم اجتماعی و انسانی دانشگاه شیراز، دوره نوزدهم، شماره دوم،ص 112-100.##[4]     شباهنگ،رضا.(1381).تئوریحسابداری. جلداول. انتشاراتمرکزپژوهشاتتخصصیحسابداریوحسابرسیسازمان حسابرسی،تهران.##[5]   فروغی، داریوش؛ فرزادی، سعید. (1393). بررسیتأثیرتغییراتجریان‌هاینقدیبرسطحنگهداشتوجهنقدبادرنظرگرفتنمحدودیتتأمین مالیشرکت‌هایپذیرفتهشدهدربورساوراقبهادارتهران. فصلنامه مدیریت دارایی و تامین مالی، شماره چهارم، ص 36-21.##[6]   ولی زاده لاریجانی، اعظم؛ مجتهدزاده،ویدا؛ حجازی، رضوان. (1392). تأثیر کیفیت افشا بر رابطه ارزشی اقلام صورت‌های مالی. فصلنامه مدیریت دارایی و تامین مالی، شماره اول، ص 26-13.##[7]   Agrawal, A.; Jaffe, J. F., and Mandelker, G. N. (1992). The Post-Merger Performance of Acquiring Firms: A Re-Examination of an Anomaly. The Journal of Finance 47 (4): 1,605-1,621.##[8]   Al-Attar, A., and Hussain, S. (2004). Corporate Data and Future Cash Flows. Journal of Business Finance and Accounting 31: 861-903.##[9]   Amir, E.; Guan, Y., and Livne, G. (2007). The Association of R&amp;D and Capital Expenditures with Subsequent Earnings Variability. Journal of Business Finance And Accounting 34 (1 &amp; 2): 222-246.##[10]            Antoniou, A.; Petmezas, D., And Zhao, H. (2007). Bidder Gains and Losses of Firms Involved In Many Acquisitions. Journal of Business Finance AndAccounting 34: 1,221-1,244.##[11]            Barth, M.; Beaver, W. H.; Hand, J. R. M., and Landsman, W. R. (1999). Accruals, Cash Fl Ows and Equity Values. Review Of Accounting Studies 3: 205-229.##[12]            Barth, M.; Cram, D., and Nelson, K. (2001). Accruals and the Prediction of Future Cash Flows. The Accounting Review 76: 27-58.##[13]            Basu, N.; Dimitrova, L., And Paeglis, I. (2009). Family Control and Dilution in Mergers. Journal of Banking and Finance 33: 829-841.##[14]            Bergh, D. D. (1995). Size And Relatedness of Units Sold: An Agency Theory and Resource-Based Perspective.Strategic Management Journal 16: 221-239.##[15]            Biddle, G. C.; Hilary, G., and Verdi, R. S. (2009). How Does Financial Reporting Quality Relate to Investment Efficiency? Journal of Accounting And Economics 48: 112-131##[16]            Bowen, R., Burgstahler, D., &amp;Daley, L. (1986). Evidence on the Relationships between Earnings and Various Measures of Cash Flow. The Accounting Review, 61(4), 713-725.##[17]            Collins, D.; Maydew, E., and Weiss, I. (1997). Changes in the Value-Relevance of Earnings and Book Values over the Past Forty Years. Journal of Accounting and Economics 24: 39-67.##[18]            Dittmar, A., and Shivdasani, A. (2008). Divestitures and Divisional Investment Policies. The Journal of Finance ,58 (6): 2,711-2,743.##[19]            Faccio, M., Masulis, R. (2005). The Choice of Payment Method in European Mergers and Acquisitions.The Journal of Finance 60 (3): 1,345-388.##[20]            Fazzari, S.R,. (2000), Investment-Cash Flow Sensitivities Are Useful: A Comment on Kaplan and Zingales. The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 115, 595-705.##[21]            Fuller, K.; Netter, J., and Stegemoller, M. (2002). What Do Returns to Acquiring Firms Tell Us? Evidence from Firms That Make Many Acquisitions. The Journal of Finance 57 (4): 1,763-1,793.##[22]            Gadad, A.-M., and Thomas, H. M. (2004). Do Asset Sales Lead To Improvements in Operating Performance.Applied Economics 36: 865-871.##[23]            Garca Lara, J. M, Garca Osma, B., AndPenalva, F. (2010). Accounting Conservatism and Firm Investment efficiency, Working Paper Available aHttp://Papers.Ssrn.Com/Sol3/Papers.Cfm?Abstract_Id=1383642(Access on 8 May 2012).##[24]            Haynes, M.; Thompson, S., and Wright, M. (2002). The Impact of Divestment on Firm Performance: Empirical Evidence from a Panel of UK Companies. Journal of Industrial Economics 50: 173-196.##[25]            Healy, P. M.; Palepu, K. G., and Ruback, S. (1992). Does Corporate Performance Improve After Mergers?,Journal ofFinancial Economics 31: 135-175.##[26]            Hillier, D.; Mccolgan, P., And Werema, S. (2009). Asset Sales and Firm Strategy: An Analysis of Divestitures by UK Companies. The European Journal of Finance 15 (1): 71-87.##[27]            Hirshleifer, D, and Teoh, S. H. (2003). Limited Attention, Information Disclosure, and Financial Reporting. Journal of Accounting and Economics 36: 337-386.##[28]            Hope, O. K., and Thomas, W. B. (2008). Managerial Empire Building and Firm Disclosure. Journal of Accounting Research 46 (3): 591-626.##[29]            Hubbard, R., and Palia, D. (1999). A Re-Examination of the Conglomerate Merger Wave of the 1960s: an Internal Capital Market View. Journal of Finance 54: 1,131-1,152.##[30]            Jensen, M. (1993). The Modern Industrial Revolution: Exit and Failure of Internal Control Mechanisms. The Journal of Finance 48: 831-880.##[31]            John, K., and ofek, E. (1995). Asset Sales and Increase in Focus. Journal of Financial Economics 37:105-126.##[32]            Juknevicius, M., Minzararu, D. (2011). The Relevance of Earnings and Cash Flows Measures in Explaining Security Returns over Long Intervals: Evidence from Sweden. Msc Thesis in Accounting and Financial Management, Stockholm School of Economics.##[33]            Kerstein, J., And Kim, S. (1995). The Incremental Information Content of Capital Expenditures. The Accounting Review, 70 (3): 513-526.##[34]            Kim, M., and Kross, W. (2005). The Ability of Earnings to Predict Future Operating Cash Flows Has Been Increasing-Not Decreasing. Journal of Accounting and Economics 43: 753-780.##[35]            Kusuma,H. (2014). The Incremental Information Content of the Cash Flow Statement: an Australian Empirical Investigation.International Journal of Business Administration 4:90-102.##[36]            Lasfer, M.; Sudarsanam, S., and Taffler, R. (1996). Financial Distress, Asset Sales and Lender Monitoring.Financial Management 25: 57-66.##[37]            Lee, B. S., Nohel, T. (1997). Value Maximization and the Information Content of Corporate Investment With Respect to Earnings. Journal of Banking and Finance 21: 661-683.##[38]            Li,D.(2010). Financial Constraints: R&amp;D Investment, and StockReturns. Rady School of Management University of Colifornia Sandiego 1-6,22-24##[39]            Livnat, J., and Zarowin, P. (1990). The Incremental Information Content of Cash-Flow Components. Journal of Accounting and Economics 13: 25-46.##[40]            Loughran, T., and Vijh, A. M. (1997). Do Long-Term Shareholders Benefit From Corporate Acquisitions? The Journal of Finance 52 (5): 1,765-1,790.##[41]            Martin, K. J. (1996). The Method of Payment in Corporate Acquisitions, Investment Opportunities, and Management Ownership. The Journal of Finance 51 (4): 1,227-1,246.##[42]            Mcconnell, J. J., Muscarella, C. J. (1985). Corporate Capital Expenditure Decisions and the Market Value of the Firm. Journal of Financial Economics 14: 399-422##[43]            Moeller, S. B.; Schlingemann, F. P., and Stulz, R. M. (2004). Firm Size and the Gains from Acquisitions. Journal of Financial Economics 73: 201-228.##[44]            Oler, D. K. (2008). Does Acquirer Cash Level Predict Post-Acquisition Returns? Review of Accounting Studies 13: 479-511.##[45]            Rodriguez, M., and Stonegrinder, F., and Lamas, R. (2012). Do Investing Cash Flow Help In Explaining Future Corporate Performance?.Spanish Journals Financing Accounting 154: 185-208.##[46]            Rau, P. R., and Vermaelen, T. (1998). Glamour, Value and The Post-Acquisition Performance of acquiring Firms. Journal OfFinancial Economics 49: 223-253.##[47]            Savor, P., And Lu, Q. (2009). Do Stock Mergers Create Value For Acquirers? The Journal of Finance ,64 (3): 1,061-1,097.##[48]            Shleifer, A, And Vishny, R. W. (2003). Stock Market Driven Acquisitions. Journal of Financial Economics 70: 295-311.##[49]            Song, C. J.; Thomas, W. B., And Yi, H. (2010). Value Relevance of FAS N;157 Fair Value Hierarchy Informationand the Impact of Corporate Governance Mechanisms. The Accounting Review, 85 (4): 1,375-1,410.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تصمیمات تامین مالی و زمان سنجی مدیریت، شواهدی از بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Financing Decisions and Managerial Market Timing Evidence from Tehran Stock Exchange</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>از جمله عوامل برجسته در ادبیات مالی، پیگیری تصمیم‌های مدیریت هنگام تأمین منابع مورد نیاز و بررسی شرایط متفاوت مالی شرکت در هنگام این رویداد است. به­طوری که این پرسش مطرح شده است که آیا با پی­جویی تصمیم مدیریت در هنگام تأمین منابع مالی، می­توان وضعیت شرکت (از نظر ساختار مالی و عملکرد آن) را پی­گیری نمود. در این پژوهش با بررسی وضعیت تأمین مالی، برای توصیف شرایط شرکت­ها از مبانی نظری و ادبیات مالی نظیرزمان سنجی مدیریت و نظریه ترجیحی استفاده شده است. با استفاده از نمونه شامل بر1506 سال- شرکت طی دوره زمانی 1381 –1390 نتایج پژوهش­شواهدی را در مورد پذیرش فرضیه زمان سنجی مدیریت برای شرکت­های مورد مطالعه فراهم نکرده است. همچنین، نتایج نشان دهنده تأثیر منفی تأمین مالی بر بازده بازار، برای شرکت­های با خالص تأمین مالی منفی بود. در بررسی شرایط شرکت­ها در عرضه اولیه و کنترل آنها در مدل پژوهش، نتایج مشخص ساخته است که تأمین مالی خالص مثبت این شرکت­ها، تأثیر با اهمیتی بر بازده آنها داشته است. همچنین سایرنتایج پژوهش نشان داده است شرکت‌هایی که توانایی بهتری در استفاده از منابع داخلی دارند، عملکرد بهتری نیز در بازار داشته­اند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Managerial financing decisions seem to change the predictions of the financial model about how often and under what circumstances firms use financial resources. The financial accounting literature uses market timing hypothesis, pecking order theories to explain managementâs financing decision. We examine how market timing affects managementâs net financing decision using a sample of firms listed in Tehran Stock exchange over the period of 2002 to 2011. Our results do not provide support for the market timing hypothesis. We also find a negative association between net financing and firmsâ market return suggesting a negative impact of the net financing decision on firmsâ return. Our results show no association between initial public offering and firmsâ market return. This suggests that a suitable market return did not appear in initial public offerings. The findings also show that firms with an ability of using internal resources in its capital structure are more likely to perform well than expected in the capital market.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>21</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>36</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>داغانی</Family>
						<NameE>Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Daghani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>reza.daghani@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>اعتمادی</Family>
						<NameE>Hossien</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Etemadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>etemadih@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مسعود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عزیزخانی</Family>
						<NameE>masoud</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Azizkhani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه ایلام</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه ایلام</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mazizkhani@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی اصغر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>انواری رستمی</Family>
						<NameE>Aliasghar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Anvarirostami</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>anvary@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فرضیه زمان سنجی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تامین مالی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>انتخاب</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عملکرد شرکت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1]  ایزدی‌نیا، ناصر؛رحیمی‌دستجردی، محسن. (1388). تاثیر ساختار سرمایه بر نرخ بازده سهام و درآمد هر سهم،تحقیقات حسابداری،1 (3):161-136##[2]  باقرزاده،سعید. (1382).تبیین الگوی ساختار سرمایه شرکت های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، پژوهش­های مالی،1:23-48##[3]  خانی، عبداله؛ افشاری، حمیده؛ حسینی، میرهادی. (1392). آزمون تصمیمات تامین مالی، زمانبندی بازار و سرمایه گذاری واقعی در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی،1 (1): 109-122##[4]  کردستانی، غلامرضا؛پیرداوری، طناز.(1391).ساختار سرمایه، آزمون تجربی نظریه زمانبندی بازار، دانش حسابداری، 3 (9):142-123##[5]  نصیرزاده،فرزانه؛مستقیمیان،علیرضا.(1389). آزمون نظریه­های ساختار سرمایه توازی ایستا (مصالحه ایستا) و سلسله مراتبی در شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار، پیشرفت­هایحسابداری،2: 133-158##[6].    Acharya, A. H. Almeida, and M. Campello. (2007) Is Cash Negative Debt? Ahedging Perspective on Corporate Financial Policies. Journal of Financial Intermediation, 16, 515-554.##[7].    Admandia R. (2013). Q Comparison BetweenTiming and Pseudo Timing, Journal of Business Finance &amp;Accounting,37(5-6), 612–647.##[8].    Hegab B.C. (2009).External Financing: Market Timing or Magerial Optimism, A Dissertation Presented In For The Degree Doctor of Business Administration - Finance, College of Business Louisiana Tech University.##[9].    Hovakimian, A., G. Hovakimian and H. Tehranian. (2004). Determinants of Target Capital Structure: The Case of Dual Debt and Equity Issues, Journal of Financial Economics, 71,517-540.##[10].  Jensen, Michael C. And William H. Meckling. (1976). Theory of the Firm: Managerial Behaviour, Agency Costs and Ownership Structure. Journal of Financial Economics3(4):305-360.##[11].  Kevin K. Li.(2008). Expected Holding of Cash, Future Performance and Stock Return, Working Paper, University of Toronto.##[12].  Leary, M.T. And M.R. Roberts. (2005). Do Firms Rebalance Their Capital Structures? Journal of Finance, 60(6), 2575-2619.##[13].  Lemmon M L. and Zender J. F. (2010). Debt Capacity and Tests of Capital Structure Theories., 45(5), 1161-1187.##[14].  Lewis, Craig M. and Tan, Y. (2014).Debt-Equity Choices, Growth Options and Market Timing, Working Paper,Owen Graduate School of Management, Vanderbilt University,United States.##[15].  Loughran, T. And Ritter, J.R. (1995). ‘The New Issues Puzzle’, Journal of Finance, 50, 23-51.##[16].  Malmendier, U. G. Tate, J. Yan. (2011). Overconfidence and Early-Life Experiences: The Effect of Managerial Traits on Corporate Financial Policies, Journal of Finance, 66(5), 1687–1733.##[17].  Mikkelson, W., and M. Partch. (2003). Do Persistent Large Cash Reserves Hinder Performance? Journal of Financial And Quantitative Analysis32( 2),275-294##[18].  Modigliani, F and Miller, M.H. (1958). The Cost of Capital,Corporation Finance and The Theory of Investment, AmericanEconomical Review, 261-297.##[19].  Modigliani, F. And Miller M. H. (1963). Corporate Income Taxes And The Cost of Capital: A Correction, American Economic Review, 53: 433-443##[20].  Myers, S. C. (2001). Capital Structure,The Journal of Economic Perspectives, 15(2);81-102.##[21].  Myers, S. C. And Majulf, N. S.(1984). Corporate Financing and Investment Decisions When Firms Have Information That Investors Do not Have, Journal ofFinancial Economics, 13,187-221##[22].  Neck H. M. (2001). Firm Growth Following The Initial Public Offering: The Impact of Organizational Slack on the Productive Opportunity of High-Technology Entrepreneurial Firms, University of Colorado at Boulder, DissertationsPublishing,No3034333.##[23].  Richardson S. (2006).Over-Investment of Free Cash Flow, Review of Accounting Studies,11(2-3),159-189##[24].  Richardson S. A. And Sloan R. G. (2003). External Financing And Future Stock Returns, Working Paper, The Rodney L. White Center For Financial Research,Wharton School,University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia.US.##[25].  Schultz,P.(2003).‘Pseudo Market Timing and TheLong-Run Underperformance of Ipos’, Journal Of Finance, 58(2); 483-518.##[26].  Simutin, M. (2010). Excess Cash and Stock Returns. Financial Management, 39)3(: 1197 1222.##[27].  Sloan R.G., Scott A. R. (2003) External Financingand Future Stock Returns, the Rodney L. White Centre for Financial Research University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia,USA.##[28].  Sodjahin, William R.(2013) Change in Cash-Holding Policies and Stock Return Predictability in the Cross Section, Financial Analysts Journal69(1).##[29].  Wang Chih-Yung, Yu-Fen Chen, Chia-Wen Yu.(2013), Managerial Optimism and Post-Financing Stock Performance in Taiwan: A Comparison of Debt and Equity Financing, Economics Letters, 119(3), 332-335.##[30].  Welch L. (2004).Capital Structure and Stock Returns, Journal of Political Economy, 112(1), 106-131.##[31].  Van Horn, J.C., (1995).Fundamentals of Financial Management, Practice Hall, 9th Edition.##                                                               ##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی آناتومیک رابطه بازده سهام و نوسان‌پذیری غیرسیستماتیک؛ شواهدی از بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>An Anatomic Study of the Relationship between Stock Return and Idiosyncratic Volatility Evidences from Tehran Stock Exchange</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف پژوهش حاضر توضیح خلاف قاعده نوسان‌پذیری غیرسیستماتیک بر مبنای تجزیه‌ نوسان‌های غیرسیستماتیک به دو مؤلفه نوسان‌های غیرسیستماتیک مورد انتظار (EIV) و نوسان‌های غیرسیستماتیک غیرمنتظره (UIV) و بررسی اثر تفکیکی آن در توضیح تغییرات بازده مقطعی سهام منفرد است. رابطه اخیر در نمونه‌ای­ متشکل از 95 شرکت پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران طی سال­های 1381 تا 1390 با استفاده از مدل فاما-مک‌بث (1973) و رویکرد تحلیل سبد سرمایه گذاری بررسی می‌شود. شواهد به دست آمده حاکی از آن است که EIV به تنهایی قادر به تبیین تغییرات بازده نیست، لیکن با احتساب همزمان EIV و UIV، ضریب مثبت UIV به لحاظ آماری معنادار می­گردد. نتایج به دست آمده پس از احتساب تأثیر متغیرهای کنترل و نیز در صورت استفاده از رویکرد تحلیل سبد سرمایه گذاری، کماکان برقرار است. لذا به نظر می‌رسد منشأ بروز خلاف قاعده نوسان‌پذیری غیرسیستماتیک در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران ناشی از اثرگذاری نوسان‌پذیری غیرسیستماتیک غیرمنتظره است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The purpose of this study is to explain the opposite of the idiosyncratic volatility based on breaking up the idiosyncratic volatility into expected idiosyncratic volatility (EIV) and unexpected idiosyncratic volatility (UIV) and analyzing its split effects on the explanation of cross-sectional changes of individual stock. This relationship is studied in a sample consisting of 95 companies approved in the Tehran Stock Exchange during the years 2002 and 2011 using Fama-Macbeth regression model (1973) and the portfolio approach. The evidences from the study show that EIV alone is not able to explain the return changes, so by taking both EIV and UIV simultaneously, the positive coefficient of UIV becomes meaningful in terms of the statistics. If size, book value to market value ratio, momentum, liquidity and dilatory effect are controlled, the results would remain the same. So it seems like the main source of the opposite of the idiosyncratic volatility in Tehran Stock Exchange is caused by the unexpected idiosyncratic volatility.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>37</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>48</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مریم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>دولو</Family>
						<NameE>maryam</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>davaloo</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ma_davallou@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عظیم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رجبی</Family>
						<NameE>azim</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>rajabi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>rajabi.azim1367@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نوسان‌پذیری غیرسیستماتیک کل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نوسان‌پذیری غیرسیستماتیک مورد انتظار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نوسان‌پذیری غیرسیستماتیک غیرمنتظره</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بازده مقطعی سهام</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1]   دولّو، مریم. (1391)، آزمون جامع قیمت‌گذاری ریسک غیرسیستماتیک: شواهدی از بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، پایان نامه دکتری، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی.##[2]   Ang, A, Hodrick, R, Xing, Y and Zhang, X. (2006).the Cross-Section of Volatility and Expected Returns”, Journal of Finance, 61, 259-299.##[3]   Bali, T and Cakici, C. (2006). Idiosyncratic Volatility and the Cross-Section of Expected Returns, Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis, forthcoming.##[4]   Chua, C, Goh, J and Zhang, Z. (2010). Expected Volatility, Unexpected Volatility and the Cross-section of Stock Returns, Journal of Financial Economics, 2, 103-123.##[5]   Fu, F. (2009). Idiosyncratic Risk and the Cross-Section of Expected Stock Returns, [Online] (Cited 28 April 2014) Available From www.SSRN.com&gt;.##[6]   Guo, H and Savickas, R. (2005). Idiosyncratic Volatility, Stock Market Volatility, and Expected Stock Returns, Working Paper.##[7]   Malkiel, B and Xu, Y. (2006). Idiosyncratic Risk and Security Returns, Working paper, University of Texas at Dallas.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تاثیر ارزشگذاری بیش از حد سهام بر مدیریت سود واقعی شرکتهای پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Effect of Over-valuation Stock Price on Real Earnings Management in Listed Companies of Tehran Stock Exchange</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>ارزش‌گذاری بیش از حد سهام به مفهوم بالاتر بودن قیمت بازار سهام نسبت به ارزش ذاتی آن است. ادبیات موجود نشان می‌دهد که مدیران شرکت­هایی که سهام آنها بیش از حد ارزش­گذاری شده برای حفظ این موقعیت، به مدیریت سود واقعی روی می‌آورند. لذا در این پژوهش، تأثیر ارزش‌گذاری بیش از حد سهام بر مدیریت سود واقعی بررسی شده است. برای انجام این پژوهش، نمونه‌ای متشکل از 80 شرکت در طی دوره زمانی 1391-1383 بررسی شد. معیارهای مدیریت سود واقعی شامل جریان‌های نقدی عملیاتی غیرعادی، هزینه تولید غیرعادی و هزینه‌های اختیاری غیرعادی است. علاوه‌ بر این، نسبت قیمت بازار به ارزش ذاتی سهام به عنوان معیار ارزش‌گذاری بیش از حد سهام در نظر گرفته شده است. برای بررسی تأثیر ارزش‌گذاری بیش از حد بر مدیریت سود واقعی از تحلیل رگرسیون چند متغیره به روش داده‌های ترکیبی استفاده شده است. نتایج بررسی­ها نشان داد که ارزش‌گذاری بیش از حد سهام بر جریان‌های نقد عملیاتی غیرعادی، هزینه اختیاری غیرعادی و هزینه تولید غیرعادی به عنوان معیارهای مدیریت سود واقعی تأثیر معنادار دارد. به عبارت دیگر از این نتایج می‌توان استنباط کرد که شرکت‌هایی با ارزش­گذاری بیش از حد، تمایل زیادی برای استمرار این موقعیت از طریق مدیریت سود واقعی دارند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The concept of overvaluation is the market price of share higher than its intrinsic value. Financial and accounting literature indicates that the managers of overvalued firms use the real earnings management to maintain this position. The aim of this study is to investigate the effect of over-valuation stock prices on real earnings managemen. Target sample consists of 80 companies during 1383-1391. Following Badertscher (2011), proxies of real earnings management are including of abnormal operating cash flows, abnormal production costs and abnormal discretionary expenses. Also, the ratio of the market price to intrinsic value is considered as a proxy of stock over-valuationØ Residual income model was used to measure the intrinsic valueØ Panel data method was applied to examine the effect of over-valuation on real earnings management. Results indicate that the over-valuation has significant effect on abnormal operating cash flows, abnormal discretionary expenses and abnormal production costs as the proxies of real earnings management. In other words, these results can be deduced that firms with higher value of shares are expected tendency to sustain high performance and earnings management.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>49</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>66</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عربصالحی</Family>
						<NameE>mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>arabsalehi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه اصفهان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه اصفهان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mehdi_arabsalehi@ase.ui.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نرگس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حمیدیان</Family>
						<NameE>narges</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>hamidian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه اصفهان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه اصفهان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>nargeshamidian@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>زیبا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قجاوند</Family>
						<NameE>ziba</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>ghojavand</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>موسسه آموزش عالی صنعتی فولاد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>موسسه آموزش عالی صنعتی فولاد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>zibaghojavand@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت سود واقعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جریان‌های نقد عملیاتی غیرعادی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هزینه اختیاری غیرعادی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هزینه تولید غیرعادی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ارزش‌گذاری بیش از حد سهام</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1]   بهارمقدم، مهدی؛ حسنی‌فرد، حبیبه. (1389). بررسی رابطه بین رویدادهای مالی واقعی ومدیریت سود درشرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادارتهران،تحقیقات حسابداری، 6. 24-1.##[2]   پاکیزه، کامران؛ بشیری‌جویباری، مهدی. (1392). تأثیر ارزشیابی نادرست بر تصمیم‌های سرمایه‌گذاری شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. فصلنامه مدیریت دارایی و تامین مالی، 3، 98-81.##[3]     ثقفی، علی. (1390). نقش گزارشگری مالی در همگرایی قیمت و ارزش ذاتی.فصلنامه بورس اوراق بهادار، 13، 4: 253-280.##[4]     شیرین‌بخش، شمس‌الله؛ حسن‌خوانساری، زهرا. (1384). کاربردEviewsدر اقتصاد سنجی. انتشارات پژوهشکده امور اقتصادی.##[5]   قربانی، سعید؛ جوان، علی اکبر، ناظمی، مهدی. (1390). تأثیر مدیریت واقعی سود بر جریان‌های نقدی عملیاتی آتی.پژوهش‌های تجربی حسابداری مالی،1: 150 – 134.##[6]     گجراتی، دامودار. (1386). مبانی اقتصاد سنجی. ترجمه حمید ابریشمی. انتشارات دانشگاه تهران، چاپ چهارم.##[7]   مرادزاده فرد، مهدی؛ عدیلی، مجتبی. (1389). بررسی رابطه بین دستکاری فعالیت‌های واقعی و هزینه حقوق صاحبان سهام در شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران.فصلنامه عملی ـ پژوهشی بورس اوراق بهادار، 7: 54-35.##[8]     مرادی، جواد؛ محمودی، لیدا. (1390). واگرایی قیمت و ارزش ذاتی سهام و بازدهی مورد انتظار. فصلنامه مدیریت، 21: 13-1.##[9]   Badertscher, B.A. (2011).Overvaluation and the Choice of Alternative Earnings Management Mechanisms. The Accounting Review,. 86,.5,.1491-1518.##[10]       Barton, J., and G. Waymire. (2004). Investor Protection under Unregulated Financial Reporting. Journal ofAccounting and Economics,.38,. 117–128.##[11]       Chi, J., and M. Gupta. (2009). Overvaluation and Earnings Management. Journal of Banking and Finance,.33(9),.1652–1663.##[12]       Cohen, D., A. Dey, and T. Lys. (2008). Real and Accrual Based Earnings Management in the Pre and Post Sarbanes Oxley Periods. The Accounting Review,. 83,. 757-787.##[13]       Dechow, P., S. Richardson, and I. Tuna. (2000). Are Benchmark Beaters Doing Anything Wrong? Working paper, University of Michigan.##[14]       Dechow, P.M., Skinner, D.J. (2000). Earnings Management: Reconciling the Views of Accounting Academics, Practitioners and Regulators. Accounting Horizons,. 14,. 235-250.##[15]       Fudenberg, D. and J. Tirole. (1995). A Theory of Income and Dividend Smoothing Based on Incumbency Rents. Journal of Political Economy,. 103,. 75-93.##[16]       Frankel, R. and Lee, C. M. (1998). Accounting Valuation, Market Expectation and Cross-Sectional Stock Return. Journal of Accounting and Economics,.25,.283-319.##[17]       Graham, J., C. Harvey, and S. Rajgopal. (2005). The economic implications of corporate financial reporting. Journal of Accounting and Economics,. 40,. 3,. 3-73.##[18]       Graham, J., Harvey, C., S, Rajgopal. (2006). Value Destruction and Financial Reporting Decisions. Journal of Financial Analysts,. 27-39.##[19]       Healy, P., and J. Wahlen. (1999). A Review of the Earnings Management Literature and its Implications for Standard Setting. Accounting Horizons,. 17,. 365-38.##[20]       Jensen, M. (2005).Agency Cost of Overvalued Equity. Financial Management,. 34,. 5-19.##[21]       Lee, C., Myers, J. and B, Swaminathan. (1999).What is the Intrinsic Value of Dow? Journal of Finance,.54,.1693-1741.##[22]       Roll, R. (1986).The Hubris Hypothesis of Corporate Takeovers. Journal of Business,. 59,. 197-216.##[23]       Roychowdhury, S. (2006). Earnings Management through Real Activities Manipulation. Journal of Accounting and Economics,. 42,. 335-370.##[24]       Song, S. Tan, J. and Yi, Y. (2014). IPO Initial Returns in China: Underpricing or Overvaluation? China Journal of Accounting Research,. 7,.1,. 31-49.##[25]       Schipper, k (1989). Commentary on Earning Management, Accounting. Accounting Horizons,.3, 91-102.##[26]       Tate, G., and U, Malmendier. (2005). CEO Overconfidence and Corporate Investment. Journal of Finance, 60, 2661-2700.##[27]       Wang, H., W,Du. (2012). Overvaluation, Financial Opacity and Crash Risk. Available at http://ssrn.com.##[28]       Yang, K. and Anand M. V. (2013). Are Small Firms Less Vulnerable to Overpriced Stock Offers? Journal of Financial Economics,. 110,.1,. 61-86.##[29]       Zhang, W.(2008).Real Activities Manipulation to Meet Analysts, Cash Flow Forecasts. University of Texas at Dallas.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی حافظه بلندمدت در نوسان‌های بازدهی شاخص بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Evaluation of Long Memory in the Volatility of Tehran Stock Exchange</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>با توجه به رشد و اهمیت روزافزون بازارهای مالی، وجود هرگونه نوسانی در این بازارها، آثار شگرفی بر اقتصاد می‌گذارد. لذا، در عرصه پویای بازارهای مالی از جمله بازار بورس اوراق بهادار پیش­بینی آینده به یکی از مهمترین مسایل در علوم مالی ارتقا یافته است. در این راستا این نوشتار با استفاده از داده­های روزانه شاخص قیمت و بازده نقدی بورس اوراق بهادار تهران طی دوره زمانی 5/1/1388 الی 30/7/1392 وجود حافظه بلندمدت در بازدهی و نیز نوسان‌های شاخص قیمت این بازار رابررسی نموده است. پس از تأیید وجود حافظه بلندمدت در سری بازدهی بورس، به کمک خانواده مدل­های واریانس ناهمسان شرطی (اعم از مدل­های غیر فرکتالی و فرکتالی) به برازش بهترین تصریح برای تبیین رفتار نوسان‌های بازدهی بورس پرداخته شد. نتایج این پژوهش، مؤید وجود حافظه بلندمدت در هر دو معادله میانگین و واریانس سری مذکور بوده است. حال آنکه، در بین مدل­های واریانس ناهمسان شرطی که در این مطالعه مورد بررسی قرار گرفته، بر اساس معیارهای اطلاعات (آکائیک و شوارتز) مدل ARFIMA(1,2)-FIGARCH(BBM) به عنوان بهترین مدل برای مدل­سازی نوسان‌های بازدهی بورس در دوره مورد بررسی، انتخاب شده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>According to the growing importance of financial markets, existence of any volatility in the market has dramatic effects on the economy. Therefore, in a dynamic financial markets including stock market, forecasting has improved to one of the most important issues in financial sciences. In this regard, this paper evaluated existence of long memory in returns and volatility of the market price index by using daily prices and returns Tehran Stock Exchange data from 2009/04/04 to 2013/10/22. The results of this study confirm the existence of long memory in both the mean and variance equations. After confirming the existence of long memory in this index, we used GARCH-type models (including non-fractal and fractal models) to track its volatility. Conclusively, comparing the information criteria (Akaike and Schwartz) of various conditional variance heteroskedasticity models, we found the performance of the ARFIMA (1,2)-FIGARCH (BBM) model is desirable.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>67</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>82</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>اکبر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کمیجانی</Family>
						<NameE>Akbar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Komijani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشکده اقتصاد دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشکده اقتصاد دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>komijani@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>اسماعیل</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نادری</Family>
						<NameE>Esmaeil</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Naderi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشکده اقتصاد دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشکده اقتصاد دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>naderi.ec@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نادیا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>گندلی علیخانی</Family>
						<NameE>Nadiya</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Gandali Alikhani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد واحد علوم و تحقیقات خوزستان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه آزاد واحد علوم و تحقیقات خوزستان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>n.alikhani@khouzestan.srbiau.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>حافظه بلندمدت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نوسانات</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بازار بورس</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدل ARFIMA</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدل GARCH</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدل FIGARCH</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1]   تهرانی، رضا؛ انصاری، حجت­اله؛ سارنگ، علیرضا. (1387). بررسی وجود پدیده بازگشت به میانگین در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران با استفاده از آزمون نسبت واریانس. بررسی­های حسابداری و حسابرسی، 15، 54.##[2]     سلیمی­فر، مصطفی؛ شیرزور، زهرا. (1389). بررسی کارایی اطلاعاتی بازار بورس به روش آزمون نسبت واریانس. مجله دانش و توسعه، 18، 31.##[3]   سعیدی، حسین؛ محمدی، شاپور. (1390). پیش‌بینی نوسان‌های بازده بازار با استفاده از مدل‌های ترکیبی گارچ- شبکه عصبی، فصلنامه بورس و اوراق بهادار، سال چهارم،16: 153-174.##[4]   عرفانی، علیرضا. (1387). پیش­بینی شاخص کل بورس اوراق بهادار تهران با مدل ARFIMA. پژوهشنامه علوم انسانی و اجتماعی- علوم اقتصادی، 8، 28.##[5]   کشاورزحداد، غلامرضا؛ صمدی، باقر. (1388). برآورد و پیش­بینی تلاطم بازدهی در بازار سهام تهران و مقایسه دقت روش­ها در تخمین ارزش در معرض خطر: کاربردی از مدل­های خانواده FIGARCH. مجله تحقیقات اقتصادی، 86، 235-193.##[6]   کمیجانی، اکبر؛ نادری، اسماعیل؛ گندلی‌علیخانی، نادیا. (1391). مقایسه انواع مدل­های واریانس ناهمسان شرطی در مدل­سازی و پیش­بینی نوسان‌های قیمت نفت. فصلنامه مطالعات اقتصاد انرژی، 9، 35، 121-146.##[7]   محمدی، تیمور؛ طالبلو، رضا. (1389). پویایی­های تورم و رابطه تورم و عدم اطمینان اسمی با استفاده از الگویARFIMA-GARCH. پژوهشنامه اقتصادی، 10،1، 170-137.##[8]    محمدی، تیمور؛ نصیری، سمیه. (1389). مقایسه مدل­های Riskmetric و GARCH در پیش­بینی نوسان‌های شاخص بازده کل بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. مجله مطالعات مالی، 6، 118-95.##[9]   مشیری، سعید؛ مروت، حبیب. (1384). بررسی وجود فرآیند آشوبی در شاخص بازدهی کل قیمت سهام بازار بورس تهران. فصلنامه پژوهش‌های اقتصادی ایران، 25، 47-64.##[10] موسایی، میثم؛ مهرگان، نادر؛ امیری، حسین. (1389). رابطه بازار سهام و متغیرهای کلان اقتصادی در ایران، فصلنامه پژوهش­ها و سیاست‌های اقتصادی، شماره 54، صص 94-73.##[11] نادری، اسماعیل. (1392). نقدی بر مقوله پیش بینی شاخص بورس: مطالعه موردی شاخص بورس تهران. ماهنامه بورس اوراق بهادار، 102: 31-28.##[12] تهرانی، رضا؛ انصاری، حجت­اله؛ سارنگ، علیرضا. (1387). بررسی وجود پدیده بازگشت به میانگین در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران با استفاده از آزمون نسبت واریانس. بررسی­های حسابداری و حسابرسی، 15، 54.##[13] سلیمی­فر، مصطفی؛ شیرزور، زهرا. (1389). بررسی کارایی اطلاعاتی بازار بورس به روش آزمون نسبت واریانس. مجله دانش و توسعه، 18، 31.##[14] سعیدی، حسین؛ محمدی، شاپور. (1390). پیش‌بینی نوسان‌های بازده بازار با استفاده از مدل‌های ترکیبی گارچ- شبکه عصبی، فصلنامه بورس و اوراق بهادار، 4،16، 153-174.##[15] عرفانی، علیرضا. (1387). پیش­بینی شاخص کل بورس اوراق بهادار تهران با مدل ARFIMA. پژوهشنامه علوم انسانی و اجتماعی- علوم اقتصادی، 8، 28.##[16] کشاورزحداد، غلامرضا؛ صمدی، باقر. (1388). برآورد و پیش­بینی تلاطم بازدهی در بازار سهام تهران و مقایسه دقت روش­ها در تخمین ارزش در معرض خطر: کاربردی از مدل­های خانواده FIGARCH. مجله تحقیقات اقتصادی، 86، 235-193.##[17] کمیجانی، اکبر؛ نادری، اسماعیل؛ گندلی علیخانی، نادیا. (1391). مقایسه انواع مدل­های واریانس ناهمسان شرطی در مدل­سازی و پیش­بینی نوسان‌های قیمت نفت. فصلنامه مطالعات اقتصاد انرژی، 9، 35: 121-146.##[18] محمدی، تیمور و طالبلو، رضا. (1389). پویایی‌های تورم و رابطه تورم و عدم اطمینان اسمی با استفاده از الگویARFIMA-GARCH. پژوهشنامه اقتصادی، 10، 1:170-137.##[19]  محمدی، تیمور؛ نصیری، سمیه. (1389). مقایسه مدل­های Riskmetric و GARCH در پیش‌بینی نوسان‌های شاخص بازده کل بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. مجله مطالعات مالی، 6،  118-95.##[20] مشیری، سعید؛ مروت، حبیب. (1384). بررسی وجود فرآیند آشوبی در شاخص بازدهی کل قیمت سهام بازار بورس تهران. فصلنامه پژوهش‌های اقتصادی ایران، 25، 47-64.##[21] موسایی، میثم؛ مهرگان، نادر؛ امیری، حسین. (1389). رابطه بازار سهام و متغیرهای کلان اقتصادی در ایران، فصلنامه پژوهش­ها و سیاست‌های اقتصادی، 54، 94-73.##[22] نادری، اسماعیل. (1392). نقدی بر مقوله پیش بینی شاخص بورس: مطالعه موردی شاخص بورس تهران. ماهنامه بورس اوراق بهادار،102، 31-28.##[23]  Alagidede, P., (2011). Return Behavior in Africa’s Emerging Equity Markets. The Quarterly Review of Economics and Finance,. 51,. 133–140.##[24]  Arouri, M., Lahiani, A., Nguyen, D.K., (2010). Forecasting the Conditional Volatility of Oil Spot and Futures Prices with Structural Breaks and Long Memory Models. International Conference on Economic Modeling, July, (Istanbul, Turkey).##[25]  Assaf, A., (2006). Dependence And Mean Reversion In Stock Prices: The Case Of The MENA Region. Research in International Business and Finance,. 20,. 3,. 286-304.##[26]  Bildirici, M., Ersin, O.O., (2013). Forecasting Oil Prices: Smooth Transition and Neural Network Augmented GARCH Family Models. Journal of Petroleum Science and Engineering,. 109,. 230-240.##[27]  Bollerslev, T., R. F. Engle and D. B. Nelson. (1994). ARCH Models in R. &quot;F. Engle and D. L. McFadden (eds.): Handbook of Econometrics&quot;,. 4, North Holland, Amsterdam.##[28]  Chkili, W., Hammoudeh, Sh., Nguyen, D., (2014). Volatility Forecasting and Risk Management for Commodity Markets in the Presence of Asymmetry and Long Memory. Energy Economics,. 41,. 1-18.##[29]  Chuang, W.I., Liu, H.H., Susmel, R., (2012). The Bivariate GARCH Approach To Investigating The Relation Between Stock Returns, Trading Volume, And Return Volatility. Global Finance Journal, In Press, Uncorrected Proof, Available online 13, Elsevier.##[30]  Conrad, C., Karanasos, M., Zeng, N., (2011). Multivariate Fractionally Integrated APARCH Modeling Of Stock Market Volatility: A Multi-Country Study. Journal of Empirical Finance,. 18,. 1,. 147-159.##[31]  Deo, R., Hsieh, M., Hurvich, C.M., (2010). Long Memory In Intertrade Durations, Counts And Realized Volatility Of NYSE Stocks. Journal of Statistical Planning and Inference,. 140,. 12,. 3715-3733.##[32]  Ding, Z., and C. W. J. Granger. (1996). Modeling Volatility Persistence of Speculative Returns: A New Approach. Journal of Econometrics,. 73, 185–215.##[33]  Dufrenot, G., Guégan, D., Peguin-Feissolle, A., (2005). Long-Memory Dynamics in A SETAR Model – Applications to Stock Markets. Journal of International Financial Markets, Institutions and Money,. 15,. 5,. 391-406.##[34]  Eizaguirre, J. C. &amp;Biscarri, J. G. &amp; Hidalgo, F. P. G. (2009). Financial Liberalization, Stock Market Volatility and Outliers in Emerging Economies, Applied Financial Economics,. 19,. 809–823.##[35]  Gewek, J. and Porter-Hudak, S. (1983). Theestimation and Application of Long Memorytime Series Models. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis,. 13, 101-116.##[36]  Harris, R.D.F., Nguyen, A., (2013). Long Memory Conditional Volatility and Asset Allocation. International Journal of Forecasting,. 29(2),. 258-273.##[37]  Huang, H., Fang, W., Miller, S.M., (2014). Does Financial Development Volatility Affect Industrial Growth Volatility? Original Research Article. International Review of Economics &amp; Finance,. 29,. 307-320.##[38]  Hull, M., McGroarty, F., (2013). Do Emerging Markets Become More Efficient as They Develop? Long Memory Persistence in Equity Indices. Emerging Markets Review, In Press, and Available online 15 November 2013.##[39]  Kang, S.H., Cheong, C., Yoon, S.M., (2010. Long Memory Volatility in Chinese Stock Markets. Physica A: Statistical Mechanics and its Applications,. 389, Issue. 7,. 1425-1433.##[40]  Kasman, A., Kasman, S., Torun, E., (2009). Dual Long Memory Property in Returns and Volatility: Evidence From The CEE Countries&#039; Stock Markets. Emerging Markets Review,. 10,. 2,. 122-139.##[41]  Kittiakarasakun, J., Tse, Y., (2011). Modeling the Fat Tails in Asian Stock Markets. InternationalReview of Economics and Finance,. 20,. 430–440.##[42]  Mishra, R.k., Sehgal, S., Bhanumurthy, N.R. (2011). A Search for Long-Range Dependence and Chaotic Structure In Indian Stock Market. Review of Financial Economics,. 20,. 2,. 96-104.##[43]  Mun, M., Brooks, R., (2012). The Roles of News and Volatility in Stock Market Correlations during the Global Financial Crisis. Emerging Markets Review,. 13, Issue. 1,. 1-7.##[44]  Ozdemir, Z.A., (2009). Linkages between International Stock Markets: A Multivariate Long-Memory Approach. Physica A: Statistical Mechanics and its Applications,. 388,. 12,. 2461-2468.##[45]  Panayides, Ph.M., Lambertides, N., Cullinane, K., (2013). Liquidity Risk Premium and Asset Pricing in US Water Transportation. Transportation Research Part E: Logistics and Transportation Review,. 52, 3-15.##[46]  Tan, P.P., Galagedera, D.U.A., Maharaj, E.A., (2012). A Wavelet Based Investigation of Long Memory in Stock Returns. Physica A: Statistical Mechanics and its Applications,. 391,. 7,. 2330-2341.##[47]  Xiu, J., Jin, Y., (2007). Empirical Study of ARFIMA Model Based On Fractional Differencing. Physica-A,.377,. 137-184.##[48]  Zhou, Jian &amp; Kang, Zhixin. (2011). A Comparison of Alternative Forecast Models of REIT Volatility. Journal of Real Estate Finance Economics,. 275-294.##[49]  Rong-Mao, Zh., Chor-yiu. (CY)S., Shiqing L. (2015). On Functional Limits of short- and Long-Memory Linear Processes with GARCH(1,1) Noises. Stochastic Processes and their Applications,. 125, 2,. 482-512.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>شبیه‏سازی الگوی تاثیر اهرم مالی بر ارزش شرکت با رویکرد پویایی‏شناسی سیستمی (مطالعه موردی: شرکت ملی صنایع مس ایران)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Simulating the effect of financial leverage model on company value via system dynamics approach (Case study: National Iranian copper industries company)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>تأمین وجوه مورد نیاز برای سرمایه‏گذاری شرکت‏ها معمولاً از طریق ابزارهای متنوع تأمین مالی صورت می‏گیرد که هر یک ویژگی‏های خاص خود را داراست. در ایران این ابزارها بیشتر به وام و سهام عادی محدود می‏شوند. این پژوهش با رویکردی ابتکاری و با استفاده از روش پویایی‏شناسی سیستمی و ارتباط داده‏های مالی و بازار سرمایه، به بررسی و شبیه‏سازی نقش اهرم مالی بر ارزش شرکت و قیمت سهام شرکت ملی صنایع مس ایران پرداخته است. الگوی سیستمی پژوهش با استفاده از این رویکرد و با نرم‏افزار Vensim DSS شبیه‏سازی و تحلیل شده است. نتایج حاکی از آن است که افزایش اهرم مالی نقش چندانی در ارزش شرکت نداشته، اما افزایش حقوق‏صاحبان‏سهام به نسبت بدهی‏ها، تأثیر بسزایی در کاهش نرخ بازده مورد انتظار سهامداران و افزایش ارزش شرکت ایفا می‏کند؛ به ‌طوری ‌که در پایان افق پژوهش نرخ هزینه سرمایه تا 7% کاهش یافته و در اواخر دوره قیمت سهام نیز تا نزدیک 8000 ریال را تجربه خواهد کرد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Financing of companies investments are usually done by some various financing tools that each of them have their own specifications. In Iran, most of these tools are limited to loans and common stocks. This study considers and simulates the role of financial leverage on intrinsic value and stock price of national Iranian copper industries company via heuristic approach and by using system dynamics method and the relations of financial and capital market data. Research systemic model has been simulated and analyzed by this approach and applying Vensim DSS software. The overall results shows, increase of financial leverage has little role on company value however increase of equity has an influential role on the decrease of stock expected return rate and increase of company value so that at the end of study horizon capital cost rate decrease till seven percent and at the late of the period the stock price will experience close to eight thousand rial.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>83</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>104</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد هاشم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>موسوی حقیقی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Hashem</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mousavi Haghighi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>مرکز تحقیقات کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی استان فارس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>مرکز تحقیقات کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی استان فارس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>musavee@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مجتبی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خلیفه</Family>
						<NameE>mojtaba</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>khalifeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه شیراز</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه شیراز</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m_khalifeh61@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پویایی‌های سیستم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ساختار سرمایه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اهرم مالی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ارزش ذاتی شرکت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بازار سرمایه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>آذر،عادل؛ کریمی، سیروس. (1388). پیش‏بینیبازدهسهامبااستفادهازنسبت‏هایحسابداریبا رویکردشبکه‏هایعصبی. تحقیقات مالی، 11(28)، 3-20.##]2[تقی‏زادهمهرجردی،روح‌اله؛فاضلیزدی،علی؛محبی، رضا. (1392). مدل‏سازیوپیش‏بینیکاراییبانک‏هایدولتیوخصوصیایرانبااستفادهازمدل‏های شبکهعصبیمصنوعی،شبکهعصبیفازیوالگوریتمژنتیک. مدیریتداراییوتامینمالی، 1(2)، 103-126.##]3[ جهانخانی،علی. (1376). بررسیعواملمؤثربرقیمتسهامومروریبرروندتغییرقیمتسهامدربورساوراقبهادارتهران.زمینه، 65،13-16.##]4[خسروی‏نیا، علیرضا. (1388). بررسی رابطه بین ساختار سرمایه با ارزش شرکت. (پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد). دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد نیشابور.##]5[خلیفهسلطانی،احمد؛اخلاقی،حسنعلی؛ساعدی، رحمان. (1393). بررسیعواملمؤثربرساختارسرمایهبااستفادهازمدلتوبیت: آزمونتجربینظریه‏هایسلسهمراتبی توازیایستاونمایندگی. مدیریتداراییوتامینمالی، 2(4)، 37-54.##]6[ رودپشتی، فریدون؛ سلیمانی‏فر، روح‌اله. (1389). بررسیرابطهبینوجوهنقدناشیاز فعالیت‌هایتأمینمالیوبازدهسهام در شرکت‌هایپذیرفتهشدهدربورستهران. فصلنامه بورس اوراق بهادار، 2 (8)، 65-89.##]7[سینایی،حسنعلی؛مرتضوی،سعیداله؛ تیموری‏اصل،یاسر. (1384). پیش‏بینیشاخصبورساوراق بهادارتهرانبااستفادهاز شبکه‌هایعصبیمصنوعی. بررسی‏هایحسابداریوحسابرسی، 12(41)، 53-89.##]8[شیخخوزانی،زهره؛حسینی،خسرو؛رحیمیان،مهدی. (1389). مدل‌سازیبهره‏برداریازمخازن چندمنظوره بهروشپویاییسیستم.&quot;مدل‏سازیدرمهندسی، 8(21)، 57-66.##]9[صفرنواده،محمد. (1380). پیش‏بینیقیمتسهامدربازاربورساوراقبهادار تهران.(پایان نامهکارشناسیارشد).دانشگاهامامصادق، تهران.##]10[صالح‏نژاد، حسن؛ غیور، وحیدرضا. (1389). تأثیرنرخبازدهدارایی‏ها ونرخبازدهحقوقصاحبانسهام و اهرممالی بر قیمت سهام شرکت‌هایپذیرفتهشدهدر بورساوراقبهادارتهران. مدیریت، 7(18)، 17-27.##]11[ طالب‏نیا، قدرت‌اله؛  سپهری، پطرو. (1385). بررسیمقایس‏هایارتباطبیننسبتبدهیبا بازده دارایی‌هادرصنایعمختلف. تحقیقات مالی، 8 (22)، 21-32.##]12[عباسی،ابراهیم؛ باقری، سحر. (1390). پیش‏بینیبازدهسهامبااستفادهازمدل‏هایغیرخطیآستانه‏ایو بررسینقشحجممعاملاتدربهبودعملکرداینمدل‏ها. تحقیقات مالی، 13(32)، 91-108.##]13[فتحی،سعید،ابزری،مهدی؛ حبیبی، سولماز. (1393). فراتحلیلعواملتعیین‏کنندهساختارسرمایهدرسطحشرکت. مدیریتداراییوتامینمالی، 2(4)، 55-74.##]14[ قالیبافاصل،حسن. (1380). مدیریتمالی. تهران:انتشاراتپورانپژوهش.##]15[ موسویحقیقی،محمدهاشم؛ستوده،فیروزه. (1392). شبیه‏سازیالگویپویایرفتاریسهامدربورساوراقبهادارتهران. مطالعاتمدیریتراهبردی، 4(14)، 35-52.##]16[‌هاشمی، سیدعباس؛ اخلاقی، حسنعلی. (1389). تأثیر اهرم مالی، سیاست تقسیم سود و سودآوری بر ارزش آتی شرکت. حسابداری مالی، 2(6)، 38-49.##[17] Banz, R., &amp; Breen, W. (1986). Sample-Dependent Results Using Accounting and Market Data: Some evidence. Journal of Finance, 41, 779-793.##[18]Berger, A. N., &amp; Bonaccorsi di Patti, E. (2006). Capital Structure and Firm Performance: A New Approach to Testing Agency Theory and an Application to the Banking Industry. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, 30, 1065–1102.##[19] Ben Zion, U., &amp; Shalit, S. (1975). Size Leverage and Dividend Record as Determinants of Equiy Risk. Journal of Finance, 13, 1015-26.##[20] Bhagat, S., &amp; Bolton, B. (2008). Corporate Governance and Firm Performance.Journal of Corporate Finance, 14, 257–273.##[21] By,j., &amp; Labak, h. (1996). Feedback and Behavioral System.Journal of System Review, 15,56-68.##[22] Davenport, M. (1971). Leverage and the Cost of Capital: Some Tests Using British Data. Economica, 138(3), 136-162.##[23] DeAngelo, H., &amp; Stulz, R. M. (2013). Why High Leverage is Optimal for Banks. NBER Working Paper No. 19139, June.##[24] Fama, E., &amp; French, K. (1988). Permanent and Temporary Components of Stock Prices.Journal of Political Economy, 96, 246-273.##[25] Feld, L. P., Heckemeyer, J. H., &amp; Overeschc, M. (2011). Capital Structure Choice and Company Taxation: a Metastudy, ZEW Discussion Paper, 11-075, 1-60.##[26] Forrester, J. W. (1997). Building a System Dynamic Model.Prepared for the MIT System Dynamic in Education Project, Massachusetts Institute of Technology.##[27] Fosu, S. (2013). Capital Structure, Product Market Competition and Firm Performance: Evidence from South Africa. The Quarterly Review of Economics and Finance, 53, 140–151.##[28] Ghosh, S. (2008). Leverage, Foreign Borrowing and Corporate Performance: Firm level Evidence for India. Applied Economics Letters, 15, 607–616.##[29] Ghosh. S., &amp; Ghosh, A. (2009).Do Leverage, Dividend Policy and Profitability Influence the Future Value of Firm.www. ssrn. com.##[30] Huang, G., &amp; Song, F. M. (2006). The Determinants of Capital Structure: Evidence from China. China Economic, 17, 14-36.##[31] Jaffe, j., Keim, D., &amp; Westerfield, R. (1989). Earnings Yields, Market Values and Stock Returns. Journal of Finance, 44, 135-148.##[32] King, M. R., &amp; Santor, E. (2008). Family Values: Ownership Structure, Performance and Capital Structure of Canadian Firms. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, 32, 2423–2432.##[33] Lee, W. (1987). The Effect of Exhcange Offers and Stock Swaps on Equity Risk and Shareholders&#039; Wealth: A Mignalling Model Approach. PhD Thesis, UCLA.##[34] Levati, M. V., Mahagaonkar, P., &amp; Qiu, J. (2012). Testing the Modigliani-Miller Theorem Directly in the Lab: A General Equilibrium Approach.Experimental Economics, 15, 693-716.##[35] Mahagaonkar, P., &amp; Qiu, J. (2009). Testing the Modigliani-Miller Theorem Directly in the Lab: A General Equilibrium Approach, Schumpeter Discussion Papers 2009-006, Available at:http://elpub.bib.uni-wuppertal.de/servlets/DerivateServlet/Derivate-1524/sdpA9006.pdf.##[36] Margaritis, D., &amp; Psillaki, M. (2010). Capital Structure, Equity Ownership and Firm Performance. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, 34, 621–632.##[37] Masulis, M. S. (1980). The Effect of Capital Structure Changes on Security Prices: A Study of Exchange Offers. Journal of Financial Economics, 8, 139-178.##[38] Modigliani, F., &amp; Miller, M. (1958). The Cost of Capital, Corporation Finance and Theory of Investment.American Economic Review, 48(3), 261–297.##[39] Modigliani, F., &amp; Miller, M. (1963). Corporate Income Taxes and the Cost of Capital: A correction. American Economic Review, 53(3), 433–443.##[40] Mondher, K. (2011). A re-Examination of the MM Capital Structure Irrelevance Theorem: A Partial Payout Approach. International Journal of Business and Management, 6(10), 193-204.##[41] Mc Millan, D. G. (2007). Nonlinear Forecasting of Stock Returns: Does Volume Help. International Journal of forecasting, 23, 115-126.##[42] Phillips, P. A., &amp; Sipahioglu, M. A. (2004). Performance Implications of Capital Structure: Evidence from Quoted U.K. Organisations with Hotel Interests. The Service Industries Journal, 24, 31–51.##[43] Pinegar, J. M., &amp; Lease, R. C. (1986). The Impact of Preferred-for-Common Exchange Offers on Firm Value.Journal of Finance, 41(4), 795-814.##[44] Sterman. J. (2000). Business Dynamics, Systems Thinking and Modeling for a Complex World. McGraw-Hill publication.##[45] Travaglini, G. (2002). L’irrilevanza Della Struttura Finanziaria: Il Teorema Modigliani- Miller, Available at www.econ.uniurb.it/materiale/5223_mm2.pdf.##[46]Tudor, E., Andrei, A. M., Badescu, A., &amp; Georgescu, I. (2014). Modigliani-Miller Theorem and Its Implications on Romanian Agricultural Policies.Procedia Economics and Finance, 13, 101–108.##[47] Weill, L. (2008). Leverage and corporate performance: Does institutional environment matter? Small Business Economics, 30, 251–265.##[48] www.irbourse.com.##[49] www.tsetmc.com.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی توان اقلام تعهدی و جریان‌های نقدی براساس ارقام اصلی در مقابل ارقام تجدید ارایه شده برای پیش‌بینی جریان‌های نقدی آتی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Comparative of Accruals Ability and Cash Flows Based on Original Figures Versus Revised Figures For Predicting Future Cash Flows</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>پیش‌بینی جریان‌های نقدی برای استفاده­کنندگان درون و برون­سازمانی دارای اهمیت ویژه­ای است. مهمترین هدف گزارش‌گری مالی ارایه اطلاعات برای پیش­بینی جریان­های نقدی بیان شده است. هدف این پژوهش مقایسه توان اقلام تعهدی و جریان­های نقدی براساس ارقام اصلی درمقابل ارقام تجدید ارایه شده برای پیش­بینی جریان­های نقدی آتی است. جامعه آماری پژوهش شامل آن دسته از شرکت­های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران است که صورت‌های مالی آنها تجدید ارایه شده است. بدین منظور از داده­های 162 سال- شرکت که از این ویژگی برخوردار بودند، طی دوره زمانی 1386 تا 1390، استفاده شده است. این پژوهش از لحاظ هدف، کاربردی و از نوع پژوهش­های توصیفی- همبستگی است. تجزیه و تحلیل داده­ها با استفاده از نرم­افزار Eviews انجام شده است. روش مورد استفاده در این پژوهش رگرسیون خطی و برای مقایسه مدل­های پژوهش از آزمون وونگ استفاده شده است. نتایج پژوهش نشان می­دهد که اقلام تعهدی تجدید ارایه شده و جریان­های نقدی تجدید ارایه شده به ترتیب نسبت به اقلام تعهدی اصلی و جریان­های نقدی اصلی دارای توانایی بیشتری برای پیش­بینی جریان­های نقدی آتی هستند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Â  Abstract  Â  Forecast of cash flows is important for users in the inside and outside the organization. The most important objective of financial reporting is to provide information to forecast cash flows is presented. The purpose of this study is The Comparative of Accruals Ability and Cash Flows Based on Original Figures Versus Revised Figures For Predicting Future Cash Flows. The statistical society of the research comprises those firms listed in The Tehran Stock Exchange and whose financial lists have been restated. To fulfil the research, data from 162 year-firm from the year 1386 to the year 1390 have been collected, The present research in terms of purpose is practical and is a descriptive-correlation research. The data are analyzed using the Eviews software. The method used in the resarch is the linear regression, and the Vuong test is used to compare the research models. The research results display that the restated accruals and the restated cash flows are, respectively, more ability of predicting the future cash flows, compared to the main accruals and the main cash flows.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>105</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>116</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>هاشم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ولی پور</Family>
						<NameE>Hashem</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>valipour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد فیروزآباد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد فیروزآباد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>h.valipour@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>احسان</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>زحمت کش</Family>
						<NameE>Ehsan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Zahmatkesh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد مرودشت</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد مرودشت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>e.zahmatkesh64@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>غلامرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بحرانی فرد</Family>
						<NameE>Gholamreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Bahranifard</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد مرودشت</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد مرودشت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>rezabahrani62@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اقلام تعهدی اصلی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اقلام تعهدی تجدید ارایه شده</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جریان های نقدی اصلی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جریان های نقدی تجدید ارایه شده</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جریان های نقدی آتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1]  ایزدی‌نیا، ناصر؛قوچی‌فرد، حمزه. (1391). بررسی رابطه بین جریان‌های نقد عملیاتی، سود خالص و اجزای اقلام تعهدی با جریان‌های نقد آزاد آتی شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. فصلنامه پژوهش­های حسابداری مالی، سال چهارم، 4: 19-36.##[2]  ثقفی، علی؛فدایی، حمیدرضا. (1386). گزینشمدلیکارآمدبرایپیشبینی جریان‌هاینقدیبراساسمقایسهمدل‌هایمربوطدرشرکت‌هایپذیرفتهشدهدر بورساوراقبهادارتهران. فصلنامهبررسی‌هایحسابداریوحسابرسی،دوره14،50: 3-25.##[3]  خدادادی،ولی؛دستگیر،محسن؛جلیلی،امیر. (1388). بررسی توانایی پیش­بینی جریان­های نقدی با استفاده از جریان­های نقدی و مولفه‌های تعهدی سودهای گذشته. تحقیقات حسابداری، 26:4-54.##[4]  غلامعلی‌پور، رضا. (1383). بررس توانایی اقلام تعهدی غیر­اختیاری در پیش­بینی سود و جریان­های نقدی آتی. پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی.##[5]  میرفخرالدینی، حیدر؛معین‌الدین، محمود؛ ابراهیم‌پور، علیرضا. (1388). مقایسه توانایی جریان‌های نقدی واقلام تعهدی در پیش‌بینی جریان‌های نقدی آتی. بررسی‌های حسابداری و حسابرسی، 55: 99-116.##[6]  ودیعی، مهدی؛ فخریان، محمدحسین. (1389). بررسیمحتوایفزایندهاقلامتعهدینسبتبهاقلامنقدیدر پیش­بینیجریان‌هاینقدیآینده. مجلهتوسعهوسرمایه، 6: 29-56.##[7]     Akbar, S. &amp;Zulfiqar, AS. &amp; Stark, AW. (2011). The Value Relevance of Cash Flows, Current Accruals, and Non-Current Accruals in the UK. International Review of Financial Analysis, 20: 311-319.##[8]     Badertscher, BA. &amp; Collins, DW. &amp; Lys, TZ. (2012). Discretionary Accounting Choices and the Predictive Ability of Accruals with respect to Future Cash Flows. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 53: 330-352.##[9]     Defond, M and Hung, M. (2001). The Role of Accruals in Predicting Future Cash Flows and Stock Returns, Online, www.ssrn.com.##[10] Farshadfar, Sh.(2008). The Relative Ability of Earnings and Cash Flow Data in Forecasting Future Cash Flow. Pacific Accounting Review, 20: 254-268.##[11] Ibrahim, El. Ebaid, S.(2011). Accruals and the Prediction of Future Cash Flows. Management Research Review, 34: 838-853.##[12] Ryan, GS. Tucker, WJ. Zarowin, PA. (2006). Ciassification and Market Pricing of the Cash Flow and Accruals on Trading Positions. The Accounting Review, 81: 443-472.##[13] Shubita, M,F. (2013). Accruals and Cash Flows- A Case of Jordan. Interdisciplinary Journal of Contemporary Research in Business, 5: 428-441.##[14]Wasley, E, C, and Wu, J, SH. (2005). Why Do Managers Voluntarily Issue Cash Flow Forecasts?,Online, www.ssrn.com.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				