<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Relation between Working Capital Management and Investment Inefficiency</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارتباط بین مدیریت سرمایه در گردش و ناکارایی سرمایه گذاری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>17</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>38</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">20645</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2016.20645</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>یونس</FirstName>
					<LastName>بادآورنهندی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تبریز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>وحید</FirstName>
					<LastName>تقی زاده خانقاه</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تبریز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Working capital management refers to the management of current assets, and current liabilities to create a balance between current assets and current liabilities. By effective management of working capital, shareholders can earn the maximum return for investment in assets. Hence, the present study investigates the relation between working capital management and investment inefficiency at listed forms in the Tehran Stock Exchange for the period of 2005-2012. The results show that receivables collection period, debt payment period and cash conversion cycle efficiency are negatively related to the investment inefficiency, while there is no relation between inventory turnover period and inefficient investment. Also evidences indicate that cash conversion cycle, cash holdings and the current ratio are positively related to the investment inefficiency. Overall, in can be stated that the efficient management of working capital reduces the deviation from optimal investment.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مدیریت سرمایه در گردش به مدیریت دارایی‌ها و بدهی‌های جاری اشاره دارد و برای ایجاد تعادل بین آنها به‌کار می‌رود، بطوری که از طریق مدیریت موثر سرمایه در گردش، سهامداران می‌توانند حداکثر بازده را برای سرمایه‌گذاری در دارایی‌ها کسب کنند. بنابراین انتظار می‌رود مدیریت کارای سرمایه در گردش مشکلات مربوط به سرمایه‌گذاری را تا حدی کاهش دهد. از این رو، هدف پژوهش حاضر بررسی ارتباط بین مدیریت سرمایه در گردش و ناکارایی سرمایه‌گذاری شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران برای دوره مالی 1385-1391 است. نتایج پژوهش نشان می‌دهد که بین دوره وصول مطالبات، دوره پرداخت بدهی و کارایی چرخه تبدیل وجه نقد با ناکارایی سرمایه‌گذاری ارتباط منفی و معنی‌داری وجود دارد، در حالی که ارتباطی بین دوره گردش موجودی کالا با ناکارایی سرمایه‌گذاری مشاهده نشد. همچنین شواهد نشان داد که بین چرخه تبدیل وجه نقد، نگهداشت وجه نقد و نسبت جاری با ناکارایی سرمایه گذاری ارتباط مثبت و معنی‌داری وجود دارد. در کل می‌توان بیان کرد که مدیریت کارای سرمایه در گردش موجب کاهش انحراف از سطح مطلوب سرمایه‌گذاری می‌شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت سرمایه در گردش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">وجه نقد مازاد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ناکارایی سرمایه گذاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشکلات نمایندگی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_20645_26433f036d30e7ac50fb6813c186f0af.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
