<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Managerial Overconfidence on Debt Maturity Structure in Listed Companies in Tehran Stock Exchange</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر بیش ‌اطمینانی مدیریت در ساختار سررسید بدهی در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>89</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>106</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">21350</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21350</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مسعود</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسنی القار</LastName>
<Affiliation>مربی گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم انسانی، دانشگاه بزرگمهر قائنات، قائن، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نظام الدین</FirstName>
					<LastName>رحیمیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه حسابرسی، دانشکده علوم انسانی، دانشگاه خاتم، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>08</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Financing policies made by managers can play a key role in the risk and wealth creation for stochkholders. However, identifying effective factors in managers` financing decisions is of great importance. Overconfidence is one of the most important personality traits of managers. Overconfidence is effective in risk taking. Overconfident managers overestimate future returns of business projects due to false confidence. Therefore, they might overestimate the likelihood and impact of positive shocks of future cash flows for these projects. Meanwhile, they may underestimate the negative shocks. They believe that their business entities have been undervalued in the capital market and can choose shorter maturity debt and increase shareholder wealth. They prefer to issue bonds rather than stocks. This study aims to examine the effect of a psychological factor (managerial overconfidence) on debt maturity structure. The sample consisted of selected companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange from 2007 to 2014. Two scales which are based on managers` bias to forecast earnings and investment decisions are employed to measure the managerial overconfidence. The results show that managerial overconfidence has a positive and significant effect on debt maturity structure. Overconfident managers take shorter debt maturity structure by applying higher percentage of short-term debt. Liquidity risk related to this financing policy would not prevent them from such behavior.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">سیاست‌های تأمین مالی که مدیران اتخاذ می‌کنند، نقش مهمی در ریسک و ایجاد ثروت برای سهامداران دارد؛ بنابراین شناخت عوامل مؤثر در تصمیم‌های تأمین مالی مدیران، اهمیت بسیاری دارد. بیش­اطمینانی از مهم‌ترین ویژگی­های شخصیتی مدیران است که در ریسک­پذیری تأثیر دارد. مدیران بیش­اطمینان به‌دلیل اعتماد به نفس کاذب، بازده­های آتی پروژه­های واحد تجاری را بیشتر برآورد می­کنند؛ از این‌رو، ممکن است احتمال وقوع و تأثیر شوک­های مثبت جریان­های نقدی آتی حاصل از این پروژه­ها را بیشتر برآورد کنند و درمقابل، برآورد کمتری از شوک­های منفی داشته باشند. آنان معتقدند واحدهای تجاری تحت مدیریتشان در بازار سرمایه، کمتر از واقع ارزش­گذاری شده‌اند و با انتخاب بدهی با سررسید کوتا‌­تر، ثروت سهامداران را افزایش می‌دهند. هدف پژوهش حاضر، بررسی تأثیر یک عامل روان‌شناسی (بیش­اطمینانی مدیریت) در ساختار سررسید بدهی است. جامعة آماری پژوهش را شرکت­های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در سال­های 1386 تا 1393 تشکیل می­دهد. در این پژوهش برای اندازه­گیری بیش­اطمینانی مدیریت از دو سنجه مبتنی بر سوگیری مدیران در پیش­بینی سود و تصمیم‌های سرمایه­گذاری مدیران استفاده شده است. نتایج پژوهش نشان می­دهد بیش­اطمینانی مدیریت، تأثیر مثبت معناداری در ساختار سررسید بدهی دارد و شرکت‌های با مدیران بیش­اطمینان، با انتخاب درصد بیشتری از بدهی کوتاه­مدت، ساختار سررسید بدهی کوتاه­تری اتخاذ می­کنند و ریسک نقدشوندگی مربوط به این سیاست تأمین مالی، آنان را از این رفتار باز نمی­دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بیش‌اطمینانی مدیریت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ریسک نقدشوندگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساختار سررسید بدهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قیمت‌گذاری نادرست</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21350_f0ecf63962068eb840d3fe896c0a01e7.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
