<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Impact of Debt Maturity on Stock Price Crash Risk with an Emphasis on Information Asymmetry</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر سررسید بدهی در خطر سقوط قیمت سهام با تأکید بر عدم تقارن اطلاعاتی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>87</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>104</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">21211</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21211</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>وحید</FirstName>
					<LastName>تقی زاده خانقاه</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری حسابداری دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تبریز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>قدرت اله</FirstName>
					<LastName>طالب نیا</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار حسابداری، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران، تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>26</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Short-term debt subjects managers to frequent monitoring, thus effectively reducing managerial discretion and enhancing information disclosure. Since lenders are more sensitive to decreases than increases in firm stock price, they have strong incentives to scrutinize borrowers and gather information about their financial conditions and future prospects. This research aims to study the economic concequences of debt maturity, to the impact of debt maturity choice on stock price crash risk of listed companies in Tehran Stock Exchange. In this regard, 120 companies were evaluated for the period 2008-2013. To test the hypothesis of the study panel data is used by software Eviews 7. We find that firms with a larger proportion of short-term debt tend to have lower future stock price crash risk, consistent with short-term debt playing an effective monitoring role over managers and constraining their bad news hoarding behavior. Our results also show that the inverse relation between short-term debt and future crash risk is more pronounced among firms with higher degree of information asymmetry. Overall, our paper shows that short-term debt not only preserves creditors’ interests, but also protects the value of shareholders.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">بدهی‌های کوتاه‌مدت، ساز و کاری است که مدیران را در معرض نظارت‌های مکرر قرار می‌دهد و موجب کاهش اختیارات مدیریت می‌شود؛ بنابراین کیفیت افشای اطلاعات را بهبود می‌بخشد. از آنجا که وام‌دهندگان حساسیت بیشتری به کاهش قیمت سهام شرکت به نسبت افزایش آن دارند، انگیزه‌های زیادی برای نظارت بر وام‌گیرندگان و جمع‌آوری اطلاعات دربارۀ وضعیت مالی آنها خواهند داشت. پژوهش حاضر با مطالعۀ جنبه‎ای از پیامدهای سررسید بدهی، تأثیر سررسید بدهی را در خطر سقوط قیمت سهام در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران بررسی می‌کند. در این راستا، تعداد 120 شرکت برای دورۀ زمانی 1388-1393 بررسی شد. برای آزمون فرضیه‌های پژوهش از داده‌های تابلویی با نرم‌افزار آماری Eviews استفاده شده است. شواهد نشان داد شرکت‌هایی که بدهی‌های کوتاه‌مدت زیادی دارند، خطر سقوط سهام کمی خواهند داشت. این شواهد با این ادعا سازگار است که بدهی‌های کوتاه‌مدت، نقش نظارتی مؤثری در مدیریت دارد و ذخیرۀ اخبار بد توسط مدیران را محدود می‌کند. نتایج نشان داد تأثیر منفی بدهی‌های کوتاه‌مدت در خطر سقوط قیمت سهام برای شرکت‌های با عدم تقارن اطلاعاتی زیاد، بیشتر است. به‌طور کلی، یافته‌ها نشان داد بدهی‌های کوتاه‌مدت نه‌تنها از منافع سهامداران محافظت می‌کند، ارزش سهامداران را نیز حفظ می‌کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ذخیرۀ اخبار بد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سررسید بدهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سقوط قیمت سهام</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عدم تقارن اطلاعاتی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21211_cf0dbfff84cfa6197ec33b59b62b9543.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
