<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Estimating the return on investment opportunities in financial markets due to their interaction relation and establishing optimized portfolio by Artificial Intelligence</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>پیش بینی بازده فرصت های سرمایه گذاری در بازارهای مالی ایران با توجه به رفتار متقابل بازارها و تشکیل سبد بهینه سرمایه گذاری به وسیله هوش مصنوعی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>35</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>50</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19897</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>سالمی نجف آبادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد مبارکه</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نصرالله</FirstName>
					<LastName>سعادت فر</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرزاد</FirstName>
					<LastName>کریمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد  مبارکه</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This project is looking for increasing return on investment, by presenting models based on artificial intelligence. Investment in financial markets could be considered in short-term (daily) and middle-term (monthly) basis. hence the daily data in Tehran Stock Exchange and the rates of foreign exchange and gold coins have been extracted for the period Mar. 2010 to Sep. 2012 and recorded as the data into the neural networks and the genetic programming model. Also the monthly rate of return and risk of 20 active companies of the stock exchange, and the monthly risk values of foreign exchange and gold coin, as well as bank deposits were used as genetic algorithms in order to provide optimum investment portfolios for the investors. The results obtained from executing the models indicates the efficiency of both methods of artificial neural network and also genetic programming in the short-term financial markets predictions, but artificial neural networks show a better efficiency. Also the efficiency of genetic algorithm was approved in improving the rate of return and risks, via identifying the optimum investment portfolios.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف این پژوهش افزایش بازده سرمایه‌گذاری با ارائه مدل‌هایی مبتنی بر هوش مصنوعی است. سرمایه گذاری در بازارهای مالی را می توان در بعدهای کوتاه مدت (روزانه) و میان مدت (ماهانه) بررسی کرد. در بعد کوتاه مدت داده‌های روزانه بازارهای بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، ارز و سکه بهار آزادی از ابتدای سال 1389 تا پایان شهریور ماه 1391 استخراج شده و به عنوان ورودی به شبکه‌های عصبی (ANN) و مدل برنامه‌نویسی ژنی (GP) وارد شدند تا با استفاده از آنها قیمت روز آتی این بازارها پیش بینی شود. همچنین در بعد میان مدت بازده و ریسک ماهانه 20 شرکت فعالتر بورس و ریسک ماهانه بازار ارز و سکه بهار آزادی و سپرده بانکی به وسیله الگوریتم ژنی مورد استفاده قرار گرفت تا سبدهای سرمایه‌گذاری بهینه به سرمایه‌گذاران ارائه کند. نتایج حاصل از اجرای مدل ها بیانگر کارایی هر دو روش شبکه های عصبی مصنوعی و برنامه نویسی ژنی در پیش بینی کوتاه مدت بازارهای مالی است، در حالیکه شبکه های عصبی مصنوعی کارایی بهتری از خود بروز می‌دهند. همچنین کارایی الگوریتم ژنی در بهبود بازده و ریسک سرمایه گذاری از طریق شناسایی سبدهای بهینه سرمایه گذاری نیز به اثبات رسید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازارهای مالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ریسک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شبکه عصبی مصنوعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">برنامه نویسی ژنی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوریتم ژنی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_19897_bcf69f14d6efeaa38027c87787b3c25f.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
