<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1399</YEAR>
<VOL>8</VOL>
<NO>1</NO>
<MOSALSAL>28</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>0</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تحلیل نقش معاملات بلوکی در ایجاد بازده غیرعادی و تأثیر بر نوسانات غیرسیستماتیک در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Analyzing the Role of Block Trade in Generating Abnormal Returns and Impact in Idiosyncratic Volatility in Tehran Stock Exchange</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: معاملات بلوکی سهام بخش مهمی از معاملات بورس اوراق بهادار تهران را تشکیل می‌‌دهد؛ این معاملات شامل معاملۀ حجم‌ زیادی از سهام در قیمت‌های توافقی است که به‌طور معمول با قیمت‌های جاری و نوسانی بازار تفاوت دارد. کمیت بالای معاملات بلوکی سبب شده است پژوهش‌‌های مهمی در این حوزه انجام شود. هدف اصلی این پژوهش، مطالعه دربارۀ محتوای اطلاعاتی معاملات بلوکی سهام است. روش: برای این منظور 208 معاملۀ بلوکی در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران برای دورۀ زمانی 1395-1387 با استفاده از روش مطالعۀ رویدادی تجزیه‌و‌تحلیل شده است. نتایج: نتایج پژوهش نشان می‌‌دهد تراکنش‌های معاملات بلوکی سهام، نشانه‌‌ای مهم برای سرمایه‌گذارانی‌ است که در بورس اوراق بهادار فعالیت می‌کنند. شواهد نشان‌دهندۀ آن است که بعد از انجام معاملات بلوکی صرف و کنترلی، بازده‌های غیرعادی انباشتۀ مثبت معنادار مشاهده می‌‌شود. در کل این بازده‌‌‌‌های غیرعادی انباشته حاکی است سهامداران نسبت به انجام معاملات بلوکی واکنش غیرعادی نشان می‌دهند. نتایج نشان داد بعد از انجام معاملات بلوکی نوسانات غیرسیستماتیک کاهش یافته است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: Block trade is a significant part of stock exchange transactions. They involve trading a large volume of stocks at agreed prices that usually differ from the volatile and spot market prices. The large volume of block Trade has pushed academics to conduct a wide range of researches in this area. The main goal of this paper is to study the information content of block Trade. Method: For the above purpose, gathered data from 208 block trades in the Tehran Stock Exchange during the years of 2008-2016 were analyzed by the event study method. The results indicate that those block Trades are influential indicators for investors engaged in the stock exchange. Results: Evidence shows that after premium and controlled block trades, there exist significant cumulative abnormal returns. Overall, such cumulative abnormal returns imply the abnormal shareholder response to the block Trades. The results also demonstrate there are significant reductions in idiosyncratic volatility following block Trades.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>22</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مهربان پور</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammadreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mehrabanpour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه حسابداری و مالی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه حسابداری و مالی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mehrabanpour@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>تهرانی</Family>
						<NameE>Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Tehrani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه مدیریت مالی و بیمه، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه مدیریت مالی و بیمه، دانشکده مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>rtehrani@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حمید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>جمشیدی</Family>
						<NameE>Hamid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Jamshidi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه حسابداری و مالی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه حسابداری و مالی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hamid92jamshidi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>معاملات بلوکی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سهامدار بلوکی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بازده غیرعادی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نوسانات غیرسیستماتیک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] احمدپور، الف.، و نصیری، م. (1394). بررسی عدم‌تقارن تأثیر قیمت معاملات بلوکی بین خرید و فروش. دانش سرمایه‎گذاری، 4 (16)، 74-59.##[2] احمدپور، الف.، و نصیری، م. (1395). بررسی تأثیر قیمت معاملات بلوک در بازار سهام ایران. تحقیقات مالی، 18 (1)، 23-38.##[3] احمدپور، الف.، آقاجانی، ح.، و فدوی، م. (1392). بررسی رابطۀ بین حجم معاملات و تغییر قیمت سهام در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. راهبرد مدیریت مالی، 1 (1)، 95-75.##[4] بدری، الف.، و کوچکی، الف. (1392). حجم معاملات و بازده سهام: شواهدی از بورس اوراق بهادار تهران براساس تحلیل مالی رفتاری. فصلنامۀ حسابداری مالی، ۵ (۱۸)، 24-1.##[5] تالانه، ع.، محمودی، م.، و شرفی، ک. (1392). محتوای اطلاعاتی حجم غیرعادی معاملات سهام شرکت‌های بورس تهران. تحقیقات مالی، 15 (1)، 16-1.##[6] رضایی‌دولت‌آبادی، ح.، و صادق‌فلاح، ر. (1393). تحلیل دیدگاه سهامداران بزرگ به عمل واگذاری بلوکی سهام برای تأمین مالی بنگاه به روش مچینگ (مورد مطالعه: شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران). مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی، 2 (2)، 64-39.##[7] قائمی، م.، فرجی‌ملایی، س.، و کیانی، آ. (1392). بررسی واکنش بازار نسبت به ورود یا خروج از فهرست شاخص پنجاه شرکت فعال‌تر در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی، 1 (3)، 48-33.##[8] قائمی، م.، معصومی، ج.، و آزادی، م. (1390). سنجش بازده غیرعادی سهام در شرایط وقفۀ معاملاتی. پژوهش‌های حسابداری مالی، 3 (3)، 126-113.##[9] Agarwalla, S., &amp; Pandey, A. (2010). Price impact of block trades and Price behavior surrounding block trades in the indian capital market. Journal of Indian Institute of Management, 20, 1-63. http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.1572997.##[10] Ahmadpour, A., &amp; Nasiry, M. (2015). The examination asymmetry Price impact of block trades between buying and selling. Journal of Investment Knowledge, 4 (16), 59-74. (in persian).##[11] Ahmadpour, A., &amp; Nasiri, M. (2016). The examination price impact of block trade in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Financial Research, 1 (18), 23-38. (in persian). doi: 10.22059/jfr.2016.59616.##[12] Ahmadpour, A., Aghajani, H., &amp; Fadavi, M. (2014). The examination relationship between stock price changes and trading volume in companies accepted at the Tehran Stock Exchange. Financial Management Strategy, 1 (1), 1-24. (in persian). doi: 10.22051/JFM.2014.956.##[13] Alzahrani, A. A., Gregoriou, A., &amp; Hudson. R. (2013). Price impact of block trades in the Saudi Stock Market. Journal of International Financial Markets Institutions and Money, 23, 322-341. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.intfin.2012.11.003.##[14] Ang, A., Hodrick, R. J., Xing, Y., &amp; Zhang, X. (2006). The cross‐section of volatility and expected returns. The Journal of Finance, 61 (1), 259-299.##[15] Avramov, D., Chordia, T., Jostova, G., &amp; Philipov, A. (2013). Anomalies and financial distress. Journal of Financial Economics, 108 (1), 139-159. https://doi.org/10.1016/ j.jfineco.2012.10.005.##[16] Badri, A., &amp; Kuchaki, A. (2013). Trading volume and stock returns in Tehran Stock Exchange. Financial Accounting, 5 (18), 1-24. (in persian). URL: http://qfaj.ir/article-1-178-fa.html.##[17] Bali, T. G., Cakici, N., &amp; Whitelaw, R. F. (2011). Maxing out: Stocks as lotteries and the cross-section of expected returns. Journal of Financial Economics, 99 (2), 427-446. https://doi.org/10.1016/ j.jfineco.2010.08.014.##[18] Barberis, N., &amp; Huang, M. (2001). Mental accounting, loss aversion and individual stock returns. The Journal of Finance, 56 (4), 1247-1292. https://doi.org/10.1111/0022-1082.00367.##[19] Barclay, M. J., &amp; Holderness, C. G. (1989). Private benefits from control of public corporations. Journal of Financial Economics, 25 (2), 371-395. https://doi.org/ 10.1016/0304-405X(89)90088-3.##[20] Barclay, M. J., &amp; Holderness, C. G. (1991). Negotiated block trades and corporate control. The Journal of Finance, 46 (3), 861-878. https://doi.org/ 10.1111/j.1540-6261.1991.tb03769.x.##[21] Bethel, J. E., Liebeskind, J. P., &amp; Opler, T. (1998). Block share purchases and corporate performance. The Journal of Finance, 53 (2), 605-634. https://doi.org/10.1111/0022-1082.244195.##[22] Bian, J., Wang, J., &amp; Zhang, G. (2012). Chinese block transactions and the market reaction. China Economic Review, 23 (1), 181-189. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chieco. 2011.10.001.##[23] Boyer, B., Mitton, T., &amp; Vorkink, K. (2009). Expected idiosyncratic skewness. The Review of Financial Studies, 23 (1), 169-202. https://doi.org/10.1093/ rfs/hhp041.##[24] Brown, S. J., &amp; Warner, J. B. (1985). Using daily stock returns: The case of event studies. Journal of Financial Economics, 14 (1), 3-31. https://doi.org/10.1016/0304-405X(85)90042-X.##[25] Byrka-Kita, K., Czerwiński, M., &amp; Preś-Perepeczo, A. (2018). What Drives Shareholder Reaction and Wealth Effect in Block Trades? Evidence from the Warsaw Stock Exchange. Emerging Markets Finance and Trade, 54 (7), 1586-1607. doi: 10.1080/1540496X.2017.1315333.##[26] Campbell, J. Y., Lettau, M., &amp; Malkiel, B. G. (2001). Have individual stocks become more volatile? An empirical exploration of idiosyncratic risk. The Journal of Finance, 56 (1), 1-43. https://doi.org/10.1111/0022-1082.00318.##[27] Campbell, J. Y., Lo, A., &amp; MacKinlay AC. (1997). The Econometrics of Financial Markets. Princeton University Press: Princeton, NJ. ISBN 0-691-04301-9.##[28] Cao, C., Simin, T., &amp; Zhao, J. (2006). Can growth options explain the trend in idiosyncratic risk. The Review of Financial Studies, 21 (6), 2599-2633. https://doi.org/10.1093/rfs/hhl039.##[29] Chan, L. K., &amp; Lakonishok, J. (1993). Institutional trades and intraday stock price behavior. Journal of Financial Economics, 33 (2), 173-199. https://doi.org/ 10.1016/0304-405X(93)90003-T.##[30] Chauhan, Y., Wadhwa, K., Syamala, S. R., &amp; Goyal, A. (2015). Block-Ownership structure, bank nominee director and crash-risk. Finance Research Letters, 14, 20-28. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.frl.2015.07.002.##[31] Drees, F., &amp; Schiereck, D. (2008). New outside blockholders, performance and governance in Germany. Journal of Business Management, 1, 129-143. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-8349-8886-7_2.##[32] Drees, F., Mietzner, M., &amp; Schiereck, D. (2013). Effects of corporate equity ownership on firm value. Review of Managerial Science, 7 (3), 277-308. doi: https://doi.org/10.1007/012-0080-2s11846.##[33] Faccio, M., Marchica, M., &amp; Mura, R. (2011). Large shareholder diversification and corporate risk-taking. Review of Financial Studies, 24 (11), 3601–3641. https://doi.org/10.1093/rfs/hhr065.##[34] Fama, E. F., Fisher, L., Jensen, M. C., &amp; Roll, R. (1969). The adjustment of stock prices to new information. International Economic Review, 10 (1), 1-21. doi: 10.2307/2525569.##[35] Ghaemi, H., Faraji Malaei, S., &amp; Kiani, A. (2013). The examination of reaction the arket to entry or exit the index of 50 more active companies in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Asset Management and Financing, 1 (3), 48-33. (in persian).##[36] Ghaemi, M., Masoumi, J., &amp; Azadi, M. (2011). Estimates abnormal stock returns in trading breakdown. Financial Accounting Research, 3 (9),113-126. (in persian).##[37] Gregoric, A., &amp; Vespro, C. (2003). Block trades and the benefits of control in Slovenia, Finance Working Paper, Electronic copy. Available at http://ssrn.com/abstract_id=444500. http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.444500.##[38] Gregoric, A., &amp; Vespro, C. (2009). Block trades and the benefits of control in Slovenia. Economics of Transition, 17 (1), 175-210. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-0351.2009.00332.x.##[39] Han, B., &amp; Kumar, A. (2013). Speculative retail trading and asset prices. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis, 48 (2), 377-404. https://doi.org/ 10.1017/S0022109013000100.##[40] Han, Y., &amp; Lesmond, D. (2011). Liquidity biases and the pricing of cross-sectional idiosyncratic volatility. The Review of Financial Studies, 24 (5), 1590-1629. https://doi.org/10.1093/rfs/hhq140.##[41] Holderness, C. G., &amp; Sheehan, D. P. (1988). The role of majority shareholders in publicly held corporations: An exploratory analysis. Journal of Financial Economics, 20, 317-346. https://doi.org/10.1016/0304-405X(88)90049-9.##[42] Hou, K., Xue, C., &amp; Zhang, L. (2015). Digesting anomalies: An investment approach. The Review of Financial Studies, 28 (3), 650-705. https://doi.org/10.1093 /rfs/hhu068.##[43] Ibikunle, G., &amp; Gregoriou, A. (2018). The price impact of block emissions permit trades. in: Carbon Markets. (pp. 91-128). Palgrave Macmillan, Cham. https://doi.org/ 10.1007/978-3-319-72847-6_4.##[44] Kose, j., Litov, L., &amp; Yeung, B. (2008). Corporate governance and risk-taking. The Journal of Finance, 63 (4), 1679–1728. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-6261.2008. 01372.x.##[45] Kurek, B. (2016). The information content of equity block trades on the Warsaw Stock Exchange: Conventional and bootstrap approaches. Journal of Forecasting, 35 (1), 43-53. https://doi.org/ 10.1111/j.1540-6261.2008.01372.x.##[46] Kurek, B. (2014). The information content of equity block trades on the Warsaw Stock Exchange: An estimation of shares&#039; returns with the usage of simple linear regression and multivariate adaptive regression splines. Journal of Forecasting, 33 (6), 433-454. https://doi.org/10.1002/ for.2299.##[47] Lee, J. S., &amp; Wei, C. Y. (2012). Types of shares and idiosyncratic risk. Emerging Markets Finance and Trade, 48, 68-95.##[48] Leledakis, G. N., Davidson, I., &amp; Smith, J. (2004). Does firm size predict stock returns? Evidence from the London Stock Exchange. Available at: SSRN: https://ssrn.com/abstract=492283 or http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.492283http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.492283.##[49] Maddala, G. S .(2001). Introduction to Econometrics. USA: Wiley.##[50] Maynes, E., &amp; Rumsey. J. (1993). Conducting event studies with thinly traded stocks. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, 17 (1), 145-157. https://doi.org/10.1016/0378-4266(93)90085-R.##[51] Merton, R. C. (1987). A simple model of capital market equilibrium with incomplete information. The Journal of Finance, 42 (3), 483-510. https://doi.org/10.1111/ j.1540-6261.1987.tb04565.x.##[52] Mietzner, M., &amp; Schiereck, D. (2016). Value creation by block acquisitions and theimportance of block owner identity. Finance Research Letters, 17, 118-124. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.frl.2016.02.004.##[53] Nartea, G. V., Wu, J., &amp; Liu, Z. (2013). Does idiosyncratic volatility matter in emerging markets? Evidence from China. Journal of International Financial Markets Institutions and Money, 27, 137-160. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.intfin.2013.09.002.##[54] Park, Y. W., Selvili, Z., &amp; Song, M. H. (2008). Large outside blockholders as monitors: Evidence from partial acquisitions. International Review of Economics &amp; Finance, 17 (4), 529-545. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.iref.2007.05.006.##[55] Parrino, R., Sias, R., &amp; Starks, L. (2003). Voting with their feet: Institutional ownership changes around forced CEO turnover. Journal of Financial Economics, 68 (1), 3–46. https://doi.org/10.1016/ S0304-405X(02)00247-7.##[56] Puche, B., Braun, R., &amp; Achleitner, A. K. (2015). International evidence on value creation in private equity transactions. Journal of Applied Corporate Finance, 27 (4), 105-122. http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ ssrn.2496899.##[57] Rezaei Dolatabadi, H., &amp; Sadegh Fallah, R. (2014). Analyzing the views of large shareholders on the practice of divestiture a stock block to finance the firm based on mating in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Asset Management and Financing, 1 (3), 48-33. (in persian).##[58] Scholes, M. S. (1972). The market for securities: Substitution versus price pressure and the effects of information on share prices. The Journal of Business, 45 (2), 179-211.##[59] Sudarsanam, S. (1996). Large shareholders takeovers and target valuation. Journal of Business Finance &amp; Accounting, 23 (2), 295-314. https://doi.org/ 10.1111/j.1468-5957.1996.tb00914.x.##[60] Talane, A., Mahmoudi, M., &amp; Sharafy, K. (2013). Informational content of abnormal trading volume. Financial Research, 15 (1), 1-16. (in persian). doi. 10.22059/JFR.2013.35429.##[61] Trojanowski, G. (2008). Equity block transfers in transition economies: Evidence from Poland. Economic Systems, 32 (3), 217-238. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecosys. 2007.11.002.##[62] Xu, Y., &amp; Malkiel, B. G. (2004). Idiosyncratic risk and security returns. AFA 2001 NewOrleans Meetings, Available at: SSRN: https://ssrn.com/abstract=255303 or http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.255303.##[63] Zafar, N., Urooj, S. F., &amp; Durrani, T. K. (2008). Interest rate volatility and stock return and volatility. European Journal of Economics Finance and Administrative Sciences, 14, 135-140.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارزیابی کارآیی الگو‌های گارچ در برآورد ریسک سیستماتیک دارایی‌‌های مالی شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Evaluating the Effectiveness of GARCH Models in the Estimation of Systematic Risk in listed companies of the Tehran Stock Exchange</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>بازار سهام هر کشوری علاوه بر منعکس‌کردن ساختار اقتصادی آن کشور، منبع مهم گردش سرمایه در آن محسوب می‌شود؛ بنابراین، شناخت عوامل ایجادکنندۀ بی‌ثباتی در بازار سهام اهمیت زیادی برای برنامه‌‎ریزان اقتصادی دارد. از عوامل شناخته‌شده در مدیریت سبد سهام، مطالعه دربارۀ رفتار ریسک سیستماتیک است. هدف این پژوهش الگو‌سازی ریسک سیستماتیک با استفاده از الگوهای گارچ[1]، ایگارچ[2]، ام گارچ[3]، آرفیما - گارچ[4] و آرفیما - فیگارچ[5]  است که بر بررسی باقی‌ماندۀ الگوی رگرسیونی متمرکز است و متغیر وابستۀ آن بازده بازار و متغیر مستقل آن لگاریتم طبیعی تغییرات شاخص قیمت و بازده نقدی[6] به‌منزلۀ سودآوری سبد بازار است؛ ازاین‌رو، داده‌های مرتبط برای ‌174‌‌ شرکت در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران و به‌صورت روزانه برای بازۀ زمانی 1394-1385 استخراج شد. پس از تحلیل و بررسی داده‌‌ها در نرم‌افزار اُکس متریکس[7] و بررسی الگوها با استفاده از سه معیار مجذور میانگین مربعات خطا[8]، میانگین قدر مطلق خطا[9] و ضریب تایل[10]، نتایج نشان داد الگوی آرفیما - فیگارچ در هر سه معیار کمترین خطا را دارد که نشان‌دهندۀ کارآیی زیاد الگو در برآورد بتای ریسک سیستماتیک است.   [1]. GARCH   [2]. E-GARCH   [3]. M-GARCH   [4]. ARFIMA-GARCH   [5]. ARFIMA- FIGARCH   [6]. TEDPIX   [7]. OXmetrics   [8]. RMSE   [9]. MAE   [10]. TIC</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The stock market of each country, in addition to reflecting its economic structure, is considered as an important source of capital Circulation of that country. Therefore, recognizing the causes of instability in market is of great importance for economic planners. The purpose of this research is systematic risk modeling using GARCH, E-GARCH,  M-GARCH، ARFIMA-GARCH AND ARFIMA- FIGARCH models that is focuses on the residual review of the regression model , whose dependent variable is the market return and the independent variable, the natural logarithm of the change in the price index and cash return (TEDPIX) as a market portfolio. Accordingly, the relevant data for 174 companies in Tehran stock exchange were extracted daily for the period 1385-1394. After analyzing and checking the data in OXmetrics software and examining the models using three criteria, RMSE، MAE &amp; TIC, the results showed that the ARFIMA-FIGARCH model had the least error in terms of all three criteria, which indicates the efficiency of the model in the systematic risk beta estimation.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>23</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>40</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نعمت</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>راستگو</Family>
						<NameE>nemat</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>rastgoo</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری ،گروه حسابداری ، واحد کاشان ، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی ، کاشان ، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری ،گروه حسابداری ، واحد کاشان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>nemat.rastgoo@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>پناهیان</Family>
						<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>panahian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار ،گروه حسابداری،واحد کاشان، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی ، کاشان ، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار ،گروه حسابداری،واحد کاشان، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>h.panahian@iaukashan.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ریسک سیتماتیک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الگوهای گارچ</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شاخص نابرابری تایل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>عباسی نژاد، ح. و تشکینی، ا. (1389). اقتصادسنجیکاربردیپیشرفته، تهران: انتشارات دانشکده علوم اقتصادی و نور علم.##فلاح شمس، م. (1389). بررسی مقایسه‌ای کارایی مدل ریسک سنجی و مدل اقتصادسنجی GARCH  در پیش بینی ریسک بازار در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. مهندسی مالی و مدیریت پرتفوی، 5: 159-137##فلاح شمس، م. و پناهی، ی. (1393). مقایسه کارایی مدل‌های خانواده GARCH در مدل‌سازی و اندازه‌گیری ریسک نقد شوندگی بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، دانش سرمایه‌گذاری، 9: 21 – 41 .##حسین‌پور، ع. و سعیدی، پ. (1395). رابطه بین نسبت‌های مالی و ریسک سیستماتیک در صنعت سیمان در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. مطالعات بررسی‌های مدیریت، 2:  84-80 .##کیقبادی، ا. و احمدی، م. (1395). مقایسه کارایی روش‌های GARCH و ARCH در پیش بینی ارزش در معرض ریسک جهت انتخاب پرتفولیوی بهینه، پژوهش‌های حسابداری مالی و حسابرسی، 32: 63-82 .##کشاورز حداد، غ. (1395). اقتصاد سنجی داده‌های خرد و ارزیابی سیاست، تهران: نشر نی.##رحمانی، ع.؛ پیکارجو، ک. و عزیزی، م. (1393). رابطه بتای بازار سهام با متغیر های کلان اقتصادی و اطلاعات حسابداری، دانش سرمایه گذاری، 10: 47 -66.##Abbasi Nejad, H., &amp; Tashkini, A. (2010). Advanced Applied Econometrics. Tehran: Economical Science Faculty. (in persian).##Alalaya, B. T. (2014). A case study: Study of Amman Stock Exchange volatility during 1994–2013. International Business Research, 5, 80-90. Doi: 10.5539/ibr.v7n5p80.##Baillie, R. T., Bollerslev, T., &amp; Mikkelsen. H. O. (1996). Fractionally integrated generalized autoregressive conditional heteroscedasticity. Journal of Econometrics, 74, 3-30. Doi: 10.1016/S0304-4076(95)01749-6.##Baillie, R. T., &amp; Chung, F. C. (1996). Analysing inflation by the fractionally integrated ARFIMA–GARCH model. Journal of Applied Econometrics, 11, 23-40. Doi: 10.1002/ (SICI) 1099-1255 (199601) 11:13.0.CO;2-M.##Brealey, R. A., Myers&#039;s, C., &amp; Allen. F. (2006). Principiosde Finanzas Corporativas. Madrid: McGraw-Hill. ISBN: 978-007-340510-0.##Brimble, M., &amp; Hodgson, A. (2007). Assessing the risk relevance of accounting variables in diverse economic conditions. Managerial Finance, 33, 553-573. Doi: 10.1108/03074350710760296.##Brooks, R. D., Foff, R. W., &amp; Mckenzie. M. D. (1998). Time‐varying beta risk of Australian industry portfolios: A comparison of modeling techniques. Australian Journal of Management, 23 (1), 1-22. Doi: 10.1177/031289629802300101.##Cai, Z., Ren, R. W. (2011). A new estimation on time-varying betas in conditional CAPM. Miscellaneous Papers. 7: 211-217. Available at: http://www.fas.nus.edu.sg/ecs/events/seminar/seminar-papers/16 Aug11.pdf.##Ceremeno, R., &amp; Grier, K. (2001). Modeling GARCH processes in panel data: Theory, simulations and examples. working paper. University of Oklahama. Available at: https://www.researchgate.net/publication/253914511_Modeling_GARCH_processes_in_Panel_Data_Theory_Simulations_and_Examples.## Choudhry, T., &amp; Wu, H. (2009). Forecasting the weekly time- varying beta of Uk firms: GARCH models vs Kalman Filter method. European Journal of Finance, 15 (4), 437-444. Doi: 10.1080/13518470802604499.##Damodaran, A. (2010). Applied Corporate Finance. New York: John Wiley &amp; Sons.##Elyasiani, E., &amp; Mansur, I. (2005). The association between market and exchange rate risks and accounting variables: A GARCH model of the Japanese banking institutions. Review of Quantitative Finance and Accounting, 25, 183-206. Doi: 10.1007/s11156-005-4248-6.##Fabozzi, F., &amp; Francis, J. (1978). Beta as a random coefficient. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis, 13, 101-116. Doi: 10.2307/2330525.##Faff, R., Hillier, W., &amp; Hillier. D. J. (2000). Time varying beta risk: An analysis of alternative modelling techniques. Journal of Business Finance &amp; Accounting, 27: 523–554. Doi: 10.1111/1468-5957.00324.##Fallah Shams, M. (2010). Comparative study of the effectiveness of risk assessment model and GARCH econometric model in market risk forecasting of Tehran Stock Exchange. Financial Engineering and Securities Management, 6, 137-157. (in persian). Available at: http://fej.iauctb.ac.ir/article_511785.html.##Fallah Shams, M., &amp; Panahi, Y. (2014). Efficiency comparison among GARCH models in modeling and liquidity measurement; A case study of Tehran Stock Exchange .Investment Knowledge, 3, 21-42. (in persian). Available at: http://jik.srbiau.ac.ir/article_7592.html.##Fama, E., &amp; French. K. R. (1995). Size and book to market factors in earning and returns. Journal of Finance, 50, 131-155. Doi: 10.1111/j.1540-6261.1995.tb05169.x.##Girardi, G., &amp; Ergün, A. T. (2013). Systemic risk measurement: Multivariate GARCH estimation of Covar. Journal of Banking and Finance, 37, 3169-3180. Doi: 10.1016/j.jbankfin.2013.02.027.##Granger, C. W. J., &amp; Joyeux, R. (1980). An introduction to long memory time series models and fractional difference. Journal of Time Series Analysis, 1: 15-29. Doi: 10.1111/j.1467-9892.1980.tb00297.x.##Hosking, J. R. M. (1981). Fractional differencing. Biometrika, 68 (1), 165-176.Doi: 10.2307/2335817.##Hosseinpour, A., &amp; Saeidi, P. (2016). The relationship between financial ratios and systematic risk in cement industry in Tehran stock exchange. Research Journal of Management Reviews, 2 (2), 80-84. (in persian). Available at: http://jafesjournal. com/fulltext/paper-29012016211230.pdf.##Kearney, C., &amp; Patton, A. J. (2000). Multivariate GARCH modeling of exchange rate volatility transmission in the European monetary system, Financial Revew, 41, 29-48. Doi: 10.1111/j.1540-6288.2000.tb01405.x.##Keshavarz Haddad, G. )2015(. Microeconomic Data Economics and Policy Evaluation. Tehran: Ney Press. (in persian).##Keyghobadi, A. R., &amp; Ahmadi, M. (2017). Comparison of the efficiency of GARCH and ARCH methods in forecasting value at risk for optimal portfolio selection. Financial Accounting and Audit Research, 32, 63-82. (in persian). Available at: http://faar.iauctb.ac.ir/article-528671.html.##Luchtenberga, K. F., &amp; Vu, Q. V. (2015). The 2008 financial crisis: Stock market contagion and its Determinants. Research in International Business and Finance, 33, 178-203. Doi: 10.1016/j.ribaf.2014.09.007.##Mergner. S, &amp; Bulla, J. (2008). Time-varying beta risk of Pan-European industry portfolios: A comparison of alternative modeling techniques. European Journal of Finance, 14, 771-802. Doi: 10.1080/13518470802173396.##Nelson, D. B. (1991). Conditional heteroskedasticity in asset returns: A new approach. Econometrica, 59, 34-70. Doi: 10.2307/2938260.##Nelson, C. R., &amp; Charles, I. P. (1982). Trends and random walks in macroeconomic time series: Some evidence and implications. Journal of Monetary Economics, 10 (2), 139–162. Doi: 10.1016/0304-3932(82)90012-5.##Nieto, B., Orbe, S., &amp; Zarraga. A. (2014). Time-varying market beta: Does the estimation methodology matter? Sort-Statistics and Operations Research Transactions, 38, 13-42. Available at: https://www.raco.cat/index.php/SORT/article/view/277216.##Noseleit, F. (2013). Entrepreneurship, structural change and economic growth. Journal of Evolutionary Economics, 23 (4), 735–766. Doi: 10.1007/s00191-012-0291-3.##Pederzoli, C. (2006). Stochastic volatility and GARCH: A comparison based on Uk stock data. European Journal of Finance, 12, 41-59. Doi: 10.1080/13518470500039121.##Poon, H., &amp; Granger, C. (2003). Forecasting volatility in financial markets: A review. Journal of Economic Literature, 41 (2), 478–539. Doi: 10.1257/002205103765762743.##Rahmani, A., Peikarjoo, K., &amp; Azizi. M. (2014). The relationships between market beta with macroeconomic variables and accounting information. Investment Knowledge, 3: 47-66. (in persian). Available at: http://jik.srbiau.ac.ir/article-7605.html.##Ribeiro, P. P., Ceremeno, R., &amp; Curto. J. D. (2016). Sovereign bond markets and pnancial volatility dynamics: Panel-GARCH evidence for six Euro area countries. Finance Research Letters, 21, 107-114. Doi: 10.1016/j.frl.2016.11.011.##Robinson, F. P. (2003). Time Series with Long Memory. New York: Oxford University Press.##Turkyilmaz, S. (2014). Long memory behavior in the returns of Pakistan stock market: ARFIMA-FIGARCH models. International Journal of Economics and Financial, 4(2), 400-410. Available at: http://www.econjournals.com/index.php/ijefi/article/view/784.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی واکنش سرمایه‌گذاران به سود غیرمنتظره در شرایط عدم‌ ‌اطمینان‌ بازار</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Analysis of Investors’ Reaction to Unexpected Earnings Under Market Uncertainty</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: در شرایط عدم ‌اطمینان‌، سرمایه‌گذاران اطلاعات کافی دربارۀ جریان‌های نقد آتی شرکت‌ها ندارند و دربارۀ وضعیت آتی بازار ابهام وجود دارد. در این شرایط طبق قانون بیز، ورود هر سیگنال اطلاعاتی (مانند اعلام سود) ممکن است عدم ‌اطمینان را کاهش دهد و سبب واکنش بیشتر سرمایه‌گذاران نسبت به اعلام سود شود؛ بنابراین، هدف پژوهش حاضر بررسی واکنش سرمایه‌گذاران نسبت به سود غیرمنتظره در شرایط عدم‌ اطمینان بازار است.
روش: بدین منظور نمونه‌ای شامل 162 شرکت پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در دورۀ زمانی 1384 تا 1394 انتخاب شد. برای محاسبۀ عدم اطمینان بازار از دو روش فرمول محاسباتی و گارچ استفاده شد.
نتایج: نتایج آزمون فرضیه‌ها نشان می‌‌دهد زمانی که عدم اطمینان بالایی در بازار وجود دارد (نسبت به عدم اطمینان پایین)، واکنش سرمایه‌گذاران به اعلام سود سالانۀ شرکت‌ها بیشتر است. در شرایط عدم‌اطمینان بالا، سرمایه‌گذاران نسبت به اخبار بد سود (زیان غیرمنتظره) واکنش بیشتری از خود نشان می‌‌دهند که این واکنش با رویکرد محافظه‌کاری همخوانی دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objectives: Under uncertainty, investors do not have enough information about the firm&#039;s future cash flows and there is ambiguity about future state of the market. In this situation, according to Bayes&#039; rule, when the market receives information signals (such as firms’ earnings announcements), it may reduce uncertainty and results in more investors&#039; reaction to earnings announcement. The purpose of this study is investigating investors&#039; reaction to unexpected earnings under market uncertainty.
Method: For doing so, a sample of 162 companies listed in the Tehran Stock Exchange in the period 1384 to 1394 have been selected. Two methods (the computational formula and GARCH method) were used for calculating market uncertainty.
Results: The results of hypotheses test indicated when market uncertainty is high (compared to lower uncertainty), investors’ reaction to earnings announcement is more. Also, under high market uncertainty, investors display more reaction to bad news that this response is consistent with the conservatism approach.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>41</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>56</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نرگس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حمیدیان</Family>
						<NameE>narges</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>hamidian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری حسابداری، دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصاد دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری حسابداری، دانشکده علوم اداری</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>nargeshamidian@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عربصالحی</Family>
						<NameE>Mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Arabsalehi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصاد دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصاد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mehdi_arabsalehi@ase.ui.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>هادی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>امیری</Family>
						<NameE>hadi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>amiri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار اقتصاد، گروه اقتصاد، دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصاد دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار اقتصاد، گروه اقتصاد، دانشکده علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>h.amiri@ase.ui.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اعلام سود سالانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سود غیرمنتظره</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بازده غیرعادی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عدم اطمینان بازار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>منابع فارسی##آقایی، م.؛ ثقفی، ع.؛ نتاج، غ. و اسدنیا، ج.. (1391). تاثیر اعلان سود فصلی شرکت‌ها بر تامین نیاز اطلاعاتی ذینفعان،. حسابداری مالی، 16: 39-1.##سوری، ع. (1394). افتصادسنجی همراه با کاربرد Eviews و Stata، تهران: نشر فرهنگ­شناسی.##فلاح شمس، م. (1389). بررسی مقایسه‌ای کارایی مدل ریسک سنجی و مدل اقتصادسنجی GARCH در پیش بینی ریسک بازار بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، مجله مهندسی مالی و مدیریت پرتفوی، 5: 137-159.##زمردیان، غ.؛ شعبان‌زاده، م. و نجفی شریعت زاده، ا. (1394). بررسی اثرپذیری بازار سرمایه ایران از عدم اطمینان سیاست پولی و مالی، مجله مهندسی مالی و مدیریت اوراق بهادار، 25: 81-106.##زنجیردار، م. و مصلحی‌عراقی، م. (1395). تاثیر تغییرات عدم عدم اطمینان، سود غیرمنتظره هر سهم، اخبار خوب و بد و پیش­بینی سود هر سهم در شرایط مختلف اقتصادی بر ریسک سرمایه­گذاری،  فصلنامه سیاست‌های مالی و اقتصادی، 13: 76-55.##صالحی، م.؛ موسوی شیری، م. و ابراهیمی سویزی، م. (1393). محتوای اطلاعاتی سود اعلان شده و پیش‌بینی شده هر سهم در تبیین بازده غیرعادی سهام، پژوهش‌های حسابداری مالی و حسابرسی، 21 :117-140.##مرادزاده فرد، م.؛ عدل‌زاده، م.؛ فرج‌زاده، م. و عظیمی، ص. (1392). عدم اطمینان اطلاعاتی، عدم تقارن اطلاعاتی و فرصت‌های رشد، مطالعات تجربی حسابداری مالی، 39: 145-125.##مرفوع، م. و عدل‌زاده، م. (1393). عدم اطمینان اطلاعاتی و واکنش کمتر از حد سرمایه­گذاران، پژوهش­های تجربی حسابداری، 13: 169-189.##References##Agapova, A., &amp; Madura, J. (2016). Market uncertainty and earnings guidance. The Quarterly Review of Economics and Finance, 61, 97-111.##Aghaie, M. A., Saghafi, A., Taghi Nataj, G., &amp; Asadniya, J. (2013). The effect of quarterly earnings announcement on stakeholder’s information needs. Quarterly Financial Accounting, 16, 1-39. (In Persian).##Ball, R., Sadka, G., &amp; Sadka, R. (2009). Aggregate earnings and asset prices. Journal of Accounting Research, 47, 1097-1133.##Bansal, R., &amp; Yaron, A. (2004). Risks for the long run: A potential resolution of asset pricing puzzles. Journal of Finance, 59, 1481–1509.##Bird, R., &amp; Yeung, D. (2012). How do investors react under uncertainty? Pacific-Basin Finance Journal, 20, 310-327.##Bittlingmayer, G. (1998). Output, stock volatility, and political uncertainty in a natural Experiment: Germany, 1880–1940. Journal of Finance, 53, 2243–2257.##Bonsall, S., Bozanic, Z., &amp; Fischer, P. (2013). What do management earnings forecasts convey about the macro economy? Journal of Accounting Research, 51 (2), 225-266.##Chai, D., Faff, R., &amp; Gharghori, P. (2010). New evidence on the relation between stock liquidity and measures of trading activity. International Review of Financial Analysis, 19, 181-192.##Choi, H. (2014). When good news is not so good: Economy-Wide uncertainty and stock returns. Journal of Business Finance and Accounting, 41 (9 and10), 1101-1123.##Choi, H. (2015). A Tale of two uncertainties. Loyola University Chicago. Working paper. Access date 2016.##David, A., &amp; Veronesi, P. (2001). Inflation and earnings uncertainty and the volatility of assetprices: An Empirical Investigation. Working Paper, University of Chicago.##Detemple, J. B. (1986). Asset pricing in a production economy with incomplete information. Journal of Finance, 41, 383–391.## Fallah Shams, M. F. (2011). A comparable evaluation of efficiency between risk metrics model and GARCH econometrics model to forecast market risk in Tehran Stock Exchange. Financial Engineering and Portfolio Management, 1(5), 137-159. (In Persian).##Francis, J., Lafond, R., Olsson, R., &amp; Schipper, K. (2007). Information uncertainty and the post-earnings-announcement drift. Journal of Business Finance and Accounting, 34, 403–433.##Gennotte, G. (1986). Optimal portfolio choice under incomplete information. Journal of Finance, 41, 733–746.##Gilboa, I., &amp; Schmeidler, D. (1989). Maxim expected utility with non-unique prior. Journal of Mathematical Economics, 18, 141–153.##Gyamfi-Yeboah, F., David C., &amp; Naranjo, A. (2012). Information, uncertainty and behavioral effects: Evidence from abnormal returns around real estate investment trust earnings announcements. Journal of International Money and Finance, 31, 1930-1952.##Knight, F. H. (1921). Risk, uncertainty and profit. Boston: MA. Hart, Schaffner &amp; Marx; Houghton Mifflin Company.##Lewellen, J., &amp; Shanken, J. (2002). Learning, asset-pricing tests and market efficiency. Journal of Finance, 57(3), 1113-1145.##Marfoua, A., &amp; Adlzadeh, M. (2014). Information uncertainty and investors’ under-reaction. Journal of Empirical Research in Accounting, 4 (1), 169-177. (In Persian).##Moradzadehfard M., Adlzadeh, M., Farajzadeh, M., &amp; Azimi, S. (2013). Information uncertainty, information asymmetry and growth options. Empirical Studies in Financial Accounting Quarterly, 10 (39), 125-145. (In Persian).##Ozoguz, A. (2009). Good times or bad times? Investors’ uncertainty and stock returns. The Review of Financial Studies, 22(1), 4377-4422.##Pástor, L., &amp; Veronesi, P. (2009). Learning in financial markets. Annual Review of Financial Economics, 1, 361-381.##Rogers J. L., Skinner, D. J., &amp; Buskirk, A. (2009). Earnings guidance and market uncertainty. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 48(1), 90-109.##Salehi, M., Mousavi Shiri, M., &amp; Ebrahimi Swizi, M. (2014). The information content of declared dividends per share and predicted earnings per share in explaining abnormal stock return. The Financial Accounting and Auditing Researches, 6(21), 117-140. (In Persian).##Souri, A. (2015). Econometrics. Tehran: Farhangshenasi. (In Persian).##Veronesi, P. (1999). Stock market overreaction to bad news in good times: A rational expectations equilibrium model. Review of Financial Studies, 12, 975–1007.##Williams, C. (2009). Asymmetric Responses to Earnings News: A Case for Ambiguity. Dissertation for the degree of Doctor of Philosophy in the Kenan-Flagler Business School.##Williams, C. (2015). Asymmetric responses to earnings news: A case for ambiguity. The Accounting Review, 90(2), 785-817.##Xu, Z. (2010). Two Essays on Information Ambiguity and Informed Traders’ Trade-size Choice. Dissertation for the degree of Doctor of Philosophy. University of South Florida.##Zanjirdar, M., &amp; Moslehi Araghi, M. (2016). The impact of changes in uncertainty, unexpected earning of each share and positive or negative forecast of profit per share in different economic condition. Quarterly Journal of Fiscal and Economic Policies, 4 (13), 55-76 (In Persian).##Zolotoy, L., Frederickson, James R., &amp; Lyon. J. (2017). Aggregate earnings and stock market returns: The good, the bad and the state-dependent. Journal of Banking and Finance, 77, 157-175.##Zomorodian, G., Shabanzadeh, M., &amp; Najafi Shariatzadeh, I. (2016). Examining the effect of uncertainty in monetary and fiscal policy on capital markets. Financial Engineering and Portfolio Management, 6(25), 81-106. (In Persian).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مدل‏سازی ارزش در معرض ریسک قراردادهای آتی سکۀ بهار آزادی با درنظرگرفتن حافظۀ تاریخی در مشاهدات: کاربردی از الگو‏های FIAPARCH-CHUNG</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Modeling Value at Risk of Futures Contract of Bahar Azadi Gold Coin with Considering the Historical Memory in Observations
Application of  FIAPARCH-CHUNG Models</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: ارزش در معرض ریسک ابزاری استاندارد و مناسب برای اندازه‌گیری ریسک بالقوۀ زیان‌های اقتصادی در بازارهای مالی است که امروزه به‌طور وسیعی برای کنترل و پیش‌بینی انواع ریسک‌ بازاری، اعتباری و مالی استفاده می‌شود. روش: در این مطالعه با بهره‏گرفتن از معیارهای اطلاعات نشان داده شد بهترین الگویی که می‌تواند طی دورۀ 26/9/1392 تا 6/8/1395 نوسانات بازده آتی‌های سکۀ بهار آزادی را نمایش دهد، الگوی MA(1)-FIAPARCH-CHUNG(2,d,1) است. در ادامه ارزش در معرض ریسک، با توجه به الگوی ذکرشده در دو موقعیت خرید و فروش برای این دارایی سنجیده و برای تأیید خوب‌بودن فرایند محاسبۀ ارزش در معرض ریسک از آزمون کوپیک استفاده شد. نتایج: طبق نتایج، ارزیابی ویژگی عدم‌تقارن و حافظۀ ‏بلندمدت در نوسانات بازده ممکن است سبب انتخاب الگوی ارزش در معرض ریسک مناسب برای عملکرد مدیریت ریسک در بازار آتی‌های سکۀ تهران شود و تحلیل‏ها در این پژوهش می‏تواند ابزاری باارزش برای فعالیت در بورس کالای ایران محسوب شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: Value-at-Risk (VaR) is a standard tool for measuring potential risk of economic losses in financial markets, thus it is largely used in controlling and predicting a wide variety of risks such as market, credit, and financial risks. Method: Applying criteria information, this study shows that the best model for measuring the volatility of coin’s futures return, during the period 2013/12/17 to 2016/10/27, is MA(1)-FIAPARCH-CHUNG (2, d, 1). According to the applied model, the VAR, for short- and long-term positions, was calculated and, then, to confirm the accuracy of the applied VAR, Kupic test was run. Resutls: Our findings indicate that asymmetry evaluation and long-term memory of return volatility can ensure a more accurate VAR model which enhances the quality of the risk management process in the Tehran Futures Market.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>57</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>82</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مجتبی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بیگ خورمیزی</Family>
						<NameE>Mojtaba</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Biek Khormizi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>مهندسی مالی، دانشکده صنایع، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد تهران جنوب، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>مهندسی مالی، دانشکده صنایع، دانشگاه آزاد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>st_m_beikkhormizi@azad.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>میثم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رافعی</Family>
						<NameE>Meysam</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rafei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه اقتصاد امور عمومی، دانشکده اقتصاد، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران, ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه اقتصاد امور عمومی، دانشکده اقتصاد، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.rafei@khu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ارزش در معرض ریسک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>حافظۀ بلندمدت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نوسان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قرارداد آتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سکه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] پویانفر، الف.، و افشاری، ن. (1396). محاسبۀ ودیعۀ اولیۀ قرارداد آتی سکۀ طلا با استفاده از رویکرد ارزش در معرض ریسک و نظریۀ ارزش فرین. چهارمین همایش بین‌المللی و ششمین همایش بین‌المللی ایده‌های نوین در علوم مدیریت و اقتصاد.##[2] حسینی‌امینی، الف.، و نجفی، الف. (1392). تعیین سبد بهینۀ سرمایه‌گذاری در صنایع مختلف بورس اوراق بهادار تهران با استفاده از رویکرد##VaR-Multivariate GARCH. دانش مالی تحلیل اوراق بهادار، 6 (20)، 44-29.##[3] دلاوری، م.، و رحمتی، ز. (1389). بررسی تغییرپذیری نوسانات قیمت سکۀ طلا در ایران با استفاده از مدل‌های ARCH. دانش و توسعه، 17 (30)، 68-51.##[4] شاه‌مرادی، الف.، و زنگنه، م. (1386). محاسبۀ ارزش در معرض خطر برای شاخص‌های عمدۀ بورس اوراق بهادار تهران با استفاده از روش پارامتریک. تحقیقات اقتصادی، 79، 149-121.##[5] عباسی، الف. (1392). برآورد و ارزیابی ارزش در معرض ریسک در بازار فارکس. مهندسی مالی و مدیریت اوراق بهادار، 4 (17)، 44-23.##[6] عباسی، الف.، تیمورپور، ب.، و برجسته‌ملکی، م. (1388). کاربرد ارزش در معرض ریسک (VaR) در تشکیل سبد سهام بهینه در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. مجلۀ تحقیقات اقتصادی، 44 (87)، 114-91.##[7] کشاورزحداد، غ.، و صمدی، ب. (1388). برآورد و پیش‌بینی تلاطم بازدهی در بازار سهام تهران و مقایسۀ دقت روش‌ها در تخمین ارزش در معرض خطر: کاربردی از مدل‌های خانوادۀ FIGARCH. تحقیقات اقتصادی، 44 (1)،235-193.##References##[8] Abbasi, E. (2013). The estimate and evaluation of value at risk in forex market. Financial Engineering and Securities Management, 4 (17), 23-44. (in persian).##[9] Abbasi, E., Teymourpour, B., &amp; Barjesteh Maleki M. (2009). Optimum portfolio selection using value at risk in Tehran Stock Exchange. Tahghighat-e-Eghtesadi, 44 (87), 91-114. (in persian).##[10] Baillie, R. T., Bollerslev, T., &amp; Mikkelsen, H. O. (1996). Fractionally integrated generalized autoregressive conditional heteroscedasticity. Journal of Econometrics, 74, 3-30. DOI: 10.1016/S0304-4076(95)01749-6.##[11] Bee, M., &amp; Miorelli, F. (2010). Dynamic VaR models and the peaks over threshold method for market risk measurement: An empirical investigation during a financial crisis. Journal of Risk Model Validation, 9, 1-40.##[12] Bollerslev, T. (1986). Generalized autoregressive conditional heteroscedasticity. Journal of Econometrics, 31, 307-327. DOI: 10.1016/0304-4076(86)90063-1.##[13] Chkili, W., Hammoudeh, S., &amp; Khuong Nguyen, D. (2014). Volatility forecasting and risk management for commodity markets in the presence of asymmetry and long memory. Energy Economics, 41, 1–18. DOI: 10.1016/j.eneco.2013.10.011.##[14] Delavari, M., &amp; Rahmati, Z. (2010). The analysis of volatility of gold coin price fluctuations in Iran using arch models. Journal of Knowledge and Development, 17 (30), 51-68. (in persian).##[15] Demiralay, S., &amp; Ulusoy, V. (2014). Value-at-risk predictions of precious metals with long memory volatility models. MPRA Munich Personal RePEc Archive. MPRA Paper No. 53229: 1-25.##[16] Demireli, E. (2010). Value at risk analysis and long memory: Evidence from fiaparch in Istanbul Stock Exchange. Atatürk Üniversitesi İktisadi ve İdari Bilimler Dergisi, 24 (4), 217-228.##[17] Hosseyni Imeni, A., &amp; Najafi, A. (2013). Investigation optimize portfolio with use of VaR-multivariate garch. Financial Knowledge of Security Analysis, 6 (20), 29-44. (in persian).##[18] Jeremić, Z., &amp; Terzić, I. (2014). Empirical estimation and comparison of normal and student-t linear VaR on the Belgrade Stock Exchange. Sinteza, 10, 289-302. DOI: 10.15308/sinteza-2014-298-302.##[19] Kampbell, J. Y., Lo, A. W., &amp; Craig Mackinlay, A. (1997). The Econometrics of Financial Market. The United Kingdom: Princeton University press.##[20] Kang, S., &amp; Yoon, S. M. (2008). Value-at-risk analysis of the long memory volatility process: The case of individual stock returns. The Korean Journal of Finance, 21, 4-18.##[21] Kasman, A. (2009). Estimating value-at-risk for the Turkish stock index futures in the presence of long memory volatility. Central Bank Review, 1: 1-14.##[22] Keshavarz Hadad, G., &amp; Samadi, B. (2008). An appraisal on the performance of figarch models in the estimation of VaR: The case study of Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Economic Research (Tahghighat- e- Eghtesadi), 44 (1), 193-235. (in persian).##[23] Kupiec, P. (1995). Techniques for verifying the accuracy of risk management models. Journal of Derivatives, 3, 73-84.##[24] Kuttu, S. (2017). Modelling long memory in volatility in sub-saharan African equity markets. Research in International Business and Finance, 44, 176-185. DOI: 10.1016/j.ribaf.2017.07.073.##[25] Lanouar, C. (2016). Breaks or long range dependence in the energy futures volatility: Out-of-sample forecasting and VaR analysis. Economic Modelling, 53, 354–374. DOI: 10.1016/j.econmod.2015.12.009.##[26] Liu, H. C., Cheng, Y. J., &amp; Tzou, Y. P. (2009). Value-at-risk-based risk management on exchange traded funds: The Taiwanese experience. Banks and Bank Systems, 4 (2): 20-28.##[27] Mabrouk, S. (2016). Forecasting daily conditional volatility and h-step-ahead short and long VaR accuracy: Evidence from financial data. The Journal of Finance and Data Science, 2, 136-151. DOI: 10.1016/j.jfds.2016.06.001.##[28] Mighri, Z., Mokni, K., &amp; Mansouri, F. (2010). Empirical analysis of asymmetric long memory volatility models in value-at-risk estimation. The Journal of Risk, 13 (1), 55-128. DOI: 10.21314/JOR.2010.216.##[29] Pouyanfar, A., &amp; Afshari, N. (2016). Calculation of initial margin of the gold coin futures contract by using the value at risk approach and extreme value theory. The 4th National Conference in Management, Economics and Accounting. (in persian).##[30] Shahmoradi, A., &amp; Zanganeh, M. (2007). The parametric methods for estimating the value at risk for Tehran Stock Exchange indices. Tahghighat- e- Eghtesadi, 79, 121-149. (in persian).##[31] Slim, S., Koubaa, Y., &amp; BenSaïda, A. (2017). Value-at-risk under lévy garch models: Evidence from global stock markets. Journal of International Financial Markets, Institutions &amp; Money, 46, 30-53. DOI: 10.1016/j.intfin.2016.08.008.##[32] Stavroyiannis, S., &amp; Zarangas, L. (2013). Out of sample value-at-risk and backtesting with the standardized pearson type-iv skewed distribution. Panoeconomicus. Panoeconomicus, 60 (2), 231-247. DOI: 10.2298/PAN1302231S.##[33] Su, J. (2017). How do financial features affect volatility forecasts? Evidence from the oil market and other markets. Asia Pacific Management Review, 23 (2), 95-107. DOI: 10.1016/j.apmrv.2016.11.003.##[34] Tsay, R. S. (1951). Analysis of Financial Time Series. Translated by: Ahmad Nabizadeh, Tehran: The Commerce Printing &amp; Publishing Company.##[35] Wu, P. T., &amp; Shieh, S. J. (2007). Value‐at‐risk analysis for long‐term interest rate futures: Fat‐tail and long memory in return innovations. Journal of Empirical Finance, 14 (2), 248‐259. DOI: 10.1016/j.jempfin.2006.02.001.##[36] Yoon, S. M., &amp; Kang, S. H. (2007). A skewed student-t value-at-risk approach for long memory volatility processes in Japanese financial markets. International Economic Studies, 11, 211-242. DOI: 10.11644/KIEP.JEAI.2007.11.1.169.##[37] Yoon, S. M., Woo, H., &amp; Kang, S. H. (2011). VaR analysis for the Shanghai stock market. In the proceeding of the 2011 International Conference on Advancements in Information Technology with workshop of ICBMG. IPCSIT. IACSIT Press, 20, 228-232.##[38] www. Ime.co.ir##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>راهبرد‌های تداوم مبتنی بر نقاط مرجع؛ شواهدی از سوگیری‌‌ اتکا و تعدیل</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Momentum Strategies Based on Reference Points; Evidence from Adjustment and Anchoring Bias</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>اهداف: براساس مطالعات تجربی مالی، راهبرد سرمایه‌گذاری تداوم ممکن است سبب بازده اضافی در میان‌مدت شود. ازجمله عوامل ایجاد تداوم که از سوگیری‌ اتکا و تعدیل تأثیر می‌گیرد، اتکا بر نقاط قیمتی مرجع و تعدیلات بعدی قیمت است. در این پژوهش با نقاط مرجع مطرح در ادبیات موضوع، راهبرد‌های سرمایه‌گذاری تداوم مبتنی بر این نقاط ارزیابی می‌شود.
روش: این مطالعه با استفاده از روش تحلیل سبد و نمونه‌ای متشکل از 108 شرکت پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران طی دوره‌ای ده‌ساله، از ابتدای سال 1386 تا انتهای سال 1395 انجام شده است.
نتایج: نتایج پژوهش نشان می‌دهد سرمایه‌گذاران متأثر از سوگیری اتکا و تعدیل، نقاط مرجع مبتنی بر آستانه‌های حدی با بازۀ حداکثر یک‌ساله (به‌ویژه حداکثر قیمت 26 هفته) را بیش از سایر نقاط مرجع، نقطۀ اتکای خود قرار می‌دهند و با تعدیلات بعدی قیمت، الگوی تداوم بازده را ایجاد می‌کنند. نتایج تجزیه‌وتحلیل رگرسیون نشان می‌دهد این بازده با تعدیل ریسک و اعمال متغیرهای کنترل، قوی و ازلحاظ آماری معنادار است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: According to empirical financial studies, a momentum investment strategy can lead to excess returns in the medium term. One of the driving factors of momentum return is adjustment and anchoring bias. Investors’ anchor to reference point price and consequent price adjustment drive momentum in price trends. In this research, based on reference points price stated by literature, Momentum investment strategies are investigated.
Method: Using portfolio study and studying 108 firms listed in Tehran Stock Exchange over the period from 2007 to 2017 (1386-1395 in Solar Hijri-Iranian calendar), the study has been conducted.
Results: Results indicate that investors, applying adjustment and anchoring bias, select reference points based on price extremes up to one year (especially high 26 week price) more than other reference point’s prices as anchor, generating then momentum return by this adjusted price. Furthermore, the results of the regression analysis revealed that with risk adjustments and applying other control variables, this return is robust and statistically significant.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>83</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>104</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>غلامحسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>اسدی</Family>
						<NameE>Golamhossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Asadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت مالی و بیمه، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت مالی و بیمه، دانشکدۀ</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>h-assadi@sbu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مریم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>دولو</Family>
						<NameE>Maryam</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Davallou</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه مدیریت مالی و بیمه، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه مدیریت مالی و بیمه، دانشکدۀ</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ma_davallou@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سبحان</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>اسکینی</Family>
						<NameE>Sobhan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Eskini</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه مدیریت مالی و بیمه، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه مدیریت مالی و بیمه، دانشکدۀ</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>s_eskini@sbu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>راهبرد تداوم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اتکا و تعدیل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نقاط مرجع</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فروواکنش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1-   فلاح‌پور، سعید، و رسول سعدی، و غلامرضا ابوترابی‌فرد (1392). رابطه بین بازده روزانه سهام انفرادی و بالاترین قیمت 52 هفته گذشته در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. فصلنامه بورس اوراق بهادار تهران 6(22): 73-101.##2-     دولو، مریم و جوادیان، بهاره (1396). مومنتوم &quot;زمان بندی بالاترین قیمت 52 هفته&quot;: شواهدی از بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. دانش مالی تحلیل اوراق بهادار. 35(10):63-77.##3-     بدری، احمد، و علیرضا شواخی زواره (1390) نقاط مرجع، قیمت سهام و حجم معاملات: شواهدی از بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. فصلنامه بورس اوراق بهادار 3(12): 151-173.##4-     رضا زاده، الهه و فلاح‌شمس، میر فیض (1392) اثر تمایلی زیان گریزی سرمایه گذاران بر اساس حجم معاملاتIPO در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، دانش مالی تحلیل اوراق بهادار، 6 (1): 75-86##References##[1] Asness, C. S., Moskowitz, T. J. &amp; Pedersen. L. H. (2013). Value and momentum everywhere. The Journal of Finance, 68 (3), 929–985. https://doi.org/10.1111/jofi.12021.##[2] Atanasov. V., &amp; Nitschka, T. (2014). The size effect in value and momentum factors: Implications for the cross-section of international stock returns. Tinbergen Institute Discussion Paper 13-180/IV/DSF66. https://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ ssrn.2351711.##[3] Badri. A., &amp; Shavakhi, A. (2011). Reference points, stock price and trading volume: Evidences from Tehran Stock Exchange. Quarterly Journal of Securities Exchange, 12 (3), 151-173. (in Persian). http://journal.seo.ir/article_10909.html.##[4] Baker. M., Pan. X., &amp; Wurgler, J. (2012). The effect of reference point prices on mergers and acquisitions. Journal of Financial Economics, 106 (1): 49–71. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfineco.2012.04.010.##[5] Barroso. P., &amp; Santa-Clara, P. (2015). Momentum has its moments. Journal of Financial Economics, 116 (1), 111-120. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfineco.2014.11.010.##[6] Baucells. M., Weber. M., &amp; Welfens, F. (2011). Reference-point formation and updating. Management Science, 57 (3), 506–519. https://doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.1100.1286.##[7] Bhootra. A., &amp; Hur. J. (2013). The timing of 52-week high price and momentum. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, 37 (10), 3773-3782. https://doi.org/10.1016/ j.jbankfin.2013.05.025.##[8] Birru. J. (2015). Confusion of confusions: A test of the disposition effect and momentum. The Review of Financial Studies, 28 (7), 1849-1873. https://doi.org/10.1093/rfs/hhv007.##[9] Chaves. D (2012). Eureka! A momentum strategy that also works in Japan. SSRN Electronic Journal. https://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.1982100.##[10] Chen, A., &amp; Yang, W. (2016). Echo effects and the returns from 52-week high strategies. Finance Research Letters, 16 (1), 38-46. Doi: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.frl.2015.10.015.##[11] Chordia. T., &amp; Shivakumar. L. (2002). Momentum, business cycle and time-varying expected returns. The Journal of Finance, 57 (2), 985–1019. https://doi.org/10.1111/1540-6261.00449.##[12] Davallou. M., &amp; Javadian. J. (2017). The timing of 52-week high price momentum: Evidence from Tehran Stock Exchange. Financial Knowledge of Securities Analysis, 35 (10), 63-77. (in Persian). http://jfksa.srbiau.ac.ir/article_10664.html.##[13] Fallahpour. S., Sadi. R., &amp; Aboutorabi. G. (2013). The relationship between daily return of individual stocks and the highest price in last 52 weeks in Tehran Stock Exchange. Quarterly Journal of Securities Exchange, 22 (6), 73-101. (in Persian). http://journal.seo.ir/article_10999.html.##[14] Fama, E. (1995). Random walks in stock market prices. Financial Analysts Journal, 21 (5), 55-59. http://dx.doi.org/10.2469/faj.v51.n1.1861.##[15] Fama, E., &amp; French. K. (1996). Multifactor explanations of asset pricing anomalies. The Journal of Finance, 51 (1), 55–84. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-6261.1996.tb05202.##[16] Fama. E., &amp; Ferench. K. (2012). Size, value and momentum in international stock returns. Journal of Financial Economics, 106(3), 457-472. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfineco. 2012.05.011.##[17] Fama. E., &amp; MacBeth. D. (1973). Risk, return and equilibrium: Empirical tests. Journal of Political Economy, 81 (3), 607–636. https://doi.org/10.1086/260061.##[18] Frazzini. A. (2006). The disposition effect and underreaction to news. The Journal of Finance, 61 (4), 2017-2046. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-6261.2006. 00896.x.##[19] George, T., &amp; Hwang, C. (2004). The 52-week high and momentum investing. The Journal of Finance, 59 (5), 2145-2176. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-6261.2004. 00695.x.##[20] Gneezy, U. (2005). Updating the reference level: Experimental evidence. Experimental Business Research, 3 (1), 263-284. https://link.springer.com/chapter/ 10.1007/0-387-24244-9_12.##[21] Goyal. A., &amp; Wahal. S. (2015). Is momentum an echo?. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis, 50 (6), 1237–1267. https://doi.org/10.1017/ S0022109015 000575.##[22] Grinblatt, M., &amp; Han, B. (2004). Prospect theory, mental accounting and momentum. Journal of Financial Economics, 78 (2), 311–339. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfineco. 2004.10.006.##[23] Grinblatt, M., &amp; Keloharju, M. (2001). What makes investors trade?. Journal of Finance, 56 (2), 589–616. https://doi.org/10.1111/0022-1082.00338.##[24] Hao. Y., Hsiang-Hui. D., Keng-Yu. D., &amp; Kuan-Cheng. D. (2016). The 52-week high and momentum in the Taiwan stock market: Anchoring or recency biases?. International Review of Economics and Finance, 43 (3), 121–138. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.iref.2015.10.035.##[25] Hong, X., Jordan, B., &amp; Liu. M. (2015). Industry information and the 52-week high effect. Pacific-Basin Finance Journal, 32 (C), 111-130. https://doi.org/10.1016/ j.pacfin.2015.02.011.##[26] Jackson, A., &amp; Johnson, T. (2006). Unifying underreaction anomalies. Journal of Business, 79 (1), 75-114. https://doi.org/10.1086/497406.##[27] Jegadeesh, N. (1990). Evidence of predictable behavior of security returns. Journal of Finance, 45 (3), 881–898. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-6261.1990. tb05110.x.##[28] Jegadeesh, N., &amp; Titman, S. (1993). Returns to buying winners and selling losers: Implications for stock market efficiency. Journal of Finance, 48 (1), 65-91. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-6261.1993.tb04702.x.##[29] Jegadeesh N., &amp; Titman, S. (2001). Profitability of momentum strategies: An evaluation of alternative explanations. The Journal of Finance, 56 (2), 699–720. https://doi.org/10.1111/0022-1082.00342.##[30] Kahneman, D. (1992). Reference points, anchors, norms and mixed feelings. Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes, 51 (2), 296–312. https://doi.org/10.1016/0749-5978(92)90015-Y.##[31] Kahneman, D., &amp; Tversky, A. (1979). Prospect theory: An analysis of decision under risk. Econometrica, 47 (2), 263–292. http://dx.doi.org/10.2307/1914185.##[32] Li, J., &amp; Yu, J. (2012). Investor attention, psychological anchors and stock return predictability. Journal of Financial Economics, 104 (2), 401–419. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfineco.2011.04.003.##[33] Moskowitz, T. J., &amp; Grinblatt, M. (1999). Do industries explain momentum? The Journal of Finance, 54 (4), 1249-1290. https://doi.org/10.1111/0022-1082.00146.##[34] Newbold. P., Carlson. W., &amp; Thorne. B. (2013). Statistics for Business and Economics. London. Pearson Education.##[35] Newey. W., &amp; West. W. (1987). A simple, positive semi-definite, heteroskedasticity and autocorrelation consistent covariance matrix. Econometrica, 55 (3), 703-708. 10.2307/1913610.##[36] Novy-Marx. R. (2012). Is momentum really momentum? Journal of Financial Economics, 103 (3), 429-453. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfineco.2011.05.003.##[37] Rezazadeh, E., &amp; Falahshams, M. (2013). Trading volume impact of the loss aversion in Tehran Stock Exchange. Financial Knowledge of Securities Analysis, 17 (6), 75-83. (in Persian). http://jfksa.srbiau.ac.ir/article_2612.html.##[38] Sakr. A., Ragheb. M., Ragab. A., &amp; Abdou. R. (2014). Return anomalies disposition effect and momentum: Evidence from the Egyptian stock market. International Journal of Economics and Finance, 6 (2), 181-961. https://doi.org/10.5539/ijef.v6n2p181.##[39] Shefrin, H., &amp; Statman, M. (1985). The disposition to sell winners too early and ride losers too long: Theory and evidence. The Journal of Finance, 40 (3), 777–790. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-6261.1985.tb05002.x.##[40] Sinha. R. (2016). Underreaction to news in the US stock market. Quarterly Journal of Finance, 6 (2), 1-46. https://doi.org/10.1142/S2010139216500051.##[41] Wang. H., Yan. J., &amp; Yu. J. (2017). Reference-dependent preferences and the risk–return trade-off. Journal of Financial Economics, 123 (2), 395-414. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfineco.2016.09.010.##[42] www.tsetmc.com.##[43] www.codal.ir##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>نقش انضباطی بدهی‌ها، عدم تقارن اطلاعاتی و ارزش شرکت: رویکرد گشتاورهای تعمیم‌یافتۀ دومرحله‌ای</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Disciplining Role of Debts, Information Asymmetry, and Firm Value: 
Two-Step Generalized Methods of Moments</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: براساس نظریۀ سلسله‎‌مراتبی[1]، در شرایط عدم‌تقارن اطلاعاتی[2]، تأمین مالی ازطریق بدهی‌ها ممکن است هزینه‌های گزینش نامناسب را کاهش و ارزش شرکت را افزایش دهد و مانند ابزار انضباط مالی عمل کند. هدف این پژوهش، بررسی تأثیر نقش انضباطی نسبت اهرمی بر رابطۀ بین عدم‌تقارن اطلاعاتی و ارزش شرکت است.
روش: برای آزمون فرضیه‌های پژوهش، از داده‌های 148 شرکت پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران که با رویکرد حذف سیستماتیک گزینش شده‌اند، در بازۀ زمانی 1396-1386 استفاده شده است. برای کنترل اثر درون‌زایی احتمالی نسبت اهرمی که ممکن است ناشی از وجود رابطۀ علی معکوس از ارزش شرکت به نسبت اهرمی‌ باشد، الگو‌ها با رویکرد گشتاورهای تعمیم‌یافتۀ دومرحله‌ای برآورد شده‌اند.
نتایج: نتایج پژوهش نشان می‌دهد عدم‌تقارن اطلاعاتی و نسبت اهرمی، تأثیر منفی و معناداری بر ارزش شرکت دارند و نسبت اهرمی، رابطۀ منفی بین عدم‌تقارن اطلاعاتی و ارزش شرکت را تضعیف می‌‌کند. افزون بر آن، در شرکت‌هایِ دارای فرصت‌های رشد بالاتر (پایین‌تر)، تأثیر عدم‌تقارن اطلاعاتی بر ارزش شرکت، قوی‌تر (ضعیف‌تر) است. یافته‌های پژوهش با پیش‌بینی‌های مطرح در نظریۀ سلسله‌مراتبی سازگاری دارد.
نوآوری: در پژوهش‌های داخلی به تعامل بین عدم‌تقارن اطلاعاتی و نسبت اهرمی در اثرگذاری بر ارزش شرکت و مسئلۀ مهم تورش درون‌زایی حاصل از علیت معکوس از ارزش شرکت به نسبت اهرمی، توجه نشده است. در این پژوهش، علاوه بر لحاظ‌کردن دو مسئلۀ ذکرشده، شدت رابطۀ بین عدم‌تقارن اطلاعاتی و ارزش شرکت در شرکت‌های دارای فرصت‌های رشد بالا و پایین با هم مقایسه شده است.


[1]. Pecking order theory


[2]. Information asymmetry</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: According to the pecking order theory, in the context of information asymmetry, debt financing can decrease the adverse selection costs, increase the firm value, and serve as a financial disciplinary device. The main objective of this research is to investigate the effect of the disciplinary role of leverage on the relationship between information asymmetry and firm value.
Method: For hypotheses testing, this paper uses data for 148 firms listed in Tehran Stock Exchange that are selected, using systematic deletion, during 2007-2017. To control the potential endogeneity of leverage ratio which can create a reverse causality between firm value and leverage ratio, our models are estimated by using the two-step generalized method of moments (GMM) estimator.
Results: The results indicate that the information asymmetry and the leverage ratio have a negative and significant effect on the firm value, and the negative relationship between information asymmetry and firm value is weakened by leverage ratio. Besides, the results reveal that the negative effect of information asymmetry on the firm&#039;s value is stronger (weaker) for firms with higher (lower) growth opportunities. These findings are consistent with the predictions of the pecking order theory.
Innovations: Internal studies have not scrutinized the interaction between information asymmetry and leverage ratios in influencing firm value. Likewise, the issue of endogenous bias resulting from the inverse causality of leverage ratio has never been addressed. In this study, in addition to considering the above two issues, the intensity of the relationship between information asymmetry and firm value in companies with high and low growth opportunities is compared.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>105</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>122</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عباس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>افلاطونی</Family>
						<NameE>Abbas</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Aflatooni</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار حسابداری، گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم اقتصادی و اجتماعی، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، همدان، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار حسابداری، گروه حسابداری، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>a.aflatooni@basu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ارزش شرکت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عدم‌تقارن اطلاعاتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نسبت اهرمی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نظریۀ سلسله مراتبی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نقش انضباطی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] تقی‌زاده‌خانقاه، و.، و طالب‌نیاز، ق. (1397). تأثیر سررسید بدهی در خطر سقوط قیمت سهام با تأکید بر عدم‌تقارن اطلاعاتی. مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی، 6 (3)، 104-87.##[2] خدارحمی، ب.، فروغ‌نژاد، ح.، شریفی، م.، و طالبی، ع. (1395). تأثیر عدم تقارن اطلاعاتی بر ریسک سقوط آتی قیمت سهام شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی، 4 (3)، 58-39.##[3] رضایی، ف.، و پیری، ع. (1390). تأثیر ساختار مالکیت، ساختار سرمایه و نقدینگی بر ارزش بازار شرکت‌ها. پژوهش‌های حسابداری مالی و حسابرسی، 3 (11)، 174-155.##[4] ستایش، م.، غفاری، م.، و رستم‌زاده، ن. (1392). بررسی تأثیر عدم‌تقارن اطلاعاتی بر هزینه سرمایه. پژوهش‌های تجربی حسابداری، 2 (9)، 146-125.##[5] شمس، ش.، یحیی‌زاده‌فر، م.، و عباس‌زاده، س. (1396). بررسی رابطۀ بین اهرم مالی و عدم‌تقارن اطلاعاتی در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‎‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. تحقیقات حسابداری و حسابرسی، 9 (2)، 121-104.##[6] صدیقی، ر.، عالی‌فامیان، م.، و شاهوردی‌زاده، ش. (1396). رابطة بین عدم‌تقارن اطلاعاتی و ارزش شرکت با تأکید بر نقش اهرم مالی و فرصت‌های رشد. بررسی‌های حسابداری، 5 (1)، 96-81.##[7] فروغی، د.، و آدینه‌جونقانی، الف. (1391). رابطۀ بین میزان افشای اطلاعات و ارزش شرکت. پژوهش‌های حسابداری مالی و حسابرسی، 4 (15)، 142-117.##[8] قربانی، س.، و عدیلی، م. (1391). نگهداشت وجه نقد، ارزش شرکت و عدم‌تقارن اطلاعاتی. دانش حسابداری، 3 (8)، 131-149.##[9] کاشانی‌پور، م.، و مؤمنی‎یانسری، الف. (1391). بررسی نقش عدم‌تقارن اطلاعاتی در تصمیمات ساختار سرمایۀ شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. تحقیقات حسابداری و حسابرسی، 4 (14)، 22-1.##[10] کردستانی، غ.، و فدائی‌کلورزی، الف. (1391). بررسی رابطۀ بین عدم‌تقارن اطلاعاتی و ساختار سرمایه در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‎‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. پژوهش حسابداری، 2 (3)، 100-77.##[11] مقدم، ع.، حلاج، م.، و شریفی، الف. (1394). تأثیر عدم‌ تقارن اطلاعاتی بر رابطۀ کیفیت سود و هزینۀ سهام عادی: بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. پژوهش‌های حسابداری مالی، 7 (4)، 72-57.##[12] هاشمی، ع.، و اخلاقی، ح. (1389). تأثیر اهرم مالی، سیاست تقسیم سود و سودآوری بر ارزش آتی شرکت. فصلنامۀ حسابداری مالی، 2 (6)،##[13] Agarwal, P., &amp; O&#039;Hara, M. (2007). Information risk and capital structure.‏ https://ssrn.com/abstract=939663.##[14] Bharath, S. T., Pasquariello, P., &amp; Wu, G. (2008). Does asymmetric information drive capital structure decisions? The Review of Financial Studies, 22 (8), 3211-3243.‏ https://doi.org/10.1093/rfs/hhn076.##[15] Botosan, C. A. (1997). Disclosure level and the cost of equity capital. The Accounting Review, 72 (3), 323-349.‏##[16] Danso, A., &amp; Adomako, S. (2014). The financing behaviour of firms and financial crisis. Managerial Finance, 40 (12), 1159-1174.‏ https://doi.org/10.1108/MF-04-2014-0098.##[17] Dierkens, N. (1991). Information asymmetry and equity issues. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis, 26 (2), 181-199.‏ https://doi.org/10.2307/ 2331264.##[18] Drobetz, W., Grüninger, M. C., &amp; Hirschvogl, S. (2010). Information asymmetry and the value of cash. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, 34 (9), 2168-2184.‏ https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jbankfin.2010.02.002.##[19] Foroghi, D., &amp; Adineh Jounaghani, A. (2012). The relationship between firm value and rate of information disclosure. Financial Accounting and Auditing Researches, 4 (15), 117-142. (In Persian).##[20] Fosu, S., Danso, A., Ahmad, W., &amp; Coffie, W. (2016). Information asymmetry, leverage and firm value: Do crisis and growth matter? International Review of Financial Analysis, 46, 140-150.‏ https://doi.org/10.1016/j.irfa.2016.05.002.##[21] Gao, W., &amp; Zhu, F. (2015). Information asymmetry and capital structure around the world. Pacific-Basin Finance Journal, 32, 131-159.‏ https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pacfin. 2015.01.005.##[22] Ghorbani, S., &amp; Adili, M. (2012). Firm value, cash holdings and information asymmetry. Accounting Knowledge, 3 (8), 131-149. (In Persian).##[23] Grossman, S. J., &amp; Hart, O. D. (1982). Corporate financial structure and managerial incentives. Working Paper No. R0398. National Bureau of Economic Research.##[24] Hashemi, S. A., &amp; Akhlaghi, H. (2010). The effect financial leverage, dividend policy and profitability in the future value of firm. Quarterly Financial Accounting, 2 (6), 38-49. (In Persian).##[25] He, W. P., Lepone, A., &amp; Leung, H. (2013). Information asymmetry and the cost of equity capital. International Review of Economics &amp; Finance, 27, 611-620.‏ https://doi.org/10.1016/j.iref.2013.03.001.##[26] Jensen, M. C. (1986). Agency costs of free cash flow, corporate finance and takeovers. The American Economic Review, 76 (2), 323-329.‏##[27] Kashanipour, M., &amp; Momeni Yansari, A. (2012). Investigating the role of information asymmetry in capital structure decisions on firms listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. Accounting and Auditing Research, 4 (14), 1-22. (In Persian).##[28] Khodarahmi, B., Foroughnejad, H., Sharifi, M., &amp; Talebi, A. (2016). The impact of information asymmetry on the future stock price crash risk of listed companies in the Tehran Stock Exchange. Asset Management and Financing, 4 (3), 39-58. (In Persian).##[29] Kordestani, G. R., &amp; Fadaei Kalvarzi, E. (2012). Investigating the relationship between information asymmetry and capital structure in firms listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Accounting Research, 2 (3), 77-100. (In Persian).##[30] Krishnaswami, S., &amp; Subramaniam, V. (1999). Information asymmetry, valuation and the corporate spin-off decision. Journal of Financial Economics, 53 (1), 73-112.‏ https://doi.org/10.1016/S0304-405X (99) 00017-3.##[31] Krishnaswami, S., Spindt, P. A., &amp; Subramaniam, V. (1999). Information asymmetry, monitoring, and the placement structure of corporate debt. Journal of Financial Economics, 51 (3), 407-434.‏ https://doi.org/10.1016/S0304-405X (98) 00059-2.##[32] Kutner, M. H., Nachtsheim, C., &amp; Neter, J. (2004). Applied Linear Regression Models. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin.##[33] Leary, M. T., &amp; Roberts, M. R. (2010). The pecking order, debt capacity and information asymmetry. Journal of Financial Economics, 95 (3): 332-355.‏ https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfineco.2009.10.009.##[34] Lu, C. W., Chen, T. K., &amp; Liao, H. H. (2010). Information uncertainty, information asymmetry and corporate bond yield spreads. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, 34 (9), 2265-2279.‏ https://doi.org/ 10.1016/j.jbankfin.2010.02.013.##[35] Maury, B., &amp; Pajuste, A. (2005). Multiple large shareholders and firm value. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, 29 (7), 1813-1834.‏ https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jbankfin.2004.07.002.##[36] Moghaddam, A., Hallaj, M., &amp; Sharifi, A. (2016). Direct and mediated associations among earnings quality, information asymmetry and the cost of common equity of companies in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Financial Accounting Research, 7 (4), 57-72. (In Persian).##[37] Morgan, T., Anokhin, S., &amp; Wincent, J. (2018). When the fog dissipates: The choice between value creation and value appropriation in a partner as a function of information asymmetry. Journal of Business Research, 88, 498-504.‏ https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jbusres.2017.11.032.##[38] Myers, S. C. (1984). The capital structure puzzle. The Journal of Finance, 39 (3), 574-592.‏ https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-6261.1984.tb03646.x.##[39] Myers, S. C. (2001). Capital structure. Journal of Economic perspectives, 15(2), 81-102.‏ https://doi.org/10.1257/jep.15.2.81.##[40] Myers, S. C., &amp; Majluf, N. S. (1984). Corporate financing and investment decisions when firms have information that investors do not have. Journal of Financial Economics, 13 (2), 187-221.‏ https://doi.org/10.1016/0304-405X(84) 90023-0.##[41] Nagano, M. (2017). Sukuk issuance and information asymmetry: Why do firms issue sukuk? Pacific-Basin Finance Journal, 42, 142-157.‏ https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pacfin.2016.12.005.##[42] Opler, T. C., &amp; Titman, S. (1994). Financial distress and corporate performance. The Journal of Finance, 49 (3), 1015-1040.‏ https://doi.org/10.2307/ 2329214.##[43] Petacchi, R. (2015). Information asymmetry and capital structure: Evidence from regulation FD. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 59(2-3), 143-162.‏ https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacceco.2015.01.002.##[44] Rezaei, F., &amp; Piri, A. (2011). The influence of ownership structure, capital structure and cash holding on firm’s market value. Financial Accounting and Auditing Researches, 3 (11), 155-174. (InPersian).##[45] Ross, S. A. (1977). The determination of financial structure: The incentive-signalling approach. The Bell Journal of Economics, 8(1), 23-40. https://doi.org/10.2307/ 3003485‏.##[46] Ryen, G. T., Vasconcellos, G. M., &amp; Kish, R. J. (1997). Capital structure decisions: What have we learned?. Business Horizons, 40 (5), 41-51.‏ https://doi.org/10.1016/S0007-6813 (97) 90085-9.##[47] Saam, N. J. (2007). Asymmetry in information versus asymmetry in power: Implicit assumptions of agency theory? The Journal of Socio-Economics, 36 (6), 825-840.‏##[48] Seddighi, R., Alifamian, M., Shahverdyzadeh, S. (2018). The relationship between information asymmetry and firm value: the role of financial leverage and growth opportunities. Journal of Iranian Accounting Review, 5 (17), 81-96.##[49] Setayesh, M., Ghaffari, M., &amp; Rostam Zade, N. (2013). Investigating the impact of information asymmetry on cost of capital. Empirical Research in Accounting, 2 (4), 125-146. (In Persian).##[50] Shams, S., Yahyazadefar, M., &amp; Abbaszade, S. (2017). Investigating the relationship between financial leverage and information asymmetry in firm listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. Accounting and Auditing Research, 9(2), 104-121. (In Persian).##[51] Shen, C. H. H. (2014). Pecking order, access to public debt market and information asymmetry. International Review of Economics &amp; Finance, 29,##291-306.‏ https://doi.org/10.1016/ j.iref. 2013.06.002.##[52] Taghizadeh Khanqah, V., &amp; Talebniaz, G. (2018). The impact of debt maturity on stock price crash risk with an emphasis on information asymmetry. Asset Management and Financing, 6 (3), 87-104. (In Persian).##[53] Tang, T. T. (2009). Information asymmetry and firms’ credit market access: Evidence from Moody&#039;s credit rating format refinement. Journal of Financial Economics, 93 (2), 325-351.‏ https://doi.org/ 10.1016/j.jfineco.2008.07.007.##[54] Venkatesh, P. C., &amp; Chiang, R. (1986). Information asymmetry and the dealer’s bid-ask spread: A case study of earnings and dividend announcements. The Journal of Finance, 41 (5), 1089-1102. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-6261.1986.tb02532.x.##[55] WWW. Codal.ir.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی الگوی جریان اطلاعاتی قیمت سهام مبتنی بر نقش انگیزۀ شهرت مدیران؛ شواهدی از شرکت‌‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A Study on Stock Price Informativeness Model based on the Role of Managers’ Reputation Motivation (Evidence from the Companies Listedin Tehran Stock Exchange)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>اهداف: افشای اطلاعات به‌وسیلۀ شرکت‌‌ها، از ابزارهای مهم مدیران برای انتقال اطلاعات مربوط به عملکرد مالی به سرمایه‌گذاران، اعتباردهندگان و سایر افراد ذینفع و از دلایل مهم تقاضا برای جریان اطلاعاتی قیمت سهام، مسائل نمایندگی و عدم‌تقارن اطلاعات است. عوامل متعددی ازجمله انگیزۀ شهرت مدیران، بر شفافیت و غنای اطلاعاتی قیمت سهام مؤثر است؛ زیرا تلاش بالقوه برای به ‌‌تصویر کشیدن مطلوبیت عملکرد در جهت اهدافی همچون اعتباربخشی و اعتمادسازی برقرار است. روش: در همین راستا، هدف این پژوهش تبیین تأثیر انگیزۀ شهرت مدیران بر غنای اطلاعاتی قیمت سهام است. برای رسیدن به این اهداف داده‌های 910 سال - شرکت (130 شرکت برای 7 سال) جمع‌‌آوری‌شده از گزارش‌های مالی سالیانۀ شرکت‌‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در طی دورۀ زمانی 1390 تا 1396 آزمون شده است. نتایج: یافته‌‌های پژوهش نشان می‌‌دهد بین انگیزۀ شهرت مدیران و غنای اطلاعاتی قیمت سهام، ارتباط معنی‌دار و مثبتی وجود دارد و اندازۀ شرکت و اهرم مالی بر غنای اطلاعاتی قیمت سهام تأثیر مثبت و معناداری ندارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objectives: Informativeness by companies is of great importance for managers to transfer information about financial performance to investors, creditors and other stakeholders, and is one of the significant reasons for requesting information on stock prices, informativeness issues, and information asymmetry. Several factors affect the transparency and informativeness of stock prices – including managers’ reputation motivation– which results from their potential effort to display the benefit of operation in terms of goals such as credibility and trust-building. Method: Thus, the purpose of this study is to explain the effect of managers&#039; reputation motivation on stock price disclosure. To do so, the evidence of 910 firm-year (130 companies for 7 years), collected from annual financial reports of companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange from 2011 to 2017, was tested. Results: Research findings show a significant relationship between the managers&#039; reputation motivation and stock price disclosure. Further, the size of the company has a positive and significant impact on stock price disclosure.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>123</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>136</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مجید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>منتشری</Family>
						<NameE>Majid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Montashery</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مهندسی مالی دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه یزد، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مهندسی مالی دانشکده مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>montashery@stu.yazd.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>داریوش</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فرید</Family>
						<NameE>Daryush</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Farid</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه حسابداری و مالی، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه یزد، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه حسابداری و مالی، دانشکده مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>fareed@yazd.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>انگیزۀ شهرت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>غنای اطلاعاتی قیمت سهام</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شفافیت اطلاعات</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] افلاطونی، ع. (1393). تجزیه و تحلیل آماری با Eviews در تحقیقات حسابداری و مدیریت مالی. تهران: ترمه.##[2] بشیرخداپرستی، ر.، صبا، م.، و برومندزاده، ح. (1397). کارآیی مدل پنج‌عاملی فاما و فرنچ در سهام تهاجمی و تدافعی. راهبرد مدیریت مالی،##6 (4)، 109-130.##References##[3] Adams, R., &amp; Ferreira, D. (2008). Do directors perform for pay? Journal of Accounting and Economics, 46, 154-171. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacceco.2008.06.002.##[4] Adams, R. B., &amp; Ragunathan, V. (2015). Lehman sisters (Unpublished Working Paper).Available at: SSRN3046451. http://www.fmaconferences.org/Orlando/Papers/AdamsRagunathan.pdf##[5] Aflatooni, A. (2015). Statistical Analysis with Eviews in Accounting and Finance Research. Tehran: Terme. (In Persian).##[6] Akbas, F., Meschke, F., &amp; Wintoki, M. B. (2016). Director networks and informed traders. Journal of Financial Economics, 62, 1–23. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacceco. 2016.03.003.##[7] Armstrong, C. S., Balakrishnan, K., &amp; Cohen, D. (2012). Corporate governance and the information environment: Evidence from state antitakeover laws. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 53 (1-2), 185-204. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacceco. 2011.06.005.##[8] Armstrong, C. S., Core, J. E., &amp; Guay, W. R. (2014). Do independent directors cause improvements in firm transparency? Journal of Financial Economics, 113 (3), 383-403. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfineco. 2014.05.009.##[9] Bashir Khodaparast, R., Saba, M., &amp; Boroumandzadeh, H. (2019). Performance of Fama and French five-factor model in offensive and defensive stocks. Financial Management Strategy, 6 (4), 109-130.##[10] Beekes, W., Pope, P., &amp; Young, S. (2004). The link between earnings timeliness, earnings conservatism and board composition: Evidence from the UK. Corporate Governance: An International Review, 12 (1), 47-59. https://doi.org/ 10.1111/j.1467-8683.2004.00342.x.##[11] Ben-Nasr, H., &amp; Cosset, J. C. (2014). State ownership, political institutions and stock price in formativeness: Evidence from privatization. Journal of Corporate Finance, 29, 179-199. https://doi.org/ 10.1016/j.jcorpfin.2014.10.004.##[12] Chen, X., Cheng, Q., &amp; Wang, X. (2015). Does increased board independence reduce earnings management? Evidence from recent regulatory reforms. Review of Accounting Studies, 20 (2), 899-933. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11142-015-9316-0Chen, Q., Goldstein, I., &amp; Jiang, W. (2006). Price in formativeness and investment sensitivity to stock price. The Review of Financial Studies, 20 (3), 619-650. https://doi.org/10.1093/rfs/hhl024.##[13] Du, J., Hou, Q., Tang, X., &amp; Yao, Y. (2018). Does independent directors’ monitoring affect reputation? Evidence from the stock and labor markets. China Journal of Accounting Research, 11 (2), 91-127. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjar.2018. 01.002.##[14] Fahlenbrach, R., Low, A., &amp; Stulz, R. M. (2010). Why do firms appoint CEOs as outside directors? Journal of Financial Economics, 97(1), 12-32. https://doi.org/ 10.1016/j.jfineco.2010.01.003.##[15] Fahlenbrach, R., Low, A., &amp; Stulz, R. M. (2017). Do independent director departures predict future bad events? Review of Financial Studies, 30, 2313–2358. https://doi.org/10.1093/rfs/hhx009.##[16] Fama, E. F. (1980). Agency problems and the theory of the firm. Journal of Political Economy, 88(2), 288-307. https://doi.org/ 10.1086/260866.##[17] Fama, E. F., &amp; French, K. R. (2015). A five-factor asset pricing model. Journal of Financial Economics, 116 (1), 1-22. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfineco.2014.10.010.##[18] Fama, E. F., &amp; Jensen, M. C. (1983). Agency problems and residual claims. The Journal of Law and Economics, 26(2), 327-349. https://doi.org/10.1086/467038.##[19] Ferreira, D., Ferreira, M. A., &amp; Raposo, C. C. (2011). Board structure and price in formativeness. Journal of Financial Economics, 99, 523–545. https://doi.org/ 10.1016/j.jfineco.2010.10.007.##[20] Ferreira, M. A., &amp; Laux, P. A. (2007). Corporate governance, idiosyncratic risk and information flow. The Journal of Finance, 62 (2), 951-989. https://doi.org/ 10.1111/j.1540-6261.2007.01228.x.##[21] Gul, F. A., Srinidhi, B., &amp; Ng, A. C. (2011). Does board gender diversity improve the in formativeness of stock prices? Journal of Accounting and Economics, 51 (3), 314-338. https://doi.org/ 10.1016/j.jacceco.2011.01.005.##[22] Hutton, A. P., Marcus, A. J., &amp; Tehranian, H. (2009). Opaque financial reports, R2 and crash risk. Journal of Financial Economics, 94 (1), 67-86. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfineco.2008.10.003.##[23] Hwang, B-H., &amp; Kim, S. (2009). It Pays to Have Friends. Journal of Financial Economics, 93, 138–158. https://doi.org/ 10.1016/j.jfineco.2008.07.005.##[24] Jiang, W., Wan, H., &amp; Zhao, S. (2016). Reputation concerns of independent directors: Evidence from individual director voting. Review of Financial Studies, Stud, 29 (3), 655–696. https://doi.org/ 10.1093/rfs/hhv125.##[25] Jin, L., &amp; Myers, S. C. (2006). R2 around the world: New theory and new tests. Journal of Financial Economics, 79, 257–292. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfineco. 2004.11.003.##[26] Kim, J. B., Li, Y., &amp; Zhang, L. (2011). Corporate tax avoidance and stock price crash risk: Firm-level analysis. Journal of Financial Economics, 100(3), 639-662. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfineco.2010.07.007.##[27] Knyazeva, A., Knyazeva, D., &amp; Masulis, R. W. (2013). The supply of corporate directors and board independence. The Review of Financial Studies, 26(6), 1561-1605. https://doi.org/10.1093/rfs/hht020.##[28] Lang, M., Lins, K. V., &amp; Maffett, M. (2012). Transparency, liquidity and valuation: International evidence on when transparency matters most. Journal of Accounting Research, 50 (3), 729-774. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1475-679X.2012. 00442.x.##[29] Lee, Y. C., &amp; Wang, M. C. (2017). How does corporate control affect the appointment, auditing expertise and reputation of independent directors? Evidence from Taiwan. The Quarterly Review of Economics and Finance, 64, 130-140. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.qref.2016.06.010.##[30] Leuz, C., &amp; Wysocki, P. D. (2016). The economics of disclosure and financial reporting regulation: Evidence and suggestions for future research. Journal of Accounting Research, 54 (2), 525-622. https://doi.org/10.1111/1475-679X.12115.##[31] Masulis, R. W., &amp; Mobbs, S. (2014). Independent director incentives: Where do talented directors spend their limited time and energy? Journal of Financial Economics, 111 (2), 406-429. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfineco.2013.10.011.##[32] Masulis, R.W., Wang, C., &amp; Xie, F. (2012). Globalizing the boardroom – the effect of foreign directors on corporate governance and firm performance. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 53, 527–554. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacceco.2011.12.003.##[33] Ota, K., Kawase, H., &amp; Lau, D. (2019). Does reputation matter? Evidence from share repurchases. Journal of Corporate Finance, 58, 287-306. https://doi.org/ 10.1016/j.jcorpfin.2019.05.006.##[34] Roll, R. (1988). R2. The Journal of Finance. 43, 541–566. https://doi.org/ 10.1111/j.1540-6261.1988.tb04591.x.##[35] Ryan, J. R. H. E., &amp; Wiggins III, R. A. (2004). Who is in whose pocket? Director compensation, board independence and barriers to effective monitoring. Journal of Financial Economics, 73 (3), 497-524. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfineco.2003.11.002.##[36] Shivdasani, A. (1993). Board composition, ownership structure and hostile takeovers. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 16 (1-3), 167-198. https://doi.org/10.1016/0165-4101(93) 90009-5.##[37] Sila, V., Gonzalez, A., &amp; Hagendorff, J. (2017). Independent director reputation incentives and stock price in formativeness. Journal of Corporate Finance, 47, 219-235. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcorpfin. 2017.09.018.##[38] Umutlu, M. (2019). Does idiosyncratic volatility matter at the global level? The North American Journal of Economics and Finance, 47, 252.268. https://doi.org/ 10.1016/j.najef.2018.12.015.##[39] Wang, L. (2015). Protection or expropriation: Politically connected independent directors in China. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, 55, 92-106. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jbankfin.2015.02.015.##[40] WWW. Tse.ir/archive##[41] WWW. Codal.ir##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				