<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1396</YEAR>
<VOL>5</VOL>
<NO>3</NO>
<MOSALSAL>18</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>0</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تبیین مدل ورشکستی جهت شناسایی بانک‌های سالم و در معرض خطر</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Explaining the Model of Bankruptcy Prediction to Identify Healthy and Risky</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>ورشکستگی بانک‌ها پدیده‌ای است که اخیراً بانک مرکزی، بانک‌ها و مؤسسات مالی و اعتباری به آن توجه کرده‌اند. از آنجایی‌که نشانه‌های بالقوۀ ورشکستگی قبل از وقوع ورشکستگی نمایان می‌شود؛ شناسایی متغیرهای هشدار و پیش‌بینی به‌موقع و صحیح این بحران، فرصتی را در اختیار مدیران و اعتباردهندگان برای انجام فعالیت‌های بازدارنده قرار می‌دهد. در این مقاله تلاش می‌شود با استفاده از صورت‌های مالی بانک‌های کشور در دورۀ زمانی 1385-1393 و به‌کارگیری شاخص ثبات بانکی به‌عنوان شاخص‌ ورشکستگی، بانک‌های ورشکسته شناسایی شوند. برای شناسایی بانک‌های ورشکسته، تابع کرنل این شاخص، ترسیم و نقطۀ استرس آن محاسبه شد، به‌گونه‌ای‌که بانک‌هایی که کمتر از نقطۀ استرس قرار دارند، ورشکسته و در  غیر این صورت سالم در نظر گرفته شدند. برای برآورد الگو، ابتدا با به‌کارگیری روش تجزیه تشخیص، عواملی که بانک‌های سالم و در معرض خطر را می‌توانند بشناسند، شناسایی و سپس با به‌کارگیری الگوی لاجیت، الگوی مناسب برای پیش‌بینی ورشکستگی بانک‌ها طراحی شد. برای بررسی صحت تفکیک دو نمونۀ سالم و ورشکسته با استفاده از آزمون F و لامبدای ویلکس، میانگین متغیرهای مستقل دو نمونه بررسی و سپس برای بررسی تفاوت اهمیت متغیرهای مستقل الگو از آزمون بزرگی همبستگی درون‌گروهی بین متغیرها استفاده شد. نتایج نشان‌دهندۀ دقت 87 درصدی الگوی تجزیه تشخیص و 2/98 درصدی الگو لاجیت در انطباق با شرایط محیطی شبکۀ بانکی کشور است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Bank failure is a phenomenon that has attracted the attention of the central bank, banks and financial institutions. Since the signs of potential failure are detected before the bankruptcy, identifying warning variables, and prediction of the crisis timely provide an opportunity for managers and creditors to create preventive activities. In this paper, using the financial statements in the period 1385-1393 and Z-score index as an indicator of bankruptcy, bank failures are detected. To identify the failed banks, we use the kernel function of the index and the stress of index is calculated. Banks that are under stress point are considered risky and otherwise healthy. For estimate of model, discriminate analysis was used to identify the factors that enable to distinguish healthy and risky banks, then, using the logit model, a model was developed for predicting banks failure. To verify separation of two groups of banks we checked Wilks Lambda, F and two independent samples mean, then to evaluate the importance of the different independent variables in a model we used intercorrelation between variables. The results showed 87 percent accuracy of discriminant analysis and 98.2 percent logit model in compliance with the Iran`s banking network environment.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>18</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>اعظم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>احمدیان</Family>
						<NameE>azam</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>ahmadyan</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه بانکداری ، پژوهشکده پولی و بانکی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه بانکداری ، پژوهشکده پولی و</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>azam_ahmadyan@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهسا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>گرجی</Family>
						<NameE>mahsa</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>gorji</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مهندسی مالی،گروه مهندسی صنایع، دانشکده مهندسی صنایع، دانشگاه رجاء، قزوین، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مهندسی مالی،گروه مهندسی صنایع،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.gorji@hotmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نسبت‌های مالی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ورشکستگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تجزیه تشخیص</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>لاجیت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Abiola A, B., Felicia O, O. and Folasade B. A. (2015). Predicting bank failure in Nigeria using survival analysis approach. Journal of South African Business Research, 2:17. Article ID 965940.  ##[2]Altman E. L. (1968). Financail ratios, disarmament analysis and the prediction of corporate bankruptcy.The Journal of Finance.23(4): 598- 609.##[3]Altman, E., R. Haldeman, and P. Narayanan. (1977). Zeta analysis: A new model to identify bankruptcy risk of corporations. Journal of banking and Finance. June, 1977.##[4]Asif, K. M., Akhtar, W., Ullah, A. I., Z. &amp; Risat, I. (2013). Islamic banking: An appraisal of insolvency hazard. International Journal of Academic Research in Accounting, finance and management sciences, 3(4): 1-10.##[5]Beaver W. H. (1966). Financial ratios as predictors of failure. Journal of Accounting Research .4:71-111.##[6]Bussiere, M. and Fratzscher, M. (2006). Towards a new early warning system of financial crises. Journal of International Money and Finance.25: 953–973.##[7]Frankel, J. A. and G. Saravelos. (2010). Are leading indicators of financial crisis useful for assessing country vulnerability? Evidence from the 2008–09 global crisis. NBER Working Paper No. 16047.##[8]Frankel, J. A. and A. K. Rose. (1996). Currency crashes in emerging markets: An empirical treatment. Journal of International Economics. 41(3–4): 351–366.##[9]Fulmer, John G. Jr., Moon, James E., Gavin, Thomas A., Erwin, Michael J. (1984). A bankruptcy classification model for small firms. Journal of Commercial Bank Lending, 25-37.##[10]Gaytán, A; Johnson, C. A. (2002). A review of the literature on early warning systems for banking crises. Central Bank of Chile Working Paper. No. 183, Santiago, October2002.##[11]Ghodrati, H; Maanavi Moghadam, A. h. (1389). The accuracy of models predicting bankruptcy in Tehran Stock Exchange, Accounting Research, Autumn 1389, No.7.##[12]Horrigan, J. o. (1968). A short history of financial ratio analysis. The Accounting Review, 284-294.##[13] Ivicic, L; Kunovac, D; Lijubaj, I. (2008). Measuring bank insolvency risk in CEE countries. The Fourteenth Dubrovnik Economic Conference. Organized by Croatian National Bank.##[14]Kaminsky, G. L. and C. M. Reinhart. (1996). The Twin crises: The causes of banking and balance of payments problems. Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, International Finance Discussion Papers.544.##[15] Komeijani, A. (2015). The role of banking system in Iranian Economy. Role of public relations in the banking industry, Conference in Central Bank of Iran. (In Persian).##[16] Lepetit, L; Strobel, F. (2015). Bank insolvency risk and Z_Score measures: A refinement. Finance Reaearch Letters. 13:214-224.##[17]Li, X. Escalante, C. L. Epperson, J. E. (2014). Agricultural banking and bank failures of the late 2000s financial crisis: A survival analysis using Cox Proportional Hazard model. Southern Agricultural Economics Association (SAEA) Annual Meeting, Dallas, Texas, 1-4 February 2014##[18]Mayes, David G. &amp; Hanno, S. (2014).The effectiveness of capital adequacy measures in predicting bank distress. Vienna: SUERF - The Europe. Money and Finance Forum [u.a.].SUERF studies ; 2014, 1.##[19]Samad, A. (2012). Credit risk determinants of bank failure: Evidence from US bank failure.International Business Research. 5(9).##[20]Shumway, T. (2001). Forcasting bankruptcy more accurately: A simple hazard model.The Journal of Business, 74(1): 101-124.##[21]Tatom, J. (2012).Predicting failure in the commercial bank industry. Munchin Personal RePEc Archive, MPRA Paper No.34608.##[22]Zaghdoudi, T. (2013).Bank failure prediction with logistic regression. International Journal of Economics and Financial Issues. 3(2):537-543.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی پیامدهای سیاست سود تقسیمی رو به رشد در شرایط محدودیت مالی و موقعیت رقابتی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Increasing Dividend Policy Outcomes in Terms of Financial Constraints and Competition</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف پژوهش حاضر، بررسی پیامدهای سیاست افزایش سود تقسیمی در شرایط محدودیت مالی و با توجه به موقعیت رقابتی شرکت‌ها است. نمونۀ آماری پژوهش شامل 145 شرکت است که در دورۀ زمانی 1389 تا 1393 از بین شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران انتخاب و آزمون فرضیه‌ها نیز به کمک داده‌های تلفیقی و روش حداقل مربعات تعمیم‌یافته و روش گشتاورهای تعمیم‌یافته انجام شده است. یافته‌های پژوهش نشان می دهد واکنش بازار سرمایه (شامل بازده غیرعادی و گردش معاملات) به افزایش سود تقسیمی در شرکت‌هایی با محدودیت مالی نسبت به شرکت‌های بدون محدودیت مالی، ضعیف تر است. همچنین کاهش تمرکز و درنتیجه، افزایش رقابت در فروش محصولات در شرکت هایی با محدودیت مالی، باعث تضعیف بیشتر واکنش بازار به خبر افزایش سود تقسیمی می شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The main purpose of this study is to investigate the consequences of the growing dividend policy in terms of financial constraints and conpetition. The investigation covers five years 2010-2014 and the sample consists of 145 listed companies in Tehran’s Stock Exchange. The dynamic analysis is conducted using a combination of the GMM approach and instrumental variables to check for endogeneity in variables. According to the results, the reaction of the capital market and stock turnover of companies after increasing dividend in firms with financial constraints, compared with firms without financial constraints, is weaker. This is especially the case for constrained firms that are in more competitive industries.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>19</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>34</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مشکی میاوقی</Family>
						<NameE>mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>meshki miavaghi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار مالی، گروه حسابداری، دانشگاه پیام نور، رشت، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار مالی، گروه حسابداری، دانشگاه پیام</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mhd.meshki@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فاطمه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صرفه جو</Family>
						<NameE>fatemeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>sarfehjoo</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد، حسابداری ، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی- واحد رشت</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد، حسابداری ، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی-</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>farzanehsarfehjoo19@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تقسیم سود</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رقابت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>محدودیت در تأمین مالی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>واکنش بازار سرمایه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF> [1] Aharony, J., Swary, I. (1980). Quarterly dividend and earnings announcements and stockholders returns: An empirical analysis. Journal of Finance, 35: 1–12.## [2] Almeida, H., Campello, M., Weisbach, M. S. (2007). The cash flow sensitivity of cash, Journal of Finance, 59(4): 1777–1804.##[3] Anvary Rostamy, A., Etemadi, H., Movahed, M. (2013). Investigation of the Impact of Product Market Competition on Dividend Policies. Journal of Asset management and financing, 1 (2): 1-18##[4] Aydin, A., A, Cavdar, S. C. (2015). Corporate governance and dividend policy: An empirical analysis from Borsa Istanbul Corporate Governance Index. Journal of Asset Accounting and Finance Research, 4 (3): 66-76.##[5] Badavar nahandi, Y., Darkhor, S. (2014). The Relationships Among Financial Constraint, Cash Value and Net Investment in Firms Listed, Journal of Empirical Research in Accounting, 2(8): 167-189.## [6] Campello, M., (2003). Capital structure and product markets interactions: evidence from business cycles. Journal of Financial Economics, 68: 353–378.##[7] Chen, S., Wang, Y. (2012). Financial constraints and share repurchases. Journal of Financial Economics, 105(2): 311-331.##[8]        Datta, Sudip, Mai Iskandar-Datta, Vivek Singh (2013). Product market power, industry structure and corporate earnings management. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance. Http://dx.doi.org /10.1016/ j.jbankfin.03.01.## [9] Fosu. S. (2013). Capital structure, product market competition and firm performance: Evidence from South Africa. The Quarterly Review of Economics and Finance. Electronic copy available at: http://www .sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1062976913000197.##[10] Giroud.X and Mueller.H. (2011). Corporate governance, product market competition, and equity prices. The Journal of Finance. Vol. Lxvi, No. 2.##[11] Jahankhani, A., Ghorbani, S. (2006). Identifying and understanding the determinants of dividend policy, Journal of Financial Reseach, 7(2): 27-48.##[12] Jensen, M. C. (1986). Agency costs of free cash flow, Corporate Financial and Takeovers,  AEA Papers and Proceedings, 76 (2): 323-329.##[13] Kim. T. N. (2011). The Impact of corporate cash holdings and dynamic financial constraints on investment-cash flow sensitivity. Electronic copy availableat: http:// ssrn.com/abstract = 1743142.##[14] Masters, N., Faff, R., Pathan, S. (2015). Financial constraints and dividend policy, Electronic copy available at: http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=228696.##[15] Meshki, M., Asi, R. M. (2012). An investigation of Relationship between Management Forecast Error with Abnormal rate of return and systematic risk at Tehran Stock Exchange, Journal of Accounting and Auditing, 66: 53-68.##[16] Michaely, Roni; Roberts, Michael R. (2012). Corporate dividend policies: Lessons from private firms. Review of Financial Studies, 25(3):  711-746.##[17] Myers, S.C. and Majluf, N.S. (1984). Corporate financing and investment decisions when firms have information that investors do not have, Journal of Financial Economics, 12 (3): 187-221.##[18] Rozeff, M. S. (1982). Growth, beta and agency costs as determinants of dividend payout ratios, Journal of Financial Research, 5 (3): 249-259.##[19] Stephens, C., Weisbach, M. (1998). Actual share reacquisitions in open- market repurchase programs. Journal of Finance, 53, 313–333.##[20] Watts, R. L., Zimmerman, J. L. (1986). Positive Accounting Theory, Prentice-Hall.##[21] Whited, T., Wu, G. (2006). Financial constraints risk. Review of Financial Studies, 19: 531-559.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی ثبات ساختار سرمایه در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Capital Structure Stability in Tehran Stock Exchange</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>ثبات ساختار سرمایه بدین معنی است که شرکت‌ها موقعیت فعلی اهرم خود را نسبت به سایر شرکت‌ها (اهرم بالاتر یا پایین‌تر) در طول زمان حفظ می‌کنند. میزان این ثبات با ارزیابی قدرت توضیحی اهرم هر دوره برای اهرم دوره‌های آینده اندازه‌گیری می‌شود. پژوهش حاضر با استفاده از اطلاعات 113 شرکت برای دورۀ زمانی 1379 تا 1392 میزان ثبات ساختار سرمایه را در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران بررسی کرده  است؛ سپس با استفاده از روش‌های شبیه‌سازی، سه الگوی اصلی را ارزیابی کرده که در مبانی نظری موضوع برای تبیین رفتار اهرم معرفی شده است. معیار انتخاب بهترین الگو، توانایی آن برای تولید اهرم با ثبات مشابه اهرم واقعی است. نتایج، نشان‌دهندۀ بی‌ثباتی ساختار سرمایه در طول دورۀ مدّنظر است. همچنین مجموعه‌ای از الگوهایی که قائل به اهرم هدف هستند، به‌عنوان مجموعه‌ای معتبر برای تبیین رفتار اهرم معرفی می‌شوند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Cross-sectional stability of the leverage means that a firm’s current high or low leverage (relative to other firms) reliably predicts a comparable relative position in future cross-sections. The extent of stability in the cross-section is gauged by assessing the explanatory power of the current cross-section for future cross-sections going forward one year at a time and extending well into the future. This study examines the stability of leverage for 113 componies in Tehran Stock Exchange over the period 1999–2012. It conducts simulations that gauge the ability of random financing and a variety of leverage targeting models to replicate the instability of the crosssection over long horizons. The results show instability in leverage ratios. Target leverage models do a good job replicating the substantial instability of the actual leverage cross-section.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>35</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>56</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>منیژه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رامشه</Family>
						<NameE>manijeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>ramsheh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری حسابداری، دانشکده علوم اجتماعی و اقتصاد، گروه حسابداری، دانشگاه الزهراء</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری حسابداری، دانشکده علوم اجتماعی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.ramshe@qom.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>غلامرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سلیمانی امیری</Family>
						<NameE>gholamreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>soleimani amiri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار دانشکده علوم اجتماعی و اقتصاد، گروه حسابداری، دانشگاه الزهراء</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار دانشکده علوم اجتماعی و اقتصاد، گروه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>gh_soleimany@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رسول</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>اسکندری</Family>
						<NameE>rasool</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>eskandari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>مدرس بخش حسابداری و مالی، دانشگاه سالفورد انگلستان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>مدرس بخش حسابداری و مالی، دانشگاه سالفورد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>r.eskandari@salford.ac.uk</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قره خانی</Family>
						<NameE>MOHSEN</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>GHARAHKHANI</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیارگروه مهندسی مالی، دانشکده مالی، موسسه آموزش عالی ایرانیان، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیارگروه مهندسی مالی، دانشکده مالی، موسسه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mohsen.gharakhani@iranian.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ثبات ساختار سرمایه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نظریۀ توازن پویا</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الگوهای اهرم هدف</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الگوی رفتار تصادفی اهرم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شبیه‌سازی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Chang, X, and Dasgupta S. (2009). Target behavior and financing: How conclusive is the evidence? Journal of Finance 64: 1767–1796.##[2] Chen, L, and Zhao X. (2007). Mechanical mean reversion of leverage ratios. Economic Letters 95: 223–229.##[3] Dang, V. A., Kim, M. and Shin, Y. (2012). Asymmetric capital structure adjustments: new evidence from dynamic panel threshold models. Journal of Empirical Finance. 19(4): 465-482.##[4] DeAngelo, H and Roll R. (2015). How stable are corporate capital structures? The Journal of Finance, VOL. LXX, NO. 1: 373-418.##[5] Fama, E., French, K.R. (2002). Testing tradeoff and pecking order predictions about dividends and debt. Review of Financial Studies 15: 1-37.##[6] Fama, E., French, K.R. (2005). Financing decisions, who issues stock? Journal of Financial Economics 51: 545-512.##[7] Fama, E., French, K.R. (2012). Capital structure choices. Critical Finance Review 1: 59–101.##[8] Fathi, S., Abzari, M., Habibi, S. (2014). Determinants of capital structure: Meta-analysis, Asset Management and Financing, 2(1), 55-74.      ##[9] Faulkender, M., M. J. Flannery, K. W. Hankins, and J. M. Smith. (2012). Cash flows and leverage adjustments. Journal of Financial Economics 103 (3): 632-646.##[10] Fischer, E, Heinkel R, and Zechner J. (1989). Dynamic capital structure choice: theory and tests, Journal of Finance 44: 19–40.##[11] Flannery, M. J. &amp; Rangan, K. P. (2006). Partial adjustment toward target capital structures. Journal of Financial Economics. 79(3): 469-506.##[12] Frank, M, and Goyal V. (2008). Trade-off and pecking order theories of debt, in Espen Eckbo, ed.: Handbook of Empirical Corporate Finance (Elsevier B.V., Amsterdam, The Netherlands).##[13] Gorji, A, and Raei, R. (2015). Identification of capital structure adjustment speed using a dynamic model of optimal capital structure; emphasis on product market competition factor. Financial Knowledge of Security Analysis (Financial I Studies). 8(25): 43-67.##[14] Graham, J R, Leary, M T. (2011). A Review of Empirical Capital Structure Research and Directions for the Future. Annual Review of Financial Economics. Vol. 3: 309-345.##[15] Hashemi, S.A, Keshavarzmehr, D. (2015). The Investigation of Asymmetry in speed of capital structure adjustment: dynamic panel threshold models. Financial Engineering and Securities Management (Portfolio Management). 6(23): 59:78.##[16] Hovakimian, A, and Li G. (2011). In search of conclusive evidence: How to test for adjustment to target capital structure. Journal of Corporate Finance 17: 33–44.##[17] Hovakimian A, T. Opler, S. Titman. (2001). The debt-equity choice. J. Fin. and Quant. Analysis 36: 1-24.##[18] Huang R, Ritter J. (2009). Testing theories of capital structure and estimating the speed of adjustment. J. Financ. Quant. Analysis 44: 237 – 271.##[19] Kayhan A, Titman S. (2007). Firms’ histories and their capital structures. J. Financ. Econ. 83: 1-32.##[20] Kayo, EK &amp; Kimura, H. (2011). ‘Hierarchical determinants of capital structure’. Journal of Banking and Finance. vol. 35: 358-371.##[21] Leary, M. T., and Roberts M. R. (2005). Do firms rebalance their capital structures? Journal of Finance 60: 2575–2619.##[22] Lemmon M, Roberts M, Zender J. (2008). Back to the beginning: persistence and the cross-section of corporate capital structures. J. Finance 63: 1575-1608.##[23] Miller, M. (1977). Debt and taxes, Journal of Finance 32: 261–276.##[24] Minton, B, and Wruck K. (2001). Financial conservatism: Evidence on capital structure from low leverage firms. Working paper. The Ohio State University.##[25] Mousavi Haghighi, M, H.,  Khalifeh, M. (2015). Simulating the effect of financial leverage model on company value via system dynamics approach (Case study: National Iranian copper industries company), Asset Management and Financing,  3(3): 83-104.##[26] Myers S. (1984). The capital structure puzzle. J. Finance 39: 575-592.##[27] Nasirzadeh, F, Mostaghiman, A.R. (2010). Testing the static trade-off and pecking order theories in capital structure of TSE accepted companies. Journal of Accounting Advances. 2(2): 133-158.##[28] Öztekin, Ö. and Flannery, M. J. (2012). Institutional determinants of capital structure adjustment speeds. Journal of Financial Economics. 103(1): 88-112.##[29] Parsons, C, and Titman S. (2008). Empirical capital structure: A review, Foundations and Trends in Finance 2: 1–93.##[30] Rauh, J, and Sufi A. (2011). Explaining corporate capital structure: Product markets, leases, and asset similarity. Review of Finance 16: 115–155.##[31] Sheri Anaghiz, S., Rahmani, A., Bolo, G., Mohseni Maleki, B. (2015). Financial Flexibility and Capital Structure Adjustment Speed, Journal of Empirical Reasearch of Financial Accounting, 2(2), 73-87.##[32] Shyam-Sunder, L, and Myers S. C. (1999). Testing static tradeoff against pecking order models of capital structure. Journal of Financial Economics. 51: 219–244.##[33] Strebulaev, I, and Yang B. (2013). The mystery of zero-leverage firms. Journal of Financial Economics. 109: 1–23.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>عوامل مؤثر در بروز رفتار سرمایه‌گذاران با رویکرد پدیدارنگاری</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Factors Affecting the Behavior of Investors Regarding Phenomenographical Approach</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>تصمیم­گیری سرمایه­گذاران در بازارهای مالی از عوامل فراوانی متأثر است که بسیاری از آنها در رویکردهای عقلانی تصمیم­گیری توجیه‌شدنی نیست. عواملی مانند نظام ارزشی، اعتقادات و پیشفرض‌های فرهنگی موجب بروز سوگیری در فرایند تصمیم‌گیری می‌شود که رفتار و تصمیم‌های سرمایه‌گذاران را تحت تأثیر قرار می‌دهد. کانون توجه این پژوهش، شناخت عوامل رفتاری و ارائۀ الگوی تصمیم‌گیری سرمایه‌گذاران با تأکید بر مؤلفه‌های فرهنگی است. فرضیه‌های مبنایی پژوهش، از مرور نظریه و پژوهش­های مرتبط، استخراج و برای پیشبرد مراحل پژوهش، طرح پژوهش ترکیبی در بخش‌های کیفی و کمّی پژوهش، انتخاب و عملیاتی می­شود. در مرحلۀ کیفی ضمن اتخاذ استراتژی پدیدارنگاری، مصاحبه­های نیمه‌ساختاریافتۀ عمیق با خبرگان تصمیم­گیری رفتاری انجام شد. داده‌های حاصل از مصاحبه­ها با استفاده از روش تحلیل محتوا تحلیل و براساس آن، پرسشنامۀ پژوهش طراحی شد. در این قسمت با بهره‌گیری از استراتژی پیمایش، تعداد 500 پرسشنامه به‌صورت نمونه­گیری در دسترس، توزیع و 316 پرسشنامه تکمیل و جمع­آوری شد. داده‌های حاصل از پرسشنامه با نرم­افزارهای SPSS و Amos Graphics و با استفاده از روش معادلات ساختاری تحلیل شد. نتایج پژوهش نشان می‌دهد در مقولۀ فرهنگ، مؤلفه­های نظام ارزشی، کانون­کنترل، تحمل ­ابهام، عادت به سرمایه­گذاری و افق زمانی در کنار مقوله­های شخصیت، سوگیری­ شناختی و سوگیری ­عاطفی، تصمیم‌های سرمایه‌گذاران را شکل می‌دهد و موجب بروز رفتارهای توده­وار در تصمیم­گیری می­شود. همچنین با وجود تأیید تأثیر مقولۀ زمان در سایر پژوهش­ها، تحلیل داده­ها نشان داد الگوی رفتاری تصمیم­گیری سرمایه­گذاران بورس اوراق بهادار خراسان رضوی متأثر از عامل زمان نیست.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Decisions of investors in the financial markets is influenced by many factors, many of which are not justified in making rational decisions. Factors such as values, beliefs and cultural assumptions cause bias in the decision-making process that affect the behavior and decisions of the investors. The focus of this article is to provide a pattern of behavior and decision-making factors for investors with an emphasis on cultural factors. Basic assumptions are elucidated from literature review and relevant researches. The mixed method research was selected and operated in order to progress the research at the qualitative and quantitative parts. At the qualitative part, semi structured in-depth interviews were conducted with behavioral decision making experts considerating phenomenography strategy. Data from the interviews were analyzed using content analysis method according to which the questionnaire was designed. At this stage, the survey strategy was conducted, and then 500 questionnaires were distributed as available sampling method and 316 completed questionnaires were collected. The data were analyzed using SPSS and Amos Graphics softwares using structural equation modeling. The results indicate that fators such as value system, locus of control, uncertainty acceptance, habit to investment and time horizon are the main components of cultural category which besides personality, cognitive and emotional biases form investor’s decision making that lead to herding behavior. Despite the past researches confirmed the effect of time, data analysis showed that khorasan razavi investor’s behavioral model is not affected by the time factor.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>57</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>76</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید مرتضی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>غیور باغبانی</Family>
						<NameE>s.Morteza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ghayour Baghbani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه مدیریت دانشگاه بین المللی امام رضا (ع)، مشهد،</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه مدیریت دانشگاه بین المللی امام</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>s.ghayour@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>امید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بهبودی</Family>
						<NameE>omid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>behboodi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد شاهرود</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه آزاد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>behboodi_omid276@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تصمیم‌گیری سرمایه‌گذاران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سوگیری‌های شناختی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سوگیری‌های عاطفی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سوگیری‌های مالی ـ رفتاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مؤلفه‌های فرهنگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Badri, A. (2009). Behavioral Finance Knowledge and Capital Management. Keyhan publication, Tehran.##[2] Bazerman, M. H., &amp; Moore, D. A. (2008). Judgment in managerial decision making. 8th Edition, John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc.##[3] Brian, M., Lucey &amp; Davling, M. (2014). Cultural Behavioral Finance in Emerging Markets, Handbook of Emerging Markets and the Global Economy. Edited by: Mohamed El Hedi Arouri, Sabri Boubaker and Duc Khuong Nguyen, 327-346.## [4] Broihanne, M. H., Merli, M., &amp; Roger, P. (2014). Overconfidence, risk perception and the risk-taking behavior of finance professionals. Finance Research Letters. 11(2): 64-73.## [5] Chandra, A., &amp; Ravinder, K. (2011). Determinants of individual investor behaviour: An orthogonal linear transformation approach. Jamia Millia Islamia (Central University), New Delhi.##[6] Chui, A. C., Titman, S., &amp; Wei, K. J. (2010). Individualism and momentum around the world. The Journal of Finance. 65(1): 361-392.##[7] Danaee Fard, H., Kazemi, S. H. (2010). Promoting Interpretive Research in Organization:Overviewof Philosophical Foundations and Conduction Process of Phenomenography. Journal of Management Studies in Development &amp; Evaluation. 20 (61): 121 - 147.##[8] Duclos, R. (2015). The psychology of investment behavior: biasing financial decision-making one graph at a time. Journal of Consumer Psychology. 25 (2): 317-325.##[9] Farlin, J. D. (2006). Antecedents and consequences of heuristic biases: Evidence from individual investors and small business owners. Touro University International.##[10] Gholipour A. (2007). Management of Organizational Behavior: Iindividual Level. Tehran: The Organization for Researching and Composing University Textbooks in the Humanities (SAMT).##[11] Gigerenzer, G., &amp; Selten, R. (Eds.), (2002). Bounded rationality: The adaptative toolbox. MIT Press.##[12] Guiso, L., Sapienza, P., &amp; Zingales, L. (2009). Cultural biases in economic exchange? The Quarterly Journal of Economics. 124(3): 1095-1131.##[13] Haugen, R. (2009). The new finance. 4th Edition. Prentice Hall Publishing.##[14] Hubert, F. (2001). Behavioral finance-theory and practical application. Business Economics. 36(3): 63-69.##[15] Kim, K, A., Nofsinger, J, R. (2008). Behavioral finance in Asia&quot;, Pacific Basin Finance Journal. 16: 1-7.## [17] La Porta, R., Lopez-de-Silanes, F., Shleifer, A., and Vishny, R. (2000). Investor protection and corporate governance. Journal of financial economics. 58(1): 3-27.##[18] Lal, D. (2001). Unintended consequences: The impact of factor endowments, culture, and politics on long-run economic performance. (7). MIT Press.##[19] Macintyre, A. (2006). Thought Western in Ethics, Macintyre&#039;s View Point. Translated by Shahriari Hamid. Tehran: The Organization for Researching and Composing University Textbooks in the Humanities (SAMT).##[20] Mirkamali, M. (2007). Leadership and management training. Tehran: Yastarun Publication.##[21] Mohsin Khan, S., &amp; Mirakhor, A. (1991). Theoretical Studies in Islmic Banking and Finance. Translated By Ziyaee Bigdeli, Mohammad Taghi, Higher Institue Banking of Iran.##[22] Nelson, M., Evelyne, M. &amp; Enrico, U. (2008). The effects of behavioural factors in investment decision-making: A survey of institutional investors. International Journal of Business and Emerging Markets. 1(1): 24-41##[23] Pompian, M. (2006). Behavioral finance and wealth management: How to build optimal portfolios that account for investor biases. John Wiley and Sons, Inc.##[24] Raee R., Falah Pour S. (2004). Behavioral Finance: A Different Approach of Behavioral Finance Area. Financial Researches Press. 18: 78-106.##[25] Raee, R., &amp; Talangi, A. (2004). Advanced Investment management. Tehran: The Organization for Researching and Composing University Textbooks in the Humanities (SAMT).##[26] Rezaeian, A. (2008). Fundamentals of organizational behavior management. Tehran: The Organization for Researching and Composing University Textbooks in the Humanities (SAMT).##[27] Rizzi, J.V. (2008). Behavioral basis of the financial crisis. Journal of Applied Finance. 18 ( 2): 84-96.##[28] Robbins, S. (2011). Essentials of organizational behavior with mymanagementlab. Pearson Education Limited.##[29]. Schultz, D., &amp; Schultz, S. (1999). Theories of Personality. Yahya Seyed Mohammadi, Homa publication, 2nd edition, Tehran.##[30] Schwartz, H. (2002). Herbert Simon and behavioral economics. Journal of Socio-Economics. 31(3): 181-189.##[31] Sedghi, H. (2005). Investigation and Identification of Investor&#039;s Behavorial Dominant Styles in Tehran Stock Exchange. Thesis of financial management Imam Sadeq University, Tehran.##[32] Teddlie, C. &amp; Tashakkori, A. (2012). Common core characteristics of mixed methods research. A review of critical issues and call for greater convergence. American Behavioral Scientist. 56(6): 774-788.##[33] Tuyon, J. &amp; Ahmad Z. (2016). Behavioural finance perspectives on Malaysian stockmarket efficiency. Borsa Istanbul Review, doi: 10.1016/j. bir.2016.01.001.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی رابطۀ خوش‌بینی مدیریتی و هموارسازی سود در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigating the Relationship between Managerial Optimism and Earnings Smoothing in Companies Listed in Tehran Stock Exchange</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>چکیده مدیران، هموارسازی سود را تحت تأثیر عوامل مختلفی انجام می‌دهند و خصوصیات مدیران، سبک تصمیم‌گیری آنها را پیرامون این موضوع تحت تأثیر قرار می‌دهد. یکی از این خصوصیات، خوش‌بینی است که با بررسی این موضوع به شناخت بهتری در زمینۀ عملکرد شرکت‌ها و نحوۀ تصمیم‌گیری دربارۀ خرید سهام آنها می‌توان دست یافت. هدف این پژوهش، بررسی چگونگی تأثیر خوش‌بینی مدیریتی در هموارسازی سود است. نمونۀ آماری  شامل 107 شرکت از بین شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادر تهران برای یک دورۀ یازده‌ساله (1393-1383) انتخاب شده است. از معیار تغییرات سود خالص به دارایی کل برای سنجش هموارسازی سود و معیار تعداد روزهای افزایش قیمت سهام برای خوش‌بینی مدیریت استفاده شده ‌است. همچنین متغیرهای تأثیرگذار در هموارسازی سود (متغیر وابسته) ازجمله مشکلات نمایندگی، عدم تقارن اطلاعاتی و حاکمیت شرکتی برای بررسی دقیق‌تر مسأله به کار گرفته شده ‌است. داده‌ها با استفاده از نرم‌افزار تدبیر‌پرداز و ره‌آورد نوین و سایت‌های رسمی سازمان بورس اوراق بهادار تهران و به‌صورت سالانه جمع‌آوری شده ‌است. از رگرسیون چند‌‌متغیره مبتنی بر داده‌های ترکیبی به‌عنوان الگویی برای آزمون فرضیۀ پژوهش استفاده شده ‌است. تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها نیز با استفاده از نرم‌افزار ایویوز انجام شده است. نتیجۀ این مطالعه نشان می‌دهد مدیران خوش‌بین، بیش از مدیران منطقی، به هموارسازی سود توجه می‌کنند؛ به عبارت دیگر، صورت‌های مالی شرکت‌هایی که مدیران خوش‌بین اداره می‌کنند، سودهای هموار بیشتری را نشان می‌دهد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Earnings smoothing is concerned with and influenced by various factors. In this regard, managers&#039; properties and traits can affect the style of making decisions investigating &quot;optimism can result in our better and more precise cognition about the firms&#039; performance particularly in making decisions regarding purchasing stock.This research studies how managerial optimism can influence earnings smoothing. In this regard, 107 listed companies in Tehran Stock Exchange in a period of 11 years (2005-2015) were selected as the sample. The index of net income divided to total assests is used to assess the earnings smoothing, and the index of the number of increase in the price of stock days is used to appraise the management optimism. Also, effective variables on earnings smoothing (the dependent variable) such as agency problems, asymmetric information, and corporate governance have been used to investigate the issue in-depth. The obtained data were gathered annually by the help of &quot;Tadbir Pardaz&quot;, &quot;Rahavard Novin&quot;, and official site of Tehran Stock Exchange. Multivariable regression model was applied in order to test the research hypotheses. Data were anaysed by “Eviews8&quot; software. The results present that optimistic managers are more capabable of earnings smoothing. In other words, the financial manifests and lists of the companies administered by the optimistic managers present more smooth earnings.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>77</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>88</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>یحیی زاده فر</Family>
						<NameE>mahmood</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>yahyazadehfar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد دانشگاه مازندران-بابلسر، دانشکده علوم اقتصاد و اداری، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد دانشگاه مازندران-بابلسر، دانشکده علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>myahyafar@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>شهاب الدین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شمس</Family>
						<NameE>shahaboldin</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>shams</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشگاه مازندران-بابلسر،دانشکده علوم اقتصاد و اداری، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشگاه مازندران-بابلسر،دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>shams@umz.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مریم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نادری</Family>
						<NameE>maryam</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>naderi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی دانشگاه مازندران، دانشکده علوم اقتصاد و اداری، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی دانشگاه مازندران،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>marinaderi7@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تورش رفتاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خوش‌بینی مدیریتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هموارسازی سود</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Badri, A. (1998). Identifying the Effective FactorsonEarning Smoothing in Society of Quoted Companies in Tehran Stock Exchange. Thesis in accounting PHD course. University of Tehran [in Persian].##[2] Barros, L., &amp; Silveira, A. D. (2008). Overconfidence, managerial optimism, and the determinants of capital structure. Brazilian Review of Finance. 6(3).##[3] Beidleman, C. R. (1973). Income smoothing: the role of management. The Accounting Review. 48: 653-667.##[4] Bergstresser, D. B., &amp;philippon, T. (2006). CEO incentives and earnings management. Journal of Financial Economics. 80: 511-529.##[5] Bouwman, C. H. S. (2009). Managerial optimism and the market&#039;s reaction to dividend changes. Retrived from mit.edu.##[6] Bouwman, C. H. S. (2014). Managerial optimism and earnings smoothing. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance. 41: 283–303.##[7] Campbell, T. C., Gallmeyer, M., Johnson, S. A., Rutherford, J., &amp;Stanley, B. W. (2011). CEO optimism and forced turnover. Journal of Financial Economics. 101(3): 695-712.##[8] DeAngelo, H., DeAngelo, L., &amp;Stulz, R. M. (2006). Dividend policy and the earned/contributed capital mix: a test of the lifecycle theory. Journal of Financial Economics. 81: 227–254.##[9] Deshmukh, S., Goel, A., &amp;Howe, K. (2013). CEO overconfidence and dividend Policy. Journal of Finance Intermediation. 22(3): 440-463.##[10] Eckel, N. (1981). The income smoothing hypothesis revisited. Abacus. 17(1):  28-40.##[11] Etemadi, H., &amp;Abdoli, L.  (2015). Income smoothing and stock price peforance in financial crisis. Quarterly Financial Accounting. 25(7): 1-28 [in Persian].##[12] Ge, W., Matsumoto, D., &amp;Zhang, J. (2011). Do CFOs have style? An empirical investigation of the effect of individual CFOs on accounting practices. Contemporary Accounting Research. 28: 1141-1179.##[13] Ghaemi, M. H., Gheytasvand, M., &amp;Tujaki, M. (2003). Income smoothing effect on stock returns in companies listed in the Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of the Accounting and Auditing Review. 10(3): 131-150 [in Persian].##[14] Graham, J. R., Harvey, C. R., &amp;Rajgopal, S. (2005). The economic implivation of corporate financial reporting. Journal of Accounting and Economics. 40: 3-73.##[15] Healy, P. M. (1985). The effect of bonus schemes on accounting decisions. Journal of Accounting and Economics. 7(1): 85-107.##[16] Heaton, J. B. (2002). Managerial optimism and corporate finance. Financial Management. 31: 33-45.##[17] Hepworth, S. R. (1953). Smooth period income, The Accounting Reviwe. 12:  32-39.##[18] Hoang, M. L., Tan, F. J. , Lai, D. C., Celniker, S. E., Hoskins, R. A., Dunham, M. J., Zheng, Y., &amp;Koshland, D. (2010). The relationship between the cost of representation, optimism over management and cash flow sensitivity. Published: December 2, DOI: journal.pgen.1001228.##[19] Hribar, P., &amp;Yang, H. (2012). CEO overconfidence and management Forecasting. Working Paper.##[20] Jarboui, S., Forget, P., &amp;Boujelbene, Y. (2014). Transport firms’ inefficiency and managerial optimism: a stochastic frontier analysis.  Journal of Behavioral and Experimental Finance. 3: 41–51.##[21] Kermani, E., Kargar, E. F., &amp;Zarei, E. (2014). The effect of managerial overconfidence on profit smoothing evidence from Tehran Stock Exchange. Research Journal of Finance and Accounting. 5(9): 111-118.##[22] Klein, A. (2002). Adult committee, board of director characteristics, and earnings manپagement. Journal of Accounting and Economics. 33: 375-400.##[23] Lang, M., Raedy, J. S., &amp;Wilson, W. (2006). Earnings management and cross listing: are reconciled earnings comparable to US earnings? Journal of Accounting and Economics. 42: 255-283.##[24] Li, S., &amp;Richie, N. (2016). Income smoothing and the cost of deb. China Journal of Accounting Research. 1-16.##[25] Malmendier, U., &amp;Tate, G. (2008). Who makes acquisitions? CEO overconfidence and the markt&#039;s reaction. Journal of Financial Economics. 89: 20-43.##[26] Martinez, A. L., &amp;Castro, M. A. R. (2011). The smoothing hypothesis, stock returns and risk in Brazil. Brazilian Administration Review. 8(1): 1-20.##[27] Molanazari, M., &amp;Karimizand, S. (2007). Survey the relatianship among income smoothing and firm size, and type of industries in listed componies in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of the Accounting and Auditing Review. 14(1): 83-100 [in Persian].##[28] Myers, J. N., Myers, L. A., &amp;Skinner, D. J. (2007). Earnings momentum and earnings management. Journal of Accounting, Auditing and Finance. 22(2): 249-284.##[29] Omidakhgar, M., &amp;Jelvofazan, S. (2015). Effect of income smoothing on unsystematic risk of companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Accounting Knowledge. 6(20): 123-145 [in Persian].##[30] Pinghsun, H., Yan, Z., Donald, R. D., &amp;Jacquelyn, S. M. (2009). Do artificial income smoothing and real income smoothing contribute to firm value equivalently? Journal of Banking &amp; Finance. 33: 224-233.##[31] Pompian, M. M. (2010). Behavioral finance and asset management knowledge. Ahmad Badri. Tehran: Keyhan [in Persian].##[32] Purheydari, O., &amp;Aflatuni, A. (2006). Survey of objective of earning smoothing in listed companies in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of the Accounting and Auditing Review. 13(44): 55-70 [in Persian].##[33] Scherand, C. M., &amp;Zechman, S. L. (2012). Executive overconfidence and the slippery slope to financial misreporting. Journal of Accounting and Economics. 53: 29-311.##[34] Smith, E. D. (1976). The effect of the separation of ownership from control on accounting ploicy decisions. Accounting Review. 4: 707-723.##[35] Talebniya, G., &amp;Darvish, H. (2014). The relatianship between cash holdings and earning smoothing. The Financial Accounting and Auditing Researches. 6(24): 71-87 [in Persian].##[36] Wardhana, L. I., Lepetit, S., &amp;Meslier, C. (2014). Do asymmetric anformation and ownership structure matter for dividend payout decisions? Evidence from European banks. From archives-ouvertes.fr.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بسط الگوی قیمت‌گذاری دارایی‌های سرمایه‌ای برای سبد سرمایه‌گذاری صنایع فعال در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Extending Capital Asset Pricing Model for Industrial Portfolio in Tehran Stock Exchange</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT> این پژوهش برای الگو‌سازی، تخمین و تحلیل رفتار ریسک سیستماتیک، به بسط و تخمین الگوی سنتی قیمت‌گذاری دارایی‌های سرمایه‌ای، برای سبد سرمایه‌گذاری صنایع فعال در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران اقدام می‌کند. بدین‌منظور، از الگو‌های خودرگرسیونی واریانس ناهمسان شرطی تعمیم‌یافته و اشورت-سگوئین و داده‌های روزانۀ بازده بورس اوراق بهادار تهران و صنایع فعال در آن، از مهرماه سال 1376 تا شهریور 1394 بهره می‌برد. نتایج به‌دست‌آمده همانند نتایج پژوهش‌های کشور‌های توسعه‌یافته و در حال توسعه، نشان می‌دهد ضریب بتای الگوی سنتی قیمت‌گذاری دارایی‌های سرمایه‌ای، در طول زمان تغییر می‌‌کند؛ بنابراین استفاده از این الگو با بتای ثابت، برای الگوسازی ریسک سیستماتیک و پیش‌بینی بازده آیندۀ دارایی‌های مالی، ممکن است به نتایج گمراه‌کننده‌ای منجر شود. همچنین یافته‌ها نشان می‌‌دهد الگوی سنتی قیمت‌گذاری دارایی‌های سرمایه‌ای و الگوی اشورت-سگوئین، دقت پیش‌بینی تقریباً یکسان و هر دو الگو نسبت به الگوی خودرگرسیونی واریانس ناهمسان شرطی تعمیم‌یافته، دقت پیش‌بینی کمتری دارند. ریسک سیستماتیک حاصل از تخمین الگوی خودرگرسیونی واریانس ناهمسان شرطی تعمیم‌یافته و الگوی اشورت-سگوئین، روند خاصی را  دنبال نمی‌‌کند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In order to model, estimate and make a comparative analysis of the behavior of systematic risk, this paper, by using daily data from 09.28.1997 to 09.22.2015, estimates and extends the traditional Capital Asset Pricing Model for industrial portfolio in Tehran Stock Exchange, with DBEKK_GARCH and Shwert_Seguin Models. Findings show that estimated systematic risk for the Iranian industrial portfolio is time-varying. Therefore, using the traditional Capital Asset Pricing Model, with constant beta, may not be a good idea for modeling systematic risk and forecasting the expected returns of capital assets, as it may lead us to misleading results. Also findings show that the traditional CAPM and Shwert_Seguin models have almost identical forecast accuracy, although their accuracy is less than the DBEKK_GARCH model. The estimated systematic risk, from DBEKK_GARCH and Shwert_Seguin models, does not show any trend behavior over time.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>89</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>104</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حیدری</Family>
						<NameE>Hasan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Heidari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار اقتصاد دانشگاه ارومیه، دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت، گروه اقتصاد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار اقتصاد دانشگاه ارومیه، دانشکده اقتصاد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>h.heidari@urmia.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حیدرپور</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hidarpour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>مدرس مدعو دانشگاه پیام نور آذربایجان‌غربی، دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، گروه اقتصاد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>مدرس مدعو دانشگاه پیام نور آذربایجان‌غربی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ah2909532054@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الگوی خودرگرسیونی واریانس ناهمسان شرطی تعمیم یافته</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الگوی اشورت-سگوئین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الگوی قیمت‌گذاری دارایی‌های سرمایه‌ای</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ریسک سیستماتیک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Alinezhad, M., Shoul, A. &amp; Bahreini, M. (1392). The effect of institutional investment on systematic risk in firms accepted in Tehran Stock Exchange. Accounting, financial management and investing Second national conference.##[2] Bajpai, S., Sharma, A. K. (2015). An Empirical Testing of Capital Asset Pricing Model in India. Elsevier Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences. 189(2015): 259 – 265.##[3] Barberis, N., Greenwood, R., Jin, L., &amp; Shleifer, A. (2014). X-CAPM: An extrapolative capital asset pricing model. Journal of Financial Economics. 115(2014):1–24.##[4] Bollerslev, T. (1986). Generalized autoregressive conditional heteroskedasticity. Journal of Econometr-ics. 31(3):307–327.##[5] Choudhry, T. &amp; Wu, H.)2009). Forecasting the weekly time-varying beta of UK firms: GARCH Models vs. Kalman filter method. European Journal of Finance. 15(4), 437-444.##[6] Engle, R. F. (1982). Autoregressive conditional heteroscedasticity with estimates of the variance of United Kingdom inflation. Econometrica. 50(4):987–1007.##[7] Engle, R. F. &amp; Kroner, K. F. (1995). Multivariate simultaneous generalized ARCH. Econometric Theory. 11(01):122–150.##[8] Fang, H. &amp; Lai, T.Y. (1997). Co-kurtosis and capital asset pricing. Financial Review. 32(2):293–307.##[9] Hwang, S. &amp; Satchell, S. E. (1999). Modelling emerging market risk premia using higher moments. International Journal of Finance &amp; Economics. 4(4):271–296.##[10] Jarque, C. M. &amp; Bera, A. K. (1980). Efficient tests for normality, homoscedasticity and serial independence of regression residuals. Economics Letters. 6 (3):255–259.##[11] Lintner, J. (1965). The valuation of risk assets and the selection of risky investments in stock portfolios and capital budgets. Review of Economics and Statistics. 47(1):13–37.##[12] Mergner, S. &amp; Bulla, J. (2008). Time-varying beta risk of pan-European industry portfolios: A comparison of alternative modeling techniques. European Journal of Finance. 14 (8):771–802.##[13] Neslihanoglu, S. (2014). Validating and Extending the Two-Moment Capital AssetPricing Model for Financial Time Series. PH.D Thesis. School of Mathematics and Statistics, College of Science and Engineering, University of Glasgow.##[14] Odabasi, A. (2003). Some estimation issues on betas: A reliminary investigation in the Istanbul Stock Exchange. Bogazici Journal: Review of Social, Economic and Administrative Studies. 17(2):1–11.##[15] Piri, P., Heidari, H. &amp; Raouf, S. (1392). The relationship between systemic risk and economic value added in Iran. Journal of Economic Research and Policies.21 (66): 169-186##[16] Reddy, M. S., Durga, S. (2015). Testing the validity of CAPM in Indian stock markets. International Journal of Multidisciplinary Research and Development. 2(2): 56-60##[17] Saeidi, A. &amp; Ramsheh, M. (1390). Determinant factors of systematic risk in Tehran Stock Exchange. Financial Accounting Researches. 1(7): 125-142##[18] Schwert, W., &amp; Seguin, P. (1990). Heteroskedasticity in Stock Returns, Journal of Finance. Vol (45):1129-1155.##[19] Sharpe, W. F. (1964). Capital asset prices: A theory of market equilibrium under conditions of risk. The Journal of Finance. 19(3):425–442.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تأثیر اطمینان بیش از حد مدیریت بر مدیریت سود مبتنی بر اقلام تعهدی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigating the Effect of Managerial Overconfidence and Accrual-based Earnings Management</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT> بیش‌اطمینانی، اعتقاد بی­اساس دربارة توانایی­های شناختی، قضاوت­ها و استدلال شهودی فرد است. مدیران بیش‌اطمینان درنتیجۀ این باور که اطلاعات ویژ­ه­ای در اختیار دارند (که دیگران در اختیار ندارند)، دقت اطلاعات خود و به‌تبع آن، سودها و جریان‌های نقدی آیندۀ واحد تجاری را بیش از حد تخمین می­زنند و چشم‌انداز مثبتی از ریسک و بازده آینده دارند. هدف این پژوهش، بررسی تأثیر بیش‌اطمینانی مدیریت در مدیریت سود مبتنی بر اقلام تعهدی در 95 شرکت پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در سال­های 1386 تا 1393 است. در این پژوهش برای اندازه­گیری بیش‌اطمینانی مدیریت از دو معیار مبتنی بر سرمایه‌گذاری و اهرم مالی استفاده شده است. تجزیه و تحلیل نتایج حاصل از آزمون فرضیۀ پژوهش، نشان‌دهندۀ وجود ارتباط مثبت و معنادار بین بیش­اطمینانی مدیریت براساس هر دو شاخص بیش‌اطمینانی مدیریت مبتنی بر سرمایه­گذاری و اهرم مالی بر مدیریت سود مبتنی بر اقلام تعهدی است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Overconfidence can be summarized as unwarranted faith in one’s intuitive reasoning, judgments, and cognitive abilities. Overconfident managers by the belief that they possess special information (that the others do not) overestimate their information integrity and consequently their firms’ future earnings and cash flows, and usually have positive perspective on firm’s future risk and return. The aim of this study is to investigate the impact of managerial overconfidence on accrual-based earnings management in 95 companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange during the years 2006 to 2014. In this study, in order to measure managerial overconfidence, two criteria based on investment and financial leverage was implemented. The results showed that there is a positive and significant relationship between managerial overconfidence (based on both overinvestment and financial leverage) on accrual-based earnings management.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>105</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>116</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید کاظم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ابراهیمی</Family>
						<NameE>kazem</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>ebrahimi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه حسابداری دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت. دانشگاه سمنان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه حسابداری دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت.</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>kebrahimi@semnan.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>صادق</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سربازی آزاد</Family>
						<NameE>sadegh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>sarbazi-azad</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد حسابداری. دانشگاه سمنان. دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت گروه حسابداری</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد حسابداری. دانشگاه سمنان. دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sadeghazad90@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بیش‌اطمینانی مدیریت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت سود</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت سود مبتنی بر اقلام تعهدی اختیاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF> [1] Ahmed, A. S., &amp; Duellman, S. (2013). Managerial overconfidence and accounting conservatism. Journal of Accounting Research, 51(1), 1-30.## [2] Ahmadpour, A., &amp; Shahsavari, M. (2016). Earnings management and the effect of earnings quality in relation to bankruptcy level (Firms listed in Tehran Stock Exchange). Iranian Journal of Management Studies, 9(1), 77-99[In Persian].##[3] Arabsalehi, M., &amp;; Hashemi, M. (2015). the effect of managerial overconfidence on tax avoidance, Accounting and Auditing Studies, 22(1), 85-104 [In Persian].##[4].Blue, Gh. &amp; Hasani Alghar, M. (2015). Empirical measures of earnings quality, Accounting and Auditing Studies, 3(12), 46-69 [In Persian].##[5] Bouwman, C. H. (2014). Managerial optimism and earnings smoothing. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, 41, 283-303.##[6] Ben-David, I., Graham, J. R., &amp; Harvey, C. R. (2010). Managerial miscalibration (No. w16215). National Bureau of Economic Research.##[7] Chen, S., Lai, S., Liu, C., &amp; Mc Vay, S. (2014). Overconfident Managers and Internal Controls. Working Paper, National Taiwan University and University of Washington.##[8] Campbell, T. C., Gall Meyer, M., Johnson, S. A., Rutherford, J., &amp; Stanley, B. W. (2011). CEO optimism and forced turnover. Journal of Financial Economics, 101(3), 695-712.##[9] Cohen, D. A., &amp; Zarowin, P. (2010). Accrual-based and real earnings management activities around seasoned equity offerings. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 50(1), 2-19##[10] Duellman, S., Hurwitz, H., &amp; Sun, Y. (2015). Managerial overconfidence and audit fees. Journal of Contemporary Accounting &amp; Economics, 11(2), 148-165.##[11] Fakhari, H., &amp; Adili, M. (2012). The relationship between free cash flow and earnings management through real activities, Accounting and Auditing Studies, 19(70), 63-78 [In Persian].##[12] Francis, J., Allen, H., Rajgopal, S., &amp; Amy, Y. (2008). CEO Reputation and Earnings Quality. Contemporary Accounting Research, 25 (1), 109-147.##[13] Hasas Yeganeh, Y., Hasani Alghar, M., &amp; Marfou, M. (2015). Managerial Overconfidence and Audit Fees, Accounting and Auditing Studies, 22(3), 363-384 [In Persian].##[14] Heaton, J. B. (2002). Managerial optimism and corporate finance. Financial management, 33-45.##[15] Hejazi, r., Mohamadi, Sh., aslani, Z., &amp; Aghajani, M. (2012). Earnings management prediction using neural networks and decision tree in TSE, Accounting and Auditing Studies, 19(12), 31-46 [In Persian].##[16] Hsieh, T. S., Bedard, J. C., &amp; Johnstone, K. M. (2014). CEO overconfidence and earnings management during shifting regulatory regimes. Journal of Business Finance &amp; Accounting, 41(9-10), 1243-1268.##[17] Khodamipour, A.,   Dorri Sedeh, M., &amp; Pouresmaily, A. (2015). The effect of managerial overconfidence on the conservatism with respect to the role of external monitoring, Accounting and Auditing Studies, 22(2), 183-202[In Persian].##[18] Khodamipour, A., Khorshidi, A., &amp; Shirzad, A. (2014). The impact of disclosure quality on the various earnings management, Accounting and Auditing Studies, 20(4), 21-38[In Persian].##[19] Kothari, S. P., Leone, A. J., &amp; Wasley, C. E. (2005). Performance matched discretionary accrual measures. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 39(1), 163-197.## [20] Lo, K. (2008). Earnings management and earnings quality. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 45(2), 350-357.##[21] Li, F. (2010). Manager&#039;s self-serving attribution bias and corporate financial policies. Working Paper, University of Michigan.##[22] Libby, R., &amp; Rennekamp, K. (2012). Self‐serving attribution bias, overconfidence, and the issuance of management forecasts. Journal of Accounting Research, 50(1), 197-231.##[23] Malmendier, U., &amp; Tate, G. (2005). Does overconfidence affect corporate investment? CEO overconfidence measures revisited. European Financial Management, 11(5), 649-659.##[24] Malmendier, U., Tate, G., &amp; Yan, J. (2007). Corporate financial policies with overconfident managers (No. w13570). National Bureau of Economic Research.##[25] Molanazari, M., Ramsheh, M. (2014). Managerial overconfidence and accounting conservatism, Journal of Accounting Knowledge, 5(16), 55-79 [In Persian].##[26] Nazemi, A, M. (2010). Real earnings management based on Accounting figures accrual earnings management, CPA Journal, 114-119[In Persian].##[27] Presley, T. J., &amp; Abbott, L. J. (2013). AIA submission: CEO overconfidence and the incidence of financial restatement. Advances in Accounting, 29(1), 74-84.##[28] Pompian, M. M. (2011). Behavioral Finance and Wealth Management: How to Build Optimal Portfolios that Account for Investor Biases (Vol. 667). John Wiley &amp; Sons.##[29] Ramsheh, M., &amp; Molanazari, M. (2014). Managerial overconfidence and accounting conservatism, Journal of Accounting Knowledge, 5(16), 55-79 [In Persian].##[30] Schrand, C. M., &amp; Zechman, S. L. (2012). Executive overconfidence and the slippery slope to financial misreporting. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 53(1), 311-329.##[31] Schrand, C. M., &amp; Zechman, S. L. (2012). Executive overconfidence and the slippery slope to financial misreporting. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 53(1), 311-329.##[32] Valizadeh, L. Z. (2009). The results of actual earnings management (Msc dissertatio), Alzahra University.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارزیابی تأثیر سرمایه‌گذاری در عملکرد آینده با درنظرگرفتن سطح محدودیت مالی شرکت</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Evaluation of the Effect of Investment on Future Performance Considering the Level of Firm Financial Constraint</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>عوامل متعددی در نقش سرمایه‌گذاری بر عملکرد شرکت اثرگذار هستند. محدودیت در تأمین مالی ازجملۀ این عوامل است. هدف پژوهش حاضر، بررسی تأثیر سرمایه­گذاری در سودآوری و «بازده خرید و نگهداری تعدیل‌شدۀ آینده» با درنظرگرفتن سطح محدودیت مالی شرکت است. برای تجزیه و تحلیل داده­ها و آزمون فرضیه­ها از الگو­های رگرسیون چندمتغیره و داده­های ترکیبی استفاده شده است. شاخص محدودیت مالی شرکت با استفاده از رگرسیون لاجیت رتبه‌ای برآورد شده است. نمونۀ آماری برای آزمون فرضیه­های پژوهش، متشکل از 120 شرکت پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، در دورۀ زمانی 1387 تا 1393 است. یافته­های پژوهش نشان‌دهندۀ تأثیر متفاوت سرمایه­گذاری در سودآوری آینده در شرکت­های با محدودیت مالی نسبت به شرکت­های بدون محدودیت مالی است. این یافته­ با مبانی نظری سازگار است؛ اما شواهدی دال بر تأثیر متفاوت سرمایه­گذاری در بازده خرید و نگهداری تعدیل‌شدۀ آیندۀ شرکت­های با محدودیت مالی نسبت به شرکت­های بدون محدودیت مالی یافت نشد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The effects of investment on firm performance depends on several factors. One of the most important factors is firm financial constraint. This study aimed to investigate the effect of investment on firms’ future profitability and buy-and-hold market adjusted returns considering the level of firm financial constraint. For statistical analysis in this study, multiple regression models were used. The firm financial constraint was measured using ordered logit regression. This research has been conducted on 120 listed companies in Tehran Stock Exchange based on data mentioned in financial annual reports between2008–2014. Results indicated different effects of investment on future profitability in constraint firms in comparison to non-constraint firms. These findings largely concur with theoretical background. However, no evidence could be found for different effects of investment on future buy-and-hold market adjusted stock return in constraint and non-constraint firms.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>117</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>132</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ریحانه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>هادیان</Family>
						<NameE>REYHANE</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>HADIAN</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری دانشگاه اصفهان، دانشکدۀ علوم اداری و اقتصاد، گروه حسابداری</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری دانشگاه اصفهان، دانشکدۀ علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>r_hadian@ase.ui.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید عباس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>هاشمی</Family>
						<NameE>SEYED ABBAS</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>HASHEMI</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار دانشگاه اصفهان، دانشکدۀ علوم اداری و اقتصاد، گروه حسابداری</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار دانشگاه اصفهان، دانشکدۀ علوم اداری</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>a.hashemi@ase.ui.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سعید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صمدی</Family>
						<NameE>SAEED</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>SAMADI</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار دانشگاه اصفهان، دانشکدۀ علوم اداری و اقتصاد، گروه اقتصاد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار دانشگاه اصفهان، دانشکدۀ علوم اداری</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>s.samady@ase.ui.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بازده خرید و نگهداری تعدیل‌شدۀ آیندۀ سهام</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایه‌گذاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سودآوری آینده</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>محدودیت مالی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Arabsalehi, M, Ashrafi, M. (2011). The role of cash reserves in determining investment-cash flow sensitivity of listed companies in TSE, Financial Accounting Research, 3(9): 75-94.##[2] Baharmoghadam, M, Davoody , S.  Yousef zadeh, N.Aazami, Z.(2015), The investigation effect of investments (including cash and non-cash) in explaining future performance of the listed companies in tehran stock exchange,Asset Management and Financing, 3(3):1-20.##[3] Bahramfar, N, Estiri, Z, (2001), Investigation of information content of##Capital expenditurein the Listed Companies in Tehran Stock Exchange, M.A Thesis .University of Tehran.##[4] Bavarsad, B, Sinaei, H, Delavaripour, J, (2013), Study on the relationship between financial constraints and stock return in tehran stock exchange,International Journal of Economy, Management and Social Sciences, 2(5):166-183.##[5] Brooks, C. (2014) .Introductory econometrics for finance. 3rd edition. New York: Cambridge University Press.##[6] Buehlmaier M. M.  and Whited, T, (2014), Looking for Risk in Words: A Narrative Approach to Measuring the Pricing Implications of Financial Constraints, Ross School of Business, University of Michigan, Working Paper##[7] Carreira, C, Silva, F, (2013), Do size, age and dividend policy provide useful measures of financing constraints? New evidence from a panel of Portuguese firms, Columbia University ,Working Papers.##[8] Cooper, M. J., Gulen H., and Schill M. J. (2008). Asset growth and the cross-section of stock returns. The Journal of Finance, 63(4): 1609-1651.##[9] Dechow, P. M., Richardson, S. A., &amp; Sloan, R. G. (2008). The persistence andpricing of the cash component of earnings. Journal of Accounting Research, 46(3): 537-566.##[10] Denis, D, J. Sibilkov, V.(2010). Financial constraints, investment, and the value of cash holdings, Review of Financial Studies, 23(1): 247-269.##[11] Espinosa, R, (2015), Financial Constraints, Corporate Investment and Future Profitability, Phd Thesis on Business Administration, University of California, Berkeley.##[12] Fazzari, S. M., Hubbard, R. G., Petersen, B. C. (1988). Financing constraints on corporate investment. Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, 19(1): 141-206.##[13] Foroghnejad, H. Moradi, M. Heidari, H, Masomi, KH H(2016),Stock liquidity, investment efficiency, and firm&#039;s performance: evidence from tehran stock exchange, Journal of Investment Knowledge,  5(18): 179-196.##[14] Hadlock, Charles. J .Joshua R .Pierce, )2010(, New evidence on measuring financialconstraints: movingbeyond the KZ Index, Review of Financial Studies, 23(5): 1909-1940.##[15] Harris, M. and Raviv, A. (1990). Capital Structure and the Informational Role of Debt. Journal of Finance, 45(2): 321-349.##[16] Hashemi ,S.A,  Amiri ,H, Moshtaghian, M. (2016), The impact of operating cash flows on external financing, considering the firm financial constraint and inflation, Financial Accounting Research, 7(4):19-38.##[17] Jensen, M. C. (1986). Agency costs and free cash flow, corporate finance and takeovers. American Economic Review, 76(2): 659-665.##[18] Kanani-Amiri , M, (2008),  Financial constraints and stock return in capital market , DaneshvarRafrar, 14(26): 17-30.##[19] Kaplan, Steven N., and Luigi Zingales, 1997, Do investment-cash flow sensitivities provideuseful measures of financing constraints?,The Quarterly Journal of Economics. 112(1): 169–215.##[20] Lamont , Owen , Polk Christopher , and Saa- Requejo Jesus, (2001) Financial constraints and stock return volatility. The review of Financial Studies. 14(2): 529-554.##[21] Li, dongmei, (2010), Financial constraints, R&amp;D investment, and stock returns, The Review of Financial Studies, 24(9): 2974-3007.##[22] Lin, Huidan,  Parvasini, Daniel , (2012), The effect of financing constraints on risk, Review of Finance, 20(5): 1835-1865.##[23] Liu, J. F, Lee, N, R , Lin, Y.B, Hong ,Z. P. (2015), The capital investment increases and stock returns, Asian Economic and Financial Review, 5(1): 1-11##[24] Modigliani F., and M.H. Miller (1958), The Cost of capital corporation finance and the theory ofinvestment,  American Economic Review, 48 (3):261-297.##[25] Pathan , S . Faff. R . W. Fernandez. C. Masteres .N . (2014), Financial constraints and dividend policy, available at http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2286962.##[26] Talane, Abdolreza, Hejrankesh, Hadis, (2012), An empirical analysis of weak form and semi-strong form efficiency of tehran stock exchange, Accounting Research, 3(12): 1-23.##[27] Titman, S., Wei, K. C. J., &amp;Xie, F. (2004). Capital investments and stock returns. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis,39(4): 677-700.##[28] Whited, T., and G. Wu, (2006), Financial constraints risk, Review of Financial Studies. 19(2): 531-559.##[29] Yang, jie, (2015), Equity and debt financing constraints, McDonough School of Business, Georgetown University, Working Paper.##[30] Yari. Akbaralah, (2009), To Study the weak from of efficiency of the capital market in Tehran Stock Exchange, Journal of Securities Exchange, 1(4): 75-108.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>محافظه‌کاری و عملکرد ارزش سهام در بحران مالی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Conservatism and Stock Value Performance in Financial Crisis</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف اصلی این پژوهش، بررسی رابطۀ محافظه‌کاری و عملکرد ارزش سهام (که براساس بازده سهام و بازده غیرعادی سهام اندازه‌گیری شده است) در شرایط بحران مالی است. اطلاعات لازم از صورت‌های مالی 71 شرکت دارای بحران مالی و 71 شرکت بدون بحران مالی در بازۀ زمانی 1383 تا 1392 جمع‌آوری شده است. ملاک طبقه‌بندی بحران مالی شرکت‌ها عبارت است از: 1.سه سال متوالی زیان گزارش کند، 2. سود تقسیمی هر سال نسبت به سال قبل بیش از 40 درصد کاهش پیدا کرده باشد، 3. مشمول مادۀ 141 قانون تجارت شده باشد. برای آزمون فرضیه‌های پژوهش، رگرسیون چندمتغیره با استفاده از داده‌های ترکیبی استفاده شده است. نتایج پژوهش نشان می‌دهد در شرکت‌های بدون بحران مالی، بین محافظه‌کاری با بازده سهام و بازده غیرعادی سهام، رابطۀ منفی و معناداری وجود دارد، در حالی که در شرکت‌های دارای بحران مالی بین محافظه‌کاری با بازده سهام و بازده غیرعادی سهام، رابطۀ مثبت و معناداری وجود داردکه نشان می‌دهد شرکت‌های دارای بحران مالی، سیاست‌های محافظه‌کارانۀ بیشتری نسبت به شرکت‌های بدون بحران مالی اتخاذ می‌کنند. در نتیجه زیان ارزش سهام آنها کمتر از شرکت‌های بدون بحران مالی است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The main purpose of this research is to consider the relationship between conservatism and stock value performance (measured by stock return and abnormal returns) in financial crisis. Using information in the financial statements of 71 financial distressed companies and 71 financial non-distressed companies during the period 2004 to 2014. Criteria for the classification of financial distressed companies include: (1) three consecutive years of losses report, (2) dividend every year over the previous year more than 40% declined and (3) Article 141 of the Commercial Code. To test research hypotheses multivariate regression models is utilized. The results show that for the financial non-distressed companies, there is significant negative relation between conservatism with return stock and abnormal return stock. However, for the financial distressed companies, there is significant positive relation between conservatism with return stock and abnormal return stock. In other words, the financial distressed companies adopt more conservative policies than do the financial non-distressed companies, which shows loss of value of their stock is less than that of the financial non-distressed companies.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>133</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>150</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>اعتمادی</Family>
						<NameE>hossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Etemadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار دانشگاه تربیت مدرس دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد – گروه حسابداری</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار دانشگاه تربیت مدرس دانشکده مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>etemadih@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>لیلا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عبدلی</Family>
						<NameE>leila</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>abdoli</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد – گروه حسابداری</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>lamastiyan@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>محافظه‌کاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عملکرد ارزش سهام</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بحران مالی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Ahmed, A. S., &amp; Duellman, S. (2011). Evidence on the role of accounting conservatism in monitoring managers’ investment decisions. Accounting &amp; Finance. 51(3): 609-633.##[2] Asadi, G. H.,  &amp; Bayat, M. (2015). The impact of conditional and un conditional conservatism on firm value. Journal of  Management Accounting. 24(8):1-12.##[3] Ball, R., Kothari, S. P., &amp; Robin, A. (2000). The effect of international institutional factors on properties of accounting earnings. Journal of Accounting and Economics.29(1): 1-51##[4] Ball, R., &amp; Shivakumar, L. (2005). Earnings quality in UK private firms: Comparative loss recognition timeliness. Journal of Accounting and Economics. 39(1): 83-128.##[5] Basu, S. (1997). The conservatism principle and the asymmetric timeliness of earnings. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 24(1): 3–37.##[6] Biddle, G. C., Mary L. M. &amp; Frank M. S. (2010) Accounting conservatism and Bankruptcy Risk, Financial Accounting and Reporting Section, Available at : www . ssrn.com, 1-20.##[7] Biddle, G., Ma, M., &amp; Song, F. (2011). Accounting conservatism and bankruptcy risk. Working paper, University of Hong Kong.##[8] Eslami B. G., Nikomaram, H &amp; Banimahdi, B.  (2012). Relation between accounting conservatism and financial crises in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Financial Knowledge of Securities Analysis. 1(9): 125-146.##[9] Easley, D., O&#039;Hara, M. (2004). Information and the cost of capital. The Journal of Finance. 59(4): 1553-1583.##[10]           Francis, B., Iftekhar, H., &amp; Wu, Q. (2012). The benefits of conservative accounting to shareholders: Evidence from the financial crisis. Lally School of Management and Technology, Working Paper.##[11]           Haji, Z., &amp; Ghaammaghmi, M. (2012).Investigation on the role of conservative the reduction of company bankruptcy risk. Journal of Management Accounting. 2(13): 1-15.##[12]           Hendriksen, E.S. &amp; Berda, M. F. (1992). Accounting theory, 5th Edition, Irwin: Pence-Hill.##[13]           Gigler, F., Kanodia, C., Sapra, H., &amp; Venugopalan, R. (2009). Accounting conservatism and the efficiency of debt contracts. Journal of Accounting Research. 47(3): 767-797.##[14]           Givoly, D. &amp; Hayn, C. (2000), The changing time-series properties of earnings, cash flows and accruals: Has financial reporting become more conservative? Journal of Accounting and Economics. 29(3):287-320.##[15]           Guay, W., &amp; Verrecchia, R. (2006). Discussion of an economic framework for conservative accounting and bushman and piotroski (2006). Journal of Accounting and Economics. (42): 149-165.##[16]           Jantadej, P. (2006).Using the combination of cash flow components to predict finance distress. Ph.D. The Graduate College at the University of Nebraska.##[17]           Jensen, M. C., &amp; Meckling, W. H. (1976). Theory of the firm: managerial behavior, agency costs and ownership structure. Journal of Financial Economics. 3(4): 305-360.##[18]           Kim, Y., Li, S., Pan, &amp; Zuo, L. (2013). The role of accounting conservatism in the quality market: Evidence from seasoned equality offering. http://Paper.ssrn.com/ sol3/Paper.cfm?abstract_id = 2170179##[19]           Kim, J. B., &amp; Yi, C. H. (2006). Ownership structure, business group affiliation, listing status, and earnings management: Evidence from Korea. Contemporary Accounting Research. 23(2): 427-464.##[20]           Kim, J.-B., &amp; Zhang, L. (2010). Does accounting conservatism reduce stock price crash risk? Firm-level evidence. Working paper, City University of Hong Kong.##[21]           Klein, A., &amp; Marquardt, C. (2006) Fundamentals of accounting losses, The Accounting Review 81(1):2-19.##[22]           LaFond, R., &amp; Watts, R. L. (2008). The information role of conservatism. The Accounting Review. 83(2): 447-478.##[23]           Lemmon, M., &amp; Lins, K. (2003). Ownership structure, corporate governance, and firm value: evidence from the East Asian financial crisis. The Journal of Finance. 58(4):1445-1468.##[24]           Louis, H., Sun, A., &amp; Urcan, O. (2012). Value of cash holdings and accounting conservatism. Contemporary Accounting Research, Forthcoming.##[25]           Manganarisa, P., Spathisa, C., &amp; Dasilasb, A. (2015).  The effects of mandatory IFRS adoption and conditional conservatism on European bank values. Journal of International Accounting, Auditing and Taxation. 24:72-81.##[26]           McKee, T. M., Eilifsen. A., &amp; Lensberg, T. (2006). Bankruptcy theory development and classification via genetic programming European. Journal of Operational Research.169: 667-697.##[27]           Mitton, T. (2002). A cross-firm analysis of the impact of corporate governance on the East Asian financial crisis. Journal of Financial Economics. 64(2): 215-241.##[28]           Pastena, V. &amp; Ruland., W. (1986). The Merger / Bankruptcy alternative. Journal of Accounting Research. 61(2): 288-301.##[29]           Setayesh, M. &amp; Jamalianpour, M. (2011). Studying existence of conditional conservatism and negative news of Future on listed companies in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Accounting Advances. 3(58): 15-119.##[30]           Ryan, S. (2006) Identifying conditional conservatism. European Accounting Review. 15(4):511‐525.##[31]           Vichitsarawong, T., &amp; Eng, L. (2010). The impact of the Asian financial crisis on conservatism and timeliness of earnings: Evidence from Hong Kong, Alaysia, Singapore, and Thailand, Journal of International Financial Management and Accounting. 21:32-61.##[32]           Watts, R. L. (2003) Conservatism in accounting, Part I: Explanations and implications. Accounting Horizons. 17(3):207‐221.##[33]           Zhang, J. (2008). The contracting benefits of accounting conservatism to lenders and borrowers. Journal of Accounting and Economics 45(1): 27-54.##[34]           Ziobrowski A. J., Ping C., James W. B., &amp; Brigitte J.  (2004). Abnormal returns from the common stock investments of the U.S. senate. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis. 39(4):98-195.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تأثیر هزینۀ تبلیغات در عملکرد مالی با میانجی‌گری ارزش برند در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigating the Effect of Advertisement Cost on the Financial Performance of the Firms Listed in Tehran Stock Exchange with the Mediating Role of Brand Equity</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>با توجه به گسترش رقابت و مواجه‌شدن مشتریان با انبوهی از کالاها و خدمات از سوی عرضه‌کنندگان مختلف، تبلیغات یکی از مهم‌ترین ابزارهای رساندن صدای شرکت‌ها به بازارها است. با توجه به اینکه تبلیغات برای بنگاه‌ها، هزینه‌های زیادی در بردارد و سالانه میلیون­­ها ریال صرف آن می­شود، همواره مدیران بنگاه­های اقتصادی انتظار دارند بازدهی متناسب با این میزان سرمایه‌گذاری به دست آورند. این مقاله با هدف پاسخگویی به این پرسش، تأثیر هزینۀ تبلیغات در عملکرد مالی شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار را با میانجی­گری ارزش برند بررسی کرده است. در این پژوهش، داده‌های مربوط به 88 شرکت به‌صورت ترکیبی و برای دورۀ زمانی 1389 تا 1394 با استفاده از رگرسیون چندمتغیره تجزیه ‌و تحلیل شده است. در این پژوهش از معیار کیو توبین برای سنجش ارزش برند استفاده‌ شده است. نتایج پژوهش نشان داد ارزش برند، نقش میانجی در ارتباط بین هزینۀ تبلیغات و عملکرد مالی (نرخ بازده دارایی­ها و نرخ بازده حقوق صاحبان سهام) بر عهده دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Considering the fact that consumers are exposed to a lot of goods and services from different suppliers, advertisement is one of the most powerful ways to echo the voice of the firms in such environments. Since advertising is an expensive activity and has a burden on companies’ budgets, managers and shareholders always like to know if it has a rational and significant output regarding their investment and expenditures (they like to know if it has a significant return on investment). This paper, seeking to answer this question of managers and shareholders, has investigated the effect of advertising costs on the financial performance of the firms listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. We used data of 88 firms from 2010-2015 and multivariate regression to analyze this data. Q Tobin is used to measure brand equity. Results show that brand equity has a mediating role in the relationship between advertising costs and financial performance.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>151</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>162</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>اکبری</Family>
						<NameE>Mohsen</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Akbari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار مدیریت دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، گروه مدیریت دانشگاه گیلان، دانشگاه گیلان، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، گروه مدیریت</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار مدیریت دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>akbarimohsen@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهسا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فرخنده</Family>
						<NameE>Mahsa</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Farkhonde</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، گروه مدیریت دانشگاه گیلان، دانشگاه گیلان، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، گروه مدیریت</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی دانشکده ادبیات</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mahsa.farkhondeh85@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>معصومه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قاسمی شمس</Family>
						<NameE>Masoomeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ghasemi Shams</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، گروه مدیریت دانشگاه گیلان، دانشگاه گیلان، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، گروه مدیریت</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی دانشکده ادبیات</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>masoomeh.shams68@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ارزش برند</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اندازه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عملکرد مالی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نسبت اهرمی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هزینۀ تبلیغات</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Assef, G., Josiassen, A., Mattila, A., &amp; Cvelbar, L. (2015). Does advertising spending improve sales performance?. International Journal of Hospitality Management. 48: 161–166.##[2] Başgoze, P., &amp; Sayin, C. (2013). The effect of R&amp;D expenditure (investments) on firm value: Case of Istanbul stock exchange. Journal of Business Economics and Finance.  2 (3): 5-12.## [3] Belo, f., Lin X., Vitorino, M. A. (2014). Brand capital and firm value.  University of Pennsylvania - The Wharton School.##[4] Conchar, M. P., Crask, M. R., &amp; Zinkhan, G. M. (2005). Market valuation models of the effect of advertising and promotional spending: A review and Meta-Analysis. Journal of the Academy of Marketing Science. 33: 445–460.##[5] Deanna Wang, H., Sengupta,S. (2016). Stakeholder relationships, brand equity, firm performance: A resource-based perspective. Journal of Business Research. 69(12): 5561–5568.##[6] Eng, L., Keh, H. (2007). The effects of advertising and brand value on future operating and market performance. Journal of Advertising. 36(4): 91-100.##[7] Erickson, G., Jacobson, R. (1992). Gaining comparative advantage through discretionary expenditures: the returns to R&amp;D and advertising, Management Science. 38(9): 1264-1279##[8] Forootan, O., Taghipoor, M., Ghabdiyan, B. (1391). The trademark’s value and its relation with performance indicators, A Quarterly Journal of Empirical Research of Financial Accounting. 2(4): 125-139. (In Persian)##[9] González-Pedraz, C., Mayordomo, S. (2011). Trademark activity and the market performance of U.S. commercial banks, Journal of Business Economics and Management. 14: 2-27.##[10] Greene, W. (2011). Econometric Analysis. Seventh ed. USA:  Prentice-hall.##[11] Hasanzadeh, M. (1389). Advertising cost and marketing value. Journal of Business Management. 3(36): 25-36. (In Persian)##[12] Hsu, J., Shawm, J. (2008). Advertising expenditure, intangible value and risk: a study of restaurant companies. International Journal of Hospitality Management. 27(2): 259-267.##[13] Jacobson, R., Mizik, N. (2003). Trading off between value creation and value appropriation: the financial implications of shifts in strategic emphasis. Journal of Marketing. 67: 63–76.##[14] Karen S.C., Gulding, C. (1999). Strategic brand valuation: a cross functional perspective.  Business Horizons. 42(4): 53-62.##[15] Kee Ho, H., Tat Keh, H., Mei Ong, J. (2005). The effects of R&amp;D and advertising on firm value: An examination of manufacturing and nonmanufacturing firms. Transactions on Engineering Management. 52(1): 3-14.##[16] Khodadadi, N. (1387). Investigating effect advertising cost on intangible firm value of listed companies in Tehran stock exchange.  A Quarterly Journal of Studies of Financial Accounting. 24: 53-78. (In Persian)##[17] Kundu, A. (2008). Advertising and firm value: mapping the relationship between advertising, profitability and business strategy in India. Working Paper: Indian Business Academy Bangalore. India.##[18] McAlister, L., Srinivasan, R., Jindal, N., Cannella, A. (2015). Advertising effectiveness: the moderating effect of firm strategy. Journal of Marketing Research. 53(2): 207-224.## [19] Peterson, R., Jeong, J. (2010). Exploring the impact of advertising and R&amp;D expenditures on corporate brand value and firm-level financial performance.  Journal of the Academic Marketing Science. 38: 677–690.##[20] Salehi, M. (1392). Investigating effect advertising on financial performance and risk of listed companies in Tehran stock exchange, The 11th Accounting Conference, Mashhad Ferdosi University (In Persian).##[21] Srindhar, S., Narayanan, S., Srinvasan, R. (2014). Dynamic relationships among R&amp;D, advertising, inventory and firm performance. Journal of academic marketing science. 42: 277-290.##[22] Srivastava, R.K., Rubinstein, D.J., Joshi, Y. V. (2006). Linking marketing metrics to financial performance. Zyman Institute of Brand Science.##[23] Srivastavar, R., Merino, M., Srinivasan, R. (2006). Advertising, R&amp;D and variability of cash flow and intangible firm value. Working Paper: Institute Technology of Autonomo de Mexico.##[24] Ukiwe, A. (2009). The joint impact of brand value and advertising on corporate financial performance and on stock return: a case study of the computer industry, Walden University##[25] Zolfaghari, A. (2012). Analyzing impact of brand value and advertising costs on financial performance of listed companies in Tehran stock exchange from view point of Shareholders. Journal of Basic and Applied Scientific Research. 2(6): 5459-5465.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی رابطۀ توسعۀ جهانی و سطح نگهداشت وجه نقد شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران با استفاده از رگرسیون تابلویی آستانه‌ای</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigating the Relationship between Global Development and the Level of Cash Holdings in Companies Listed in Tehran Stock Exchange Using Panel Threshold Regression</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در دهه­های اخیر، روند جهانی‌سازی شرکت­ها و شکل‌گیری فضاهای رقابتی جدید به توجه ویژه به امر صادرات به‌عنوان عاملی حیاتی برای بقا و رشد بسیاری از شرکت­ها منجر شده است. در این پژوهش، پس از طبقه‌بندی شرکت­های نمونۀ مدّنظر به دو گروه شرکت‌های محلی و با توسعۀ جهانی، رابطۀ سطح نگهداشت وجه نقد و توسعۀ جهانی شرکت­ها بررسی شد. در این راستا، تعداد 88 شرکت پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در دورۀ زمانی 1389 تا 1393 بررسی شد. نتایج حاصل از آزمون­های پژوهش نشان می­دهد، گرایش شرکت­ها به سوی جهانی‌شدن، نقش تعیین‌کننده­ای در سطح نگهداشت وجه نقد آنها دارد. همچنین بر مبنای نتایج پژوهش آشکار شد رابطۀ U معکوسی بین افزایش صادرات در راستای توسعۀ جهانی شرکت­ها و سطح نگهداشت وجه نقد آنها وجود دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>During recent decades, corporate globalization and the new competitive environment have led to the formation of specific attention to exports as a crucial factor to the survival and growth of many companies. In this study, the sample was divided into two groups, local and global developed companies, and the relationship between level of cash holding and the level of global development was studied. In this regard, 88 companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange during the period 2009 to 2014 were studied. The results of the tests indicate that the trend toward globalization plays a determining role in corporate cash holdings. Also based on the results, it was evident that an inverted U relationship between exports increased in line with global development and corporate cash holdings.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>163</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>176</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سعید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فرزادی</Family>
						<NameE>saeed</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>farzadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>مربی گروه حسابداری دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری موسسه آموزش عالی امام جواد (ع) یزد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>مربی گروه حسابداری دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>farzadi_isfahanuni@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>صابر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مولایی</Family>
						<NameE>saber</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>molaei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری اقتصاد گروه اقتصاد دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصاد دانشگاه اصفهان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری اقتصاد گروه اقتصاد دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>saber.molai@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>توسعۀ جهانی شرکت‌ها</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سطح نگهداشت وجه نقد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الگوی رگرسیون آستانه‌ای</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Arabsalehi, M., Ashrafi Azarkharani, M. (2011). Investment-Cash flow Sensitivity of Cash Reserves in Firms Listed on Tehran Stock Exchange. M.A Thesis. Isfahan University.##[2] Arata, H. H. Sheng, M. Lora, I. (2015). Internationalization and Corporate Cash Holdings: Evidence from Brazil and Mexico.  RAC Jeniuro, 19: 1-19.##[3] Alimov,A (2014). Product MarketCompetition and the Value of Corporate Cash. Research Centre for International Economics. City University of Hong Kong.##[4] Almeida, H. Campello, M., Weisbach, M.S. (2004). The cash flow sensitivity of cash, Journal of Finance, 59:39-56.##[5] Azimi, M. Sabagh, M. (2014). Value relation of cash holdings in companies listed in of Tehran Stock Exchange. Quarterly Financial Accounting. 21:61-80.##[6] Bao, D., Chan, K., &amp; Zhang, W. (2012). Asymmetric cash flow sensitivity of cash holdings. Journal of Corporate Finance, 18: 690-700.##[7] Beuselinck, C., Yan, D. (2016). Determinants of cash holdings in multinational corporation’s foreings subsidiaries: U.S. subsidiaries in china. Corporate Governance: An International Review, 25: 49-63.##[8] Bodnar, G. Weintrop, J. (1997). The valuation of the foreign income of U.S. multinational firms: A growth opportunities perspective. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 24: 69-98.##[9] Chiang, Y.-C., &amp; Wang, C.-D. (2011). Corporate international activities and cash holdings. African Journal of Business Management, 5:2992-3000.##[10] Chang, K. Noorbakhsh, A. (2006). Corporate cash holdings, foreign direct investment, and corporate governance. Global Finance. Journal, 16: 111-133.##[11] Chen CJP, Cheng CSA, He J, Kim J (1997). An investigation of the relationship between international activities and capital structure. Journal of International Business Studies, 28(3): 563-577.##[12] Doukas J. A., Pantzalis, C (2003). Geographic diversification and agency costs of debt of multinational firms. Journal of Corporate Finance, 9: 59-92.##[13] Dittmar, A., Duchin, R. (2013). Looking in the rear view mirror: The effect of managers’ professional experience on corporate cash holdings. Journal of Finance, 50: 1-51.##[14] Fakhari, H., Taghavi, R., Bashirijuybari, M. (2015). The impact of product market competition on the market value of cash holdings of companies, The knowledge of Financial Accounting Journal. 1:47-65.##[15] Foroughi, D., Farzadi, S. (2013). The Effect of Changes In Cash Flows on Cash Holdings With a View To Financing Constraints Of Listed Companies In Tehran Stock Exchange. M.A Thesis. Isfahan University.##[16] Foroughi, D., Farzadi, S. (2014). The effect of changes in cash flows on cash holdings with regard to the limitation of financial companies listed on Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Asset Management and Financing. 2:21-36.##[17] Grant R. M. (1987). Multinationality and performance among British manufacturing companies. Journal of International Business Studies, 18(1): 79-89.##[18] Garcia-Teruel, P. J. P. Martinez-Solano, J. &amp; Sanchez-Ballesta, P. (2009). Accruals quality and corporate cash holdings, Journal of Accounting and Finance, 49: 95-115.##[19] GuneyYilmaz، OzkanAydin، OzkanNeslihan، (2003). Additional international evidence on corporate cash holdings, available at www.ssrn.com, id=406721.##[20] Hansen B. E. (1999). Threshold effects in non-dynamic panels: Estimation, testing and inference. Journal of Econometrics. 93: 345-368.##[21] Hittman R., Stevehollen (2010). International evidence on cash holdings and expected managerial agency problems. Review of Financial Studies, 20(4):1087-1112.##[22] Hymer (1976). The threshold of internationalization: replication, extension, and reinterpretation manage. International Reviews, 34(2): 165-186.##[23] Izadiniya, N. &amp; Rasaeiyan A. (2010). Monitoring tools of corporate governance, cash holdings and performance of listed companies in Tehran Stock Exchange. Research and Economic Policies. 55: 141-154.##[24] Kadapakkam P. R. Kumar, P., &amp; Riddick, L., (1998). The impact of cash flows and firm size on investment: the international evidence. Journal of Banking and Finance 22:293-320.##[25] Kashanipour, M. Naqinejad, B. (2009). The effect of financing constraints on cash flow sensitivity of cash. Accounting Research Journal. 2:72-93.##[26] Kashanipour, M., Rasekhi, S, Naqinejad, B. &amp; Rasaeiyan, A. (2010). Financial constraints and the sensitivity of investment to cash flows in the Tehran Stock Exchange. Accounting Advances Journal. 3:51-74.##[27] Lee K. C., Kwok C. (1988). Multinational corporations vs. domestic corporations: international environmental factors and determinants of capital structure. Journal of International Business Studies, 19(1): 195-217.##[28] Lee S, Habet DM (2004). Corporate international activity and debt financing. Journal of International Business Studies, 33(1): 129-147.##[29] Opler, T., Pinkowitz, L., &amp; Stulz, R. (1999). The determinants and implications of corporate cash holdings. Journal of Finance Economics, 52(1): 3-46.##[30] Ozkan A., Ozkan N. (2004). Corporate cash holdings: An empirical investigation of UK companies. Journal of Banking Finance, 28: 2103–2134.##[31] Riddick, L., Whited, T., 2009. The Corporate propensity to save. The Journal of Finance, 64, 1729-1766.##[32] Ramirez, A., Tadesse, S. (2009). Corporate cash holdings, uncertainty avoidance, and the multinationality of firm. International Business Review, 18, 387-403.##[33] Rasaeiyan, A., Hanjari, S. &amp; Rahimi, F. (2010).The effect of regulatory mechanisms of corporate governance in the cash holdings. Research of Financial Accounting Journal. 6:11-21. [34] Tahmasebi, I., Soleimani, S. (2011). The impact of macroeconomic variables on stock returns Investment Companies listed on Tehran Stock Exchange. Economic Research Journal, 5:209-236.##[35] Whited, T. M., Wu, G. (2006). Financial constraint risk. Review of Financial Studies. 19, 531–559.##[36] Wright F. W., Madura, J., &amp; Wiant, K. (2002). The differential effects of agency costs on multinational corporations. Applied Financial Economics, 12: 347-359##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تعیین نسبت بهینۀ پوشش ریسک قراردادهای آتی سکه: رهیافت مقایسه‌ای</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Determining the Optimal Hedge Ratio of Gold Coin Futures; A Comparative Approach</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف این پژوهش، محاسبۀ نسبت بهینۀ پوشش ریسک قرارداد آتی سکۀ بهار آزادی با استفاده از روش‌های مختلف اقتصادسنجی و مقایسۀ کارایی نتایج آنها با یکدیگر است. الگو‌های استفاده‌شده عبارت است از OLS، VAR، VECM که نسبت بهینۀ پوشش ریسک را به‌صورت ایستا و ثابت در طول زمان تخمین می‌زند و الگو‌های چندمتغیرۀ گارچ شامل CCC-GARCH، DCC-GARCH انگل و DCC-GARCH تز و تسو است که نسبت بهینۀ پوشش ریسک را به‌صورت متغیر در طول زمان تخمین می‌زند. دورۀ زمانی مدّنظر از تاریخ 05/09/1387 تا 11/03/1394 است و در این بازه از قیمت‌های نقدی و آتی سکۀ بهار آزادی استفاده شده است. برای افزایش همبستگی بین بازده‌های آتی و نقدی در محاسبۀ نسبت بهینۀ پوشش ریسک علاوه بر بازده روزانه از بازده هفتگی نیز استفاده‌ شده است. درنهایت، مقایسۀ معیار کارایی برای الگو‌های مختلف نشان می‌دهد استفاده از الگو‌های چندمتغیرۀ گارچ در بازده‌های روزانه، عملکرد بهتری دارد؛ اما در بازده‌های هفتگی این الگو­ها، کارایی بیشتری نسبت به الگو‌های ایستا نمی‌تواند حاصل کنند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The aim of this study is to calculate the optimal hedge ratio of gold coin future contrasts with different econometric methods and compare their hedging effectiveness with each other. Used models are OLS, VAR and VECM that estimate the hedge ratio to be static over the time and multivariate GARCH models that estimate the hedge ratio to be vary over the time. The studied time period was from Tuesday, November 25, 2008 to Monday, June 01, 2015 and we have used the future and spot prices of gold coin in this period. To increase the correlation between future and spot returns we have calculated the optimal hedge ratio with weekly returns in addition to daily returns. Finally, the comparisons show that the use of multivariate GARCH models leads to better performance in daily returns but in weekly returns, static models have better results.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>177</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>196</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سیدبابک</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ابراهیمی</Family>
						<NameE>seyed babak</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>ebrahimi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، دانشگاه صنعتی خواجه ‌نصیرالدین طوسی، دانشکده مهندسی صنایع، گروه مهندسی مالی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، دانشگاه صنعتی خواجه ‌نصیرالدین</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>b_ebrahimi@kntu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>تسبیحی</Family>
						<NameE>ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>tasbihi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مهندسی مالی،دانشگاه صنعتی خواجه‌نصیرالدین طوسی، دانشکده مهندسی صنایع، گروه مهندسی مالی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مهندسی مالی،دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>atabihi@mail.kntu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>حداقل واریانس</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قرارداد آتی سکه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کارایی پوشش ریسک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نسبت بهینۀ پوشش ریسک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>MGARCH</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1]  Baillie, R. T., &amp; Myers, R. J. (1991). Bivariate garch estimation of the optimal commodity futures hedge. Journal of Applied Economics. 6(2), 109-124.##[2]  Bollerslev, T. (1986). Generalized autoregressive conditional heteroskedasticity. Journal of Econometrics, 31(3), 307-327.##[3]  Bollerslev, T. (1990). Modelling the coherence in short-run nominal exchange rates: a multivariate generalized ARCH model. The Review of Economics and Statistics, 498-505.##[4]  Byström, H. N. (2003). The hedging performance of electricity futures on the Nordic power exchange. Applied Economics, 35(1), 1-11.##[5]  Copeland, L. S., &amp; Zhu, Y. (2006). Hedging effectiveness in the index futures market: Cardiff Business School.##[6]  Ederington, L. H. (1979). The hedging performance of the new futures markets. The Journal of Finance, 34(1), 157-170.##[7]  Engle, R. F., &amp; Granger, C. W. (1987). Co-integration and error correction: representation, estimation, and testing. Econometrica: Journal of the Econometric Society, 251-276.##[8]  Engle, R. F., &amp; Sheppard, K. (2001). Theoretical and empirical properties of dynamic conditional correlation multivariate GARCH: National Bureau of Economic Research.##[9]  Ghosh, A. (1993). Cointegration and error correction models: Intertemporal causality between index and futures prices. Journal of Futures Markets, 13(2), 193-198.##[10]             Ghosh, A. (1993). Hedging with stock index futures: Estimation and forecasting with error correction model. Journal of Futures Markets, 13(7), 743-752.##[11]             Howard, C. T., &amp; D&#039;Antonio, L. J. (1984). A risk-return measure of hedging effectiveness. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis, 19(01), 101-112.##[12]             Bahrami, J., &amp; Mirzapoor Babajan, A. (2013). Optimal hedge ratio for gold coin futures contracts traded in iran mercantile exchange (IME). Journal of Economic Research and Policies, 20(64), 175-206.##[13]             Johnson, L. L. (1960). The theory of hedging and speculation in commodity futures. The Review of Economic Studies, 139-151.##[14]             Junkus, J. C., &amp; Lee, C. F. (1985). Use of three stock index futures in hedging decisions. Journal of Futures Markets, 5(2), 201-222.##[15]             Kahl, K. H., &amp; Tomek, W. G. (1986). Forward-pricing models for futures markets: Some statistical and interpretative issues. Food Research Institute Studies, 20(1).##[16]             Lien, D., Shrestha, K., &amp; Wu, J. (2016). Quantile estimation of optimal hedge ratio. Journal of Futures Markets, 36(2), 194-214.##[17]             Lien, D., Tse, Y. K., &amp; Tsui, A. K. (2002). Evaluating the hedging performance of the constant-correlation GARCH model. Applied Financial Economics, 12(11), 791-798.##[18]             Moosa, I. (2003). The sensitivity of the optimal hedge ratio to model specification. Finance Letters, 1(1), 15-20.##[19]             Myers, R. J., &amp; Thompson, S. R. (1989). Generalized optimal hedge ratio estimation. American Journal of Agricultural Economics, 858-868.##[20]             Park, T. H., &amp; Switzer, L. N. (1995). Bivariate GARCH estimation of the optimal hedge ratios for stock index futures: A note. Journal of Futures Markets, 15(1), 61-67.##[21]             Sah, A. N., &amp; Pandey, K. K. (2011). Hedging effectiveness of index futures contract: The case of S&amp;P CNX Nifty. Global Journal of Finance and Management, 3(1), 77-89.##[22]             Sajad, R., &amp; Torosian, A. (2014). Exchange rate optimal hedge ratio by gold futures in Iran. Journal of Investment Knowledge, 3(12), 1-24.##[23]             Tse, Y. K., &amp; Tsui, A. K. C. (2002). A multivariate generalized autoregressive conditional heteroscedasticity model with time-varying correlations. Journal of Business &amp; Economic Statistics, 20(3), 351-362.##[24]             Wang, G.-J., Xie, C., He, L.-Y., &amp; Chen, S. (2014). Detrended minimum-variance hedge ratio: A new method for hedge ratio at different time scales. Physica A: Statistical Mechanics and its Applications, 405, 70-79.##[25]             Wang, J., &amp; Hsu, H. (2010). Hedge ratio stability and hedging effectiveness of time‐varying hedge ratios in volatile index futures markets: Evidence from the Asian financial crisis*. Asia‐Pacific Journal of Financial Studies, 39(5), 659-686.##[26]             Zhou, J. (2015). Hedging performance of REIT index futures: A comparison of alternative hedge ratio estimation methods. Economic Modelling.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				