<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Measuring systemic risk in the financial institution via dynamic conditional correlation and delta conditional value at risk mode and bank rating</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اندازه‏ گیری ریسک سیستمیک با استفاده از کسری نهایی مورد انتظار و ارزش در معرض خطر شرطی و رتبه‌بندی بانک‌ها</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>16</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">23292</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2019.112150.1283</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>عیوضلو</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت مالی و بیمه ،  دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران 
تهران، بزرگراه جلال آل احمد، جنب پل گیشا، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، اتاق 130</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9336-078X</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>رامشگ</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد مالی-حقوق مالی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Systematic risk (in economics often called aggregate risk or undiversifiable risk) is vulnerability to events which affect aggregate outcomes such as broad market returns, total economy-wide resource holdings, or aggregate income. In many contexts, events like earthquakes and major weather catastrophes pose aggregate risks they affect not only the distribution but also the total amount of resources. In this paper we study systemic risks in the Iranian banking sector by using two famous systemic risk measures theMES (marginal expected shortfall) and CoVaR. To compute both measures we employ Engle&#039;s dynamic conditional correlation model. Our empirical analysis shows, first, that although these two systemic risk measures differ in defining the contributions to systemic risk, both are qualitatively very similar in explaining the cross-sectional differences in systemic risk contributions across banks. Last, using a threshold VAR model, we suggest an overall systemic risk measure – the aggregateMES – and its associated threshold value for use as an early warning indicator. The paper is innovative in terms of the use of statistical models (dynamic conditional correlation model) and available data Looking for the rating of commercial banks using by approaches MES and COVAR.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">ریسک سیستمیک به خطر شکست سیستم مالی یا شکست کل بازار اطلاق می‌شود. این ریسک می‌تواند از بی‌ثباتی یا بحران در مؤسسات مالی نشأت بگیرد و در اثر سرایت به کل نظام مالی انتقال یابد. به‌عبارتی ریسک سیستمیک به میزان به‌ هم‌پیوستگی در یک سیستم مالی اشاره دارد جایی‌که شکست در یک نهاد مالی می‌تواند به بحران کل سیستم منجر شود. در مقاله حاضر به تخمین ریسک سیستمیک با استفاده از دو روش کسری نهایی موردانتظار و ارزش در معرض خطر شرطی با استفاده از مدل‏های نوسان شرطی پویا در بین بانک‏های تجاری پرداخته شده است. نتایج پژوهش نشان می‌دهد در سنجش ریسک سیستمیک بین بانک‌های تجاری دو روش کسری نهایی مورد انتظار و ارزش در معرض خطر شرطی نتایج مشابه ارائه می‌کنند. پژوهش حاضر با استفاده از شاخص صنعت بانکداری و با بکارگیری مدل‏های آستانه‏ای خودهمبستگی برداری به تعریف یک آستانه به‌منظور مدل‌سازی بحران پرداخته است. پژوهش حاضر از این لحاظ نوآوری دارد که با استفاده از مدل‏های اماری (الگوی همبستگی شرطی پویا یکی از روش‏های مبتنی بر گارچ چند متغیره) و داده‏های دردسترس به دنبال رتبه‏بندی بانک‏های تجاری با استفاده از دو رویکرد کسری نهایی مورد انتظار و ارزش در معرض خطر شرطی است</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ریسک سیستمیک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کسری نهایی موردانتظار (MES)</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزش در معرض خطر شرطی (COVAR)‏</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل همبستگی شرطی پویا (DCC)</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل‏های آستانه‏ای خودهمبستگی برداری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_23292_751a6e8b0bce78149793a49655108049.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
