<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigation of the Relationship between Working Capital Efficiency and Deviation from the Optimal Level of Capital Structure in Firms Listed in Tehran Stock Exchange</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی رابطۀ کارآیی سرمایه در گردش با انحراف از سطح بهینۀ ساختار سرمایه در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>71</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>84</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">23538</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2019.113193.1309</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>زلقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه حسابداری، دانشکدۀ اقتصاد و علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، همدان، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7507-5897</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>روح اله</FirstName>
					<LastName>آماره</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی‌ارشد، گروه حسابداری، دانشکدۀ اقتصاد و علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، همدان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;Objective: &lt;/strong&gt;Business units are looking for new ways to improve their financial performance and reduce their risk level while financing. Considering previous studies focusing on the role of working capital efficiency on companies finance, we aim to examine the relationship between working capital efficiency and deviation from the optimal level of capital structure.
&lt;strong&gt;Method: &lt;/strong&gt;In this research, two main hypotheses are proposed; firstly, to examine the previously mentioned relationship, and secondly, to measure the difference between the efficiency of working capital and the capital structure in terms of over-leveraged and under-leveraged companies. The data sample is restricted to 179 Firms listed in Tehran Stock Exchange during 2006-2017.
&lt;strong&gt;Results: &lt;/strong&gt;The results demonstrate that with increasing working capital efficiency, the amount of capital structure deviation from the optimal level can be reduced. In addition, the relationship between the efficiency of working capital and the deviation from the optimal level of capital structure in over-leveraged firms is significantly higher than under-leveraged firms.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;اهداف:&lt;/strong&gt; واحدهای تجاری، راهکارهای جدیدی برای رشد و بهبود عملکرد مالی و کاهش ریسک در تأمین منابع مالی جستجو می‌کنند. با توجه به نقش کارآیی سرمایه در گردش در نحوۀ تأمین مالی شرکت‌ها، هدف، بررسی رابطۀ کارآیی سرمایه در گردش با انحراف از سطح بهینۀ ساختار سرمایه است. نوآوری این پژوهش استفاده از الگوی باتاچاریا برای اندازه‌‌گیری کارآیی سرمایه در گردش است.
&lt;strong&gt;روش:&lt;/strong&gt; دورۀ مدنظر برای آزمون فرضیه‌ها، سال‌‌های 1385 تا 1396 بوده و از داده‌‌های 172 شرکت پذیرفته‌‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران استفاده شده است.
&lt;strong&gt;نتایج:&lt;/strong&gt; نتایج حاصل از تخمین الگوی‌‌ پژوهش نشان می‌‌دهد با افزایش کارآیی سرمایه در گردش می‌توان میزان انحراف ساختار سرمایه از سطح بهینه را کاهش داد. افزون بر این، رابطۀ کارآیی سرمایه در گردش با انحراف از سطح بهینۀ ساختار سرمایه در شرکت‌های بیش‌اهرمی به‌‎صورت معناداری از شرکت‌های کم‌اهرمی، قوی‌تر است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارآیی سرمایه در گردش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساختار سرمایۀ بهینه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بیش‌اهرمی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کم‌اهرمی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_23538_490c3da242fa619aca2306e20cb24be1.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
