<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Role some of Corporate Governance Mechanisms in Reducing the Risk of Share Price crash in Accepted Companies in Tehran Stock Exchange</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی نقش برخی سازوکارهای حاکمیت شرکتی در کاهش ریسک ریزش قیمت سهام شرکتهای پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>31</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>50</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19929</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>تنانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه حسابداری دانشگاه علوم اقتصادی تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>صدیقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد حسابداری علوم و تحقیقات ساوه، بانک آینده، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>امیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد حسابداری دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The current study was conducted to investigate the role of corporate governance mechanisms in reducing the risk of share price crash in accepted companies in Tehran stock exchange. To fulfill the purpose of the study, form variable board independence the institutional shareholders, the interior auditor, and the separation of CEO’s duties from those of the CIO were applied as the variables of corporate governance, and 163 companies within 2004-2011 were selected as the sample for the study which totally formed 884 year-company. The analysis of the data showed a meaningful and indirect relationship between institutional shareholders and the risk of share price crash, and a meaningful and direct one between the ratio of board independence and the risk of share price crash. Also, it indicated a direct relationship between the interior auditor and the separation of CEO’s duties from those of the CIO on one hand and the risk of share price fall on the other, but this was not statistically supported. Pedagogically, corporate governance mechanisms affects share price crash.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 115%; font-family: &#039;Arial&#039;,&#039;sans-serif&#039;; font-size: 11pt; mso-ascii-font-family: Calibri; mso-ascii-theme-font: minor-latin; mso-fareast-font-family: Calibri; mso-fareast-theme-font: minor-latin; mso-hansi-font-family: Calibri; mso-hansi-theme-font: minor-latin; mso-bidi-theme-font: minor-bidi; mso-ansi-language: EN-US; mso-fareast-language: EN-US; mso-bidi-language: FA;&quot; lang=&quot;FA&quot; dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;هدف از این پژوهش، بررسی نقش برخی سازوکارهای حاکمیت&lt;br /&gt;شرکتی در کاهش ریسک ریزش قیمت سهام شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار&lt;br /&gt;تهران است.از سهامداران نهادی، نسبت اعضای غیر موظف هیأت مدیره نسبت به اعضای هیأت&lt;br /&gt;مدیره، وجود حسابرس داخلی و تفکیکوظایف مدیرعاملازرییسهیاتمدیره به عنوان متغیرهای&lt;br /&gt;حاکمیت شرکتی استفاده شده و تعداد 163 شرکت در دوره زمانی 90-1383 به عنوان نمونه&lt;br /&gt;آماری انتخاب شدند. یافته‌های پژوهش حاکی از وجود رابطه منفی و معنادار بین&lt;br /&gt;سهامداران نهادی و ریسک ریزش قیمت سهام، و رابطه مثبت و معنادار بین نسبت اعضای&lt;br /&gt;غیر موظف هیأت مدیره و ریسک ریزش قیمت سهام است؛ به طور کلی، نتایج نشان می­دهد که&lt;br /&gt;سازوکارهای نظام راهبری شرکتی، عاملی تأثیرگذار بر ریسک ریزش قیمت سهام است.&lt;/span&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خطر سقوط قیمت سهام</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حسابرسی داخلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حاکمیت شرکتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سهامداران نهادی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استقلال هیأت مدیره</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_19929_6e6441907c8a8e07100ed4f9d8578b31.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
