<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Rating Tehran Stock Exchange Industries Based on Risk Criteria from the Perspective of Institutional Investors: A Data Envelopment Analysis Approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رتبه‌بندی صنایع بورس تهران بر اساس معیارهای ریسک از منظر سرمایه‌گذاران نهادی؛ رویکرد تحلیل پوششی داده‌ها (DEA)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>49</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>64</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">20639</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2016.20639</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فریدون</FirstName>
					<LastName>رهنمای رودپشتی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات، تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرزانه</FirstName>
					<LastName>اشعریون قمی زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حامد</FirstName>
					<LastName>تاجمیر ریاحی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه امام صادق(ع)</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The goal of this research is to rate Tehran Stock Exchange industries based on different risk criteria from the perspective of institutional investors. We first reviewed the literature of industry risk criteria and then we interviewed some managers working in institutional investors. In the next step all the risk criteria were evaluated by institutional investors’ managers to select more important criteria using a questionnaire with Likert scale. Finally the selected criteria in the last step ranked by AHP process to identify the best industries for investment from the view point of institutional investors. In the second phase of the research we ranked the TSE industries based on Anderson Peterson Model and the weighted risk criteria. The results show that three of eight important risk criteria for industry analysis from institutional investor’s viewpoint are industry return volatility p/e volatility and sum of days symbols closed in the industry. Finally, basic metals and financial services are identified as two less risky industries selected by institutional investors based on the eight risk criteria.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">سرمایه‌گذاران نهادی طبق قانون بازار سرمایه عبارت‌اند از: شرکت­های سرمایه‌گذاری و صندوق­های مشترک. این دسته از سرمایه‌گذاران به نظر می‌رسد از جهت معیارهای انتخاب صنعت و ریسک مدنظر، با سرمایه‌گذاران خرد متفاوت باشند. در این پژوهش که رویکرد آن کیفی ـ کمی است، از روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی، جهت رتبه‌بندی معیارهای ریسک و از تحلیل پوششی، جهت رتبه‌بندی صنایع مختلف استفاده‌شده است. نتایج پژوهش حاضر، حاکی از آن است که از منظر سرمایه‌گذاران نهادی جهت رتبه‌بندی صنایع بورس، هشت معیار ریسک مدنظر قرار می‌گیرد. مهم‌ترین معیارهای ریسک به ترتیب عبارت­اند از: دامنه نوسان بازده صنعت، دامنه نوسان قیمت به عایدی صنعت و مجموع تعداد روزهای توقف نماد در صنعت. در میان صنایع بورس از منظر نهادی­ها و با توجه به معیارهای ریسک کاراترین و کم ریسک­ترین صنایع، صنعت زیر بنایی فلزات اساسی و فعالیت­های مالی و واسطه‌گری است.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;  </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رتبه بندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صنایع بورس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معیارهای ریسک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل پوششی داده‌ها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل سلسله مراتبی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_20639_037d3f72683ded0e2967b7f50a10cd41.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
