<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1396</YEAR>
<VOL>5</VOL>
<NO>1</NO>
<MOSALSAL>16</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>116</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر مدیریت واقعی سود و انگیزه‌های مدیریت بر چسبندگی هزینه‌ها</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Effect of Real Earnings Management and Managerial Incentives on Sticky Costs</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>پژوهش حاضر تأثیر مدیریت واقعی سود و انگیزه‌های مدیریت بر میزان چسبندگی هزینه‌ها را بررسی می‌کند. چسبندگی هزینه به این معنی است که نسبت کاهش هزینه‌ها در هنگام کاهش فروش کمتر از نسبت افزایش هزینه‌ها در هنگام افزایش فروش است. طبق نظریۀ‌ تصمیم‌های آگاهانه، چسبندگی هزینه‌ها نتیجۀ تصمیم‌های آگاهانۀ مدیران است. این مطالعه بر حالتی تمرکز می‌کند که در آن مدیران به هنگام کاهش فروش، با انگیزۀ پرهیز از زیان و کاهش سود، به تعدیل آگاهانۀ منابع اقدام می‌کنند. جامعۀ آماری این پژوهش، شامل نمونه‌ای از 135 شرکت حاضر در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران برای یک دورۀ 10 ساله از سال 1383 تا 1392 است. برای آزمون فرضیه‌ها از الگوی رگرسیونی چندمتغیره‌ استفاده شده است. نتایج نشان می‌دهد مدیران هنگام کاهش فروش یعنی زمانی که برای پرهیز از زیان انگیزه دارند، کنار‌گذاشتن منابع بدون استفاده را سرعت می‌بخشند و منابع را به‌طور آگاهانه تعدیل می‌کنند. این تصمیم آگاهانه، چسبندگی هزینه‌ها را کاهش می‌دهد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>This research aims to investigate the effect of real earnings management and managerial incentives on sticky costs. Sticky costs phenomenon represents that the costs do not change in proportion to changes in sales. In other words, the percentage of the reduction in costs when sales are reducing is less than the percentage of cost increase when the sales are increasing. In accordance with the “deliberate decision” theory, costs become sticky because of the deliberate decision of managers. This study focuses on managers’ resource adjustments when sales decline. The resource adjustments motivated to meet earnings targets and the ensuing cost structures. The research include a sample of 135 companies in the Tehran Stock Exchange for a period of 10 years from 2003 to 2013. For testing the hypothesis, multiple regression models based on panel data analysis is used. The results indicate that when managers face incentive to avoid losses, they accelerate sliding adjustment of slack resources for sales decreases. These decisions diminish the degree of cost stickiness.  </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>16</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>غلامرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>منصورفر</Family>
						<NameE>Gholamreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mansourfar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه حسابداری و مدیریت دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت دانشگاه ارومیه، ارومیه، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه حسابداری و مدیریت دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>g.mansourfar@urmia.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حیدری</Family>
						<NameE>Mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Heidari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه حسابداری و مدیریت دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت دانشگاه ارومیه، ارومیه، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه حسابداری و مدیریت دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.heydari@urmia.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>طاهره</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کولانی</Family>
						<NameE>Tahereh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Colani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه حسابداری و مدیریت دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت دانشگاه ارومیه، ارومیه، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه حسابداری و مدیریت دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>taharehcolani@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت واقعی سود</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>انگیزههای مدیریت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>چسبندگی هزینه ها</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نظریۀ تصمیم‌های آگاهانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اهداف سود</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1]   Anderson, M. C, Banker R. Huang, R. Janakirman, S. (2007). Cost behavior and fundamental analysis of SG&amp;A costs, Journal of Accounting, Auditing &amp; Finance. 22(1): 1-28.##[2]   Anderson, M. C.Banker, R. Janakiraman,  S. (2003). Are selling, general and administrative costs&quot;sticky&quot;?. Journal of Accounting Research. 41(1): 47-63.##[3]   Banker, R. and Chen, L. (2008). Predicting earnings sing a model based on cost variability and cost stickiness. The Accounting Review. 81(2): 285-307.##[4]   Banker, R. M. Ciftci, R. Masruwala. (2011). Managerial optimism and cost behavior. Working Paper, Temple University.##[5]   Banker, R. D. Byzalon, D. and. Plehn-Dujowich, J. M. (2011). Sticky cost behavior: Theory and evidence. Working paper, Temple University.##[6]   Bolou, G. Moazez, E. Khan-Hosseini, D. NikooNesbati, M. (2012). The relationship between managers’ standpoints and ‘sticky prices’ in tehran stock exchange. The Journal of Planning and Budgeting. 17(3): 79-95.##[7]   Burgstahler, D. and Dichen, I.(1997). Earnings management to avoid earnings decreases and losses. Journal of Accounting and Economics. 24(1): 99–136.##[8]   Calleja, K. Steliaros, M. and Thomas, D.C. (2006).  A note on cost stickiness: Some international comparisons. Management Accounting Research. 17(2): 127-140.##[9]   Chen,C. L, H. L,U and Sougiannis ,T. (2012). The agency problem, corporate governance and the asymmetrical behavior of selling, general, and administrative costs. Contemporary Accounting Research. 29(1): 252- 82.##[10]         Cohen, D. Dey, A. and Lys, T. Z.(2008). Real and accrual-based earnings management in the pre and post-sarbanes-oxley periods. The Accounting Review. 83(3): 757–87.##[11]         Dechow, P. and Sloan, R. G. (1991).  Executive incentives and the horizon problem: An empirical investigation. Journal of Accounting and Economics. 14(1): 51–89.##[12]         Ghaemi, M .H. Nematolahi, M. (2006). To study the behavior of selling, general, and administrative (S G&amp;A) cost and cost of goods sold in manufacturing firms accepted Tehran security exchange. Accounting Studies. 18(4): 71-89.##[13]         Ghaemi M .H. Nematolahi M.(2007). Further evidence on the sticky behaviour of operating costs and financial expenses in manufacturing firms accepted tehran security exchange Committ. Auditing Knowledge. 22(4): 16-29.##[14]          Gunny, K. (2005). What are the consequences of real earnings management?. Retrivef from: http://ssrn.com/abstract=816025.##[15]         Heydari, M. (2014). Examining managerial overconfidence behavioral explanation effect on cost stickiness: Comparison with economic and agency theory based factors. Accounting Studies QuarterlyJournal. 21(2): 151-172.##[16]          Kama, I. Weiss, D. (2012). Do Earning targets and managerial incentives affect sticky costs?. Journal of Accounting Research. 51(1): 201-224##[17]         Kama, I. Weiss, D. (2010). Do managers’ deliberate decisions induce sticky costs?. Working paper, Tel Aviv University.##[18]         . Khaleghi Moghadam, H. Karami, F.(1999). Predicting earnings using a model based on cost variability and cost stickiness. Experimental Studies Financial Accounting. 23(3): 19-42.##[19]         Kordestani, G. Mortazavi S, M. (2012). The identification of determinant factors costs stickiness. Journal of Financial Accounting Research. 13(3): 13-32.##[20]         Kordestani, G. Mortazavi, S.M. (2012). The impact of managers deliberate decisions on costs stickiness. Journal of Accounting Studies Quarterly. 67(1): 73-90.##[21]         Mansourfar, Gh. Ziaei, R. (2013). Real and accounting earnings management and the level of conservatism in successful and unsuccessful firms. Journal of Financial Accounting Research. 5(3): 19-40.##[22]         Medeiros, O. R. Costa, P. S.(2004). Cost stickiness in Brazilian firms. Online: http://www.ssrn.com.##[23]         Namazi, M. (1998). The behavioral implications of “activity-based costing” (ABC) in managerial accounting. Journal of Accounting Studies Quarterly. 27(1): 71-106.##[24]         Namazi, M. Davanipor, E. (2009). Empirical evaluation of the sticky behavior of costs in the Tehran stock exchange market. Journal of Accounting Studies Quarterly. 6(4): 85-102.##[25]         Petersen, M. (2009). Estimating standard errors in finance panel data sets: Comparing approaches. The Review of Financial Studies. 22(1): 435–80.##[26]         Ranjani Krishnan. (2015) Management accountant—what ails thee?. Journal of Management Accounting Research. 27(1): 177-191.##[27]         Roychowdchury,S. (2006). Earning management through real activities manipulation. Journal of Accounting and Economics. 42(3): 335-70.##[28]         Sepasi, S. Fathi, Z. Sheibe, S. (2014). Empirical investigation of cost stickiness in Tehran stock exchange. Journal of Empirical Research in Accounting. 13(4):163-177.##[29]         Subramaniam, c. Weidenmier, M. L. (2003). Additional evidence on the sticky behavior of costs. Working Paper, texas Christian University.##[30]         Thomas, W. Guenther · Anja Riehl · Richard Rößler. (2014). Cost stickiness: state of the art of research and implications. Journal of Management Control. 24(4): 301–318.##[31]         Weiss, D. (2010). Cost behavior and analysts, earnings forecasts. The Accounting Review. 85 (4), 1441-1471.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مقایسۀ الگوی پنج‌عاملی فا ما و فرنچ با الگوی چهارعاملی کارهارت در تبیین بازده سهام شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A Comparison between Fama-French Five Factor Model and Carhart Four-Factor Model in Explaining the Stock Return of Companies Listed in the Tehran Stock Exchange</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>پیش‌بینی نرخ بازده سهام، همواره یکی از مهم‌ترین مباحث بازارهای مالی بوده است. این پژوهش با استفاده از آزمون معنی‌داری ضرایب متغیرهای توضیحی الگو‌ها و الگوی رگرسیون داده‌های ترکیبی واحدهای مقطعی و سری زمانی و ضریب تعیین تعدیل‌شده، الگوی پنج‌عاملی فاما و فرنچ و الگوی چهارعاملی کارهارت را برای تبیین بازده سهام شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در قلمرو زمانی بین سال‌های 1387 تا 1392 مقایسه کرده است. متغیرهای الگوی کارهارت شامل عوامل صرف ریسک بازار، ارزش، اندازه و مومنتوم است. در الگوی پنج عاملی فاما و فرنچ، افزون بر عوامل الگوی کارهارت از عامل سودآوری نیز استفاده شده است. نتایج پژوهش نشان می‌دهد از لحاظ آماری، عوامل صرف ریسک بازار، اندازه و ارزش بر بازده سهام تأثیر می‌گذارند و دو عامل مومنتوم و سودآوری بر بازده سهام تأثیری ندارند. به بیان دیگر نتایج پژوهش نشان می‌دهد در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، الگوی سه‌عاملی فاما و فرنچ صدق می‌کند؛ اما الگوی چهارعاملی کارهارت و پنج‌عاملی فاما و فرنچ صدق نمی‌کند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>predicting stock returns has been one of the most important financial market issues. In this paper, we compare the five-factor model of Fama and French model and four-factor model of Carhart to explain stock returns of listed companies in the Tehran Stock Exchange during 1387-1392. Carhart model variables include market risk premium, value, size and momentum. The variables included in the five factor model of Fama and French are market risk premium, value, size, momentum and profitability factors. The results show that there is a significant relation between stock return and market risk premium, size, and value factors. However, momentum and profitability do not show a significant relation with stock returns. In other words, the results show that in the Tehran Stock Exchange, Fama and French three-factor model is credible, while Carhart four-factor model and Fama and French five-factor model does not valid.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>17</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>30</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حمیدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>وکیلی فرد</Family>
						<NameE>Hamid Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Vakilifard</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه حسابداری دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه حسابداری دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه آزاد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>vakilifard.phd@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>الهه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بدریان</Family>
						<NameE>elahe</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>badrian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه حسابداری دانشکده حسابداری موسسۀ آموزش عالی و غیرانتفاعی امین فولادشهر، اصفهان، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه حسابداری دانشکده حسابداری موسسۀ آموزش</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>elahe_badrian@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ابراهیمی</Family>
						<NameE>mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>ebrahimi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه حسابداری موسسۀ آموزش عالی و غیرانتفاعی راغب اصفهانی، اصفهان، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه حسابداری موسسۀ آموزش عالی و غیرانتفاعی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ebrahimi_liv@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الگوی پنج‌عاملی فاما و فرنچ</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الگوی چهارعاملی کارهارت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مومنتوم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>صرف ریسک بازار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Hajiannejad, A. &amp; Izadinia, N. (2014). A Comparison between basic Fama and French three Factor model and basic Carhart four factors Model in Explaining the Stock return on Tehran Stock Exchange, Journal of Asset Management and Financing, Vol. 2, No. 3: 18-27.##[2] Eshraghni, A. &amp; Nashvadian, K. (2007). Testin Fama-French 3 factor model in Tehran Stock Excghange, Sharif Journal, No. 45: 35-51.##[3] Askari, R. H. (2012). Momentum factor effect on the explanatory power of fama -french three-factor model: evidence from tehran stock exchange, Journal of Accounting Knowledge, Vol. 4, No. 12:59-88.##[4] Namazi, M. &amp; Kasgari, M. (2006). Using multifactor model to describe the return of the companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchage, Journal of Social and Humanities Sciences, Vol. 26, No. 1: 120-136.##[5] Hagen, R. (1997), New Theory of Investment, (Translated by Parsaeian, A. &amp; Khodarahmi , B.), 1st ed., (2004). Tehran: Terme.##[6] Artmann, S., Finter, P., &amp; Kempf, A. (2012). Determinants of expected stock returns: Large sample evidence from the German market. Journal of Business Finance &amp; Accounting, 39(5‐6), 758-784.## [7] Carhart, M. M. (1997). On persistence in mutual fund performance. The Journal of finance, 52(1), 57-82.## [8] Campbell, J. Y., Hilscher, J., &amp; Szilagyi, J. (2008). In search of distress risk. The Journal of Finance, 63(6), 2899-2939.## [9] Chen, L., Novy-Marx, R., &amp; Zhang, L. (2011). An alternative three-factor model. vailable at SSRN 1418117.## [10] Cooper, M.J., H. Gulen and M.J. Schill. (2008). Asset Grow and the Cross-Section of Stock Returns, the Journal of Finance. 4: 1609-1651.## [11] Fama, E. F., &amp; French, K. R. (1993). Common risk factors in the returns on stocks and bonds. Journal of financial economics, 33(1), 3-56.## [12] Fama, E. F., &amp; French, K. R. (1996). Multifactor explanations of asset pricing anomalies. The journal of finance, 51(1), 55-84.## [13] Fama, E. F., &amp; French, K. R. (1997). Industry costs of equity. Journal of financial economics, 43(2), 153-193.## [14] Fama, E. F., &amp; French, K. R. (2001). Disappearing dividends: changing firm characteristics or lower propensity to pay?. Journal of Financial economics, 60(1), 3-43.## [15] Fama, Eugene F., and Kenneth R. French. (2005). Financing decisions: Who issues stock? Journal ofFinancial Economics 76, 549–582.## [16] Fama, Eugene F., and Kenneth R. French. (2006a). Profitability, investment, and average returns,Journal of Financial Economics 82, 491–518.## [17] Fama, E. F., &amp; French, K. R. (2007). Disagreement, tastes, and asset prices. Journal of Financial Economics, 83(3), 667-689.## [18] Fama, E. F., &amp; French, K. R. (2008). Dissecting anomalies. The Journal of Finance, 63(4), 1653-1678.## [19] Fama, E. F., &amp; French, K. R. (2012). Luck versus Skill in the Cross‐Section of Mutual Fund Returns. The Journal of Finance, 65(5), 1915-1947.## [20] Fama, E. F., &amp; French, K. R. (2014). Size, value, and momentum in international stock returns. Journal of Financial Economics, 105(3), 457-472.## [21] Fan, S., &amp; Yu, L. (2013). Does the alternative three-factor model explain momentum anomaly better in G12 countries?. Journal of Finance &amp; Accountancy, 12.##[22] Markovitz, H. (1952). A property of Bessel functions and its application to the theory of two rheometers. Journal of Applied Physics, 23(10), 1070-1077.## [23] Sehgal, S., &amp; Jain, S. (2011). Short-term momentum patterns in stock and sectoral returns: evidence from India. Journal of Advances in Management Research, 8(1), 99-122.## [24] Wang, J., Meric, G., Liu, Z., &amp; Meric, I. (2010). A Comparison of the Determinants of Stock Returns in the 1987 and 2008 Stock Market Meltdowns. Banking and Finance Review, 1(2), 15-26.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تحلیل نظری و تجربی تأثیر توان رقابتی بازار محصول بر بازده سهام شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Theoretical and Empirical Analysis of the Effect of Comparative Influence of Market Production on Stock Returns of Companies Listed in the Tehran Stock Exchange</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>بازده سهام یکی از معیارهای اساسی برای تصمیم‌گیری در بورس اوراق بهادار است. بازده سهام خود به‌تنهایی محتوایی اطلاعاتی دارد که بیشتر سرمایه­گذاران بالفعل و بالقوه در تجزیه و تحلیل مالی و پیش‌بینی­های خود از آن استفاده می­کنند. مطالعات متعددی در مورد بازده سهام انجام گرفته است که نشان می­دهد بازده سهام تحت تأثیر متغیرهای گوناگون قرار می­گیرد. توان رقابتی بازار محصول از جملۀ این عوامل است. هدف اصلی این پژوهش بررسی تأثیر توان رقابتی بازار محصول بر بازده سهام است. معیارهای رقابت بازار محصول در این پژوهش، شامل شاخص­های تمرکز در صنعت، قابلیت جانشینی کالا، اندازۀ بازار، شاخص Q توبین و موانع ورود (شدت سرمایه‌گذاری) هستند. برای این منظور،  نمونه­ای شامل 87 شرکت پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در دورۀ زمانی سال­های 1382 تا 1391 به روش داده­های تابلویی ارزیابی شده‌اند. نتایج پژوهش نشان می­دهد از میان شاخص­های معرفی‌شده، تمرکز صنعت، قابلیت جانشینی کالا، اندازۀ بازار و شاخص Q توبین بر بازده سهام شرکت‌های مذکور، تأثیر منفی و معنادار داشته است؛ ولی موانع ورود بر بازده سهام تأثیر معناداری نداشته است؛ بنابراین می‌توان نتیجه گرفت شرکت‌های با توان رقابتی بالا، بازده پایینی کسب کرده­اند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>One of the fundamental criteria concerning effective decision-making in the stock exchange is stock return which, on its own, possesses an information content that has been used by investors to analyze and predict financial problems. Different studies indicate that shares return will be affected by many variables, one of which is the competitive power of the product market. This study is carried out to find out the effect of the power of the product market competition on stock return of the companies accepted in the Tehran Stock Exchange. The standards of the product market competition are comprised of industry centralization index, goods replacement ability, market size, Tobins Q index, and entrance obstacles (investment intensity). In this study, a sample of 87 companies on the period of 1382 to 1392 has been selected. Considering significant meaning and relation among the presented indexes, the findings suggest that there is a significantly negative relation between industry centralization index, substitute goods capability, market size, Tobins Q index, and shares return of the firms accepted in the Tehran stock exchange. On the other hand, there is no significant relation between entrance obstacles and stock return. The results of analyses indicate that companies with high competitive power have low efficiency.  </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>31</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>44</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>احمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>گوگردچیان</Family>
						<NameE>Ahmad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Googerdchian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه اقتصاد دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصاد دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه اقتصاد دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصاد دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>agoogerdchian@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حیدری سلطان آبادی</Family>
						<NameE>Hassan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Heidary Soltanabadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه حسابداری دانشکده حسابداری دانشگاه بین‌المللی خلیج فارس، بندرعباس، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه حسابداری دانشکده حسابداری دانشگاه بین‌المللی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>heydari_9@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>زینب</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>متفرس</Family>
						<NameE>Zeinab</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mtofares</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه حسابداری دانشکده حسابداری دانشگاه بین المللی خلیج فارس، بندرعباس، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه حسابداری دانشکده حسابداری دانشگاه بین</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ro.haghighi@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بازده سهام</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>توان رقابتی بازار محصول</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شاخص هرفیندال- هیرشمن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شاخص لرنر</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1]  Tehrani, R. (2009). Financial Management, Tehran: Negahe Danesh.##[2]  Setayesh, M. &amp; Kargarfard, M. (2010). A survey on the effect of product market competition on capital structure, Journal of Empirical Research in Accounting, No. 1: 67-91.##[3]  Porter M. (2003). Competitive Strategy, (Translated by Majidi, J. &amp; Mehrpouya, M.) Tehran: Rasa Cultural Services Institution.##[4]  Sekaran, O. (2001). Research Methods in Management, Tehran: Training Center Publications.##[5]  Heidari, H. (2011). An Analysis on the Relationship between Product Market Competition Structure and Capital Structure, Ms.C. Thesis, Khalije Fars International University.##[6]  Masuminia, A. (2003). Desirable market: perfect competition, Journal of Islamic Economy, No. 80: 55-63.##[7]  Hajiha, Z. &amp; Ghassa Maher, L. (2009). A survey on the relationship between capital structure and intangible value of a business unit using Tobin`s Q in Iran`s capital market, Journal of Financial Engineering and Portfolio Management, No. 4: 104-118.##[8]  Namazi, M. &amp; Ebrahimi, s. (2011). A survey on the relationship between product competition structure and stock market, Empirical Studies in Financial Accounting Quarterly, Vol. 2, No. 1:26-36.##[9]  Campbell, J. (1987). Stock Returns and the Term Structure, Journal of Financial Economics, 18: 373-399.##[10]        Demsetz, H. (1973). Industry Structure, Market Rivalry and Public Policy. J Law Econ, 16,1–10.##[11]        Ignatieva, K.; Gallagher, D. (2010). Concentration and Stock Returns: Australian Evidence. International Conference on Economics, Business and Management IPEDR, 2, 452-474.##[12]        Jun, Sang. G, Achla M. and Shawky, H. A. (2002). Liquidity and Stock Returns in Emerging Equity Markets, Emerging Markets Review, 4: 1-24.##[13]        Dan, M., Li-yan, H. and L. ong-hui. (2007). Industry Concentration and Stock Returns in China A-Share Market. International Conference on Management Science &amp; Engineering, 14: 20-22.##[14] Keim, Donald B., and Robert F. Stambaugh. (1986). Predicting Returnsin the Stock and Bound Market, Journal of Financial Economics, 17: 357-390.##[15] Fama, E., and Kenneth F,. (1988). Dividend Yields and Expected Stock Returns. Journal of Financial Economics, 22: 3-25.##[16]  Karuna, Ch. (2007). Industry Product Market Competition Andmanagerial Incentives. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 43: 28–29.        ##[17] Guney, Y. Li, L Fairchild, R. )2011). The Relationship between Product Market Competition and Capital Structure in Chinese Listed Firms. International Review of Financial Analysis, 5: 41–51.##[18] Papanastasopoulos, G. Thomakos, D. Wang, T. (2013). Information in Balance Sheets for Future Stock Returns: Evidence from Net-Operating Assets. International Review of Financial Analysis, 20: 269–282.##[19] Hodrick, Robert J. (1992). Dividend Yield and Expected Stock Returns: Alternative Procedures for Inference and Measurement, The Review of Financial Studies, 5: 357-386.        ##[20] Hou, K., Robinson, DT. (2006). Industry Concentration and Verage Stock Returns. Journal of Finance, 61:1927–1956.##[21]  Peress, J. (2010). Product Market Competition, Insider Trading and Stock Market Efficiency. Journal of Finance, 65: 1–43.   ##[22] Hashem, N. (2010). Industry Concentration and the Cross-section of Stock Returns: Evidence from the UK, Journal of Business, Economics and management, 5: 52-93.##[23] Pandey, I. M. (2004). Capital Structure, Profitability and Market Structure: Evidence From Malaysia Asia Pacific, Journal of Economics and Business, 8(2): 78−91.##[24] Griffith, R. (2013), Product Market Competition, Efficiency and Agency Costs: An Empirical Analysis,The Institute for Fiscal Studies, Working Paper 01/12. Reduce Agency Costs? “, NBER Working Paper Series, 3: 74-80.##[25] Sharma, V. (2010). Stock Returns and Product Market Competition: beyond Industry Concentration. Review of Quantitative Finance and Accounting, 37: 283-299.##[26] Zlorackis, C. (2014). Agency Costs and Corporate Governance Mechanisms: Evidence for UK Firms. International Journal of Managerial Finance, 4(1): 37-59.##[27] Wagannathan, R, &amp; Srinivasan, S. (2014). Dose Product arket Competition, Foster Corporate Social Resposibilty? Evidence from trade liberalization, Stratejic Management Journal, 25:152-164.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارزیابی توانایی موقعیت‌سنجی مدیران صندوق‌های سرمایه‌گذاری مشترک پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران با استفاده از رویکردهای شرطی و غیرشرطی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Evaluating Market Timing Ability of Mutual Fund Managers Based on Conditional and Unconditional Approaches</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>صندوق‌های سرمایه گذاری یکی از مهم‌ترین عناصر بازارهای مالی هستند که با ایفای نقش واسطه‌گری مالی، سرمایه‌گذاری افراد را از حالت مستقیم به غیرمستقیم تبدیل می‌کنند و مزایای متعددی را برای آن‌ها به ارمغان می‌آورند. با توجه به اهمیت صندوق‌ها، در این پژوهش توانایی موقعیت‌سنجی مدیران صندوق‌های سرمایه‌گذاری با استفاده از الگوهای شرطی و غیرشرطی هنریکسون- مرتون و ترینر- مازوی و همچنین مقایسۀ دو رویکرد شرطی و غیر‌شرطی در ارزیابی عملکرد ارزیابی شد. بدین‌منظور داده‌های مربوط به بیست و سه صندوق سرمایه گذاری در سهام در دورۀ زمانی سال‌های 88 تا 92 بررسی شد. در تحلیل رگرسیون حداقل مربعات تعمیم‌یافته، از نرم‌افزار ایویوز6 استفاده شد. نتایج نشان‌دهندۀ ناتوانی موقعیت‌سنجی مدیران صندوق‌های سرمایه‌گذاری با استفاده از هر دو رویکرد شرطی و غیرشرطی بود. همچنین در مقایسۀ دو رویکرد، رویکرد شرطی، قدرت توضیح‌دهندگی بیشتری نسبت به رویکرد غیرشرطی ندارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Mutual Funds are one of the important elements of financial markets which act as financial intermediation and convert investment of amateur investors from direct condition to indirect. Given the importance of funds, this study tries to evaluate the market timing ability of managers&#039; funds using conditional and unconditional models (Treynor–Mazuy and Henriksson –Merton) and compares both conditional and unconditional approaches. Data relating to twenty-three funds are used during the period of 1388-1392, and generalized least squares regression analysis is performed by using EVIEWS6 software. The results indicate the inability of market timing in fund managers using both conditional and unconditional models. Moreover, the conditional approach does not provide higher explanatory power than the unconditional approach.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>45</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>60</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رستمی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rostami</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه مدیریت مالی و بیمه دانشکده علوم اجتماعی و اقتصاد دانشگاه الزهرا (س)، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه مدیریت مالی و بیمه دانشکده علوم اجتماعی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.rostami@alzahra.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حجت اله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>انصاری</Family>
						<NameE>Hojattolah</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ansari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشکدۀ مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشکدۀ مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران.</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hjtansari@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مرضیه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمدعلی</Family>
						<NameE>Marzieh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mohammad ali</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه مدیریت مدیریت مالی دانشکده علوم اجتماعی و اقتصاد، دانشگاه الزهرا (س)، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه مدیریت مدیریت مالی دانشکده علوم اجتماعی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>marzieh_ma89@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>توانایی موقعیت‌سنجی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>صندوق سرمایه‌گذاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رویکرد شرطی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رویکرد غیرشرطی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF> [1] Abdoh Tabrizi, H., Asadi, B., &amp; Mazaheri, S. (2013).Study of Security Selection and Market Timing Abilities in Mutual Funds in Iranian Capital Market. Financial Research, 15(2), 247-268## [2] Bodie, Z., Kane, A., &amp; Marcus, A. (2008). Investments (R. Farhadi &amp; S. M. Shariat panahi, Trans.). Tehran: Bourse.##[3] Chen, Dar-Hsin. Chuang, C. lin,j and lan,c. (2013). Market timing and stock selection ability of mutual fund managers in Taiwan: applying the traditional and conditional approaches.Applied Finance. 4(1).pp.75-90## [4] Chen, Nai-Fu.Roll, Richard and Ross, Stephen A.(1986). Economic forces and the stock market. Journal of business. 59(3).PP. 383-403.## [5] Dhar, Joyjit, and Mandal, Kumarjit. (2014). Market timing abilities of Indian mutual fund managers: an empirical analysis. DECISION. 41(3).pp.299-311## [6] Fama, Eugene F. (1972). Components of investment performance.&quot; The Journal of finance. 27(3). pp: 551-568.## [7] Ferson, Wayne E. (2010). Investment performance evaluation. Annu. Rev. Financ. Econ.2 (1). pp. 207-234.## [8] Ferson, Wayne E., and Schadt, Rudi W. (1996).Measuring fund strategy and performance in changing economic conditions. The Journal of Finance. 51(2). pp. 425-461.## [9] Ferson, Wayne E., and Warther,Vincent A.(1996).Evaluating fund performance in a dynamic market. Financial Analysts Journal. 52 (6) .pp. 20-28.## [10] Henriksson, Roy D., and Merton ,Robert C.(1981). on market timing and investment performance. II. Statistical procedures for evaluating forecasting skills. Journal of business. 54 (4). pp. 513-533.## [11] Ippolito, R.A. (1992).Consumer reaction to measures of poor quality: Evidence from the mutual fund industry.Journal of Law and Economics, 35(1).pp. 45-70## [12] khodarahmi, b., Ahmadinia, h., &amp; daghani, R.(2011). Management of Mutual Funds in Iran. Tehran: Termeh## [13] Lee, Cheng-few, and Rahman,Shafiqur. (1990).Market timing, selectivity, and mutual fund performance: An empirical investigation.Journal of Business.pp.261-278.## [14] Leite, Paulo Armada, and Maria Ceu Cortez. (2009).Conditioning information in mutual fund performance evaluation: Portuguese evidence. The European Journal of Finance, 15 (5-6). pp. 585-605.## [15] Le Sourd, Véronique. (2007). Performance measurement for traditional investment. Financial Analysts Journal, 58 (4). pp. 36-52## [16] Mashayekh, s., shahrokhi, s., &amp; Bashirimanesh, n.(2013).performnce Mutual Fund from Theory to Practice. Studies of Accounting and Auditing, 2(7), 74-91## [17] Roshangarzade, A., Ahmadi.M.R.(2011). Evaluating performance of mutual funds by measures based on post modern portfolio theory and the relationship between their rankings with measures based on modern portfolio theory. Financial Accounting Researches, 3 (7), 143-160## [18] Škrinjarić, Tihana.(2013). Market timing ability of mutual funds with tests applied on several Croatian funds. Croatian Operational Research Review .4 (1). pp. 176-186.## [19]Suppa-Aim. (2010). Mutual fund performance in emerging markets : the case of Thailand. (PhD), University of Birmingham, England.## [20] Tehrani, R., &amp; Noorbaakhsh, A.(2010). Investments: Analysis and Management. Tehran: Negahedanesh## [21] Tariverdi, Y., Faraji Armaki, M., Daghani, R., &amp; Heidarpour, F. (2013). Portfolio Performance Evaluation in mutual Funds and Investment  Companies With Henriksson – Merton Model. Journal of Empirical Research in Accounting, 2(3), 83-99## [22] Treynor, Jack, and Mazuy, Kay.(1996).Can mutual funds outguess the market. Harvard business review .44(4).pp.131-136.## [23] Ulfsdotter, A. (2011). China-focused Mutual Funds: A Study of Performance, Selectivity and Market Timing. (Bachelor Thesis in Finance), Stockholm, Sweden.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>پویایی‌های رابطۀ متغیرهای کلان و شاخص بازار سهام</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Dynamics of the Relation between Macroeconomic Variables and Stock Market Index</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>مطالعات گسترده‌ای رابطۀ بین نوسان‌های بازار سهام و متغیرهای کلان را بررسی کرده‌اند. در این پژوهش برای پیشبرد مطالعات این حوزه از الگوی اقتصادسنجی VARX-DCC-GARCH استفاده شده است. از مزیت‌های به‌کارگیری این الگو به این موارد می‌توان اشاره کرد: بررسی اثرگذاری نوسان‌های متغیرها در سطح میانگین و واریانس(نوسان‌پذیری) در قالب یک الگو، درنظرگرفتن متغیر قیمت نفت به‌عنوان یک متغیر برونزای اثرگذار بر روابط کوتاه‌مدت و بلندمدت و متغیر در طول زمان درنظرگرفتن همبستگی بین نوسان‌پذیری متغیرها. برای برآورد الگو از داده‌های ماهانۀ 1392-1381 برای اقتصاد ایران و بورس اوراق بهادار تهران استفاده شده است. براساس نتایج این الگو، متغیرهای نرخ ارز، تورم و قیمت نفت هر سه اثری مثبت در بلندمدت بر شاخص سهام دارند و نرخ ارز اثر بیشتری دارد. همچنین شوک‌های کوتاه‌مدت قیمت نفت، اثر بیشتری بر شاخص سهام دارد. همچنین بررسی همبستگی بین نوسان‌پذیری‌ها نشان می‌دهد نوسان‌پذیری نرخ ارز، اثری مثبت بر نوسان‌پذیری شاخص سهام دارد. این همبستگی در سال‌های 1387 تا 1392 تشدید شده است. همچنین نوسان‌پذیری تورم، همبستگی مثبت ضعیفی با نوسان‌های شاخص سهام دارد و نوسان‌پذیری قیمت نفت با نوسان‌پذیری بازار سهام همبستگی ندارد.       </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The relation between macroeconomic variables and stock market index has been vastly investigated in previous studies. To contribute to the literature, this study employs the VARX-DCC-GARCH econometric model. The advantages of using this new model are the consideration of variable change effectiveness in different moment levels (mean and variance of changes), inclusion of oil price as an exogenous variable that has short-run and long-run effects in this model, and the consideration of time series correlation between volatility of the variables. This model is estimated for the period of 1381 to 1391 by using Iran economic and the Tehran Stock Exchange monthly data. Results show that exchange rate, inflation and oil price have a positive effect on stock index in the long run, and the exchange rate has the strongest effect. Also in the short run horizon, oil price shocks have stronger effect on the stock index. Estimated time-varying correlations between variables volatility show that exchange rate volatility has a positive effect on stock market volatility. This correlation is reinforced during 1387 to 1391. In addition, inflation volatility has weak positive correlation with stock index volatility, while oil price volatility does not show any significant effect on stock index volatiliry.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>61</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>82</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عباسی نژاد</Family>
						<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Abbasinejad</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه اقتصادسنجی دانشکده اقتصاد دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه اقتصادسنجی دانشکده اقتصاد دانشگاه تهران،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>habasi@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>شاپور</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمدی</Family>
						<NameE>Shapour</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mohammadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه مدیریت دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه مدیریت دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>shmohmad@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سجاد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ابراهیمی</Family>
						<NameE>Sajad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ebrahimi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه اقتصاد مالی دانشکده اقتصاد دانشگاه تهران و پژوهشگر پژوهشکدۀ پولی و بانکی بانک مرکزی، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه اقتصاد مالی دانشکده اقتصاد دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ebrahimi_s@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نوسان‌پذیری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>متغیرهای کلان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شاخص کل بازار سهام</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نرخ ارز</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تورم و قیمت نفت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1]   Praei, K. &amp; Shahsavar, M. (2008). The effect of macroeconomic variables on Iran`s exchange market, Economic Researches, Vol. 9, No. 1:21-38.##[2]   Heidarim H. Bashiri, S. (2011). Investigating The Relationship Between Real Exchange Rate Uncertainty and Stock Price Index In Tehran Stock Exchange Using VAR-GARCH Models, Jorunal of Economic Modeling Research, Vol. 3, No.  9: 71-93.##[3]   Samadi, S. Nasrollahi, K. &amp; Karamalian, S. M. (2006). A survey on the relationship between financial market development and economic growth, Journal of Economic Researches, Vol. 6, No. 3: 20-43.##[4]   Karimzadeh, M. (2005). A survey on the long-run relationship between Tehran stock price index and monetary macro variables in the Iran`s economy, Journal of Iranian Economic Researches, Vol. 8, No. 26: 23-54.##[5]   Mojab, R. &amp; Barkachian, S. M. (2010). The effect of petro earcnings on petroless real production, Journal of Money and Economy, No. 9: 45-88.##[6]   Mousaee, M., Mehregan, N. &amp; Amiri, H. (2009). The relationship between stock market and macro economic variables in Iran, Journal of Economic Research and Policy, Vol. 18, No. 54: 73-94.##[7]   Antoniou, A. Garrett, I.  Priestley R. (1998),Macroeconomic variables as common pervasive risk factors and the empirical content of the arbitrage pricing theory, Journal of Empirical Finance, 5 (1998). 221–240.##[8]   Arouri, M. E. H., &amp; Rault, C. (2012). Oil prices and stock markets in GCC countries: empirical evidence from panel analysis. International Journal of Finance &amp; Economics, 17(3), 242-253.##[9]    Beltratti, A., &amp; Morana, C. (2006). Breaks and persistency: macroeconomic causes of stock market volatility. Journal of Econometrics, 131(1), 151-177.##[10]             Bilson, C. M., Brailsford, T. J., &amp; Hooper, V. J. (2001). Selecting macroeconomic variables as explanatory factors of emerging stock market returns. Pacific-Basin FinanceJournal, 9, 401−426##[11]             Christopher gan and et.al (2006),&quot;macroeconomic variables and stock market interactions: new Zeland evidence&quot;, the journal of investment management and financial innovation.89-101.##[12]             Cutler, D.M., J.M. Poterba and L.H. Summers, (1989), What moves stock prices?, Journal of Portfolio Management, 15, 4-12##[13]             Diebold Francis X and Yilmaz Kamil(2008)” Macroeconomic Volatility and Stock Market Volatility, Worldwide” NBER Working Paper No. 14269,##[14]             Dornbusch, R., &amp; Fisher, S. (1980), Exchange rates and the current account, American Economic Review, 70, 960–971.##[15]             Engle. R &amp; Sheppard. K (2001), “Theoretical and Empirical properties of Dynamic Conditional Correlation Multivariate GARCH”, National Bureau of Economic Research, Working Paper.##[16]             Engle, R. F., Ghysels, E., &amp; Sohn, B. (2013). Stock market volatility and macroeconomic fundamentals. Review of Economics and Statistics, 95(3), 776-797.##[17]             Engle. R. F (2002), “Dynamic Conditional Correlation a Simple Class of Multivariate GARCH Models”, Journal of Business and Economic Statistics, 20, 339-350.##[18]             Fama, E. F., &amp; French, K. R. (1993). Common risk factors in the returns on stocks and bonds. Journal of financial economics, 33(1), 3-56.##[19]             Gaurav A, Srivastava A, (2011), Stock Market Returns and Exchange Rates Volatility: A GARCH Application, Research Journal of Internatıonal Studıes - Issue 20##[20]             Gjerde, Ø., &amp; Saettem, F. (1999). Causal relations among stock returns and macroeconomic variables in a small, open economy. Journal of International Financial Markets, Institutions and Money, 9(1), 61-74.##[21]             Groenewold, N., and P. Fraser. (1999) ``Time-Varying Estimates of CAPM Betas.&#039;&#039; Mathematics and Computersin Simulation 48(4-6): 531-539.##[22]             Harbo I. Johansen S. Nielson B. &amp; Rahbek A.R. (1998). Asymptotic Inference on Cointegrating Rank in Partial Systems, Journal of the American Statistical Association, 16, 388-399##[23]             Ibrahim, M., &amp; Musah, A. (2014). An Econometric Analysis of the Impact of Macroeconomic Fundamentals on Stock Market Returns in Ghana. Research in Applied Economics, 6(2), 47-72.##[24]             Karoui, A. (2006). The correlation between FX rate volatility and stock exchange returns volatility: An emerging markets overview. Available at SSRN 892086.##[25]             Kilian, L., &amp; Park, C. (2009). The Impact of Oil Price S hocks on The US Stock Market. International Economic Review, 50(4), 1267-1287.##[26]             Maghyereh, A., &amp; Al-Kandari, A. (2007). Oil prices and stock markets in GCC countries: new evidence from nonlinear cointegration analysis. Managerial Finance, 33(7), 449-460.##[27]             Pebbles, G. Wilson P., (1996) The Singapore economy ,Edward Elgar, Cheltenham, UK.##[28]             Pesaran, M. H., Shin, Y., &amp; Smith, R. J. (2000). Structural analysis of vector error correction models with exogenous I(1) variables. Journal of Econometrics, 97(2), 293-343.##[29]             Pilinkus, D., &amp; Boguslauskas, V. (2015). The short-run relationship between stock market prices and macroeconomic variables in Lithuania: an application of the impulse response function. Engineering Economics, 65(5) 35-52.##[30]             Ross Stephen A, (1976), The arbitrage theory of capital asset pricing , Journal of Economic Theory, 13 ,341–360.##[31]             Sadorsky. P(1999) Oil price shocks and stock market activity, Energy Economics, 21,  449–469.##[32]             Schwert, G. W. (1989). Why does stock market volatility change over time? The journal of finance, 44(5), 1115-1153.##[33]             Subair, K., &amp; Salihu, O. M. (2004). Exchange rate volatility and the stock market: the Nigerian experience. Kwara State University.##[34]             Van Rensburg, P. (1999). Macroeconomic identification of candidate APT factors on the Johannesburg Stock Exchange. Journal for Studies in Economic and Econometrics, 23, 27-53.##[35]             Walti, S. (2005). The macroeconomic determinants of stock market synchronization. Journal of International Banking Law, 11(10), 436-41.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی ارتباط بین کیفیت‌گزارشگری مالی با کارایی سرمایه‌گذاری و تأثیر ساختار سررسید بدهی‌ها بر این رابطه</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigating the Relation between Financial Reporting Quality and Investment Efficiency and the Role of Debt Maturity in Such Relation among the Companies Listed in Tehran Stock Exchange</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>پژوهش حاضر رابطۀ بین کیفیت گزارشگری مالی با کارایی سرمایه‌گذاری شرکت­ها و همچنین اثر ساختار سررسید بدهی­ها را بر این رابطه بررسی می‌کند. بدین‌منظور، از الگوی کیفیت اقلام تعهدی دچو و دیچو ]12[ به‌عنوان معیار سنجش کیفیت گزارشگری مالی و برای اندازه‌گیری ساختار سررسید بدهی­ها از نسبت بدهی کوتاه­مدت به کل بدهی­ها استفاده شده است.علاوه بر این از مقادیر خطای الگوی رگرسیون سرمایه‌گذاری به‌عنوان معیار سنجش کارایی سرمایه‌گذاری استفاده شد. برای آزمون فرضیه­های پژوهش نیز نمونه ای متشکل از92 شرکت پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در سال های 1388 تا 1392 انتخاب شد و برای آزمون آن­ها از الگوهای رگرسیون چندگانه مبتنی بر تکنیک داده­های تلفیقی استفاده شد. یافته­های  تجربی نشان می‌دهد بین کیفیت گزارشگری مالی و ساختار سررسید بدهی با کارایی سرمایه‌گذاری شرکت، رابطۀ مثبت معناداری وجود دارد. همچنین نتایج نشان می­دهد رابطۀ بین کیفیت گزارشگری مالی و کارایی سرمایه­گذاری تحت تأثیر ساختار سررسید بدهی­ها قرار دارد و با افزایش بدهی­های با سررسید کوتاه­مدت، این رابطه تضعیف می­شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The present study aims to investigate the relation between financial reporting quality and debt maturity structure with investment efficiency of the firms listed in the Tehran Stock Exchange. To do so, Dechow and Dichev&#039;s (2002) accrual quality model is employed as a proxy for the financial reporting quality, and short-term liabilities to total liabilities ratio is used to measure the debt maturity structure. A sample of 92 firms listed in Tehran Stock Exchange from 2010 to 2014 is selected, and multiple regression model based on panel data techniques is also used to test the research hypotheses. According to the first hypothesis, there is a positively significant relation between financial reporting quality and firm&#039;s investment efficiency. Also the results of the second hypothesis indicate that there is a positively significant relation between debt maturity structure and firm&#039;s investment efficiency. Finally, the third hypothesis documents that the short term liabilities may account for the weak relation between firm&#039;s financial reporting quality and the investment efficiency.  </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>83</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>98</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صفری گرایلی</Family>
						<NameE>mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Safar graily</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه حسابداری دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد بندرگز، بندرگز، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه حسابداری دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد بندرگز،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mehdi.safari83@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فاطمه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رعنایی</Family>
						<NameE>fateme</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>ranaei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناسی ارشد حسابداری دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد گرگان، گرگان، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناسی ارشد حسابداری دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mranaei@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کیفیت گزارشگری مالی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ساختار سررسید بدهی و کارایی سرمایه‌گذاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Alcock ,Jamie A,B, Finn Frank C. and Kelvin JuiKeng Tan (2010), &quot;The Determinants of Debt Maturity in Australian Firm available at: http://ssrn.com/abstract=1728565.##[2] Berger, A., Udell, G., 1998. The economics of small business finance: the roles of private equity and debt markets in the financial growth cycle. Journal of Banking and Finance, 22, 613–673.## [3] Biddle, G., Hilary, G., 2006. Accounting quality and firm-level capital investment. The Accounting Review, 81, 963–982.## [4] Biddle, G., Hilary, G., Verdi, R.S., 2009. How does financial reporting quality relate to investments efficiency? Journal of Accounting and Economics, 48, 112–131.## [5] Beatty, Anne, Joseph Weber and J.Scott, (2007), &quot;The Role of Accounting Quality in Reducing Investment Inefficiency in the Presence of Private Information and Direct Monitoring&quot;,Working paper, The Ohio State University.##[6] Bushman, R.M., Smith, A.J., (2001). Financial accounting information and corporate governance. Journal of Accounting and Economics 32, 237–333.## [7] badavar nahandi, y, taghizadeh khangah,v (2013). the relationship between audit quality and investment efficiency. Journal of the accounting and auditing review, volume 20, number 2,p.19-42## [8] Childs, P .D .Mauer, D.C. and Ott, S.H., (2005), Interactions of Corporate Financing and Investment Decisions: The Effects of Agency Conflicts, Journal of Financial Economics, 76,P . 667-690.## [9] Chen, F., Hope, O.K., Li Q. and Wang, X. (2010). Financial reporting guality and investmetefficiency.www.Ssrn.com.## [10] Chen, F., Hope, O.K., Li, Q., &amp; Wang, X. (2011). Financial Reporting Quality and Investment Efficiency of Private Firms in Emerging Markets. The Accounting.## [11] Cohen, D.A. (2004). Quality of Financial Reporting Choice: Determinants and Economic Consequences .Working Paper, Northwestern University.## [12]Dechow, P., &amp; Dichev, I. (2002). The Quality of Accruals and Earnings: the Role of Accrual Estimation Errors. The Accounting Review, Vol. 77 (Supplement), pp. 35–59.## [13] Diamond, D.W., 1993. Seniority and maturity of debt contracts. Journal of Financial Economics, 33, 341–368.## [14] D’Mello, R., Miranda, M., (2010). Long-term debt and overinvestment agency problem. Journal of Banking and Finance 34, 324–335.## [15] Flannery, M.J., (1986). Asymmetric information and risky debt maturity choice. The Journal of Finance 41, 19–37.## [16] Francis, J., LaFond, R., Olsson, P.M., Schipper, K., (2005). The market pricing of accruals quality. Journal of Accounting and Economics 39, 295–327.## [17] Jensen, M., (1986). Agency costs of free cash flow, corporate finance, and takeovers. American Economic Review 76, 323–329.## [18] Gomariz،F.C &amp;Ballesta،J. (2014). Financial reporting quality, debt maturity and investment efficiency، Contents lists## [19]ghaemi, m,h,vatanparast,m, r (2007). Study of the role of accounting information in reducing of information asymmetry,  Journal of the accounting and auditing review,volume12,number3,p.85## [20] Healy, P.M., Palepu, K.G., 2001. Information asymmetry, corporate disclosure, and the capital markets: a review of the empirical disclosure literature. Journal of Accounting and Economics 31, 405–440.##[21]khodayi valazaghrad,m, yahyayi, m. (2012). the relationship between Financial Reporting Quality and investment efficiency, journalof accounting knowledge, volume3, number5, p.1-6.##[22] Li, Q., &amp;Wang, T. (2010). Financial Reporting Quality and Corporate Investment Efficiency: Chinese Experience. Nankai Business Review International, Vol.1, No.2, pp.197-213.## [23] Myers, S.C., (1977). Determinants of corporate borrowing. Journal of Financial.##[24] McNichols, M.F. and Stubben, S.R. (2008). Does earnings management affect firm s investment decisions? The Accounting Review, Vol. 83, pp.1571-1603.##[25] modares,A,hesarzade,R, (2009) Financial Reporting Quality and Investment Efficiency, Quarterly Journal of Securities Exchange, volume1, number2, p.85-116## [26] Ortiz-Molina, H., Penas, M.F., (2008). Lending to small businesses: the role of the loanmaturityinaddressinginformationproblems.SmallBusinessEconomics 30, 361–383.##[27] Rajan, R.G., (1992). Insiders and outsiders: the choice between informed and arm’slength debt. The Journal of Finance 47, 1367–1400.##[28]saghafi, A , Arab Mazar Yazdi, M, (2011) Financial Reporting Quality and Investment Inefficiency. financial accounting researches, Volume 2, Number 4, 1-20.##[29] Verdi, R.S. (2006). Financial Reporting Quality and Investment Efficiency.Doctoral Dissertation, University of Pennsylvania.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>توسعۀ الگوهای پیش‌بینی و ارزشیابی اولسون (1995) با لحاظ‌کردن ریسک ورشکستگی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Development of the Ohlson (1995) Prediction An Valuation Models with the Consideration of Bankruptcy Risk</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>سود حسابداری و فرض تداوم فعالیت از مبانی طراحی الگوهای پیش­بینی و ارزشیابی اولسون (1995) است. با توجه به توان تأثیرگذاری ریسک ورشکستگی بر این دو عامل، این پژوهش ضمن تعدیل این الگو­ها با لحاظ‌کردن ریسک ورشکستگی، الگو­های اولیه و تعدیل­شده در دو دورۀ تخمین 5 ساله (1382-1387) و 10 ساله (1382-1392) را با استفاده از داده­های ترکیبی 110 شرکت­ پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران ارزیابی مقایسه‌ای کرده است. نتایج پژوهش نشان می­دهد لحاظ‌کردن ریسک ورشکستگی باعث بهبود قدرت الگوهای پیش‌بینی و ارزشیابی اولسون در هر دو دورۀ تخمین 5 و 10 ساله می­شود؛ اما به­سبب رشد بی­رویّۀ قیمت­ها در سال­های 91 و 92 و شکل‌گیری حباب­های قیمتی، ارزش­هایی که هر دو الگوی اولیه و تعدیل­شده در دورۀ تخمین 10 ساله برآورد کرده‌اند به نحو معناداری پایین‌تر از ارزش­های واقعی بازار است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Accounting earnings and the continuous operation assumption are two principles of Ohlson’s (1995) prediction and valuation models. Regarding the influence of bankruptcy risk on these two factors, in this research, these models are adjusted by the inclusion of bankruptcy risk. As a result, the primary models are compared with adjusted models during a 5-year (from 2003 to 2008) and a 10-year period (from 2003 to 2013) using panel data of companies listed in the Tehran Stock Exchange. The results indicate that the inclusion of the bankruptcy risk improves Ohlson’s prediction and valuation models during both 5 and 10 years estimated periods. However, due to the uncontrolled growth of prices in 2012 and 2013, which resulted in the price bubble formation, the estimated values by both original and adjusted models during 10 years estimated period are significantly lower than the actual market values.  </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>99</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>116</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ولی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خدادادی</Family>
						<NameE>Vali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khodadad</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه حسابداری دانشکده اقتصاد و علوم اجتماعی دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، اهواز ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه حسابداری دانشکده اقتصاد و علوم اجتماعی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>vkhodadadi@scu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>واعظ</Family>
						<NameE>S.Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Vaez</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه حسابداری دانشکده اقتصاد و علوم اجتماعی دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، اهواز ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه حسابداری دانشکده اقتصاد و علوم اجتماعی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sa.vaez@scu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>امامی نایینی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Emami</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشکده اقتصاد و علوم اجتماعی دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، اهواز ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشکده اقتصاد و علوم اجتماعی دانشگاه شهید</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mohremna@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عایدات غیرعادی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ارزشیابی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ریسک ورشکستگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سود حسابداری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تداوم فعالیت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Adsera, X., &amp; Vinolas, P. (2003). FEVA: A financial and economic approach to valuation. Financial Analyst Journal. 59(2): 59-73.##[2] Aflatooni, A., &amp; Nikbakht, L. (2010). The use of econometrics in accounting. financial management and economic science. Tehran: terme: 182.##[3] Ali, A. (1994). The incremental information content of earnings, funds flow and cash flow. Journal of Accounting Research. 32: 61-74.##[4] Ali, A., &amp; Pope, P. E. (1995). The incremental information content of earnings, funds flow and cash flow: The UK Evidence. Journal of Business Finance and Accounting. 22 (1): 121-126.##[5] Altman, E.I. (1968). Financial ratios, disarmament analysis and the prediction of corporate Bankruptcy. The Journal of Finance.23: 589-609.##[6] Ataullah, A., Rhys, H., &amp; Tippett,M. (2009). Non-linear equity valuation. Accounting and Business Research. 39(1): 57-73.##[7] Barth, E., &amp; others. (1999). Accruals, cash flows, and equity values, University of North Carolina: Chapel Hill.##[8] Butler, M., Leone, A. J., &amp; Willenborg, M. (2004). An empirical analysis of auditor reporting and its association with abnormal accruals. Journal of Accounting and Economics. 37(2): 139–165.##[9] Bauman, M. P. (1999). An empirical investigation of conservatismin book value measurement. Managerial Finance. 25(12): 42-54.##[10]           Bazrafshan, a., &amp; Arefmanesh, Z. (2014). Earnings behavior in bankrupt firms: the role of auditor. Asset Management and Financing. 2(4): 1-14.##[11]           Callen, J. L., &amp; Morel, M. (2001). Linear accounting valuationwhen abnonnal earnings are AR (2). Review of Quantitative Finance and Accounting. 16: 191-203.##[12]           Callen J.L., Livnat, J.,&amp; Segal,D. (2002). Accounting restatements: are they always bad news?. Working paper. University of Toronto.##[13]           Camcho-Minano, M.D.,&amp; Campa, P. (2014). Integrity of financial information as a determinant of the outcome of a bankruptcy procedure. International Review of Law and Economics. 37: 76-85.##[14]           Charitou, A., Lambertides, N.,&amp; Trigeorgis, L. (2007). Earnings behavior of financially distressed firms: the role of institutional ownership. Abacus. 43(3): 271–296.##[15]           Charitou, A., Neophytou, E.,&amp; Charalambous, C. (2004). Predicting corporate failure: empirical evidence for the UK. European Accounting Review. 13(3): 465–497.##[16]           Choi, Y., O&#039;Hanlon, J.,&amp; Pope, P. F. (2001). Linear information models in residual income-based valuation: a development of the Dechow, Hutton and Sloan empirical approach. Working paper. Lancaster University.##[17]           Collins, D., Maydew, E., &amp; Weiss, L. (1997). Changes in the value-relevance of earnings and book values over the Past forty years. Journal of Accounting and Economics. 9: 111-138.##[18]           DeAngelo, H., DeAngelo L. &amp; Skinner, D. J. (1994). Accounting choice in troubled companies. Journal of Accounting and Economics. 17 (1–2): 113–143.##[19]           Dechow, P., Hutton, M., &amp; Sloan, R. G. (1999). An empirical assessment of the residual income valuation model. Journal of Accounting and Economics. 26: 1-34.##[20]           DeFond, M. L.,&amp; Jiambalvo, J. (1994). Debt covenant violation and manipulation of accruals. Journal of Accounting and Economics. 17(1–2): 145–176.##[21]           Etemadi, H., Dastgir, M., Momeni, M.,&amp; Farajzadeh Dehkordi, H. (2012). Discretionary accruals behavior of Iranian distressed firms. Middle Eastern Finance and Economics. 16: 44–53.##[22]           Etemadi, H., &amp; Rahimi, F. (2015). Firm’s life cycle and ohlson valuation model: evidence from iran.  Asian Economic and Financial Review. 5(4): 641-652.##[23]           Feltham, G. A.,&amp; Ohlson, J. A. (1995). Valuation and clean surplus accounting for operating and financial activities. Contemporary Accounting Research. 11 (2): 689-731.##[24]           Foster, B.P., Ward, T.J.,&amp; Woodroof, J. (1998). An analysis of the usefulness of debt defaults and going concern opinions in bankruptcy risk assessment. Journal of accounting, Auditing and Finance. 13 (3): 351-371.##[25]           Francis, J., Ohlson, P.,&amp; Oswald, D. (2000). Comparing the accuracy and explainability of dividend, free cash flow, and abnormal earnings equity value estimates. Journal of Accounting Research. 38: 45–70.##[26]           Frankel, R.,&amp; Lee, C. M. C. (1998). Accounting valuation, market expectation, and cross-sectional returns. Journal of Accounting and Economics. 25: 283-319.##[27]           Garcia Lara, J.M. B., Garcia, O.,&amp; Neophytou, E. (2009). Earning quality in ex-post failed firms. Accounting and Business Research. 39(2): 119-138.##[28]           Giner, B., &amp; Iniguez,R. (2006). An empirical assessments of the feltham-ohlson models considering the sign of abnormal earnings. Accounting and Business Research. 36 (3): 169-190.##[29]           Hand, J., &amp; Landsman, W. (1998). testing the ohlson model: v or not v. that is the question. Working Paper. University of North Carolina. Chapel Hill.##[30]           Karami, G., &amp; Beikboshrouyeh, S. (2011). Corporate governance and equity valuation: the model by using artificial neural network. Journal of The Accounting And Auditing Review. 18(64): 129-150.##[31]           Karathanassis, G.A., &amp; S. N., Spilioti. (2005). An empirical application of the clean–surplus valuation model: the case of the athens stock exchange. Applied Financial Economics. 15: 1031-1036.##[32]           Khodadadi, V., &amp; Dastgir, M., Noravesh, E., Momeny, M. (2005). Designing of linear information model on tehran stock exchange: development of ohlson model. Ph.D. Thesis. Management  Faculty of  Tehran University .##[33]           Khodadadi, V.,&amp; Emami, M.R. (2010). Comparative assessment of feltham-ohlson Sign-oriented &amp; traditional models. International Research Journal of Finance &amp; Economics. 2010. 36: 59-74.##[34]           Khodadadi, V.,&amp; Erfani, H. (2010). The relationship between industry status, market share and capital intensity with abnormal earnings persistence in public firms. Accounting knowledge. 1(1): 89-109.##[35]           Khodadadi, V., Farazmand, H.,&amp; Sheybeh, S. (2012). Assessing the valuation model based on abnormal earnings (ohlson) by notice to the macroeconomic variables. Journal of financial Accounting Research. 5(17): 41-58.##[36]           Leach, R., Newsom, P. (2007). Do firms manage their earnings prior to filing for bankruptcy?. Academy of Accounting and Financial Studies Journal. 11(3): 27-41.##[37]           Li F., Abeysekera, I.,&amp; Ma, S. (2011). Earnings management and the effect of earnings quality In relation to stress level and bankruptcy Level of Chinese Listed Firms. Corporate Ownership and Control. 9 (1):  366-391.##[38] Lintner J. (1965). The valuation of risk assets and the selection of risky investments in stock portfolios and capital budget. Review of Economics and  Statistics. 47: 13 - 37.##[39] Liu J., &amp; Ohlson A. J,(1999). The feltham-ohlson (1995) Model: Empirical Implications. Working Paper. Arizona State University and University of California at Los Angeles.##[40] Lo, K.,&amp; Lys, T. (2000). The Ohlson model: contribution to valuation theory, limitations, and empirical applications. Journal of Accounting, Auditing and Finance. 15(3): 337-370.##[41] McCrae, M.,&amp; Nitsson, H. (2001). The explanatory and predictive power of different specifications of the Ohlson (1995) valuation models. The European Accounting Review. 10 (2): 315-341.##[42] Mo, P.L., Rui, O.M.,&amp; Wu, X. (2015). Auditors&#039; going concern reporting in the pre- and post-bankruptcy law eras: Chinese Affiliates of Big 4 versus Local Auditors. The International Journal of Accounting. 50 (1): 1-30.##[43] Myers, J. (1999). Implementing residual income valuation with linear information dynamics. Accounting Review.74 (January): 1-28.##[44] Newton, G.W. (1998). Bankruptcy insolvency accounting practice and procedure: Wiley.##[45] O&#039;Hanlon, J.,&amp; K.V. Peasnell. (2002). Residual income valuation are inflation adjustments. Working Paper. Lancaster University.##[46] Ohlson, J. A. (1995). Earnings, book values, and dividends in equity valuation. Contemporary Accounting Research. 11 (2): 661-687.##[47] Ota, K. (2002). A test of the ohlson (1995) model: empirical evidence from japan. The International Journal of Accounting. 37 (2): 157-182.##[48] Peltier-Rivest, D. (1999). The determinants of accounting choices in troubled companies. Quarterly Journal of Business and Economics. 38(4). 28–44.##[49] Plenborg, T. (2002). Firm valuation: comparing the residual income and discounted cash flow approaches. Scandinavian Journal of Management. 18(3):303-318.##[50] Rosner, R. L. (2003). Earnings manipulation in failing firms. Contemporary Accounting Research. 20(2): 361-408.##[51] Saleh N. M.,&amp; Ahmed, K. (2005). Earnings management of distressed firms during debt renegotiation. Accounting and Business Research. 35(1): 69–86.##[52] SFAC NO 8. (2010). Conceptual Framework for Financial Reporting—Chapter 1, The Objective of General Purpose Financial Reporting.##[53] Sharpe W.F. (1964). Capital asset prices: A theory of market equilibrium under conditions of risk. Journal of Finance. 19(3):425-442.##[54] Stober, T. L. (1996). Do prices behave as if accounting book values are conservative? Cross-sectional tests of the Feltham-Ohlson (1995) valuation model. Working paper. University of Notre Dame.##[55] Sweeney, A. P. (1994). Debt-covenant violations and managers accounting responses. Journal of Accounting and Economics. 17(3): 281–308.##[56]  Vakilifard, H., &amp; Forough nejad. H., &amp; Khoshnood. M. (2013). Evaluation investors behavior in tehran stock exchange with analytic network process. Asset Management &amp; Financing. 1(2): 19-34.##[57] Watts, R. L. &amp; Zimmerman J. L. (1986). Positive accounting theory. New Jersey: Prentice-Hall.##[58] Yeh, C., Chi, D.,&amp; Lin, Y. (2014). Going-concern prediction using hybrid random forests and rough set approach. Information Sciences. 254: 98-110.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				