<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Relationship between Financial Constraints, the Structure of Assets and Financing in Companies Listed in Tehran Stock Exchange</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی رابطۀ محدودیت مالی، ساختار دارایی ها و تأمین مالی در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>181</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>196</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">21332</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21332</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمود</FirstName>
					<LastName>لاری دشت بیاض</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه حسابداری دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصاد دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>صالحی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه حسابداری دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصاد دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>سخاوت پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد حسابداری، گروه حسابداری موسسه آموزش عالی عطار، مشهد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The main objective of this study was to investigate the moderating effect of financial constraints of Kaplan-Zingales Index (1997) on the relationship between the structure of collateral assets and financing structure of the companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange (TSE).  To this end, the study was carried out using systematic elimination skewed sample consists of 155 firms over the period of 11 years -from 2004 to 2015. The results show that moderating effect of financial constraints on the relationship between and the total collateral assets with financial leverage and components collateral assets (property, plant and equipment, inventory, accounts receivable) with the company&#039;s financial leverage is direct and significant. The test of the third hypothesis showed that there is no moderating effect of financial constraints on the relationship between long-term assets and long-term securities held by financial leverage. Furthermore, testing the moderating effect of financial constraints on the relationship between short-term bond funds with short-term financial leverage impose a direct and significant relationship; as well as the moderating effect of short-term financial constraints on components of collateral assets (inventory, accounts receivable) with short-term financial leverage denote that there is a direct and significant relationship and non-relationship for the aforementioned issues, respectively.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر، اثر تعدیلی محدودیت ‌مالی با شاخص کاپلان و زینگالس (1997) را در رابطۀ ساختار دارایی‌های ‌وثیقه‌شدنی و ساختار‌ مالی شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار ‌تهران بررسی می‌کند. بدین‌منظور، 155 شرکت برای یک دورۀ 11 ساله (1393-1383) بررسی شده است. یافته‌ها نشان می‌دهد محدودیت مالی شرکت­ها در رابطۀ کل دارایی‌های ‌وثیقه‌شدنی با اهرم ‌مالی و اجزای دارایی‌های وثیقه‌شدنی (اموال، ماشین‌آلات و تجهیزات، موجودی‌کالا و حساب­های دریافتنی) با اهرم ‌مالی شرکت، تأثیر مثبت و معناداری دارد؛ به عبارت دیگر، با وجود محدودیت­های مالی در شرکت­ها، این رابطه تقویت می­شود. در تحلیل فرضیۀ سوم، متغیر تعدیلی محدودیت مالی در رابطۀ بین دارایی‌های بلندمدت وثیقه‌شدنی با اهرم ‌مالی بلندمدت تأثیری ندارد. متغیر تعدیلی محدودیت مالی در رابطۀ بین دارایی‌های کوتاه‌مدت وثیقه‌شدنی با اهرم مالی کوتاه‌مدت، نشان‌دهندۀ اثر مثبت و معناداری است. علاوه بر این اثر تعدیلی محدودیت‌ مالی در اجزای دارایی‌های کوتاه‌مدت‌ وثیقه‌شدنی (موجودی‌کالا و حساب­های دریافتنی) با اهرم ‌مالی کوتاه‌مدت به‌ترتیب، نشان‌دهندۀ رابطۀ مثبت و معنادار و نبود رابطه است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اهرم مالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بورس اوراق بهادار‌تهران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">محدودیت مالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساختار دارایی‌ها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">وثیقه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21332_3fca88687f45479fdbfa35aa7c0c52b9.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
