<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Complexity of  Supply Chain As an Strategic Asset and Position of Financial Performance</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>پیچیدگی زنجیرۀ تأمین به‌عنوان یک دارایی راهبردی و جایگاه عملکرد مالی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>57</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>78</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">23116</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2018.105826.1154</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید محمدعلی</FirstName>
					<LastName>خاتمی فیروز آبادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>لعیا</FirstName>
					<LastName>الفت</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مقصود</FirstName>
					<LastName>امیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمید</FirstName>
					<LastName>شریفی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت صنعتی، گروه مدیریت صنعتی، گرایش تولید و عملیات، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>08</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Supply chain management association, in a comprehensive framework, defines supply chain as a strategic asset that can create value and consequently a competitive advantage for the organization This research aims at recognizing the formation and impact of supply chain complexity as an asset on its performance. The sub-goal of this research is to analyze the position of financial performance in the impact of supply chain complexity. Thus, after reviewing theoretical literature, the dimensions and terms of the model were identified and formulated as a reference model for supply chain processes. Then, a questionnaire was designed to assess the complexity of the supply chain and its impact on performance. CRONBACH alpha was used to assess the reliability and content, and construct validity was used to assess the validity. The statistical population of this research is home appliance companies. The statistical sample consists of 50 companies in the cities of Tehran, Isfahan, Tabriz, Mashhad, Shiraz and Ahvaz. In this research, 250 questionnaires were distributed in deferent layers of supply chain and 197 questionnaires were completed. Finally, by using Factor Analysis and Structural Equation Modeling method, proposed conceptual model was analyzed. Based on research findings, the supply chain complexity of the population has significant and negative impact on performance.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">انجمن مدیریت جامع زنجیرۀ تأمین، آن را دارایی راهبردی تعریف می‌کند که برای سازمان، ارزش و مزیت رقابتی ایجاد می‌کند. هدف این پژوهش، شناخت چگونگی شکل‌گیری و اثرگذاری پیچیدگی این دارایی بر عملکرد سازمان و جایگاه عملکرد مالی در تأثیرپذیری از آن است؛ به این منظور پس از بررسی پیشینۀ نظری پژوهش، ابعاد و گویه‌های الگو شناسایی شد و الگوی مرجع فرایندهای زنجیرۀ تأمین قرار گرفت؛ سپس پرسش‌نامه‌ای برای ارزیابی پیچیدگی زنجیرۀ تأمین و بررسی اثر آن بر عملکرد طراحی شد. نمونۀ آماری شامل 50 شرکت تولید لوازم‌ خانگی در شهرهای تهران، اصفهان، تبریز، مشهد، شیراز و اهواز است. در این پژوهش 250 پرسش‌نامه در لایه‌های مختلف زنجیرۀ تأمین توزیع و 197 پرسش‌نامه تکمیل شد. درنهایت با استفاده از روش تحلیل عاملی و الگو‌سازی معادلات ساختاری، الگوی مفهومی پیشنهادی پژوهش، تجزیه‌‌وتحلیل شد. براساس یافته‌های پژوهش، پیچیدگی زنجیرۀ تأمین در جامعۀ بررسی‌شده تأثیر منفی و معناداری بر عملکرد دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیچیدگی زنجیرۀ تأمین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دارایی راهبردی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد مالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگو‌سازی معادلات ساختاری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_23116_6ebf7f2ce59ed4abd29d1f618dc3d740.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
