<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Disclosure Quality on the Value Relevance of Financial Statements Items</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر کیفیت افشا بر رابطه ارزشی اقلام صورت‌های مالی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>13</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>26</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19830</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضوان</FirstName>
					<LastName>حجازی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه الزهرا</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ویدا</FirstName>
					<LastName>مجتهدزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه الزهرا</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اعظم</FirstName>
					<LastName>ولی زاده لاریجانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه الزهرا</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>High quality accounting information is necessary for capital market health function and overall economy and is very important for investors, companies and standard setters. So, in this study the effect of disclosure quality on the value relevance of financial statements items is examined. For this, at first the value relevance of financial statements items and the value relevance of disclosure quality Characteristic with future stock return were tested. Then, the effect of disclosure quality on the relationship between financial statements items and future stock return was examined. &lt;br /&gt;The statistical population was the listed companies in Tehran Stock Exchange during 1383 to 1391. Panel data regression analysis (Time-Fixed Effect Model and Time-Random Effect Model) and Wald Test were used in the research method. The results indicated that financial statements items except operating profit and debt ratio and financial information reliability and timeliness characteristics have significant relationships with future stock return. Also, the results showed that disclosure quality and communication score has no significant effect on the value relevance of financial statements items with future stock return.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">اطلاعات حسابداری با کیفیت، شرط لازم برای کارکرد سالم بازارهای سرمایه و به طور کلی اقتصاد می‌باشد و اهمیت زیادی برای سرمایه‌گذاران، شرکت‌ها و تدوین‌کنندگان استانداردهای حسابداری دارد. با توجه به این موضوع، در این تحقیق، تأثیر کیفیت افشا بر رابطه ارزشی اقلام صورت‌های مالی بررسی شده است. به این منظور ابتدا رابطه ارزشی اقلام صورت‌های مالی و رابطه ارزشی ویژگی‌های کیفیت افشا با بازده آتی سهام مورد آزمون قرار گرفت. سپس، تأثیر کیفیت افشا بر رابطه بین اقلام صورت‌های مالی با بازده آتی سهام بررسی شد.&lt;br /&gt; جامعه آماری این تحقیق شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران طی سال‌های 1383 تا 1391 می‌باشد. در روش تحقیق از تحلیل رگرسیون داده‌های ترکیبی ( مدل اثرات ثابت زمانی و مدل اثرات تصادفی زمانی) و نیز از آزمون والد استفاده شد. نتایج تحقیق حاکی از وجود رابطه معنی‌دار بین اقلام صورت‌های مالی (به استثنای سود عملیاتی و نسبت بدهی) و ویژگی‌های قابلیت اتکا و به موقع بودن اطلاعات مالی با بازده آتی سهام است. همچنین، نتایج نشان می‌دهد که امتیاز کیفیت افشا و اطلاع‌رسانی بر رابطه ارزشی اقلام صورت‌های مالی با بازده آتی سهام تأثیر معنی‌داری ندارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازار سرمایه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کیفیت افشا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صورت‌های مالی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_19830_ea0ab6faee126a0fe2c636c4f1a5bd00.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
