<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Factors Affecting the Behavior of Investors Regarding Phenomenographical Approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>عوامل مؤثر در بروز رفتار سرمایه‌گذاران با رویکرد پدیدارنگاری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>57</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>76</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">21173</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21173</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید مرتضی</FirstName>
					<LastName>غیور باغبانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت دانشگاه بین المللی امام رضا (ع)، مشهد،</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امید</FirstName>
					<LastName>بهبودی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد شاهرود</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Decisions of investors in the financial markets is influenced by many factors, many of which are not justified in making rational decisions. Factors such as values, beliefs and cultural assumptions cause bias in the decision-making process that affect the behavior and decisions of the investors. The focus of this article is to provide a pattern of behavior and decision-making factors for investors with an emphasis on cultural factors. Basic assumptions are elucidated from literature review and relevant researches. The mixed method research was selected and operated in order to progress the research at the qualitative and quantitative parts. At the qualitative part, semi structured in-depth interviews were conducted with behavioral decision making experts considerating phenomenography strategy. Data from the interviews were analyzed using content analysis method according to which the questionnaire was designed. At this stage, the survey strategy was conducted, and then 500 questionnaires were distributed as available sampling method and 316 completed questionnaires were collected. The data were analyzed using SPSS and Amos Graphics softwares using structural equation modeling. The results indicate that fators such as value system, locus of control, uncertainty acceptance, habit to investment and time horizon are the main components of cultural category which besides personality, cognitive and emotional biases form investor’s decision making that lead to herding behavior. Despite the past researches confirmed the effect of time, data analysis showed that khorasan razavi investor’s behavioral model is not affected by the time factor.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">تصمیم­گیری سرمایه­گذاران در بازارهای مالی از عوامل فراوانی متأثر است که بسیاری از آنها در رویکردهای عقلانی تصمیم­گیری توجیه‌شدنی نیست. عواملی مانند نظام ارزشی، اعتقادات و پیشفرض‌های فرهنگی موجب بروز سوگیری در فرایند تصمیم‌گیری می‌شود که رفتار و تصمیم‌های سرمایه‌گذاران را تحت تأثیر قرار می‌دهد. کانون توجه این پژوهش، شناخت عوامل رفتاری و ارائۀ الگوی تصمیم‌گیری سرمایه‌گذاران با تأکید بر مؤلفه‌های فرهنگی است. فرضیه‌های مبنایی پژوهش، از مرور نظریه و پژوهش­های مرتبط، استخراج و برای پیشبرد مراحل پژوهش، طرح پژوهش ترکیبی در بخش‌های کیفی و کمّی پژوهش، انتخاب و عملیاتی می­شود. در مرحلۀ کیفی ضمن اتخاذ استراتژی پدیدارنگاری، مصاحبه­های نیمه‌ساختاریافتۀ عمیق با خبرگان تصمیم­گیری رفتاری انجام شد. داده‌های حاصل از مصاحبه­ها با استفاده از روش تحلیل محتوا تحلیل و براساس آن، پرسشنامۀ پژوهش طراحی شد. در این قسمت با بهره‌گیری از استراتژی پیمایش، تعداد 500 پرسشنامه به‌صورت نمونه­گیری در دسترس، توزیع و 316 پرسشنامه تکمیل و جمع­آوری شد. داده‌های حاصل از پرسشنامه با نرم­افزارهای SPSS و Amos Graphics و با استفاده از روش معادلات ساختاری تحلیل شد. نتایج پژوهش نشان می‌دهد در مقولۀ فرهنگ، مؤلفه­های نظام ارزشی، کانون­کنترل، تحمل ­ابهام، عادت به سرمایه­گذاری و افق زمانی در کنار مقوله­های شخصیت، سوگیری­ شناختی و سوگیری ­عاطفی، تصمیم‌های سرمایه‌گذاران را شکل می‌دهد و موجب بروز رفتارهای توده­وار در تصمیم­گیری می­شود. همچنین با وجود تأیید تأثیر مقولۀ زمان در سایر پژوهش­ها، تحلیل داده­ها نشان داد الگوی رفتاری تصمیم­گیری سرمایه­گذاران بورس اوراق بهادار خراسان رضوی متأثر از عامل زمان نیست.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تصمیم‌گیری سرمایه‌گذاران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سوگیری‌های شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سوگیری‌های عاطفی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سوگیری‌های مالی ـ رفتاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مؤلفه‌های فرهنگی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21173_6b511f3f2b4d910b08f520b46e0b4efb.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
