<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigating the Impact of Investor&#039;s Sentiment and Trading Behavior on Excess Return: Revised Fama and French Five Factor Model</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر تمایلات و رفتار معاملاتی سرمایه‌گذاران فردی بر بازده مازاد: الگوی تجدیدنظرشدۀ فاما و فرنچ</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>97</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>116</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">24358</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2019.116716.1418</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیده زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نصیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم اقتصادی و ادرای، دانشگاه مازندران ، بابلسر ، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>یحیی</FirstName>
					<LastName>کامیابی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم اقتصادی و اداری، دانشگاه مازندران، بابلسر، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt; Since the 1990s, the determination of the fair value of financial assets and whether this value depends only on fundamental factors in pricing models or is influenced by behavioral and psychological factors has always been a debatable issue. The behavioral finance field focuses on issues and proposes asset pricing models that incorporate behavioral decision-making aspects. The purpose of this study is to investigate the simultaneous effect of the criteria of the sentiment and individual investors trading behavior on the pricing of capital assets in 77 listed firms in Tehran Stock Exchange during the period from 2009 to 2014, using combination data method.
&lt;strong&gt;Method: &lt;/strong&gt;For this purpose, a revised Fama and French five-factor model is created by adding sentiment and individual investors trading behavior.
&lt;strong&gt;Results: &lt;/strong&gt;The experimental results showed that these two factors have a significant effect on the return on the five-factor model. In a situation where all investors are not rational, decision-makers can use the investor&#039;s psychological aspects to understand how asset pricing works.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;اهداف: &lt;/strong&gt;از دهۀ 1990 همواره تعیین ارزش منصفانۀ دارایی‌های مالی و اینکه آیا این ارزش تنها به عوامل بنیادی در الگو‌های قیمت‌گذاری بستگی دارد یا از عوامل رفتاری و روان‌شناختی نیز تأثیر می‌گیرد، مسئله‌ای بحث‌برانگیز بوده است. رشتۀ مالی رفتاری به مسائلی توجه کرده و الگو‌های قیمت‌گذاری دارایی‌های جایگزینی را ارائه داده است که جنبه‌های رفتاری تصمیم‌گیری را در بر می‌گیرند. هدف از انجام پژوهش حاضر، بررسی تأثیر همزمان معیارهای تمایلات و رفتار معاملاتی سرمایه‌گذاران حقیقی بر قیمت‌گذاری دارایی‌های سرمایه‌ای در 77 شرکت پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در دورۀ 1395 تا 1388 با روش داده‌های ترکیبی است.
&lt;strong&gt;روش: &lt;/strong&gt;به این منظور الگوی تجدیدنظرشدۀ پنج‌عاملی فاما و فرنچ با افزودن معیارهای تمایلات سرمایه‌گذار و رفتار معاملاتی سرمایه‌گذار فردی ایجاد شد.
&lt;strong&gt;نتایج: &lt;/strong&gt;نتایج تجربی نشان داد این دو عامل تأثیر بااهمیتی بر بازده مازاد در الگوی پنج‌عاملی دارند. در شرایطی که تمام سرمایه‌گذاران منطقی نیستند، تصمیم‌گیرندگان جوانب روان‌شناختی سرمایه‌گذار را برای درک چگونگی قیمت‌گذاری دارایی‌ها به کار می‌گیرند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوی پنج‌عاملی فاما و فرنچ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مالی رفتاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تمایلات سرمایه‌گذار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفتار معاملاتی سرمایه‌گذاران فردی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_24358_f8ba5238fcf12f568a4b0c1e96d32325.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
