<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Relation between Market Competition and Dividend Policies</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رابطۀ رقابت در بازار و سیاست‌های تقسیم سود</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>45</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>60</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">21111</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2016.21111</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نرگس</FirstName>
					<LastName>سرلک</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه حسابداری دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه قم، قم، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>میرزایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه حسابداری دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه قم، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This article investigates the relation between market competition and dividend policies. Using a sample of listed companies in the Tehran Stock Exchange in the period of 1387-1391, we find that firms in highly competitive industries prefer to pay more dividends. Research hypotheses are developed based on the outcome theory and substitution theory. In order to investigate the impact market competition on dividend policies. To test the hypothesis were used panel data regression model and logistic regression. Results indicate that there is a significant positive relation between dividends paid and market competition, return on assets and lifecycle. Also there is a significant negative relation between dividends paid and financial leverage. On the other hand, using the logit model, results indicate that there is a significant positive relationship between increase dividends paid and market competition. Results also demonstrate that there is a significant positive relation between omit dividends paid and return on assets and financial leverage. Also there is a significant negative relation between omitted dividends paid, market competition, growth opportunities and life cycle. &lt;br /&gt; </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف این پژوهش، بررسی رابطۀ رقابت در بازار با سیاست­های تقسیم سود شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در دورۀ زمانی 1387 تا 1391 است. فرضیه­های پژوهش برمبنای نظریه‌های پیامد، جانشینی و شکار مربوط به تأثیر رقابت در بازار بر سیاست­های تقسیم سود تدوین شده­اند. برای آزمون فرضیه­ها از الگوهای رگرسیون چندگانه با استفاده از داده­های تلفیقی و رگرسیون لجستیک استفاده شده است. برای سنجش رقابت در بازار از شاخص انتروپی استفاده شد. نتایج پژوهش نشان می­دهد بین رقابت در بازار و سود تقسیمی، رابطۀ مثبت و معنی­داری وجود دارد. همچنین رقابت در بازار با افزایش سود تقسیمی نیز رابطۀ مثبت و معنی­داری دارد. بین رقابت در بازار و حذف سود تقسیمی نیز رابطۀ منفی و معنی­داری وجود دارد. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رقابت در بازار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شاخص انتروپی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سود تقسیمی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21111_dd334402ac43df876c10aa0bd682ddd1.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
