<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Decision Making Model under Uncertain and Risky Situations Based on Dynamic Reference Point: Evidences from Tehran Stock Exchange</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>الگوی تصمیم‌گیری تحت شرایط ریسک در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران مبتنی بر نقطۀ مرجع پویا</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>51</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>68</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">21573</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21573</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>تهرانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیارگروه مالی و بیمه -دانشکده مدیریت -دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عسگر</FirstName>
					<LastName>نوربخش</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت مالی، گروه مالی و بیمه -دانشکده مدیریت -دانشگاه تهران، ‌ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>According to prospect theory gains and losses are measured from a reference point. In this paper we attempted to examine the Reference Point Adaptation level and its effect on future selling decisions. For this purpose, the required data of all firms listed in the Tehran Stock Exchange were used. The required data were available for at least one year during the period from 2004 to 2013.The results showed that the two variables, including profit (loss) size and time in a profit (Loss) position, and their interaction with each other, are involved in formation and adaptation of reference point. So that when investors are in the profit point, the reference point is the adaptation to a new level, while when investors are in the loss area, the adaptability of the new reference point level is reduced. Also, a larger total loss size and a longer time in a losing position are related to a downward shift in the reference point. According to the results, considering two variables, profit (loss) size and time in a profit (Loss) position, and their interaction with each other, we can estimate the investor&#039;s reference point adaptation level and predict investor&#039;s decision to capitulate or hold stock.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف پژوهش حاضر، تعیین سطح انطباق‌پذیری نقطۀ مرجع و تأکید بر پویایی این نقطه به‌عنوان عامل تعیین‌کنندۀ سود و زیان سهامداران و اقدام آنان به رهاکردن و یا نگهداری سهام براساس نظریۀ دورنما به‌عنوان یکی از آخرین نظریه‌های مالی رفتاری است. برآورد نحوۀ انطباق‌پذیری نقطۀ مرجع و تبیین رفتار سرمایه‌گذاران در مواجهه با سود و زیان، ضرورت انجام پژوهش را مشخص کرده است. بدین‌منظور با بهره‌گیری از داده‌های لازم در قلمرو زمانی سال‌های 1383 تا 1392، سعی شده است به مسألۀ اصلی پژوهش پاسخ داده شود.نتایج پژوهش نشان می‌دهددو متغیر میزان سود (زیان) و مدت‌زمان سود (زیان) و اثر همزمان آن‌ها در یکدیگر در شکل‌گیری سطح نقطۀ مرجع و انطباق آن نقش دارند، به‌گونه‌ای‌ که با قرارگرفتن سرمایه‌گذاران در دامنه‌های خاص تعریف‌شده برای سود، نقطۀ مرجع با سطح جدید انطباق پیدا می‌کند، درحالی ‌که قرارگرفتن سرمایه‌گذاران در ناحیۀ زیان اثر معکوسی در شکل‌گیری سطح جدید نقطۀ مرجع‌ دارد. طبق نتایج حاصل، با درنظرگرفتن متغیرهای استفاده‌شده در پژوهش، ضمن تأیید پویایی نقطۀ مرجع، با اتکاء به اثر تمایلی، سطح انطباق نقطۀ مرجع سرمایه‌گذاران و رفتار سرمایه‌گذاران نسبت به واگذاری و یا نگهداری سهام را می‌توان برآورد کرد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظریۀ دورنما</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نقطۀ مرجع</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اثر تمایلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سطح انطباق</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تصمیم‌گیری در شرایط عدم اطمینان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مالیرفتاری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21573_14d79a855120eda5386e17708956455e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
