<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" "journalpublishing3.dtd">
<article article-type="مقاله علمی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">دانشگاه اصفهان</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1170</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>دانشگاه اصفهان</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">88</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21570</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21570_232850c1c565f26c1d7ae8dbdc08d8c4.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>تامین مالی</subject>
					          		<subject>مدیریت نهادهای تامین مالی (بانک، بیمه، لیزینگ، تامین سرمایه، رتبه‌بندی اعتباری)</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>توسعۀ بخش بانکی، ساختار سرمایه و عملکرد بنگاه‌های غیر‌مالی پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار</article-title>
			        <subtitle>توسعۀ بخش بانکی، ساختار سرمایه و عملکرد بنگاه‌های غیر‌مالی پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>یاوری</surname>
			            <given-names>کاظم</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانش آموخته دکتری اقتصاد مالی، گروه اقتصاد، دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>شهیدی</surname>
			            <given-names>آمنه</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار گروه اقتصاد، دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>دهقان دهنوی</surname>
			            <given-names>محمدعلی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار گروه بانکداری اسلامی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>حیدری</surname>
			            <given-names>حسن</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار گروه اقتصاد، دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2017</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>5</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>1</fpage>
			      <lpage>20</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>05</day>
			          <month>04</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>30</day>
			          <month>06</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2017, دانشگاه اصفهان. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2017</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21570.html">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21570.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>هدف پژوهش حاضر، برآورد اثر توسعۀ بخش بانکی در عملکرد بنگاه‌های غیر‌مالی پذیرفته‌شده در سازمان بورس و اوراق بهادار ایران از مسیر اثرگذاری احتمالی بر ساختار سرمایه بنگاه‌ها است. برای دستیابی به این هدف از یک سو اثر توسعۀ بخش بانکی در ساختار سرمایه و از سوی دیگر اثر ساختار سرمایه در عملکرد بنگاه‌ها با استفاده از داده‌های تابلویی نامتوازن و در چارچوب یک سیستم معادلات مثلثی آزموده شده است. در این راستا شاخص‌های مربوط به اندازه و فعالیت بخش بانکی و معیارهای عملکردی ارزش افزوده بازار و Q توبین به کار گرفته شده است. نتایج حاصل از مطالعه نشان می‌دهد ساختار سرمایه در عملکرد بنگاه‌ها، اثر مثبت و توسعۀ بخش بانکی اثر منفی بر ساختار سرمایه و درنتیجه بر عملکرد بنگاه‌ها در ایران دارد. علاوه بر این، نتایج مطالعه نشان می‌دهد متغیرهای سودآوری، مالیات و فرصت‌های رشد ازجمله متغیرهای اثرگذار در ساختار سرمایه و متغیرهای اندازه، سودآوری، فرصت‌های رشد و درجۀ مشهودبودن دارایی‌ها از جمله متغیرهای اثرگذار در عملکرد بنگاه‌ها است.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>توسعۀ بخش بانکی</kwd>
						<kwd>ساختار سرمایه</kwd>
						<kwd>عملکرد بنگاه</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>[1] Aghaei, M. A., &amp; Kazempour, M. (2014). Capital structure and firms performance in Tehran stock exchange. International Conference on Management. Tehran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>[2] Arabsalehi, M., Farahmand, S. H.., &amp; Ramtin, M. (2011). Investigating the relationship between debt policies and firm performance of the companies listed in Tehran stock exchange. Financial Accounting. 3(2): 43-61.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>[3] Fathi, S., Abzari, M., &amp; Habibi, S. (2014). Determinants of capital structure: meta-analysis. Asset Management &amp; Financing. 2(1): 55-74.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>[4] Gholizadeh, M.H., Asadi, B., &amp; Shamsi, A. (2014). The impact of capital structure on the value of listed companies in Tehran stock exchange: static and dynamic methods of panel data. 6th Conference on Development of Financing System in Iran. Tehran. 45-65.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>[5] Gujarati, M.N. (1955). Basic Econometrics. Vol.2. Hamid Abrishami (2005). 3st Edition. Tehran: University of Tehran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>[6] Hashemi, A., &amp; Akhlaghi H. A. (2010). The effect financial leverage, dividend policy and profitably in the future value of firm.Financial Accounting. 2(6): 38-49.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>[7] Honarbakhsh, S., Birjandi, H., &amp; Birjandi, M. (2012). The survey of relative influence of business strategies on the relationship between financial leverage and performance.Knowledge of Security Analysis. 5(15): 47-58.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>[8] Khalifeh Soltani, A., Akhlaghi, H.A., &amp; Saedi, R. (2014). The investigation of factors affecting the capital structure using the Tobit models: an empirical examination of static trade-off, pecking order and agency cost theories. Asset Management &amp; Financing. 2(1): 37-54.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>[9] Kordestani, G. R., &amp; Najafi Emran, M. (2009). Determinants of debt ratio: the static trade-off and pecking order theories. Financial Research. 9(4): 73-90.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>[10] Mahmoudabadi, H., Mahdavi, G.H., &amp; Fereyduni, M. (2013). An investigation the effects of the free cash flows and agency costs on the performance of the companies listed in Tehran stock exchange (TSE(. Accounting Knowledge. 4(12): 111-131.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>[11] Mehrani, S., Kashanipoor, M., &amp; Rasaiean, A. (2009). A survey on the determinants of capital structure in Tehran stock exchange.Economic Research Review. No.4 (supplement): 125-150.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>[12] Mohamadzadeh, P., Mamipour, S., &amp; Feshari, M. (2010). Stata Applications in Econometrics.Vol.1. 1st Edition. Tehran: Press of Noreelm and Faculty of Economic Sciences.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>[13] Noferesti, M. (1999). Unit Root and Co-integration in Econometrics.1st Edition. Tehran: Cultural Services Institute of Rasa.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>[14] Pourali, M. R., &amp; Alavi, V. (2014). A review of the financing methods and theories related to capital structure. The Second Conference on Accounting, Financial Management and Investment. ISSN: 2322-3510.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>[15] Rahimian, N., Tavakolnia, E., &amp; Tirgari, M. (2013). Investigating the curvilinear relationship between capital structure with performance and firm value of companies listed in Tehran stock exchange. Financial Knowledge of Security Analysis. 6 (19): 67-79.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>[16] Almajali, A. Y., Alamro, S. A., &amp; Al-Soub, Y. Z. (2012). Factors affecting the financial performance of Jordanian insurance companies listed at Amman stock exchange. Journal of Management Research. 4(2): 266-289.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>[17] Anca, M., &amp; Petre, B. (2012). Do romanian banking institutions create shareholder value. Procedia Economics and Finance. 3: 144-151.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>[18] Antoniou, A., Guney, Y., &amp; Paudyal, K. (2002). Determinants of corporate capital structure: evidence from European countries. University of Durham.Working Paper.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>[19] Basu, K., &amp; Rajeev, M. (2013). Determinants of capital structure of Indian corporate sector: evidence of regulatory impact. The Institute for Social and Economic Change. Bangalore. Working Paper 306.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>[20] Bauer, P. (2004). Determinants of capital structure: empirical evidence from the Czech Republic. Czech Journal of Economics and Finance. 54: 1-2, 2-21.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>[21] Chen, J. J. (2004). Determinants of capital structure of Chinese listed companies. Journal of Business Research. 57: 1341-1351.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>[22] Chen, S. Y., &amp; Chen, L. J. (2011). Capital structure determinants: an empirical study in Taiwan. African Journal of Business Management. 5(27): 10974-10983.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>[23] Cheng, M. C., &amp; Tzeng, Z. C. (2011). Does leverage and efficiency affect each other.Journal of Accounting, Finance and Economics. 1(1): 77-95.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>[24] Delcoure, N. (2007). The determinants of capital structure in transitional economics. International Review of Economics and Finance. 16: 400-415.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>[25] Demirguc-Kunt, A., &amp; Levine, R. (1999). Bank-based and market-based financial systems: cross- country comparisons. World Bank, Research Working papers. DOI: 10.1596/1813-9450-2143.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>[26] Doku, J. N., Adjasi, C. &amp; Sarpong-Kumankuma, E. (2011). Financial market development and capital structure of listed firms–empirical evidence from Ghana. Serbian Journal of Management. 6(2): 155-168.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>[27] Eriotis, N., Vasiliou, D., &amp; Vontoura-Neokosmidi, Z. (2007). How firm characteristics affect capital structure: an empirical study. Managerial Finance. 33(5): 321-331.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>[28] Etudaiye-Muhtar, O. F., &amp; Ahmad, R. (2014). Banking sector development and corporate leverage: empirical evidence from South African firms.International Journal of Economics and Finance. 6(8): 278-288.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>[29] Hossain, F., &amp; Ali, A. (2012). Impact of firm specific factors on capital structure decision: an empirical study of Bangladeshi companies. International Journal of Business Research and Management. 3(4): 163-182.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>[30] Huang, D. T., &amp; Liu, Z. C. (2010). A study of the relationship between related party transactions and firm value in high technology firms in Taiwan and China. African Journal of Business Management, 4(9): 1924-1931.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>[31] Hunjra, A. I., Chani, M. I., Javed, S., Naeem, S., &amp; Ijaz, M. S. (2014). Impact of micro economic variables on firm`s performance. International Journal of Economics and Empirical Research. 2(2): 65-73.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>[32] Jensen, M. (1986). Agency costs of free cash flow, corporate finance and takeovers. American Economic Review. 76(2): 323-329.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>[33] Jensen, M., &amp; Meckling, W. (1976). Theory of the firm: managerial behavior, agency costs and ownership structure. Journal of Financial Economics. Vol.3, 4: 305-360.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>[34] Jiraporn, P., Chintrakarn, P., Kim, J. C., &amp; Liu, Y. (2013). Exploring the agency cost of debt: evidence from the ISS governance standards.Journal of Financial Services Research. 44: 205-227.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>[35] Kebewar, M., &amp; Ahmed Shah, S. M. N. (2012). The effect of debt on corporate profitability: evidence from French service sector. MPRA Paper.No. 43304.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>[36] Kodongo, O., Mokoaleli-Mokoteli, T., &amp; Maina, L. (2014). Capital structure, profitability and firm value: panel evidence of listed firms in Kenya. MPRA Paper.No. 57116.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>[37] Manawaduge, A., De Zoysa, A., Chowdhury, K., &amp; Chandarakumara, A. (2011). Capital structure and firm performance in emerging economics: an empirical analysis of Srilankan firms. Corporate Ownership &amp; Control. 8(4): 253-263.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>[38] Mansourlakoraj, R., &amp; Sepasi, S. (2015). Free cash flow, capital structure and the value of listed companies in Tehran stock exchange.International Journal of Management- Accounting and Economics. 2(2): 144-148.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>[39] Margaritis, D., &amp; Psillaki, M. (2007). Capital structure and firm efficiency. Journal of Business finance &amp; Accounting, 34(9-10): 1447-1469.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>[40] Masoud, N. (2014). The determinants of capital structure choice: evidence from Libyan firms. Research Journal of Finance and Accounting. 5(1): 67-83.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>[41] Memon, F., Bhutto, N. A., &amp; Abbas, G. (2010). Capital structure and firm performance: a case of Textile sector of Pakistan. Asian Journal of Business and Management Sciences. 1(9): 9-15.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>[42] Mokhova, N., &amp; Zinecker, M. (2014). Macroeconomic factors and corporate capital structure.Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences. 110: 530-540.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>[43] Muthama, C., Mbaluka, P., &amp; Kalunda, E. (2013). An empirical analysis of macro-economic influences on corporate capital structure of listed companies in Kenya.Journal of Finance and Investment Analysis. 2(2): 41-62.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>[44] Nguyen, D., Diaz-Rainey, I., &amp; Gregoriou, A. (2012). Financial development and the determinants of capital structure in Vietnam. Available at: http;//ssrn.com/abstract=2014834.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>[45] Niu, X. (2008). Theoretical and practical review of capital structure and its determinants.International Journal of Business and Management. 3(3): 133-139.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>[46] Pouraghajan, A. B., Malekian, E., Emamgholipour, M., Lotfollahpour, V., &amp; Mohammadpour Bagheri, M. (2012). The relationship between capital structure and firm performance evaluation measures: evidence from the Tehran stock exchange. International Journal of Business and Commerce. 1(9): 166-181.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>[47] Pourali, M. R., &amp; Roze, Z. (2013). The relationship between market value added with refined economic value added and performance accounting criteria in the firms listed in the Tehran stock exchange. International Research Journal of Applied and Basic Sciences. ISSN: 2251-838X. 4(6): 1636-1645.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>[48] Psillaki, M., &amp; Daskalakis, N. (2008). Are the determinants of capital structure country or firm specific? evidence from SMEs. Small Business Economics. 33(3): 319-333.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>[49] Ruiz-Porras, A. (2009). Financial structure, financial development and banking fragility: international evidence. Analysis Economics. 56(XXIV): 147-173.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>[50] Salawu, R. O., Asaolu, T. O., &amp; Yinusa, D. O. (2012). Financial policy and corporate performance: an empirical analysis of Nigerian listed companies. International Journal of Economics and Finance. 4(4): 175-181.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>[51] Salim, M., &amp; Yadav, R. (2012). Capital structure and firm performance: evidence from Malaysian listed companies. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences. 65: 156-166.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>[52] Sayilgan, G., Karabacak, H., &amp; Kucukkocaoglu, G. (2006). The firm-specific determinants of corporate capital structure: evidence from Turkish panel data. Investment Management &amp; Financial Innovations. 3,2: 125-139.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>[53] Sbeiti, W. M. (2008). Stock Markets Dynamics, Financial Sectors Development and Corporate Capital Structure in the GCC Countries.Thesis for the Degree of Doctor of Philosophy.Durham Business School.University of Durham.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>[54] Soumadi, M. S., &amp; Hayajneh, O. S. (2012). Capital structure and corporate performance: empirical study on the public Jordanian shareholdings firms listed in the Amman stock market. European Scientific Journal. 8(22): 173-189.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>[55] StataCorp, (2011). Stata User’s Guide. Version 12, Texas: Stata Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>[56] Tongkong, S. (2012). Key factors influencing capital structure decision and its speed of adjustment of Thai listed real estate companies. Procedia – Social and Behavioral Sciences. 40: 716-720. Available Online at: www.sciencedirect.com.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>[57] Voutsinas, K., &amp; Werner, R. A. (2011). Credit supply and corporate capital structure: evidence from Japan. International Review of Financial Analysis. 20: 320-334.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>[58] Weill, L. (2003). Leverage and corporate performance: a frontier efficiency analysis on European countries. Social Science Research Network.Working Paper Series. _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">دانشگاه اصفهان</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1170</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>دانشگاه اصفهان</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">88</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21571</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21571_d7457ac4a86722d3d90c31f954c21b66.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>1مدیریت دارایی</subject>
					          		<subject>ارزشگذاری دارایی‌های مالی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>قدرت بازار محصول و نقد شوندگی بازار سهام</article-title>
			        <subtitle>قدرت بازار محصول و نقد شوندگی بازار سهام</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>رحمانی</surname>
			            <given-names>علی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم اجتماعی و اقتصادی، دانشگاه الزهراء&amp;quot;س&amp;quot;</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>حاجی مرادخانی</surname>
			            <given-names>حدیثه</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی دکترای حسابداری، دانشکده علوم اجتماعی و اقتصادی دانشگاه الزهراء&amp;quot;س&amp;quot;</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2017</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>5</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>21</fpage>
			      <lpage>36</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>25</day>
			          <month>06</month>
			          <year>2014</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>11</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2017, دانشگاه اصفهان. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2017</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21571.html">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21571.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>براساس پیش‌بینی‌های موجود در نوشتار،قیمت سهام شرکتیکهقدرتبازار محصول بیشتری دارد، حساسیت کمتری به جریان سفارش معاملات سهام نشان میدهد که این امر به نوبۀخود به نقدشوندگی بیشتر در بازار سهام منجر می­شود. در این مقاله پیش‌بینی فوق در یک نمونه از 75 شرکت پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در دورۀ 1388 تا 1391 و با استفاده از سه معیار مختلف نقدناشوندگی (معیار آمیهود، شکاف قیمت نسبی و شکاف قیمت مؤثر) آزموده شد. نتایج حاصل از رگرسیون­های ترکیبی (پنل) نشان داد نقدشوندگی سهام به تناسب سهم بازار (شاخص اول قدرت بازار محصول) افزایش می­یابد. یافته­ها همچنین نشان می‌دهد نسبت سود عملیاتی (شاخص دوم قدرت بازار محصول)، رابطۀ معنادار و منطبق با نظریه با نقدشوندگی بازار سهام ندارد. به­ نظر می­رسد نام­آوری شرکت­ها در بازار محصول (به‌لحاظ سهم بازار) بیش از سودآوری،  موجب افزایش  نقدشوندگی سهام آن‌ها می­شود. سایر نتایج نشان می‌دهد تبلیغات در بازار محصول تأثیری مستقیم در نقدشوندگی در بازار سهام ندارد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>نقد شوندگی سهام</kwd>
						<kwd>قدرت بازار محصول</kwd>
						<kwd>معیار آمیهود</kwd>
						<kwd>شکاف قیمت نسبی</kwd>
						<kwd>شکاف قیمت مؤثر</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>[1]  احمدپور، احمد و امیر رسائیان. (1385)."رابطۀ برخی معیارهای ریسک و اختلاف قیمت پیشنهادی خرید و فروش سهام در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران". بررسی‌های حسابداری و حسابرسی، شمارۀ 46: 37- 60.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>[2]  اسلامی بیدگلی، غلامرضا و عبدالحسین صادقی باطانی. (1383)."ارائۀ قواعد فیلتر و مقایسه بازده قواعد فیلتر با روش خرید و نگهداری". تحقیقات مالی، شمارۀ 18: 3-26.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>[3]  اله یاری، اکبر.(1387). "بررسی شکل ضعیف کارایی بازار سرمایه در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران". فصلنامۀ بورس اوراق بهادار، سال 1، شمارۀ 4: 75-108.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>[4]  ایزدی نیا، ناصر و امیر رسائیان.(1389)." پراکندگی مالکیت و نقدشوندگی سهام". بررسی‌های حسابداری و حسابرسی، دورۀ 17 ، شمارۀ 60 : 3 -22.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>[5]  ایزدی نیا، ناصر و امین حاجیان نژاد.(1388)." بررسی و آزمون رفتار توده‌وار در صنایع منتخب بورس اوراق بهادار تهران".فصلنامۀ بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، سال 2، شمارۀ 7: 105-132.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>[6]  ایزدی نیا، ناصر و منیژه رامشه.(1390)." نقش ویژگی­های معاملات سهام بر نقدشوندگی سهام در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران". مجلۀ پیشرفت­های حسابداری دانشگاه شیراز، دورۀ 3، شمارۀ 1، پیاپی 3/60 : 1-27.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>[7]  ثقفی، علی و محمد مرفوع.(1390). "ریسک نقدشوندگی سهام و کیفیت سود". فصلنامۀ مطالعات حسابداری ، شمارۀ 29 : 1-37.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>[8]  دریائی، عباسعلی؛ پاکدل، عبدالله و نرگس فلاح محمدی.(1390)." تبیین رابطۀ بین حاکمیت شرکتی و نقدشوندگی سهام با استفاده از سیستم معادلات همزمان"، تحقیقات حسابداری وحسابرسی، شمارۀ 10: 132-146.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>[9]  رحمانی، علی؛ حسینی، سیدعلی و نرگس رضاپور. (1389). "رابطۀ مالکیت نهادی و نقدشوندگی سهام در ایران". بررسیۀهای حسابداری و حسابرسی ، دورۀ 17 ، شمارۀ 61 : 39-54.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>[10]          ستایش، محمدحسین؛ کاظم نژاد، مصطفی و مهدی ذوالفقاری. (1390)." بررسی تأثیر کیفیت افشا بر نقدشوندگی سهام و هزینۀ سرمایۀ شرکت­های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران". مجلۀ پژوهش­های حسابداری مالی ، سال 3 ، شمارۀ 3 ، شمارۀ پیاپی 9 : 55-74.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>[11]         سلیمی فر، مصطفی و زهرا شیرزور.(1389)." بررسی کارایی اطلاعاتی بازار بورس به روش آزمون نسبت واریانس". مجلۀ دانش و توسعه، سال 18، شمارۀ 31: 29-58.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>[12]         صلواتی، شاپور و امیر رسائیان.(1386). "بررسی رابطۀ بین ساختار سرمایه و نقدشوندگی سهام در ایران". نامۀ اقتصادی ، 63 ، جلد 3 ، شمارۀ 2 : 143-163.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>[13]         صمدی، سعید؛ نصراللهی، زهرا و امین زاهد مهر. (1386)."آزمون کارایی و وجود حباب قیمت در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران با استفاده از قاعدۀ فیلتر و الگوی CAPM". فصلنامۀ بررسی­های اقتصادی، دورۀ 4، شمارۀ 4: 91-113.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>[14]         فخاری، حسین و ابراهیم بذرافشان. (1390). "بررسی اثر نقدشوندگی بر عملکرد شرکت­ها در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران". تحقیقات حسابداری ، دورۀ 3، شمارۀ 9 : 116-129 .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>[15]         لشکری، محمد و هما مرتاضی. (1390)." نظریۀ مالی رفتاری و تأثیر آن بر حجم سرمایه‌گذاری افراد در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران". راهبرد، شمارۀ 48:26-63.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>[16]         مرادزاده، مهدی؛ رضاپور، نرگس و حجت اله فرزانی.(1389)." بررسی نقش مدیریت اقلام تعهدی در نقدشوندگی سهام شرکت­های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران". مجلۀ پژوهش­های حسابداری مالی، سال 2، شمارۀ 3 ، شمارۀ پیاپی 5 : 101- 116.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>[17]             مهرانی، ساسان و امیر رساییان.(1388)." نقدشوندگی سهام و نقدشوندگی دارایی­ها". حسابرس، شمارۀ 46: 52-56.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>[18]         یحیی زاده فر، محمود؛ شمس، شهاب الدین و سید جعفر لاریمی.(1389). "بررسی رابطۀ نقدشوندگی با بازده سهام در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران". تحقیقات مالی، دورۀ 12، شمارۀ 29: 111-128.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>[19]         یعقوب‌نژاد، احمد؛ رهنمای رودپشتی، فریدون و علی ذبیحی. (1390)." بررسی تأثیر نظام راهبری شرکتی بر نقدشوندگی سهام شرکت­های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران". فصلنامۀ بورس اوراق بهادار، سال4 ، شمارۀ 13: 157-173.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>[20]          Amihud, Y.)2002(."Illiquidity and stock returns: cross-section and time-series effects". Journal of Financial Markets 5: 31–56.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>[21]          Chun, H., Kim, J.-W., Morck, R., Yeung, B. (2008)."Creative destruction and firm-specific performance heterogeneity”. Journal of Financial Economics 89: 109–135.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>[22]          Chung H., Sheu H., and Wang J. (2009). “Do firms’ earnings management practices affect their equity liquidity?”,Finance Research Letters 6:152–158.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>[23]          Datta ,Sudip. , Datta ,Mai Iskandar. &amp; Vivek Singh. (2013). "Product market power, industry structure, and corporate earnings management". Journal of Banking &amp; Finance 37: 3273–3285.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>[24]          Demsetz, H. (1968). "The cost of transacting". Quarterly Journal of Economics 82: 33–53.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>[25]          Dennis, P.J., Weston, J.P. (2002)." Who’s informed? An analysis of stock ownership and informed trading".AFA  Atlanta Meetings.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>[26]          Gaspar, J.-M., Massa, M. (2006)."Idiosyncratic volatility and product market competition". Journal of Business 79: 3125–3152.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>[27]          Grullon, G., Kanatas, G., Weston, J.P. (2004). “Advertising, breadth of ownership, and liquidity”. Review of Financial Studies 17: 439–461.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>[28]          Irvine, P.J., Pontiff, J. (2008). "Idiosyncratic return volatility, cash flows, and product market competition". Review of Financial Studies 22: 1149–1177.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>[29]          Kale, J.R., loon,Y.C.(2011)."Product market power and stock market liquidity".Journal of Financial Markets 14: 376–410.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>[30]          Kubick, Thomas R., Lynch, Daniel P., Mayberry, Michael A., and Thomas C. Omer. (2014)."Product Market Power and Tax Avoidance: Market Leaders, Mimicking Strategies, and Stock Returns". The Accounting Review, In-Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>[31]          LaFond, R., Lang, M., Skaife, H. (2007). "Earnings Smoothing, Governance and Liquidity: International Evidence", Working paper. Available at http://ssrn.com.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>[32]          Peress, J. (2010). "Product market competition, insider trading and stock market efficiency". Journal of Finance 65: 1–43.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>[33]          Rubin, A. (2007). "Ownership level, ownership concentration and liquidity”. Journal of Financial Markets 10: 219–248.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>[34]          Tookes, H.E. (2008)."Information, trading, and product market interactions: cross-sectional implications of informed trading". Journal of Finance 63: 379–413.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>[35]          Yoon, Seokhyun Aaron. (2011). A Mathematical Methods in the Social Sciences (MMSS) Program, Northwestern University, Evanston, IL 60201, USA.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation> _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">دانشگاه اصفهان</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1170</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>دانشگاه اصفهان</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">88</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21572</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21572_5c353db025230c550cd5261bd449ef26.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>تامین مالی</subject>
					          		<subject>حاکمیت شرکتی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>حساسیت منابع خارجی به جریان وجه نقد در شرایط محدودیت‌های مالی داخلی و خارجی در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس و اوراق بهادار تهران</article-title>
			        <subtitle>جریان نقد عملیاتی، شرکت‌های محدود و نامحدود،محدودیت مالی</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>حاجیها</surname>
			            <given-names>زهره</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار و عضو هیات علمی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران شرق، دانشکده علوم انسانی، گروه حسابداری</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>محمدی چم خانی</surname>
			            <given-names>زهره</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>کارشناس ارشد حسابداری دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد سیرجان، دانشکده علوم انسانی، گروه حسابداری</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2017</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>5</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>37</fpage>
			      <lpage>50</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>23</day>
			          <month>01</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>12</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2017, دانشگاه اصفهان. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2017</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21572.html">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21572.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>ایجاد توزان بین وجه نقد موجود و نیازهای نقدی، یکی از مهم‌ترین عوامل سلامت اقتصادی و تداوم فعالیت واحدهای تجاری است. بنابراین پژوهش حاضر، حساسیت منابع خارجی را به نقدینگی در شرایط محدودیت‌های مالی داخلی و خارجی در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران بررسی می‌کند. معیار سنتی محدودیت مالی شامل اندازۀ شرکت و یکی از معیارهای مدرن محدودیت مالی، ذخایر نقدی (وجوه نقد و معادل آن) است. در این پژوهش از هر دو معیار سنتی و مدرن برای تفکیک شرکت‌ها براساس محدودیت مالی استفاده شده است. لذا اطلاعات 85 شرکت پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در سال‌های 1392-1385 به صورت تابلویی استفاده شده است. یافته‌ها نشان می‌دهد ارتباط وجه نقد عملیاتی با اندازۀ شرکت‌های دارای محدودیت مالی، مثبت و معنی‌دار است. همچنین حساسیت منابع خارجی به نقدینگی در شرکت‌هایمحدود در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران به محدودیت منابع مالی خارجی بیشتر از سایر شرکت‌ها است. تغییرات وجوه نقد در شرکت‌های دارای محدودیت مالی نسبت به شرکت‌هایی که محدودیت مالیندارند،تأثیر بیشتری درسرمایه‌گذاری دارد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>محدودیت مالی</kwd>
						<kwd>جریان نقد عملیاتی</kwd>
						<kwd>شرکت‌های محدود و نامحدود</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>[1] Aghae, M. A., &amp; Hassani, H. (2009). Study of the Effect of Managers' Personal Incentives and Corporate Governance Variables on Costs Stickiness in Companies Listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Financial Accounting Research. 1(2): 7-35.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>[2] Jahankhani, A., &amp; Kanani Amiri, M. (2006). Presentation of the Model to Determine the Capital Expenditures of Listed Companies in TSE Using Accounting Information.Daneshvar Raftar. 86: 17-57.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>[3] Hossein pour, Z. (2005). The investigation between factors effective on investment sensibility – cash flows in Companies Listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. Master dissertation.Economics and Administrative science.Esfahan University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>[4] Sepasi, S., &amp; Yabloui Khamsaloui. M. (2014).Asymmetric Cash Flow Sensitivity of Cash Holdings.The Iranian Accounting and Auditing Review. 20(4): 61-67.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>[5] Foroughi, D., &amp; Farzadi, S. (2014). The investigation of changes in cash flows on the cash holding level by financing constraint in Companies Listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. Asset Management &amp; Financing. 2(1): 21-36.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>[6] Ghorbani, S., &amp; Adili, M. (2012). Firm Value, Cash Holdings and Information Asymmetry.Journal of Accounting Knowledge. 3(8): 131-145.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>[7] Kashanipour, M., &amp; Naghinejad, B. (2009). The investigation of effect of financial constraints on cash sensivity, Accounting Research. 2:72-93.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>[8] Malekian, E., Ahmadpour, A., &amp; Mohamadi, M. (2012). An empirical investigation on factors determining cash holdings of companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. The Iranian Accounting and Auditing Review. 11(3): 96-102.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>[9] Almeida, H., Campello, M., &amp;Weisbach, M.S. (2004). The cash flow sensitivity of cash.Journal of Finance. 59:1777–1804.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>[10] Allayannis, G., Mozumdar, A. (2004). The impact of negative cash flow and influential observations on investment-cash flow sensitivity estimates. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance. 28: 901-930.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>[11] Bao, D., Chan, K., &amp; Zhang, W. (2012). Asymmetric cash flow sensitivity of cash holdings. Journal of Corporate Finance. 18: 690-700.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>[12] Denis, J.D., Sibilkov, V. (2007). Financial constraint, investment and the Value of Cash Holding. Working Paper</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>[13] Dongmi, L. (2010). Financial constraints: R&amp;D investment, and stock returns. Rady School of Management University of California San Diego 1-6: 22-24.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>[14] Fazzari, M., Steven, Hubbard, R., Glenn &amp; Petersen, C.B. (1988). Investment-cash flow sensitivities are useful, Brookings Papers on Economic Activity: 141–195.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>[15] Flannery, A.J., Mark J., Rangan, P.K. (2006). Partial adjustment toward target capital structures.Journal of Financial Economics. 79: 469–506.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>[16] Gamba, A. &amp; Triantis, A. (2008). The value of financial flexibility.Journal of Finance, 63(5): 2263-2296.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>[17] Garcia-Teruel, P. J., Martinez-Solano, J. P. Sanchez-Ballesta, P. (2008). Accruals quality and corporate cash holdings.Journal of Accounting and Finance. 49: 95–115.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>[18] Guariglia, A. (2008). Internal financial constraints, external financial constrains, and investment choice: evidence from a panel of UK firms. Center for finance and credit markets working paper. 07/03, university of Nottingham.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>[19] Harford, J., Kecskes, A., Mansi, S. (2012). Investor horizons and corporate Cash holdings.Review of Financial Studies. 19 (2): 531- 559.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>[20] Kaplan, N., &amp; Zingales, L. (1997). Investment-cash flow sensitivities are not valid measures of financing constraints. QuarterlyJournal of Economics. CXII: 169–215.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>[21] López-Gutiérrez, C., Sanfilippo-Azofra, S., &amp; Torre-Olmo. B. (2014), Investment decisions of companies in financial distress.BRQ Business Research Quarterly.ARTICLE IN PRESS.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>[22] Máñez, Juan A. María E., Rochina-Barrachina, S.L., Juan A. &amp; Vicente, O. (2015). Financial constraints and Spanish manufacturing firms’ R&amp;D and exporting strategies, available at: https://editorialexpress.com/cgi-bin/conference/download.cgi?db_name=IIOC2014&amp;paper_id=280.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>[23] Mishkin, F. S. (2007). The Economics of Money, Banking, and Financial Markets Boston: Addison Wesley. ISBN 0-321-42177-9.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>[24] Nobanee, H., Abdullatif, M., &amp; Al Hajjar, M. (2011). Cash conversion cycle and firm’s performance of Japanese firms.Asian Review of Accounting. 19: 147-156.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation> _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">دانشگاه اصفهان</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1170</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>دانشگاه اصفهان</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">88</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21573</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21573_14d79a855120eda5386e17708956455e.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>1مدیریت دارایی</subject>
					          		<subject>مدیریت ریسک دارایی های مالی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>الگوی تصمیم‌گیری تحت شرایط ریسک در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران مبتنی بر نقطۀ مرجع پویا</article-title>
			        <subtitle>الگوی تصمیم‌گیری تحت شرایط ریسک در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران مبتنی بر نقطۀ مرجع پویا</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>تهرانی</surname>
			            <given-names>رضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیارگروه مالی و بیمه -دانشکده مدیریت -دانشگاه تهران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>نوربخش</surname>
			            <given-names>عسگر</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت مالی، گروه مالی و بیمه -دانشکده مدیریت -دانشگاه تهران، ‌ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2017</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>5</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>51</fpage>
			      <lpage>68</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>16</day>
			          <month>06</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>24</day>
			          <month>08</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2017, دانشگاه اصفهان. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2017</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21573.html">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21573.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>هدف پژوهش حاضر، تعیین سطح انطباق‌پذیری نقطۀ مرجع و تأکید بر پویایی این نقطه به‌عنوان عامل تعیین‌کنندۀ سود و زیان سهامداران و اقدام آنان به رهاکردن و یا نگهداری سهام براساس نظریۀ دورنما به‌عنوان یکی از آخرین نظریه‌های مالی رفتاری است. برآورد نحوۀ انطباق‌پذیری نقطۀ مرجع و تبیین رفتار سرمایه‌گذاران در مواجهه با سود و زیان، ضرورت انجام پژوهش را مشخص کرده است. بدین‌منظور با بهره‌گیری از داده‌های لازم در قلمرو زمانی سال‌های 1383 تا 1392، سعی شده است به مسألۀ اصلی پژوهش پاسخ داده شود.نتایج پژوهش نشان می‌دهددو متغیر میزان سود (زیان) و مدت‌زمان سود (زیان) و اثر همزمان آن‌ها در یکدیگر در شکل‌گیری سطح نقطۀ مرجع و انطباق آن نقش دارند، به‌گونه‌ای‌ که با قرارگرفتن سرمایه‌گذاران در دامنه‌های خاص تعریف‌شده برای سود، نقطۀ مرجع با سطح جدید انطباق پیدا می‌کند، درحالی ‌که قرارگرفتن سرمایه‌گذاران در ناحیۀ زیان اثر معکوسی در شکل‌گیری سطح جدید نقطۀ مرجع‌ دارد. طبق نتایج حاصل، با درنظرگرفتن متغیرهای استفاده‌شده در پژوهش، ضمن تأیید پویایی نقطۀ مرجع، با اتکاء به اثر تمایلی، سطح انطباق نقطۀ مرجع سرمایه‌گذاران و رفتار سرمایه‌گذاران نسبت به واگذاری و یا نگهداری سهام را می‌توان برآورد کرد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>نظریۀ دورنما</kwd>
						<kwd>نقطۀ مرجع</kwd>
						<kwd>اثر تمایلی</kwd>
						<kwd>سطح انطباق</kwd>
						<kwd>تصمیم‌گیری در شرایط عدم اطمینان</kwd>
						<kwd>مالیرفتاری</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>[1] Arkes, Hal R., David Hirshleifer, Danling Jiang and Sonya Lim (2008).  Reference Point Adaptation: Tests in the Domain of Security Trading. Organization Behavior and Human Decision Processes, 105, 67-81.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>[2] Badri, Ahmad and ShoakhiZavare, Alireza (2010). Reference Points, Stock Price and Trading Volume: Evidences from Tehran Stock Exchange. Quarterly Journal of Securities Exchange. Volume: 3, Issue: 12.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>[3] Baker, Malcolm, and Yuhai Xuan (2009). Under New Management: Equity Issues and the Attribution of Past Returns. Working Paper.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>[4] Bartling, B.; Brandes, L.; Schunk, D. (2014). Expectations as reference points: Field evidence from professional soccer. Forthcoming in: Management Science.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>[5] Baucells, Manel, Martin Weber and Frank Welfens (2007). Reference Point Formation Over Time: A Weighting Function Approach. Working paper, University of Mannheim.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>[6] Carmen Lee, Roman Kräussl, Andre Lucas, and Leo Paas (2010). Why Do Investors Sell Losers? How Adaptation to Losses Affects Future Capitulation Decisions. Center for Financial Studies, No. 2010/23.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>[7] Chen, H., &amp; Rao, A. (2002). Close Encounters of Two Kinds: False Alarms and Dashed Hopes. Marketing Science, 21(2), 178–96.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>[8] Fehr-Duda, Schürer, and Schubert (2006).  What Determines the Shape of the Probability Weighting Function?.Economic Working Paper Series. 06/54, ETH Zurich, August 2006, 40 pages.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>[9] Frazzini, Andrea (2007). The Disposition Effect and Underreaction to News. The Journal of Finance, Vol. LXI, NO. 4.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>[10]           Gneezy, Uri (2005). Updating the Reference Point: Experimental Evidence. In Experiential Business Research. Vol. 3, ed. Rami Zwick and Amnon Rapoport, Massachusetts: Kluwer Academic Publishers.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>[11]           Gonzalez, R., &amp; Wu, G. (1999).  On the shape of the probability weighting function. Cognitive Psychology. 38, 129–166.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>[12]           Haipeng (Allan) Chen, Akshay R. Rao (2002). Close Encounters of Two Kinds: False Alarms and Dashed Hopes. Marketing Science, 21,178-196</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>[13]           Hoffmann, A. O. I., S. F. Henry &amp; N. Kalogeras (2012). Aspirations as Reference Points: An Experimental Investigation of Risk Behavior over Time. Theory and DecisionJournal.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>[14]           Huddart, S., Lang, M. and M. Yetman (2003). Psychological Factors, Stock Price Paths and Trading Volume.  Working Paper, Pennsylvania State University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>[15]           Huddart, S., Lang, M. and M. Yetman (2009). Volume and price patterns around a stock’s 52 week highs and lows: Theory and evidence. Management Science. 55(1): 16-31.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>[16]           Jahankhani, Ali; Noferesti, Mohammad: and Garaguzlu, Farhang (2009). A survey on overconfidence and trading volume. Jurnal of Business Management. Volume: 30, 105-123.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>[17]           Kahneman, D.  and Tversky, A. (1979). Prospect theory: an analysis of decision and risk. Journal of Econometrica. vol 47 (2) Pp: 263-291.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>[18]           Köszegi, Botond, and Matthew Rabin (2006). A Model of Reference-dependent Preferences. Quarterly Journal of Economics, 121(4), 1133–65.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>[19]           Larrick, Richard P. and Wu, George (1999). Goals as Reference Points. Cognitive Psychology. 38, 79–109.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>[20]           Lee, Carmen, Roman Kraeussl, Andre Lucas, and Leonard J. Paas (2008). A Dynamic Model of Investor Decision-Making: How Adaptation to Losses Affects Future Selling Decisions, TI Discussion Paper. 08-112/2.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>[21]           Odean, Terrance (1998). Are Investors Reluctant to Realize their Losses?.Journal of Finance, 53 (October), 1775-98.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>[22]           Pompian, Michael M. (2006). Behavioral Finance and Wealth Management. USA: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>[23]           Sackett, A. M., G. Wu, R. J. White, A. B. Markle (2015). Harnessing optimism: How eliciting goals improves performance. Working paper.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>[24]           Shefrin, Hersh, and Meir Statman, (1985). The disposition to sell winners too early and ride losers too long: Theory and evidence. Journal of Finance 40, 777–791.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>[25]           Suzuki, A., &amp; Kume, K. (2008). Aging, probability weighting, and reference point adaptation: An experimental study. Retrieved from Osaka University, Institute of Social and Economic Research website. ISER Discussion Paper No. 720.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>[26]           Tversky, Amos, and Daniel Kahneman (1974). Judgment under Uncertainty: Heuristics and Biases. Science, 185(4157), 1124-1131.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>[27]           Von Neumann, John, and Oskar Morgenstern (1944). Theory of Games and Economic Behavior. Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>[28]           Weber, Martin and Colin F. Camerer (1998). The Disposition Effect in Securities Trading: an Experimental Analysis. Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization. 33 (January), 167-84.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>[29]           Wu, G., and Gonzalez, R. (1999). Nonlinear decision weights in choice under uncertainty. Management Science. 45, 74–85.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>[30]           Yogo, Motohiro (2008). Asset Prices Under Rising Aspirations and Reference dependent Preferences. Journal of Business and Economic Statistics. 26, 131-43.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation> _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">دانشگاه اصفهان</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1170</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>دانشگاه اصفهان</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">88</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21172</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21172_789e4d28531c9a4cc2713c09cb4ab841.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>تامین مالی</subject>
					          		<subject>مباحث خاص تامین مالی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>شبیه‏سازی و سیاست‏گذاری درونی و بیرونی مشکلات تأمین مالی شرکت‌های کوچک و متوسط با رویکرد پویایی‏شناسی سیستمی</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>مصلح شیرازی</surname>
			            <given-names>علی نقی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار بخش مدیریت، دانشکده اقتصاد، مدیریت و علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه شیراز، شیراز، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>خلیفه</surname>
			            <given-names>مجتبی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت سیستم‏ها، بخش مدیریت، دانشکده اقتصاد، مدیریت و علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه شیراز، شیراز، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2017</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>5</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>69</fpage>
			      <lpage>92</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>12</day>
			          <month>05</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>24</day>
			          <month>02</month>
			          <year>2016</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2017, دانشگاه اصفهان. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2017</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21172.html">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21172.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>بنگاه‌های کوچک و متوسط به‌دلیل آثار زیادی که در رفع مشکلات بیکاری و رونق اقتصاد جوامع بر عهده دارند، نیروی محرک اقتصاد شناخته می‌شوند. مشکل تأمین مالی این بنگاه‌ها ازجمله مشکلات اساسی در روند فعالیت آنها است. این پژوهش- با توجه به مهم‌ترین ابزار تأمین مالی بنگاه‌های ذکرشده، یعنی بانک‌ها- با رویکردی ابتکاری و با استفاده از روش پویایی‏شناسی سیستمی، لزوم بررسی پویای متغیرهای اثرگذار را در تأمین مالی و همچنین بررسی موانع و مشکلات درونی و بیرونی بنگاه‌ها را در تأمین مالی هدف خود قرار داده است. الگوی سیستمی پژوهش و روابط علّی متغیرهای آن با توجه به مبانی پژوهش و مطالعه خدابخشیان و همکاران (2013)، توسعه یافته، الگو‏سازی شده و با استفاده از رویکرد پویایی‏شناسی سیستمی و به‌کارگیری نرم‏افزار Vensim DSS شبیه‏سازی و تحلیل شده است. نتایج نشان می‌دهد تسهیل روند دسترسی به وام و افزایش کیفیت برنامۀ کسب و کار بنگاه‌ها به‌شدت می‌تواند باعث افزایش نرخ خصوصی‏سازی، منابع مالی بانک‌ها و نرخ وام‏دهی به بنگاه‌ها و کاهش فساد اداری شود. همچنین افزایش درآمد و جریان‏های نقدی بنگاه‌ها، افزایش در بازپرداخت وام‌ها و کاهش مطالبات بانک‌ها را در پی خواهد داشت.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>پویایی‌های سیستم</kwd>
						<kwd>تأمین مالی بنگاه‌های کوچک و متوسط</kwd>
						<kwd>سهولت دسترسی به وام</kwd>
						<kwd>بدهی‌های دولت</kwd>
						<kwd>جریان‏های نقدی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Amin Beidokhti, A. A., &amp; Zargar, M. (2011). Considering existence barriers in small and medium enterprises and proposing a supportive framework. Employment and society, 138, 34-48. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>[2] Amin Beidokhti, A. A., &amp; Zargar, M. (2012). Pathology of small and medium enterprises and express of practical strategies for supporting them (case study: Semnan Province). Management &amp; Development Process, 78, 125-156. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>[3] Behr, P., &amp; Güttler, A. Plattner, D. (2004). Credit scoring and relationship lending: the case of German SME. Version 16. http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/summary?doi=10.1.1.201.7187.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>[4] Berger, A. N., &amp; Udell, G. F. (1998). The economics of small business finance: the roles of private equity and debt markets in the financial growth cycle. Journal of Banking and Finance, 22, 613–673.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>[5] Berger, A., &amp; Udell, G. (2006). A more complete conceptual framework for SME finance. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, 30, 2945-2966.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>[6] Bhattacharya, D., Faiz, N., &amp; Zohir, S. (2000). Policy for employment generation in the informal sector of Bangladesh- A study prepared for the international labor office. Dhaka: Centre for Policy Dialogue.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>[7] By, J., &amp; Labak, H. (1996). Feedback and behavioral system. Journal of System Review, 15, 56-68.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>[8] Casey, E., &amp; O'Toole, C. M. (2014). Bank lending constraints, trade credit and alternative financing during the financial crisis: Evidence from European SMEs. Journal of Corporate Finance, 27, 173–193.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>[9] Darnahal, M. (n.d.). Considering effective factors on marketing functions in small and medium enterprises. (Ms. Thesis). Islamic Azad University, Emirates Branch, UAE. (In Persian). http://tehraniec.ir/index.aspx?fkeyid=&amp;siteid=1&amp;pageid=612&amp;siteid=1</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>[10] Erghmiri, M. H. (2011). Prioritize of organizational development interventions in small and medium enterprises. (Ms. Thesis). Allameh Tabataba'i University, Tehran. (In Persian). http://tehraniec.ir/index.aspx?fkeyid=&amp;siteid=1&amp;pageid=599&amp;siteid=1</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>[11] Forrester, J. W. (1997). Building a system dynamic model. prepared for the mit system dynamic in education project. Massachusetts, Massachusetts Institute of Technology.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>[12] Hoseinzadeh, F. (2009). Position of credit measurement in developing small and early return economic enterprises. International conference of credit measurement/Ministry and Industry. (In Persian). http://www.imlco.ir/index.aspx?fkeyid=&amp;siteid=69&amp;pageid=871</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>[13] Karimi, F., &amp; Sagheb, H. (2009). Considering situation and positions of small industries of Esfehan province. Journal of Commercial Survey, 7(37), 64-82. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>[14] Khodabakhshian, A., Khosravi, M., &amp; Mashayekhi, A. N. (2013). Adverse selection in SME financing: when both bank and innovative entrepreneur lose. Proceedings of the International Conference of the System Dynamics Society.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>[15] Kővári, A., &amp; Pruyt, E. (2013). Lending to small and medium enterprises: a novel approach to credit portfolio management. Proceedings of the International Conference of the System Dynamics Society.  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>[16] Mousavi Haghighi, M. H., &amp; Khalifeh, M. (2015). Simulating the effect of financial leverage model on company value via system dynamics approach. Asset Management and Financing, 3, 83-104. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>[17] Mousavi Haghighi, M. H., Khalifeh, M., Safaei, B., &amp; Saberi, H. (2015). Simulating of stock price from the point of effective internal and external factors via system dynamics approach. Asset Management and Financing, In Press. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>[18] Mozafari, M. (2007). Small industries in today's economy. Tehran, Mazyar Publication. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>[19] Navazeni, M. (n.d.). Barriers to entrepreneurship and SME development (case study: park aria of parand). (Ms. Thesis). Garmsar Payame Noor University, Garmsar. (In Persian). http://tehraniec.ir/index.aspx?fkeyid=&amp;siteid=1&amp;pageid=616&amp;siteid=1</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>[20] Prelipceana, G., &amp; Boscoianub, M. (2014). A hybrid framework for SME financing based on the mix between governmental support and the use of a specialized investment fund in the actual context of a slow recovery after crises and turbulences. Procedia Economics and Finance, 15, 738 – 745.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>[21] Rajaeian, N. (n.d.). Evaluating SMEs’ supportive pakages in order to develop export. (Ms. Thesis). University of Tehran, International Campus-Kish Island, Kish. (In Persian). http://tehraniec.ir/index.aspx?fkeyid=&amp;siteid=1&amp;pageid=597&amp;siteid=1</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>[22] Robb, A., &amp; Robinson, D. T. (2009). The capital structure decisions of new firms. NBER Working Paper, No. 16272.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>[23] Sheikh Khozani, Z., Hosseiny, K., &amp; Rahimian, M. (2010). System dynamic modeling of multipurpose reservoir operation to estimate the optimal height of the dam. Journal of modeling in engineering, 8(21), 57-66. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>[24] Sterman. J. (2000). Business dynamics: systems thinking and modeling for a complex world. NY, McGraw-Hill publication.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>[25] Theil, H. (1966). Applied economic forecasting. Amsterdam, North Holland Publishing.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>[26] UNIDO. (2008). Small and medium sized enterprises. available at http//www.unido.org.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>[27] Yeh-Yun, L., &amp; Zhang, J. (2005). Changing structures of SME networks: lessons from the publishing industry in Taiwan. Long Range Planning, 38, 145-162.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>[28] www.akhbarbank.com/vdcjhaet.uqetozsffu.html</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>[29] www.alef.ir/vdcjttevouqeohz.fsfu.html?18txt</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>[30] www.banker.ir/tag</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>[31] www.eghtesadnews.com/Live/Stories/DEN-107025/</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>[32] www.isipo.ir</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>[33] www.mashreghnews.ir/fa/news/303284 _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">دانشگاه اصفهان</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1170</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>دانشگاه اصفهان</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">88</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21575</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21575_8e24aaef634c7011be81e7a1ff0aa74c.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>1مدیریت دارایی</subject>
					          		<subject>مدیریت ریسک سرمایه گذاری شرکتی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>تأثیر مدیریت اثربخش ریسک در عملکرد مالی شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران: نقش واسطه‌ای سرمایۀ فکری و اهرم مالی</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>عسگرنژاد نوری</surname>
			            <given-names>باقر</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار مدیریت بازرگانی، گروه مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی، اردبیل، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>امکانی</surname>
			            <given-names>پریسا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت کسب و کار، گروه مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی، اردبیل، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2017</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>5</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>93</fpage>
			      <lpage>112</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>28</day>
			          <month>12</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>26</day>
			          <month>06</month>
			          <year>2016</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2017, دانشگاه اصفهان. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2017</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21575.html">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21575.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>مدیریت اثربخش ریسک، از رویکردهای جدیدی است که برای بهبود عملکرد سازمان‌ها در شرایط عدم اطمینان محیطی استفاده می‌شود. مدیریت اثربخش ریسک به معنی کاربرد نظام‌مند سیاست‌های مدیریتی، رویه‌ها و فرایندهای مربوط به فعالیت‌های تحلیل، ارزیابی و کنترل ریسک است. این پژوهش می‌کوشد تأثیر مدیریت اثربخش ریسک را بر عملکرد مالی شرکت‌ها بررسی کرده و نقش واسطه‌ای سرمایۀ فکری و اهرم مالی را نیز در ارتباط بین این متغیر‌ها شناسایی کند. بدین منظور برخی از شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در دورۀ زمانی 1387 تا 1392مطالعه شدند. نتایج نشان می‌دهد مدیریت اثربخش ریسک بر نرخ بازده دارایی‌ها و رشد ارزش بازار، تأثیر مثبت دارد. اهرم مالی تنها در ارتباط بین مدیریت اثربخش ریسک و نرخ بازده دارایی‌ها نقش واسطه‌ای داشته، نقش واسطه‌ای سرمایۀ فکری نیز فقط در ارتباط بین مدیریت اثربخش ریسک و رشد ارزش بازار تأیید شد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>مدیریت اثربخش ریسک</kwd>
						<kwd>عملکرد مالی</kwd>
						<kwd>سرمایۀ فکری</kwd>
						<kwd>اهرم مالی</kwd>
						<kwd>بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Acharyya, M., and Mutenga, S. (2013). “The Benefits of Implementing Enterprise Risk Management: Evidence from the Non-life Insurance Industry”, available at: www.ermsymposium.org/2013/pdf/erm-2013-paper-acharyya.pdf (accessed 15 December2013).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>[2] Afshari, A., Saeedi A., Reshadi E. (2012). Influence of Financial Leverage on Investment Decisions in Companies Listed at the Tehran Stock Exchange, Management Accounting, Vol. 5, No.13,Pp. 17–29.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>[3] Ahmadvand, M. R. (2009).AShort Review of Risk Management Tasks in Economical Activities, Economical Journal, Vol .78,Pp. 5–35</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>[4] Ahmadian, Majid; Ghorbani, Rahim (2013). The Study of the Relationship between the Intellectual Capital and the Organizational Performance In the Ministry of Economy and Finance, Magazine of Economics, Vol. 11 and 12, Pp. 111–130</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>[5] Andersen, TJ. (2009). Effective Risk Management Outcomes: Exploring Effects of Innovation and Capital Structure, Journal of Strategy and Management, Vol.2,No.4, Pp. 352 – 379.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>[6] Andersen, T.J. (2006). Global Derivatives: A Strategic Risk Management Perspective. PearsonEducation, Harlow.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>[7] Appiah, K.O. (2013). Corporate Governance and Corporate Failure: Evidance from Listed UKFrims, A Doctoral thesis Submitted in Partial Fulfilment for the Award of the Degree of Doctor of Philosophy of Loughborough University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>[8] Auden, W.C., Shackman, J.D. and Onken M.H. (2006). "Top Management Team, International Risk Management Factor and Firm Performance", Team Performance Management: An International Journal, Vol.12, No.7/8, Pp. 209 – 224.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>[9] Barney, J.B. (1991). Firm Resources and Sustained Competitive Advantage. Journal ofManagement, Vol.17:Pp. 99–120.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>[10] Chen, P. (2005). Intellectual Capital Performance of Commercial Banks in Malaysia.Journal of Intellectual Capital, Vol.6,No.3,Pp. 385–396.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>[11] Chung, K. (2008). Intellectual Capital:Definitions, Categorization and Reporting Models.Journalof Intellectual Capital, Vol.9, No.4,Pp.609–638, available at: www.emeraldinsight.com/1469-1930.htm.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>[12] Ghayouri Moghaddam, A. and Hajeb, H. R. (2015). The Effect of Capital Structure on Profit Efficiency of Companies Listed in Automotive and Parts Manufacturing Industry of Tehran Stock Exchange, Asset Mangement and Financing, Vol. 3,No.1, Pp. 91–106.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>[13] Gordon, L.A., Loeb, M.P. and Tseng, C.Y. (2009). “Enterprise Risk Management and FirmPerformance: AContingency Perspective”, Journal of Accounting and Public Policy, Vol.28, (4):Pp. 301–327.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>[14] Hemati, H. and Mehrabi, A. (2011). The Relationship between Intellectual Capital and Financial   Performance of Listed Performance of Listed Companies in Tehran Stock Exchange, Accounting Research, Vol.3 ,Pp. 72–84.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>[15] Hoyt, R.E. and Liebenberg, A.P. (2011). The Value of Enterprise Risk Management, The Journal of Risk and Insurance, Vol.78, No. 4, Pp. 795– 822.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>[16] Hosseini .A; Hosseini, M.H. and  Seyedmotahari, M. (2014). The Relation between ERM Techniques and Performance of Food Industry firms Journal of Empircal Research in Accounting, Vol. 4, No.1, Pp. 45–60.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>[17] Iraji Rad, A. and Slamdost Kelidbari, M. (2015). Measuring Intellectual Capital and Its Relationship with the q Tobin ratio and Systematic Risk Beta (study of financial intermediation companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange). Asset Mangement and Financing, Vol.2, No. 4,Pp. 97–110.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>[18] Jensen, M.C. (1986). Agency Costs of Free Cash Flow, Corporate Finance and Takeovers.American Economic Review, Vol. 76, No.2, Pp. 323–329.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>[19] Jola, G. and Eslami, BJ. (2010). The Evaluation of the Relationship between Capital Structure and Systematic Risk of Companies Listed on TSE. Journal of TSE, Vol. 8, Pp. 91–113.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>[20]Khodamipour, A. and Esmaeili, A. (2011).Value-Relevance of Changes in Financial leverage for Explaining Operating Performance, Journal of Accounting knowledge , Vol.2, No.6, Pp. 65 – 92.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>[21] Khodamipour A., Hooshmand zafaranieh R., Mohmmadrezakhani V. (2014). The Effect of Capital Structure on Stock Futures Abnormal Returns with Regard to the Level of Concentration in the Industry, Journal of Financial Management Strategy,Vol.1, No.3,Pp. 131–146.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>[22] Maditinos, D., Chatzoudes, D., Tsairidis, Ch .and Theriou, G. (2011). The Impact ofIntellectual Capital on Firm’s Market Value and Financial Performance.”Journal of Intellectual Capital,Vol.12, No.1, Pp. 132–151.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>[23] Naderi Honari, R., Hossein Zadeh, Z. (2012).  Examining the Relationship between Financial leverage on the Economic Performance of the Company. The National Conference of Accounting, Financial Management and Investment, Gorgan, Golestan University of Applied Sciences.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>[24] Newbert, L. (2007). Empirical Research on the Resource-Based View of the Firm: An Assessment and Suggestions for Future Research. Strategic Management Journal,Vol.28, No.2,Pp. 121–146.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>[25] Nikoumaram, H. and Es'haghi, F. (2010). "The Relationship between the Impact of Intellectual Capital on the Performance of Value and Growth in the Tehran Stock Exchange, Financial Knowledge of Securities Analysis (financial studies), Vol.3, No.6,Pp.133-163.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>[26] Nourvash, I. and Yazdani, S. (2006).  "Evaluating the Effect of Financial Leverage and the Market value added of companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange", Scientific and Research Journal of Financial Accounting, Vol.4,Pp. 35–48.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>[27]Peter Yeoh, (2016). "Corporate Governance Failures and the Road to Crime", Journal of FinancialCrime, Vol.23, No.1, Pp. 216 – 230</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>[28]Pourzamani, Z., jahanshad, A. and Mahmoodabadi, A. (2012). "The Impact of Intellectual Capital on Market Value and Financial Performance", Accounting and Auditing Review, Vol.19, No.2,Pp. 17–30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>[29]Pourzamani, Z. and Karimi, A. (2010). "The Effect of RiskManagement Intellectual Capital onCompany’s Performance, Financial Knowledge of Security Analysis (financial studies), Vol.3, No.6, Pp. 1 – 18.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>[30] Rezaee, F., Hemmati, H. and Kargar-e-Shamloo, B. (2010). "Intellectual Capital and Financial Performance based on Value", Journal of Accounting Researches, Vol. 2, No.7 , Pp. 52 – 71.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>[31] Rahimian N., Hosseini D., Moazez E. and Nesbati N., (2012). The Impact of Intellectual Capital on the Financial Performance of Companies in the Automotive and Construction Parts Listed in the Tehran Stock Exchange, The First Regional Conference on New Approaches Accounting and Auditing, Bandar Gaz, Islamic Azad University of Bandar Gaz Branch, http://www.civilica.com/Paper-RCNAAA01-RCNAAA01_011.html.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>[32] Salim, M. and Yadav, R. (2012). Capital Structure and Firm Performance: Evidence from Malaysian Listed Companies. International Congress on Interdisciplinary Business and Social Science, Social and Behavioral Sciences, Pp. 156 – 166.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>[33] Sawa Wabwile, E. &amp; Chitiavi, S. &amp; Mwalati, B.A &amp; Ondiek Douglas, M.  (2014). Financial Leverage and Performance Variance A Mong Banks. Evidence of Tier Commercial Banks Listed On Nairobi Security Exchange Kenya, International Journal of Business and Management Invention ISSN (Online), Vol.3, No.4, Pp. 01–13.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>[34] Siti Zaleha, A.R., Che Ruhana, I. and Wan Khairuzzaman, Wan I. , (2014). "Management Accounting Systems, Enterprise Risk Management and Organizational Performance in Financial Institutions", Asian Review of Accounting, Vol.22, No.2, Pp. 128 – 144.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>[35] Spence, M. (1985). Capital Structure and the Corporation’s Product Market Environment. In: Friedman, B. (ED.), Corporate Capital Structure in the United States. University of Chicago Press, Chivago,IL. http://www.nber.org/chapters/c11426.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>[36] Stan-Maduka, E. (2010). The Impact of Risk Management Practice on the Development of African Businesses. World Journal of Entrepreneurship, Management and Sustainable Development, Vol.6,No.3, Pp. 213–219.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>[37] Souza, Rodrigo Silva De; Silva Gomes, Sônia Maria Da; Bruni, Adriano Leal; Oliveira, Gilca Garcia De;Sampaio, Márcio Santos, Faria. Juliano Almeida De. (2012). Enterprise Risk Management and Performance Improvement: A Study with Brazilian Nonfinancial Firms, in Antonio Davila, Marc J. Epstein, Jean-François Manzoni (ed.) Performance Measurement and Management Control: Global Issues, Studies in Managerial and Financial Accounting, Vol.25,Pp. 275 – 298.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>[38] Tari Verdi, Y. and Z. Damchi Jelodar, (2012). The Relationship between Risk and Performance of the Company,"Journal of Financial Accounting and Auditing, Vol.4, No.14, Pp. 43–62.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation> [39] Thomas, L.G. (1996). Dynamic Resourcefulness and the Hypercompetitive Shift, OrganizationScience,Vol.7,Pp. 221–42.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>[40]Wang, J. &amp; Lin &amp; Willie &amp; Huang&amp;Yu-Hsiang. (2010). A Performance-Oriented Risk Management Framework for Innovative R&amp;D Projects. Technovation, www.elsevier.com/locate/technovation.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>[41]Yahyazadehfar, M., Aghajani, H., Yahyatabar, F., (2014).  Investigation of the Relationship between Intellectual Capital and Companies' Performance in Tehran stock exchange, Financial Research, Vol.37, Pp. 181–199.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>[42] Zeitun, R. and Tian, G. (2007). Capital Structure and Corporate Performance: Evidence from Jordan.Australasian Accounting Business and Finance Journal, Vol.1, Pp. 40– 53.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation> _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">دانشگاه اصفهان</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1170</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>دانشگاه اصفهان</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">88</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21576</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21576_58146174faf756111d166465c0955496.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>1مدیریت دارایی</subject>
					          		<subject>صندوق‌ها (سرمایه گذاری، بازنشستگی، پوشش ریسک)</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>ارائۀ یک الگوی استوار با درجۀ محافظه‌کاری تنظیم‌شدنی برای تشکیل صندوق شاخصی در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</article-title>
			        <subtitle>ارائۀ یک الگوی استوار با درجۀ محافظه‌کاری تنظیم‌شدنی برای تشکیل صندوق شاخصی در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>بحرالعلوم</surname>
			            <given-names>محمد مهدی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، دانشکده مدیریت وحسابداری، گروه مالی و بانکداری</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>امیری</surname>
			            <given-names>مقصود</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استاد، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، گروه مدیریت صنعتی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>فلاح شمس لیالستانی</surname>
			            <given-names>میرفیض</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامیواحد تهران مرکزی، دانشکده مدیریت، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2017</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>5</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>113</fpage>
			      <lpage>128</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>29</day>
			          <month>05</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>24</day>
			          <month>02</month>
			          <year>2016</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2017, دانشگاه اصفهان. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2017</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21576.html">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21576.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>در این پژوهش، استراتژی تخصیص اثربخش دارایی‌های مالی در شرایط عدم اطمینان با هدف کاهش ریسک، کنترل هزینه، کاهش حجم معاملات و تحقق بازده مطلوب مطالعه شده است. برای پیاده‌سازی این استراتژی، تشکیل صندوق شاخصی با محدودیت عدد صحیح و در چارچوب بهینه‌سازی استوار مدّنظر قرار گرفت. با وجود اینکه تخصیص منابع با یک صندوق شاخصی، اساس تمامی راهبردهای نوین سرمایه‏گذاری است، در بازار سرمایۀ ایران کمتر به آن توجه شده و نیز ویژگی استواری آن به‌لحاظ پاسخگویی به عدم قطعیت در بازده مدّنظر دارایی‏ها تاکنون مطالعه نشده است. در این پژوهش، غربال‌گری سهام شرکت‌های پذیرش‌شده در بورس برمبنای ارزش بازار برای تعیین اقلام تشکیل‌دهندۀ صندوق و الگو‌سازی مسألۀ ردیابی شاخص به‌صورت کمینه‏سازی قدر مطلق انحراف بین بازده مدّنظر صندوق و شاخص بورس انجام شده است. نتایج حاصل از تجزیه و تحلیل داده‏ها بر انتخاب 20 سهم و بروزرسانی ترکیب صندوق بعد از سه ماه دلالت دارد. همچنین محاسبات انجام‌شده بر عملکرد مناسب صندوق‌های تشکیل‌شده در ردیابی شاخص مبتنی بر معیارهایی چون همبستگی، ریشۀ دوم میانگین مربعات خطا و بازده مازاد با بهره‌گیری از داده‌های خارج از نمونه تأکید دارد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>صندوق شاخصی</kwd>
						<kwd>ردیابی شاخص</kwd>
						<kwd>بهینه‌سازی استوار</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Andrews, C., Ford, D., &amp; Mcllinson, K. (1986). The design of index funds and alternative methods of replication. The Investment Analyst. 82: 16-23.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>[2] Bahrololoum, M.M, Tehrani, R., &amp; Hanifi, R. (2012). Designing of a heuristic algorithm for the optimal tracker fund selection: The case of Tehran stock exchange index. Accounting &amp; Auditing Research. 4(13): 20-43.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>[3] Beasley, J.E, Meade, N., &amp; Chang, T.J. (2003). An evolutionary heuristic for the index tracking problem. European Journal of Operational Research. 148: 621–643.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>[4] Bertsimas, D., Sim, M. (2004). The price of robustness. Operations Research. 35-53.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>[5] Chen, C., Kwon, R.H. (2012). Robust portfolio selection for index tracking. Computers &amp; Operations Research. 39: 829–837.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>[6] Coleman, T., Y. Li, J. H. (2006). Minimizing tracking error while restricting the number of assets. Journal of Risk. 8: 33–56.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>[7] Elton, E.J., Gruber, M.J. (1977). Risk reduction and portfolio size: An analytical solution. Journal of Business. 50: 415-437.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>[8] Fallahshams, M., Amiri, M., Bahrololoum, M.M., &amp; Gharahkhani, M. (2015), A model for core-satellite investment in Tehran stock exchange using the hybrid approach of exact and heuristic algorithms, Journal of Investment Knowledge. Accepted paper. Be printed in No.15, autumn.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>[9] Gaivoronski A.A, Krylov, S., &amp; Van der Wijst, N. (2005). Optimal portfolio selection and dynamic benchmark tracking. European Journal of Operational Research. 163(1): 115–31.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>[10] Gharahkhani, M., Sadjadi, S.J., &amp; Safari, A. (2013). Portfolio robust optimization using CAPM approach. Operation &amp; Production Management. 8(6): No.1. 61-68.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>[11] Gharahkhani, M., Fazlelahi, F.Z., &amp; Sadjadi, S.J. (2014). A robust optimization approach for index tracking problem. Journal of Computer Science. 10: 2450-2463.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>[12] Gilli, M., K¨ellezi, E. (2001).Threshold accepting for index tracking. Working paper available from the first author at department of econometrics, University of Geneva, 1211 Geneva 4. Switzerland.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>[13] Hanifi, R., Bahrololoum, M.M., &amp; Javadi, B. (2009). Design and comparative analysis of heuristic algorithms to implement index investing in Tehran stock exchange. Management Vision. 8(32): 89-108.     </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>[14] Jansen, R., Dijk, R.V. (2002). Optimal benchmark tracking with small portfolios. Journal of Portfolio Management. 28: 33–39.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>[15] Konno, H., Wijayanayake, A. (2001). Minimal cost index tracking under nonlinear transaction costs and minimal transaction unit constraints. International Journal of Theoretical and Applied Finance. 4(6): 939–58.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>[16] Meade, N., Salkin, G. (1990). Developing and maintaining an equity index fund. Journal of the Operational Research Society. 41(7): 599–607.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>[17] Modarres Y, M., Hasanzade M, M. (2009). Robust optimization of a portfolio including option, Sharif Management &amp; Industrial Engineering. 1-27(1): 93-102.     </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>[18] Rafaely, B., Bennell, J. (2006). Optimization of FTSE 100 tracker funds: A comparison of genetic algorithms and quadratic programming. Managerial Finance. 32(6): 477-492.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>[19] Roll, R. (1992). A mean/variance analysis of tracking error. Journal of Portfolio Management. 18: 13–22.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>[20] Rohweder, H.C. (1998). Implementing stock selection ideas: Does tracking error optimization do any good? Journal of Portfolio Management. 24(3): 49–59.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>[21] Rudolf, M., Wolter, H.J, &amp; Zimmermann, H. (1999). A linear model for tracking error minimization. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance. 23(1): 85–103.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>[22] Schoenfeld, A. (2004). Active index investing. Hoboken, N.C: John Wiley and Sons Inc.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>[23] Seifi, A. Hanafizadeh, P., &amp; Navabi, H.R. (2004). Robust integrated model in single period stock selection problem. Financial Research. 17: 71-96.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>[24] Soyster, A.L. (1973). Convex programming with set-inclusive constraints and applications to inexact linear programming. Operations research. 21(5): 1154-1157.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>[25]Torrubiano, R., Suarez, A. (2008). A hybrid optimization approach to index tracking. Operational Research. DOI 10.1007/s10479-008-0404-4: 1-15.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation> _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">دانشگاه اصفهان</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1170</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>دانشگاه اصفهان</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">88</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21577</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21577_3873eef696eefaa17b3530df142284f0.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>1مدیریت دارایی</subject>
					          		<subject>رویکردهای رفتاری در معاملات دارایی‌های مالی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>بررسی تأثیر رفتار توده‌وار در ریسک‌پذیری مدیران شرکت‌های سرمایه‌گذاری در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</article-title>
			        <subtitle>بررسی تأثیر رفتار توده‌وار در ریسک‌پذیری مدیران شرکت‌های سرمایه‌گذاری در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>دوستار</surname>
			            <given-names>محمد</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه گیلان، رشت، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>محمد نژاد</surname>
			            <given-names>علی رضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>کارشناس ارشد MBA، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه گیلان، رشت، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>جوادیان لنگرودی</surname>
			            <given-names>مریم</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>کارشناس ارشد MBA، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه گیلان، رشت، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2017</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>5</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>129</fpage>
			      <lpage>148</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>11</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>26</day>
			          <month>09</month>
			          <year>2016</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2017, دانشگاه اصفهان. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2017</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21577.html">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21577.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>چکیده  امروزه رفتار توده­وار، که یکی از مهم‌ترین تورش­های رفتاری در بین شرکت­های سرمایه­گذاری، مدیران و سرمایه‌گذاران است، نقش بسیار مهمی در پذیرش ریسک، بازده ­سهام و سبد سرمایه­گذاری بازی می­کند. هدف از انجام پژوهش حاضر، بررسی تأثیر رفتار توده­وار مدیران شرکت­های سرمایه­گذاری در ریسک­پذیری آنها است. جامعۀ آماری پژوهش شامل تمامی مدیران عامل و مدیران مرتبط با سرمایه­گذاری در شرکت­های سرمایه­گذاری پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران است و حجم نمونه با استفاده از فرمول کوکران 196 نفر محاسبه شد. برای تحلیل فرضیه­های ارائه‌شده در قالب الگوی مفهومی پژوهش، از روش الگوسازی معادلات ساختاری با رویکرد حداقل مربعات جزیی (PLS) استفاده شد. نتایج تحلیل­ها نشا‌ن‌دهندۀ تأیید فرضیۀ اصلی پژوهش و چهار فرضیۀ فرعی مرتبط با آن است. نتایج نشان داد بین ریسک‌پذیری و رفتار توده­وار مدیران شرکت­های سرمایه­گذاری، رابطه­ای معکوس وجود دارد. </p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>رفتار</kwd>
						<kwd>رفتار توده وار</kwd>
						<kwd>ریسک پذیری</kwd>
						<kwd>شرکتهای سرمایه گذاری</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Afjahi, A., SalehiSadaqyani, J., Mahmoudzadeh, E. &amp; AdabiFirozjayi, M. (2015).  Pattern for the Alignment of Power Types with Change Types and its Effect on Companies Performance.Journal of Management Studies in Development And Evolution, 24, 187-219.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>]2] Bikhchandani, D. &amp; Sharmas, L. (2012). Hard Behavior In Financial Markets: A Rewiew, International Monitory Fund, 279-310.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>[3] Chang, E. C., Cheng, J. W. &amp; Khorana, A. (2000). “An examination of Herd Behavior in Equity Markets: An International Perspective”, Journal of Banking and Finance. 24(10), 1651-1699.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>[4] Chin, W. W., Marcolin, B. L. &amp; Newsted, P. R. (2003). A partial least squares latent variable modeling approach for measuring interaction effects: Results from a Monte Carlo simulation study and an electronic-mail emotion/adoption study. Information systems research. 14(2), 189-217.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>[5] Davari, A. &amp; Rezazadeh, A. (1392). Modeling of structural equations with “pls”. Tehran: Jahad publications, First edition.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>[6] Demirer, R. &amp; Kutan, A. (2005). "Does Herding Behavior Exist in Chinese Stock Markets". Journal OF International Finacial Markets, Institutions and Money ,16, 123-142.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>[7] Devenow, A. &amp; Welch, I. (1996)." Rational herding in financial economics". European Economic Review.40(3-5), 603-615.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>[8] Diamond, D. (1991). Reputation acquisition in debt markets. The Journal of Political Economy, 97, 828-862.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>[9] Economou, F., Gavriilidis, C., Kallinterakis, V. &amp; Yardanov, N. (2015). “Do Fund Managers Herd in Frontier Markets - and Why?”, International Review of Financial Analysis Journal, 40, 76-87.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>[10] Einav, L., Finkelstein, A., Pascu, I. &amp; Cullen, M. (2012). “How General Are Risk Preferences? Choices under Uncertainty in Different Domains: Dataset.” American Economic Review.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>[11]  EslamiBidgoli, GH.R. &amp; Shahriari S. (2007).Examination of Herding Behavior of Invesores in Tehran Stock Exchang With Return Dis Persions During, 1380-1384. Journal of Iranian Accounting And Auditing Review, 49, 25-44.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>[12] Esmaelian, M. &amp; Alimohammadi, M. (2015). Evaluation of Investment Decision Using System Dynamics and Real Options. Journal of Asset Management and Financing, 3(1), 1-22.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>[13] Fallah Shams, M., GhalibafAsl, H.  &amp; Nobakht , S. (2011).  The Impact of Experience on Risktaking, Overconfidence and Herding of Investment Companies’ Managers in  In Tehran Stock Exchang. Quarterly Journal of Securities Exchange ,3(12), 25-42.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>[14] Fong,  K.,  Gallagher,  D.  R., Gardner,  P. &amp;  Swan,  P.  L. (2004). “A Closer Examination of Investment Manager Herding Behaviour”, Working Paper available online at www.ssrn.com.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>[15] Fischhoff, B. (1994). What forecasts (seem to) mean. International Journal of Forecasting,10, 387-403.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>[16] Fromlet, H. (2001). "Behavioral Finance – Theory and Practical Application "Business Economics, 36, 24-54.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>[17] Ghoshal, S. &amp; Nohira, N. (1989). “Internal differentiation within multinational corporations”. Strategic Management Journal, 10, 323-337.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>[18] Gilb, T. (2002). Risk Management: A practical toolkit for identifying. Analyzing and coping with project risks. 4(4), 6-17.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>[19] Graham, R. (1999). Herding among investment newsletters: Theory and evidence, The Journal of Finance. 54(1), 237-268.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>[20] Grinblatt, M. &amp; Sheridan, T. (1989). Adverse risk incentives and the design of performance-based contracts, Management Science. 35(7), 807-822.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>[21] Habibpur, K.&amp; Safari, R. (2012). Comprehensive Guide of SPSS in survey researches. Tehran: luye publications, Fifth Edition.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>[22] Hardaker, J. B., Huirne, R. B. M. &amp; Anderson, J. R. (1997). Coping with Risk in Agriculture. CAB International, Wallingford, UK.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>[23] Helland, I. S. (1990). Partial least squares regression and statistical models. Scandinavian Journal of Statistics, 97-114.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>[24] Henseler, J., Ringle, C., &amp; Sinkovics, R. (2009). The use of partial least squares path modeling in international marketing. Advances in International Marketing (AIM), 20, 277-320.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>[25] Heydar Ali, H. (1390). Analysis of multi variables data in behavioral researches. Tehran: PeikFarhang publication, Third edition.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>[26] Hirshleifer, D. &amp; Anjan, V. T. (1992), Managerial conservatism, project choice, and debt. The Review of Financial Studies. 5(3), 437-470.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>[27] Hong, H., Kubik, J. D. &amp; Amit, S. (2000). Security analysts' career concerns and</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>herding of earnings forecasts. RAND Journal of Economics. 31(1), 121-144.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>[28] Johnson, M.,   Lindbrom, H.  &amp; Platan, P. (2002). “Behavioral Finance and the Change of Investor Behavior during and after the Speculative Bubble at the End of the 1990s”. M.S Thesis, School of Economic and Management, Lund University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>[29] Jones, C. P. (2009). Investment: Analysis and Management. Eleventh Edition.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>[30] Kahneman, D. &amp; Tversky, A. (1979). Prospect Theory, an Analsis of Decision under Risk. Econometrica,47,2.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>[31] Kline P. (2012). An Easy Guide to Factor Analysis, First Edition.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>[32] Latifi, M. (1369). The Research Strategy. Journal of Management Knowledge, 1.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>[33]   Lin, H.  W.  (2012). How Herding Bias could be derived from Individual Investor Types and Risk Tolerance? World Academy of Science, Engineering and Technology.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>[34]    Lutje, T. (2009). To Be Good or To Be Better: Asset Managers’ Attitudes Towards Herding. Appl. Financ. Econ,19, 825-839.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>[35] March, J. G. &amp; Shapira, Z. (1987). Managerial Persprctive on Risk and Risk Taking Management Science,33,1404-1418.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>[36] Mazaryazdi, M., Badri, A. &amp; Azizian, A. (2013). An Empirical Investigation of Herd Behavior: Evidence from TSE. Quarterly Journal of Management and Accounting School, 11(39), 1-27.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>[37] McNichols, M.  &amp; Stubben, S. (2008). Does earnings management affect firms’ investment decisions? The Accounting Review. 83, 1571-1603.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>[38] Menkhoff, L., Schmidt, U. &amp; Brozynski, T. (2006). The Impact of Experience on Risk Taking, Overconfidence and Herding of Fund Managers: Complementary Survey Evidence. Eur. Econ, 50,1753-1766.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>[39] Moghimi, M. (2011). "Management Research”, Tehran: Rahdan Publications, first edition.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>[40]  Momeni, M., Dashti, M., Bayramzadeh, S. &amp;SoltanMohammadi, N. (1392). Modeling of structural equations. Tehran: Moalef publication, First edition.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>[41] Pattillo, C. &amp; Soderbom, M. (2000). Managerial Risk Attitudes and Firm Performance in Ghanaian Manufacturing: An Empirical Analysis Based on Experimental Data. [July 2000]. [On Line].http://www.csae.ox.ac.uk></element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>[42] Salvatore, D. (2007). International Economies, Nineth Edition.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>[43] Sarmad, Z., Bazargan, A. &amp; Hejazi, E. (1390). Researches Methods for The Behavioral Science. Tehran: Agah publication,22th edition.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>[44] Scharfstein, D. S. &amp; Jeremy C. S. (1990). Herd behavior and investment. The American Economic Review. 80(3), 465-479.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>[45] Schumacker, R. E. &amp; Lomax R. G. (2004). A Beginner’s Guide to Structural Equation Modeling. Second Edition.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>[46] Vakilifard, H. Foroughnejad, H.  &amp; Khoshnood, M. (2012). Evaluation Investor's Behavior in Tehran Stock Exchange with Analytic Network process (ANP). Quarterly Journal of Asset Management &amp;Financing ,2, 57-64.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>[47] Weber, E.  U.  &amp; Milliman, R. A. (1997). Perceived risk attitudes: Relating risk perception to risky choice. Management Science. 43(2), 123-144.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>[48] Wermers, R. (1999). “Mutual Fund Herding and the Impact on Stock Prices.” Journal of Finance, 54, 581-622.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>[49] Yates, J. (1994). The risk construct, in risk-taking behavior, John Wiley, Chichester, Chapter 1.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>[50] Yousefi, R. &amp; Shahrabadi, A. (2009).  Investigation andExamination of Herding Behavior ofInvestores in Tehran Stock Exchange.Journal Of Management Studies In Development And Evolution ,2, 57-64. _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">دانشگاه اصفهان</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1170</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>دانشگاه اصفهان</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">88</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21578</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21578_789429ea6cdd7888a48fb050a42dcb68.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>1مدیریت دارایی</subject>
					          		<subject>رویکردهای رفتاری در معاملات دارایی‌های مالی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>رفتار جمعی سرمایه گذاران در سطوح خرد و کلان و تأثیر آن در نوسان‌های بازار</article-title>
			        <subtitle>رفتار جمعی سرمایه گذاران در سطوح خرد و کلان و تأثیر آن در نوسان‌های بازار</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>دولو</surname>
			            <given-names>مریم</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار گروه مدیریت مالی و حسابداری، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>پاپائی</surname>
			            <given-names>سید سجاد</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>کارشناسی ارشد گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه البرز، قزوین، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2017</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>5</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>149</fpage>
			      <lpage>166</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>23</day>
			          <month>09</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>27</day>
			          <month>09</month>
			          <year>2016</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2017, دانشگاه اصفهان. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2017</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21578.html">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21578.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>هدف پژوهش حاضر، بررسی پدیدة رفتار جمعی سرمایه­گذاران نهادی و انفرادی در دو سطح خرد و کلان و تأثیر آن در نوسان‌های بازار است. در سطح خرد، علاوه بر مقایسۀ رفتار جمعی سرمایه­گذاران نهادی و انفرادی به روش آزمون t دو نمونه، با استفاده از رگرسیون داده­های تابلویی، تأثیر ویژگی­های بنیادی سهام در رفتار جمعی بررسی می‌شود. در سطح کلان نیز حساسیت تأثیر عوامل بازار بر رفتار جمعی دو گروه سرمایه­گذاران تحلیل و آزمون شده و تأثیر رفتار جمعی کلان در نوسان‌های بازار با استفاده از رگرسیون سری زمانی بررسی می‌شود. نتایج سطح خرد نشان می­دهد رفتار جمعی در بین هر دو گروه سرمایه‌گذاران وجود دارد و این پدیده در بین سرمایه­گذاران نهادی بیشتر است. براساس یافته‌های حاصل، میزان رفتار جمعی به ویژگی­های بنیادی سهام وابسته است که سرمایه­گذاران نهادی  نسبت به این ویژگی­ها،حساسیت بیشتری دارند. یافته­های سطح کلان نیز نشان می‌دهد علاوه بر اینکه رفتار جمعی سرمایه­گذاران نهادی بیشتر تحت تأثیر عوامل بازار به‌ویژه بازده بازار قرار دارد، این رفتار آنان در نوسان‌های بازار نیز مؤثر است. نتایج آزمون علیت گرنجر وگارچ نیز یافته­های سطح کلان را تأیید می­کند.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>رفتار جمعی</kwd>
						<kwd>سرمایه‌گذاران انفرادی</kwd>
						<kwd>سرمایه‌گذاران نهادی</kwd>
						<kwd>مالی رفتاری</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Arabmazar yazdi, M., Badri, A. &amp; Azizian, A. (2013). An Empirical Investigation of Herd Behavior: Evidence from TSE. Empirical Studies in Financial Accounting Quarterly. 11(39): 1-27. In Persian.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>[2] Ezadinia, N. &amp; Hajiannejad, A. (2009). Review and Examine the Herd Behavior in Selected Industries in Tehran Stock Exchange. Quarterly Journal of Securities Exchange. 2(7): 105-132. In Persian.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>[3] Golarzi, Gh. (2013). Intentional or Unintentional of Market Factor Beta Herding in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Financial Accounting Research .5(1): 87-96. In Persian.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>[4] Grinblat, M., Titman, Sh. &amp; Wermers, R. (1995). Momentum Investment Strategies, Portfolio Performance and Herding: a Study of Mutual Fund Behavior. The American Economic Review, 85(5): 1088-1105.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>[5] Kaniel, R., Liu, S., Saar, G. &amp; Titman, S. (2007). Investor Trading and Return Patterns Around Earnings Announcements. Working Paper, Cornell University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>[6] Khodaparast Shirazi, J., Sayrani, M. &amp; Abolfathi, S. (2011). The Characteristics of Stocks on Herding Behavior in Tehran Stock Exchange. The Financial Accounting and Auditing Researches. 3(11): 87-107.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>[7] Lakonishok, J., Shleifer, A. &amp; Vishny, R. (1992). The Impact of Institutional Trading on Stock Prices. Journal of Financial Economics. 31: 13-43.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>[8] Lin, Anchor Y. &amp; Lin, Yueh-Neng. (2014). Herding of Institutional Investors and Margin Traders on Extreme Market Movements. International Review of Economics and Finance. 33: 186–198.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>[9] Mohammadi, Sh., Raei, R., Ghalibaf, H. &amp; Golarzi, Gh. (2010). Analysis of Herd Behavior of Investors in Tehran Stock Exchange Using With State Space Model. Journal of Financial Accounting Research. 2(2): 49-60. In Persian.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>[10] Nnofsinger, J.R. &amp; Sias, R.W. (1999). Herding and Feedback Training by Institutional and Individual Investors. The Journal of Finance. 54(6): 2263-2292.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>[11] Samadi, R. (2011). An Examination of Herding Behavior by Investors In Tehran Stock Exchange Using With Lsv Model. Dissertation. University of Shahid Beheshti, Tehran. In Persian.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>[12] Sias, R. (2004). Institutional Herding. The Review of Financial Studies. 17:165-206.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>[13] Venezia, I., Nashikkar, A. &amp; Shapira, Z. (2011). Firm Specific and Macro Herding by Professional and Amateur Investors and Their Effects on Market Volatility. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance. 35:1599-1609</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>[14] Wermers, R. (1999). Mutual Fund Herding and The Impact on Stock Prices. The Journal of Finance. 54:581-622.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>[15] Wylie, S. (2005).Fund Manager Herding: A Test of the Accuracy of Empirical Results Using U.K. Data. The Journal of Business. 78(1): 381-403.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>[16] Zhang, Yu. &amp; Zheng, Xiaosong. (2016). A Study of Herd Behavior Based on the Chinese Stock Market.  Journal of Applied Management and Investments. 5(2):131-135.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation> [17] Zheng, Dazhi. Li, Huimin. Zhu, Xiaowei. (2015). Herding Behavior in Institutional Investors: Evidence from China’s Stock Market. Journal of Multinational Financial Management. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.mulfin.2015.09.001</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>[18] Yu Zhang: Shanghai University, China Xiaosong Zheng: Tallinn University of Technology, Estonia.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation> _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">دانشگاه اصفهان</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1170</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>دانشگاه اصفهان</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">88</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21579</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21579_1a9867fbd2c3dc2b29dfd066139127a5.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>تامین مالی</subject>
					          		<subject>ساختار سرمایه</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>الگویابی عوامل مؤثر در هزینۀ سرمایۀ سهام عادی: شواهدی از بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</article-title>
			        <subtitle>الگویابی عوامل مؤثر در هزینۀ سرمایۀ سهام عادی: شواهدی از بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>صالحی</surname>
			            <given-names>حمید</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی دکتری حسابداری، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز،دانشکده اقتصاد و علوم اجتماعی، گروه حسابداری</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>سجادی</surname>
			            <given-names>سید حسین</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استاد حسابداری، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، دانشکده اقتصاد و علوم اجتماعی، گروه حسابداری</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>خدادادی</surname>
			            <given-names>ولی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیاردانشکده اقتصاد و علوم اجتماعی، گروه حسابداری دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>راسخ</surname>
			            <given-names>عبدالرحمن</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استاد آمار، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، دانشکده علوم ریاضی و کامپیوتر، گروه آمار</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2017</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>5</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>167</fpage>
			      <lpage>184</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>13</day>
			          <month>04</month>
			          <year>2016</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>27</day>
			          <month>09</month>
			          <year>2016</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2017, دانشگاه اصفهان. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2017</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21579.html">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21579.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>هدف پژوهش حاضر، الگویابی معادلات ساختاری برای بررسی تأثیر عوامل مؤثر در هزینۀ سرمایۀ سهام است. پژوهش از نوع کمّی و از جنس علّی یا پس­رویدادی، ازلحاظ روش اجرا در زمرۀ همبستگی و براساس هدف، از نوع کاربردی است. برای تحلیل داده‌ها دورۀ پژوهش، از روش حداقل مربعات جزئی (PLS) و از نرم­افزار Smart PLS استفاده شده است. براساس اجرای آزمون‌های مختلف، الگو‌های اندازه‌گیری، پایایی، روایی همگرا و روایی واگرای مناسبی دارند. براساس معیارz، تمام مسیرهای مربوط به الگوی ساختاری به ‌غیر از مسیر ساختار صنعت به هزینۀ سرمایه و مسیر کیفیت گزارشگری به عملکرد مالی معنادار هستند. معیار R2 نشان‌دهندۀ برازش قوی الگوی ساختاری، معیار Q2 نشان‌دهندۀ قدرت پیش‌بینی متوسط رو به قوی الگو و معیارGOF نشان‌دهندۀ برازش قوی الگوی کلی است. نتیجۀ پژوهش نشان‌دهندۀ تأثیر مستقیم و غیرمستقیم معنادار راهبری شرکتی و تأثیر غیرمستقیم معنادار ساختار رقابتی صنعت بر هزینۀ سرمایه است، به‌گونه‌ای‌که تأثیر مستقیم راهبری شرکتی قوی‌تر از تأثیر غیرمستقیم آن است. تأثیر مستقیم ساختار صنعت بر هزینۀ سرمایه معنادار نیست.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>معادلات ساختاری</kwd>
						<kwd>راهبری شرکتی</kwd>
						<kwd>ساختار صنعت</kwd>
						<kwd>هزینۀ سرمایه</kwd>
						<kwd>کیفیت گزارشگری مالی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>1. Ahmed, S.,&amp; Hamdan. A. (2015). Impact of corporate governance on firm performance: evidence from bahrain bourse. International Management Review. 11(2): 21-37.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>2. Akins, B.,Jeffrey, N., &amp; Rodrigo, S. V. (2012). Investor competition over information and the pricing of information asymmetry. The Accounting Review.87(1): 35-58.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>3. Armstrong, C., Core, J., Taylor, D., &amp; Verrecchia, R.(2011). When does information asymmetry affect the cost of capital? Journal of Accounting Research. 49: 1-40.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>4. Ashbaugh, H., Collins, D. W., &amp; Lafond, R. (2004). Corporate governance and cost of equity capital. Available at http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>5. Badrinath, S. G., Gay, G.,&amp; Kale, J. (1989). Patterns of institutional investments, prudence, and managerial safety net hypothesis. Journal of Risk and Insurance. 56(4): 605-629.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>6. Baily, M.N.,&amp; Schultze, C.L. (1990). The Productivity of capital in a period of slower growth. Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, Special Issue Microeconomics. 369-406.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>7. Barron, O., Sheng, X., &amp; Thevenot, M. (2013). The information environment and cost of capital. Available at: http://gwu.edu/.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>8. Bhattacharya, N., Ecker, F., Olsson, P., &amp; Schipper, K. (2012). Direct and mediated association among earnings quality, information asymmetry and cost of equity. The Accounting Review. 87(2): 449-482.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>9. Bloomfield, R., &amp; Fischer, P. (2011). Disagreement and cost of capital.Journal of Accounting Research. 49(1): 41-68.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>10. Bozec, Y., &amp; Bozec, R. (2011). Corporate governance quality and the cost of capital. International Journal of Corporate Governance. 2(3): 217- 236.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>11. Bushee, B. (1998). The influence of institutional investor on myopic R&amp;D investments behavior. The Accounting Review. 73(3): 305-333.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>12. Chong, P., S., &amp; Isimoya, E. (2007). Disclosure of governance information by small and medium-sized companies. Corporate Governance. 7(5): 635-648.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>13. Dechow, P.,&amp; Dichev, I. (2002). The quality of accruals and earnings: the role of accrual estimation errors. The Accounting Review. 77: 35-59.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>14. Dhaliwal, D., Huang, S. H., Khurana, K. I. &amp; Pereira, R. (2008). Product market competition and accounting conservatism. Available at: http://ssrn.com/ abstract=1266754.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>15. Elyasiani, E., &amp; Jane-Jia, J. (2008). Institutional ownership stability and BHC performance. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance. 32(9): 1767-1781.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>16. Fama, E., &amp; French, K. (1992). The cross-section of expected stock returns. Journal of Finance. 47: 427–465.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>17. Faulkender, M., Milbourn, T., &amp; Thakor, A. (2006). Does corporate performance determine capital structure and dividend policy? Presented in Seminar at Washington University, NY, Available at:http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/paper.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>18. Francis, J. L., Olsson, R., &amp; Schipper, K. (2005). The market pricing of accruals quality. Journal of Accounting and Economics.39(2): 295-327.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>19. Gao, P. (2010). Disclosure quality, cost of capital and investor welfare. The Accounting Review.85(1): 1-29.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>20. Giroud X., &amp; Mueller, H. M. (2011). Corporate governance, product market competition and equity prices. The Journal of Finance. 66(2): 563-600.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>21. Griffith, R. (2001). Product market competition, efficiency and agency costs: an empirical analysis.IFS Working Paper, Available at: http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/paper.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>22. Hair, J. F., Sarstedt, M., Hopkins, L., &amp; Kuppelwieser, V. (2014). Partial least squares structural equation modeling (PLS-SEM): An emerging tool in business research. European Business Review. 26(2): 106 – 121.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>23. Hasasyegane, Y., Moradi, M.,&amp; Eskandari, H. (2008). The relationship between Institutional Investors and corporate value. Journal of The Accounting and Auditing Review. 15(3): 107-122.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>24. Hashem, N.,&amp; Su, L. (2015). Industry concentration and the cross-section of stock returns: evidence from the UK. Journal of Business Economics &amp; Management. 16(4): 769-785.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>25. Hejazi, R., &amp; Jalali, F. (2007). The factors affecting the cost of capital in companies listed on the Tehran Stock Exchange. Humanities and Social Sciences. No. 24: 13-30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>26. Hou, K., &amp; Robinson, D. T. (2006). Industry concentration and average stock returns. The Journal of Finance. 61(4): 1927-1956.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>27. Jensen, M. (1986). Agency costs of free cash flow, corporate finance and takeovers. American Economic Review. 76(2): 323-329.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>28. Jensen, M. C., &amp; Meckling, W. H. (1976). Theory of the firm: managerial behavior, agency costs and ownership structure. Journal of Financial Economics.3(4): 305-360.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>29. Johnstone, D., (2016). The effect of information on uncertainty and the cost of capital.Contemporary  Accounting Research. 33(2): 752-774.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>30. Kasznik, R. (1999). On the association between voluntary disclosure and earnings management. Journal of Accounting Research. 37: 57-81.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>31. Khiari, W. &amp; A. Karaa. (2013). Corporate governance and disclosure quality: taxonomy of Tunisian Listed Firms using the decision tree method based approach. Journal of Applied Economics and Business Research. 3(2): 95-117.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>32. Khodadadi, V., &amp; Taker, R. (2012). Effect of corporate governance structure on financial performance and firm value of Tehran Listed Firms. Accounting and Auditing Research. 15(4): 88-101.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>33. Lambert, R. A., Leuz, C., &amp; Verrecchia, R. E.  (2011). Information asymmetry, information precision and the cost of capital. Review of Finanace. 16(1): 1-29.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>34. Leuz, C., &amp; Wysocki, P. (2006). Economic consequences of financial reporting and disclosure regulation: areview and suggestions for future research. Working Paper, Available at: http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/paper.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>35. Lyandres, E., &amp; Watanabe, M. (2011). Product market competition and equity returns. Available at:http://people.bu.edu/lyandres/GE-comp-2011-02-17.pdf.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>36. Namazi, M.,&amp; Ebrahimi, S. (2012). Investigating the Relationship between Product Market’s Competitive Structure and Stock Return. Journal of Financial Accounting Research. 2(3): 9-27.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>37. Seyedabaszade, M., Amani, J., Khezri, A. &amp; Pashavi, G. (2012). An introduction to PLS structural equation modeling and its application to behavioral sciences. Orumieh University Publication.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>38. Sobhanifard, Y. &amp; Akhavankharazian, M. (2012). Factor analyses, structural equation modeling. Emam Sadegh University Pablication.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>39. Zhu, F. (2014). Corporate governance and the cost of capital: An international study. International Review of Finance. 14(2): 393-429.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation> _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">دانشگاه اصفهان</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1170</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>دانشگاه اصفهان</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">88</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21580</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21580_ec00b1a5130aa04d9adf861456d7dc59.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>1مدیریت دارایی</subject>
					          		<subject>سرمایه گذاری شرکتی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>نظریۀ اختیارات حقیقی برای مدیریت ریسک در پروژه‏های فناوری اطلاعات</article-title>
			        <subtitle>نظریۀ اختیارات حقیقی برای مدیریت ریسک در پروژه‏های فناوری اطلاعات</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>رسولی</surname>
			            <given-names>سیده سمیه</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانش‏آموخته کارشناسی ارشد گروه مهندسی صنایع، دانشکده فنی و مهندسی، دانشگاه شمال، آمل، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>جعفرزاده افشاری</surname>
			            <given-names>احمد</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار گروه مهندسی صنایع، دانشکده فنی و مهندسی، دانشگاه شمال، آمل، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>سلمانی سراجی</surname>
			            <given-names>مریم</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانش‏آموخته کارشناسی گروه آمار، دانشگاه پیام نور واحد ساری، ساری، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2017</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>5</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>185</fpage>
			      <lpage>200</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>23</day>
			          <month>06</month>
			          <year>2014</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>23</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2016</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2017, دانشگاه اصفهان. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2017</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21580.html">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21580.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>اغلب سازمان‏ها دربارۀ چگونگی ارزیابی سرمایه‏گذاری‏های آیندۀ فناوری اطلاعات دانش کافی ندارند. بیشتر این نوع سرمایه‏گذاری‏ها‏ براساس معیارهای شخصی مدیریت ارشد انجام می‏گیرد، درنتیجه تعداد بسیار کمی از سازمان‏ها، دانشی عمیق دربارۀ ارزش حاصل از هزینۀ صرف‌شده در حوزۀ فناوری اطلاعات دارند. در این پژوهش، روش اختیارات حقیقی به ارزش‏گذاری سرمایه‏گذاری در پروژۀ برنامه‏ریزی منابع بنگاهی با درنظرگرفتن دو اختیار گسترش و کوچک‏سازی پروژه بررسی شده است. براساس یافته‏های پژوهش، ارزش برآوردشده در روش اختیارات حقیقی با درنظرگرفتن انعطاف‏های مدیریتی، متفاوت با ارزش تخمینی به روش تنزیل جریان‏های نقدینگی به دست آمد؛ زیرا در تحلیل نتایج ارزش‏گذاری اختیار گسترش، ارزش فعلی دارایی برای عملیات جاری 8/199 میلیون تومان برآورد شده است. اگر عملیات امروز گسترش داده شود، برآورد ارزش دارایی برابر 6/308 میلیون تومان خواهد شد که این مقدار از ارزش دارایی بدون اعمال اختیار گسترش، بزرگ‌تر است و درنتیجه اعمال اختیار گسترش، ارزش مازادی معادل 8/108 میلیون تومان به همراه خواهد داشت. همچنین تحلیل نتایج ارزش‏گذاری اختیار کوچک‏سازی نشان داده است که ارزش اعمال اختیار کوچک‏سازی با استفاده از روش اختیارات حقیقی برابر 2/118 میلیون تومان است؛ بنابراین اعمال اختیار کوچک‏سازی، ارزش مازادی برای پروژه نخواهد داشت. در نهایت با ارزش‏گذاری اختیارات، اختیاری در نظر گرفته شده است که حداکثر ارزش را برای دارایی در بر داشته باشد و براساس آن نقشه‌ای راهبردی برای پروژه در طول یک سال عمر اختیارات تدوین شده است.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>نظریۀ اختیارات حقیقی</kwd>
						<kwd>سرمایه‏گذاری</kwd>
						<kwd>مدیریت ریسک</kwd>
						<kwd>فناوری اطلاعات</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Afshari, A. J., Omran, M. M.,&amp; Rasouli, S. (in press). Managing information technology investments with real options analysis (in Persian). International Journal of Industrial Engineering &amp; Production Management.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>[2] Amram, M. &amp; Kulatilaka, N. (1999). Real Options: Managing Strategic Investment in an Uncertain World.Boston: Harvard Business School Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>[3] Amram, M., Kulatilaka, N.,&amp; Henderson, J. (1999). Taking an option on IT: Technology value-real options theory evaluates technology investments by linking them to the financial market. CIO Magazine. 12: 46-53.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>[4] Andresen, J. (2001). A Framework for Selecting an IT Evaluation Method in the Context of Construction. PhD Thesis at Technical University of Denmark.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>[5] Avison, D.E., Powell, P. L., Keen, P., Klein, J.H., &amp; Ward, S. (1995). Addressing the need for flexibility in information systems.Journal of Management Systems. 7(2): 43-60.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>[6] Bachelier,L.(2011).Louis Bachelier's Theory of Speculation: the Origins of Modern Finance. Princeton NJ: Princeton University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>[7] Balasubramanian, P., Kulatilaka, N.,&amp; Storck. J. (2000). Managing information technology investments using a real-options approach. The Journal of Strategic Information Systems. 9(1):39-62.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>[8] Black, F., &amp; Scholes, M. (1973). The pricing of options and corporate liabilities. The Journal of Political Economy. 81: 637–654.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>[9] Chatterjee, D., &amp; Ramesh V. C. (1999). Real options for risk management in information technology projects. In: Proceedings of the 32nd Hawaii international conference on system sciences.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>[10] Cox, J.C., Ross, S.A., &amp;Rubinstein, M. (1979). Option pricing: a simple approach. Journal of Financial Economics. 7(1): 229–263.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>[11] Dixit, A. K., &amp; Pindyck, R.S. (1994). Investmentunder Uncertainty. Princeton: Princeton University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>[12] Esmaeilian, M., &amp; Kamal-Abadi, M. M. (2015). Evaluation of investment decision using system Ddynamics and real options (in Persian). Asset Management &amp; Financing. 3 (1):1-22.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>[13] Evans, J.S. (1991). Strategic flexibility for high technology maneuvers: a conceptual framework.Journal of Management Studies. 28(1): 69-89.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>[14] Guo,J.,&amp; Zmeskal,Z. (2016). Valuation of the China internet companyunder a real option approach.Perspectives in Science.7: 65-73.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>[15] Hull, J. (2002). Fundamentals of Futures and Options Markets.New Jersey: Prentice Hall.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>[16] Ingersoll, Jr., Jonathan, E.,&amp; Ross. S. A. (1999). Waiting to invest:investment and uncertainty. Journal ofBusiness.65(1): 1-29.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>[17] Khani, A., Afshari, H.,&amp; Hosseini, M. (2013). Examining of financial decisions, market timing and real investment on Tehran Stock Exchange (in Persian). Asset Management &amp; Financing. 1 (1):109-122.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>[18] Kim, Y.J.,&amp; Sanders, L.G. (2002). Strategic actions in information technology investment based on real option theory.Decision Support systems. 33(1): 1-11.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>[19] Kumar, R.L.(2002).Managing risks in IT projects: an options perspective.Journal of   Information &amp; Management. 40(1): 63-74.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>[20]Morgan, H. M.,&amp; Ngwenyama, O. (2015). Real options, learning cost and timing software upgrades: Towards an integrative model for enterprise software upgrade decision analysis. International Journal of Production Economics. 168: 211-223.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>[21] Myers,S.(1977).Determinants of corporate borrowing.Journal of Financial Economics.5(2):147-175.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>[22]Trigeorgis, L. (1999). Real Options and Business Strategy. London: Haymarket House Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation> _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">دانشگاه اصفهان</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1170</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>دانشگاه اصفهان</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">88</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21581</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21581_4e1613edccd9b3d702e914493f648192.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>1مدیریت دارایی</subject>
					          		<subject>رویکردهای رفتاری در معاملات دارایی‌های مالی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>رابطۀ آب و هوا با بازده و فعالیت‌های معاملاتی: شواهدی از بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</article-title>
			        <subtitle>رابطۀ آب و هوا با بازده و فعالیت‌های معاملاتی: شواهدی از بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>پورمحمدی</surname>
			            <given-names>پریسا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت مالی،گروه مدیریت مالی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>بدری</surname>
			            <given-names>احمد</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار گروه مدیریت مالی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2017</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>5</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>201</fpage>
			      <lpage>220</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>14</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>19</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2016</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2017, دانشگاه اصفهان. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2017</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21581.html">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21581.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>هدف اصلی این پژوهش، بررسی تأثیر آب و هوا در بازده و فعالیت‌های معاملاتی در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران است. متغیرهای معاملاتی شامل نقدشوندگی، گردش معاملات و نوسان‌پذیری است. برای تخمین الگو‌های رگرسیون با داده‌های سری زمانی، از روش حداقل مربعات معمولی (OLS) استفاده شده است. دورۀ زمانی پژوهش از ابتدای سال 1387 تا انتهای سال 1394 است. نتایج پژوهش نشان می‌دهد خلق و خوی افراد که با تغییر وضعیت آب و هوا تغییر می‌کند، در گردش معاملات، تأثیر معنا‌داری ندارد؛ اما متغیرهای برف، باران و سرعت باد در بازده، نقدشوندگی و نوسان‌پذیری، تأثیر معناداری دارند؛ بنابراین در پژوهش حاضر، نشان داده شد عوامل محیطی در بازده و فعالیت‌های معاملاتی به‌جز گردش معاملات، تأثیر دارد؛ بنابراین آب و هوا یکی از عوامل محیطی تأثیرگذار بر فعالیت روزمرۀ افراد است. در این بین، اختلالات خلقی فصلی یکی از مهم‌ترین شاخص‌های تأثیرگذار در رفتار معاملاتی سرمایه‌گذاران است.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>مالی رفتاری</kwd>
						<kwd>فعالیت‌های معاملاتی</kwd>
						<kwd>اثر آب و هوا</kwd>
						<kwd>اختلالات خلقی فصلی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Amihud, Y.) 2002(. Illiquidity and stock returns: Cross-section and time-series effects. Journal of FINANCE MARKET. 5, 31–56.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>[2] Badri, A., Abdolbaghi, A. (2015). Behavioral Preferences of Investors in Reaction to the Fundamental Variables Based on Sochastic Dominance. Journal of Asset Managing &amp; Financing. 3 (1) :23-40.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>[3] Cao, M., Wei, J., (2005). Stock market returns: A note on temperature anomaly. Journal of Bank Finance 29, 1559–1573.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>[4] Chang, T., Nieh, C., Yang, M., Yang, T., (2006). Are stock market returns related to the weather effects? empirical evidence from Taiwan. Phys. A Stat. Mech. Appl. 364,343–354.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>[5] Chang, S., Chen, S., Chou, R., Lin, Y., (2008). Weather and intraday patterns in stock returns and trading activity. Journal of. BANK FINANCE. 32, 1754–1766.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>[6] Cohen ,H., A., (2011).Climate,weather, and political behavior.PhD DISS.,University of Iowa. http://ir.uiowa.edu/etd/1214.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>[7]‌‌‌  Daniel,‌K.,Hirshleifer, D., Subrahmanyam, A., (1998). Investor psychology and security market under-and overreactions. Journal of Finance 1839–1885.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>[8] Dong, M., Tremblay, Andreanne., (2015). Does the weahter influence global returns. Journal of Australasian Finanace and Banking Conferece.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>[9]   Fruthwirth, M., Sogner, L. (2015). Weather and SAD related mood effects on the financial market. Journal of The Quartely Review of Economics and Finance 57. 11-13.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>[10] Hirshleifer, D., (2001). Investor     psychology and asset pricing. Journal of Finance 1533–1597.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>[11] Hirshleifer, D., Shumway, T., (2003). Good day sunshine: Stock returns and the weather. Journal of Finance 1009–1032.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>[12] Jamalianpour, M., Mahdavi, Gh (2013). Effects of Weather and Seasonal Variables on the Tehran Stock Market Liquidity. Journal of Financial Accounting Research. Volume 5, Number 3, far 2013, 5(3): 73-88</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>[13] Jing, Lu., Robin K, Chou., (2012). Does the weather have impacts on returns and trading activities in order-driven stock markets? Journal of Empirical Finance.79-93.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>[14] Kamstra, M.J., Kramer, L.A., Levi, M.D., (2007). Opposing seasonalities in treasury versus equity returns. Working Paper.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>[15] Kasper, S., (1991). Jahreazier und Befindlichekeit in der allgemeinbevokerung. Eine mehrebenenunterssuchung zur epidemiologie, biologie und therapeutischen beeinffussbarkeit saisonaler befindliclkeitssclwankungen. Monographien aus dem gesamtgebier Der Psychiatrie, Bd, 66. Springer.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>[16] Kaviani, H., Ebrahimkhani, N. Mood swings in different weathers and during seasonal changes in normal population. IJPCP. (2005). 11 (2):194-203.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>[17] Keef, S., Roush, M., (2002). The weather and stock returns in New Zealand. Q. J. Bus. Econ. 41, 61–80.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>[18]   Kramer, Lisa., http://homes.chass.utoronto.ca.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>]19[  Loughran, T., Schultz, P., (2004). Weather, stock returns, and the impact of localized trading behavior. Journal of Finance. Quant. Anal. 343–364.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>[20] Michael M, Pompian. (2009). Behavioral Finance &amp; wealth Management. Translated by Ahmad Badri.Tehran, Keihan.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>[21] Qadan, Mahmoud., Klinger, Doron., (2016).The short trading day anomaly. Journal of Empirical Fianace.Volume 38:62-80.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>]22[ Rosenthal, N., (1998). Winter Blues: Seasonal affective disorder: What it is and how to overcome it. The guilford press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>[23] Saunders, E., (1993). Stock prices and Wall Street weather. Am. Econ. Rev. 1337–1345.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>[24] Stathopoulos, T., (2009).Wind and comfort. Proceedings of European–African Conference onWind Engineering (EACWE 5). International Association forWind. Engineering, Florence Italy (July).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>[25] Symeonidis, L., Daskalakis, G., Markellos, R.N., (2010). Does the weather affect stock market volatility? Journal of Finance Research Letters 7, 214–223.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>[26] Vakilifard, H., Foroughnejad, H., Khoshnood, M. (2013). Evaluation Investor's Behavior in Tehran Stock Exchange with Analytic Network process (ANP). Journal of Asset Managing &amp; Financing. 1 (2): 19-34.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation> _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>