<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Assessing the impact of investors mental status on risk taking behavior of Tehran Stock Exchange Investors</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر حالت‌های روحی در ریسک‌پذیری سرمایه‌گذاران بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>107</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>120</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">21352</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21352</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهروز</FirstName>
					<LastName>لاری سمنانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>With respect to financial decisions in daily life of investors, in this research we assess the mental state of investors on their risk taking behavior in Tehran stock exchange. Risk taking is the degree of encouragement investors has in order to take innovation and do extraordinary jobs. Mental state is composed of sustainable emotions with external expression in different degrees and continuity for kinds of investors. All Tehran stock exchange investors were among the study and 386 samples were selected. For mental state and risk taking behavior data gathered on the basis of PANAS and risk taking standard questioners in turn. Hypothesis tested by structural equation modeling with partial least square approach. Results show risk taking is positively affected by high positive affection and low negative affection besides negatively affected by low positive affection and high negative affection. High positive affection has the highest impact and low positive affection has the lowest impact on risk taking behavior.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این پژوهش با توجه به اهمیت تصمیم‌گیری‌های مالی در زندگی افراد، تأثیر حالت‌های روحی را در ریسک‌پذیری سرمایه‌گذاران فعال در بورس اوراق‌ بهادار تهران بررسی کرده ‌است. ریسک‌پذیری صفتی است که افراد براساس آن تشویق می‌شوند به ابتکار عمل روی آورند و کارهای مخاطره‌آمیز انجام دهند. درواقع، ریسک‌پذیری تمایل فرد به قرارگرفتن در سناریوی تصمیم‌گیری است. حالت روحی، مجموعه‌ای از احساسات پایدار و با نمود خارجی است که در افراد مختلف، شدت و مدت استمرار متفاوتی دارد. جامعۀ آماری این پژوهش شامل کلیّۀ سرمایه‌گذاران بورس اوراق بهادار تهران است که از این میان، 386 نمونه انتخاب شد. برای جمع‌آوری داده‌های لازم در زمینۀ حالت‌های روحی و ریسک، به‌ترتیب از پرسشنامۀ استاندارد پاناس و پرسشنامۀ ریسک‌پذیری و برای آزمودن فرضیه‌های پژوهش از روش الگوسازی معادلات ساختاری با رویکرد حداقل مربعات جزئی استفاده‌ شد. نتایج نشان داد ریسک‌پذیری سرمایه‌گذاران تحت‌ تأثیر چهار حالت روحی عاطفۀ مثبت زیاد، عاطفۀ مثبت کم، عاطفۀ منفی زیاد و عاطفۀ منفی کم است؛ به‌گونه‌ای که با عاطفۀ مثبت زیاد و عاطفۀ منفی کم، رابطۀ مستقیم و با عاطفۀ مثبت کم و عاطفۀ منفی زیاد، رابطۀ عکس دارد. همچنین عاطفۀ مثبت زیاد، بیشترین و عاطفۀ مثبت کم،کمترین تأثیر را در میزان ریسک‌پذیری سرمایه‌گذار دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوی پاناس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حالت‌های روحی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ریسک‌پذیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عاطفۀ مثبت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عاطفۀ منفی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21352_3bcc4c9eda8bf06b073503b98ab4b29f.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
