<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The effect of conservatism on firms&#039; financing methods and propensity to save cash</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تاثیر محافظه‌کاری حسابداری بر شیوه‌ تامین مالی شرکت‌ها و گرایش به نگهداری وجه نقد</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>101</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>112</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19874</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>دینا</FirstName>
					<LastName>تاج الدینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>خدامی‌پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Due to the importance of financial reporting on users&#039; decisions and the influence of conservatism methods on the financial statements and consequently on firms&#039; financial decisions, in this survey, the relationship between accounting conservatism and financial decisions, related to firms&#039; financing methods and propensity to save cash, has been studied. Analysis of these decisions is performed according to the two visions of &quot;Efficient Contracting View&quot; and &quot;Distortion of Information View&quot;. This research is performed using a sample of firms listed on the Tehran Stock Exchange, based on the multiple regression method for model one and the Probit method for model two. The measure of Dichev and Tang (2008) has been used to estimate accounting conservatism based on quarterly data for the firms listed on the Tehran Stock Exchange over the period of 1379-1390, using rolling and time series methods, to estimate accounting conservatism for each firm over the period 1385-1390. The results indicate that the propensity to save cash corresponds with distortion of information view, showing that firms with greater reporting conservatism have a more propensity to save cash. Moreover, although the meaningful relationship between conservatism and firm&#039;s financing methods has the overall significance, but because of a greater use of debt in firms&#039; financing, it was impossible to define the type of relationship.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به دلیل اهمیت گزارشگری مالی در تصمیمات استفاده‌کنندگان و تأثیری که رویه‌های محافظه‌کاری بر صورت‌های مالی و در نتیجه بر تصمیمات شرکت دارند، در این پژوهش به بررسی رابطه بین سطح محافظه‌کاری حسابداری و تصمیمات مالی مربوط به شیوه تأمین مالی و گرایش به نگهداری وجه نقد شرکت‌ها پرداخته شده است. بررسی این دو تصمیم که نمودی از انعطاف‌پذیری مالی شرکت‌ها‌ هستند، بر پایه دو دیدگاه منافع قراردادی و تحریف اطلاعات انجام گرفته است. این پژوهش بر اساس نمونه‌ای مستخرج از اطلاعات شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران انجام شده است که درآن، مدل اول به شکل رگرسیون چند متغیره و مدل دوم به صورت پروبیت تخمین زده شده‌اند. سنجش محافظه‌کاری با استفاده از معیار دیچو و تنگ(2008)، بر اساس داده‌های فصلی شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران طی سال‌های1390-1379 به شیوه سری زمانی و به روش رولینگ برای سال‌های1390-1385برای هر شرکت محاسبه شده است. نتایج حاکی از آن است که گرایش به نگهداری وجه نقد با دیدگاه تحریف اطلاعات مطابقت داشته و شرکت‌های با محافظه‌کاری حسابداری بیشتر، به نگهداری وجه نقد بیشتری نیز گرایش دارند. علاوه بر این، اگر چه رابطه معناداری بین محافظه‌کاری حسابداری و شیوه‌های تأمین مالی وجود دارد، از معناداری کل برخوردار بوده، اما به علت استفاده بیشتر از بدهی برای تأمین مالی در شرکت‌ها، امکان بررسی نوع رابطه وجود نداشت.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">محافظه‌کاری حسابداری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شیوه تامین مالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گرایش به نگهداری وجه نقد</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_19874_93651304f6b0468969806f18e93802a8.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
