<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Modeling Banking Crisis with the Dynamic Stochastic General Equilibrium Model</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مدل‌سازی شوک مصارف در چارچوب مدل تعادل عمومی پویای تصادفی برای ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>91</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>108</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">20649</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2016.20649</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اعظم</FirstName>
					<LastName>احمدیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>پزوهشکده پولی و بانکی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Banking industry, as one of the important financial intermediation industries in Iran’s economy, faces the critical challenge of delayed loans. The existence of delayed loans decreases banks liquidity resources and their lending power. As a result, in recent years, Iranian banks have tired to change their asset portfolio from business loans to interbank loans to confront with their credit risk. Because of the strong relation between banking industry and other economic sectors in Iran, I try to analyze the reaction of macroeconomic variables (such as production and inflation) and banking variables to the shocks of delayed loans. To do so, I use annual statistics of the economic variables between 1981 to 2013 as well as calibration and Bayesian model to extract the value of dynamic stochastic general equilibrium (DSGE) parameters. Results show that the theoretic model is compatible with the economic realities. In the other, words investment and production decrease and inflation increases as delayed loans increase. Alternatively, investment and production increase and inflation decreases by increasing interbank loans.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">ایجاد بحران در سیستم بانکی ناشی از بازنگشتن مطالبات، به سرعت به بخش واقعی اقتصاد تسری می‌یابدو در نتیجه می‌تواند کل نظام اقتصادی را با مخاطراتی مواجه کند. صنعت بانکداری ایران، مهم‌ترین واسطۀ مالی است که با چالش مطالبات معوق، مواجه است؛ در نتیجه سبد تسهیلاتبانک­ها در سال‌های اخیر به‌دلیل افزایش ریسک اعتباری، تسهیلات اعطایی به سمت مطالبات شبکه بانکی تغییر کرده است. در این مقاله با توجه به ارتباط گستردۀ شبکۀ بانکی با بخش‌های کلان اقتصاد کشور، با استفاده از روش تعادل عمومی پویای تصادفی نیوکینزی و با بهره‌گیری از آمار سالانۀ اقتصاد ایران در دورۀ 1392-1360، به بررسی واکنش متغیرهای کلان اقتصادی (نظیر تولید و تورم)و متغیرهای بانکی به این دو متغیر(شوک‌های مانده مطالبات معوق و افزایش مطالبات از شبکۀ بانکی) به­عنوان شوک مصارفپرداخته شد. نتایج حاصل از بررسی آثارشوک‌های مورد بررسی، نشان داد با افزایش مطالبات معوق، سرمایه­گذاری و تولید کاهش، تورم افزایش می‌یابدوبا افزایش مطالبات از شبکۀ بانکی، سرمایه‌گذاری و تولید افزایش و تورم کاهش می‌یابد.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;color: black;&quot; lang=&quot;FA&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل تعادل عمومی پویای تصادفی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مانده مطالبات معوق</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مطالبات از شبکۀبانکی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_20649_608da3c487a6945626403ce44e285e56.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
