<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>محاسبه ارزش در معرض ریسک بر اساس تقریب کورنیش- فیشر از توزیع نرمال (مطالعه‌ای در نهادهای مالی بازار بورس اوراق بهادار تهران)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>20</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19868</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حجت اله</FirstName>
					<LastName>صادقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه یزد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرضیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>شمس</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه یزد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>A way to estimate the downside risk is the value at risk (VaR) which indicates the highest possible loss in a portfolio of financial possessions in a special time horizon at a specified level of confidence and is a suitable measure for estimating the risk of financial asset and managing it. In the present study, common parametric and non-parametric methods of estimating the risk of financial assets are reviewed. Following that, a totally different parametric method named Cornish-Fisher (CF) estimate for estimation of VaR for financial fims listed on the Tehran Stock Exchange (Investment companies, Insurance companies, Leasing companies and banks) during 2010 to 2012 have been investigated. The findings of the current study indicate that this approximation has operated well for observations whose distribution has a small discrepancy with normal distribution. Using this approximate can lead to a more suitable risk management decisions.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">یکی از روش‌های اندازه‌گیری ریسک نامطلوب (ریسک‌هایی که با قبول آنها صرف ریسک منفی شده و مخرب هستند)، ارزش در معرض ریسک (VaR) است که بیشترین کاهش ارزش یک سبد سرمایه‌گذاری از دارایی‌ها را در افق زمانی مشخص و در سطح اطمینان خاص نشان می‌دهد. در این پژوهش، به معرفی روش‌های پارامتریک و ناپارامتریک رایج محاسبه ارزش در معرض ریسک پرداخته و سپس روش پارامتریک بسیار متفاوتی به نام تقریب کورنیش -فیشر(CF) از توزیع نرمال، در مورد صنعت مالی بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، شامل: شرکت‌های سرمایه‌گذاری، بیمه، لیزینگ و بانک‌ها در سال‌های 1389 تا 1391 بررسی می‌شود . در این پژوهش مشاهده شد تنها 15 شرکت از شرکت‌های مذکور، اختلاف اندکی با توزیع نرمال دارند و توزیع غالب در نهادهای مالی بازار بورس ایران، توزیع نرمال نیست. یافته‌های این پژوهش، حاکی از آن است که این تقریب در مورد مشاهداتی که توزیع آنها اختلاف اندکی با توزیع نرمال دارد، به خوبی عمل کرده، اختلاف ناچیزی بین محاسبه VaR از دو روش نرمال و تقریب CF مشاهده می‌شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزش در معرض ریسک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تقریب کورنیش- فیشر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تقریب کورنیش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فیشر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توزیع نرمال</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش‌های پارامتریک و ناپارامتریک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت ریسک</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_19868_4f241c98313b2c4b7873076c5c102df9.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
