<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[زمستان 1396]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					
			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Isfahan]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[زمستان 1396]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[زمستان 1396]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_23323_dce11f818454c948b22249abeb469e6e.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Asset Management and Financing]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Effect of Return Dispersion on the Accrual and Investment Anomalies in Companies Listed in Tehran Stock Exchange]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[asghari, zeinab]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[soroushyar, afsaneh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[aliahmadi, saeid]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Isfahan]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Accrual anomalies]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Investment anomalies]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Stock return]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The accrual anomaly as the phenomenon in the capital market has attracted the attention of many experts to its underlying causes. The purpose of this study is to investigate the role of the cross-sectional dispersion of stock returns in the accrual anomaly and investment anomaly in the companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. The research sample that was selected using the systematic elimination method includes 147 companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange in the period of 2007-2014. The Fama and French (1993) model with return dispersion is used in order to test the research hypotheses. For analyzing the role of return dispersion in the accrual anomaly, Fama - French model was fitted by sorting the companies with high and low accruals and for analyzing the role of return dispersion in the investment anomaly, this model was fitted by sorting the companies with high and low investments. Research models were fitted using the combined data and then by using the time series method and sorting the given portfolios. The results show that the stock return dispersion does not affect accrual and investment anomalies.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21189_75de1ff92f36711ac1ecb9cd8f880ebb.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22108/amf.2017.21189]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Asset Management and Financing]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Credit Risk Management of Banking Customers Using Support Vector Machine Optimized by Genetic Algorithm with Data Mining Approach]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[jafari-eskandari, meisam]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[rohii, milad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Isfahan]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Credit Risk]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Recovery rates]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Rialclaims]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Support Vector Machine]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Credit risk management, credit scoring and risk assessment of customers is an important issue in banking industry. Credit scoring is important because if the banks fail to earn resource allocation and create a balance between the processes of mobilizing and allocating resources, they are typically faced with many problems in the future. According to official figures released by the Central Bank of Iran in recent years, the rate of bad loans increased, since the systemic strict validation to evaluate and measure the credit risk of customers do not exist. In this paper, we try to predict customer’s recovery rate index with data mining techniques. Markedly, in recent years in the world new method for measuring customer risk rather than default probability measure has been considered, but due to low precision of forecasting models widely different approaches in research and modeling is investigated. The method used in this paper is support vector regression model whose parameters selection is optimized with genetic algorithm.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21191_73805096c7a50a561d5501be2350061d.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22108/amf.2017.21191]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Asset Management and Financing]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[An Evaluation of Risk Transmission over Foreign Exchange, Real Estate and Stock Markets in Iran`s Economy (An Application of Parametric and Non-Parametric Value at Risk Approach)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Bastanzad, Hossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Davoudi, Pedram]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Isfahan]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Financial transmission mechanism]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Financial assets market]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Risk]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Spillover effect]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Value at Risk]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The international spillover remarkably affects the asset markets risks mainly through macroeconomic variables in Iran`s economy. To assess it, we evaluate VaR of assets market during 1990-2015.The results underscore the VaR which are statistically computed by the nonparametric approaches are considered more efficient than parametric approaches due to lower standard deviation and coefficient of variation as well as a better reflection of cyclical shocks.The Causality test indicates the foreign exchange VaR causes the stock price VaR while the stock price VaR simultaneously causes the mortgage price VaR.The impact of macroeconomic variables on the assets market VaRs is also estimated by the causality test as the output growth adversely inspires the VaRs of mortgage price and foreign exchange rate. Meanwhile, money base is constantly stimulated by the assets market VaRs in the short and medium term owing to money base. As a consequent, reduction in foreign exchange market risk lead to a reduction in other assets market risk and eventually overall economy. Therefore, it is desirable to design complementary mechanisms to fulfill the task.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21188_26099fb271b728c8a96f9b9a8f93da6b.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22108/amf.2017.21188]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Asset Management and Financing]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Investigating the Non-Linear Relationship between Working Capital Management with Performance and Investment in Companies Listed in Tehran Stock Exchange]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[sotoodehkia, hossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[abbasi, reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[basirat, mehdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Isfahan]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Management of working capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Stock performance]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Operational performance]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Investment]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The objective of this research is studying the effect of working capital management on the performance and investments. To do so, we gathered and analyzed panel data of 155 stocks listed in Tehran Stock Eschange during 2010-2014 using multivariate regression. The results show a significant relationship between working capital management and performance (market return) of the stocks. In addition we found a non-linear relationship between working capital management and operationa performance (ROA) of the firms listed in Tehran Stock Exchange.  Finally the results show a negative relationship between working capital management and investment in high level of working capital.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21192_0bb512cc9152e56274d541a758bd3bb4.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22108/amf.2017.21192]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Asset Management and Financing]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Comparing Profitability of the Pair Trading Strategy in Different Asset Classes]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Pakizeh, Kamran]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Habibi, Samar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Isfahan]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pair trading]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Asset classes]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Distance method]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Augmented DickyFuller (ADF) test]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Granger causality (CG) test]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Pair trading is known as the most common and one of the oldest statistical arbitrage strategies. Also, it can be considered a Market Neutral strategy. Using different classes of assets including equities of the Tehran Stock Exchange, S&amp;P 500 stocks index as well as commodities market from February 2013 through May 2015, this paper aims to compare performance of different methods of pair trading. These methods consist of the “Minimum Distance”, “Augmented Dickey-Fuller Test and Granger Causality Test” and the “Linear Regression-based method”. Empirical profitability results including a return of  15% for the Minimum Distance method, 1/4% for Augmented Dickey-Fuller Test and Granger Causality Test and 6% for the Linear Regression-based method, are incontrovertible evidences backing the assumption that higher profits are achieved in case of using different classes of assets. Furthermore, according to empirical results of using 15% return and a sharp ratio of 6/5, Minimum Distance method is found to be the best model of applying pairs trading strategy in commodities and capital markets.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21195_3cc31c9c3bec76ce398b3882f0ee4431.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22108/amf.2017.21195]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Asset Management and Financing]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Effect of Financial Status on Earnings Persistence, Predictability and Smoothing]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mashayekh, Shahnaz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Farhadi, Zahra Farhadi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Isfahan]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Healthy firms]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Bankrupt firms]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[persistence]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Predictability and Earnings smoothing]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Profit as the product of accounting information system must be of acceptable quality. Earnings quality is a broad concept with different dimensions. The aim of this study was to compare some measures of earnings quality in healthy and bankrupt companies. This paper investigates the relation between accounting-based earnings quality attributes and the financial status of Iranian companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange from 2010 to 2012 by classifying them as either ‘healthy’ or ‘bankrupt’ firms. In this regard, companies divided into three categories according to the Altman Z Index (healthy, financially distressed and bankrupt) and then were compared with each other three measures of earnings quality (persistence, predictability and smoothing) in healthy and bankrupt firms. The findings from the study show that the persistence and predictability of earnings in bankrupt companies more healthy companies, As a result, earnings quality of bankrupt companies in terms of persistence is higher than healthy companies but in terms of predictability is lower than the healthy companies. The results suggest that the smoothing in the healthy companies is more than the bankrupt companies, and this means that the quality of earnings in terms of smoothing in the bankrupt companies is higher than healthy companies.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_22200_f1df0e0189b4b27b6d8c198b13d3d438.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22108/amf.2017.91462]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Asset Management and Financing]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Working Capital Management, Corporate Performance and Financial Constraints: Evidence from Tehran Stock Exchange]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Sepasi, Sahar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hassani, Hassan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Salmanian, Lida]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Isfahan]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Working capital management]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[financial performance]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[financial constraints]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Tobin&#039;s Q ratio]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Net business cycle]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This study aimed to investigate the relationship between working capital management and corporate performance and the impact of financing constraints on the relationship. We used net business cycle in order to measure the working capital management and Tobin's Q Ratio to measure the financial performance and finally, to determine financial constrained firms and firms without financial constraints we used three proxies: KZ, KZir and WW. The sample includes 196 companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange and se analyzed a total of 1568 observations (firm-year) during the years of 2007 to 2014. For data analysis and hypothesis testing were conducted using multivariate linear regression using panel data. The results of testing showed that there is a negative and significant regression between the net trade cycle and corporate performance. Also, there is a non-linear and U-shaped relationship between the net business cycle and corporate performance. According to the results, working capital management plays an important role in the company's performance and, as far as possible, companies can reduce the net trade cycle for their value. The results indicate that companies that are faced with financial constraints have less investment in working capital than those without financial constraints. As a result, financial constraints have been a major factor in the level of investment in working capital.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21187_18c3b32c4ce3e11e697d011b331e7e85.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22108/amf.2017.21187]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Asset Management and Financing]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The effect of Consumer Price Index and Operational Cycle on the Level of Cash Holding in the Companies Listed in Tehran Stock Exchange]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[khodamipour, ahmad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[shamsodin, sahar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Isfahan]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cash Holding]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Inflation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[operating cycle]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Balance between cash and the need of cash is one of the most important factors of financial health and continuity of the activities of every business agency. At the macro level, firms are inclined to adjust and optimize their cash-holding strategies in response to changes in purchasing power due to inflation. Firms flexibly adjust their cash-holding strategies in response to changes in the external environment. At the micro level, the effect of operating cycle, which indicates the speed and turnover of corporate cash flow, on the corporate cash-holding has been studied. In this paper the effect of inflation and operating cycle on cash holdings has been studied. To pursue this purpose, the data has been extracted from companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange from 1990-2001. For stimulation of this study’s model, we used regression in panel data. The results of the analysis show a U-shaped relationship between consumer price Index (CPI) and cash holdings. Thus there is a significant negative association between cash holdings and the CPI, but the relationship is reversed when the CPI reaches a certain level. The empirical results indicate that there is not a U-shaped relationship between operating cycle and cash holdings.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21168_c809e74d86da4253b1202d0761a72b31.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22108/amf.2017.21168]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Asset Management and Financing]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Tests of Multiple Explosive Bubbles Behavior in Tehran Stock Exchange and Real State Market in Iran]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[sadeghi sharif, seed jalal]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[osoolian, mohammad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Afsharian, Amirhossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Isfahan]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Efficiency market]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Behavioral finance]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Dickey-Fuller test]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Explosive bubble]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[SADF&GSADF test]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Unit root]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Bubbles in asset markets result in diversion of savings allocations. For this reason, in macro level, the diversion of the savings disrupts investment efficiency and whole economy. Many studies in the field of behavioral finance have been undertaken to investigate this phenomenon. Recent research has shown that traditional models of unit root in the detection of explosive behaviors, especially at long ranges, are weak. In this paper, the generalized models, right-tail Dickey Fuller (RADF), and more powerful models of generalized Dickey Fuller (SUP ADF and GSADF) are used. These models, in addition to their stronger identification of explosive behaviors at long intervals, can also specify the time period of the bubbles. In this paper, the time period from 1980 to 2003 for the stock market and real state was tested. The results of this research, which is based on the advanced tests, show that the stock market and the reals state market experienced explosive bubbles behaviors in the period examined; it was 24 periods for the stock market and 12 periods for the housing market.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21169_45b916e2f7ba7453d5d8e260eb571da9.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22108/amf.2017.21169]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Asset Management and Financing]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Study of Nonlinear Relationship between Debt Financing and Cash Flow Manipulation of Listed Companies in Tehran Stock Exchange]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[zamani, aliasghar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Anvary Rostamy, Ali Asghar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Isfahan]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Debt financing]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cash flow manipulation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Second order relation]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This research expands profit quality and opportunistic behaviors towards profit management and cash flow manipulation. The goal of this research is studying the second order relation between debt financing and cash flow manipulation of 103 companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange from 2005 to 2014. Multi-variable Regression based on Extended Least Square of Pooled Data Method was used to test the assumption. The outcomes indicate a positive nonlinear second order significant relation between debt and cash flow manipulation. Namely, the managed cash flows will decrease firstly, and then increase. In other words, management prefers refraining from failure of debt contracts than the benefits of reporting high quality operational cash flows and further seeking the benefits of the effects of cash flows.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21194_247d8d5bdbdf2fd032bda2cd8300cdb0.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22108/amf.2017.21194]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Asset Management and Financing]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Asset-Liability Management of Banks Using Goal Programming Model and Fuzzy ANP (Case Study: Tejarat Bank)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Izadinia, Naser]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[ghandehari, mahsa]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[abedini, ahmad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[abedini naeini, mahdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Isfahan]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Goal Programing]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Risk]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Return]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[ANP]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Assets and liabilities management]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Maximization of the share holders` wealth is the main objective in assets and liabilities management which depends on two key factors: risk and return. To attain this, the optimal management of the balance sheet could assist to maximize the profit and minimize the risk. This study investigates primarily the functionality of risk and return, and subsequently inspects their effects on the maximization of stockholders wealth by the means of network analysis method. To realize the proposed balance sheet of Tejarat Bank, and then a Multi Objective model of goal programming model has been applied. In this work, the criterion of risk and return have been estimated as ideal parameters in order to determine the model considering the existing structural limitations. The result shows that all defined objectives except market risk has been accomplished while deviations of all parameters except market risk has been taken into account as zero.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21178_076a28c04b114693c31bc4fa52703e8a.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22108/amf.2017.21178]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Asset Management and Financing]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Role of Disclosure Quality and Accruals Quality in Reducing the Deviation from the Optimal Capital Structure]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Aflatooni, Abbas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Amirbakhtiarvand, Amin]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Isfahan]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[disclosure quality]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Accruals Quality]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Optimal capital structure]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Over-leverage]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Under-leverage]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Information asymmetry and conflicts of interest between management and shareholders leads to the phenomenon of adverse selection. Adverse selection means choosing the wrong investment choices by investors that leads to non-optimal allocation of capital market resources. In this condition, firms cannot easily finance their investment projects. This object leads the firms’ capital structures to a non-optimized mode. One way to avoid this problem is to increase the accruals quality and disclosure quality because this decreases the information asymmetry. This research investigates the effect of accruals quality and disclosure quality on deviation form the optimal capital structure in 123 firms listed in Tehran Stock Exchange during 2003-2014. The research results show that incearse in accruals quality and disclosure quality decrease the deviation from the optimal capital structure. In addition, the research findings indicate that the effect of accruals quality on deviation from the optimal capital structure in over-leveraged firms is significantly stronger than that in under-leveraged firms.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21212_eb71b45ce5235a035d2e58b3e7971dd5.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22108/amf.2017.21212]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://amf.ui.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Asset Management and Financing]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>