<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Real Earnings Management and Managerial Incentives on Sticky Costs</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر مدیریت واقعی سود و انگیزه‌های مدیریت بر چسبندگی هزینه‌ها</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>16</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">21149</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21149</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>غلامرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>منصورفر</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه حسابداری و مدیریت دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت دانشگاه ارومیه، ارومیه، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>حیدری</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه حسابداری و مدیریت دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت دانشگاه ارومیه، ارومیه، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>طاهره</FirstName>
					<LastName>کولانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه حسابداری و مدیریت دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت دانشگاه ارومیه، ارومیه، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This research aims to investigate the effect of real earnings management and managerial incentives on sticky costs. Sticky costs phenomenon represents that the costs do not change in proportion to changes in sales. In other words, the percentage of the reduction in costs when sales are reducing is less than the percentage of cost increase when the sales are increasing. In accordance with the “deliberate decision” theory, costs become sticky because of the deliberate decision of managers. This study focuses on managers’ resource adjustments when sales decline. The resource adjustments motivated to meet earnings targets and the ensuing cost structures. The research include a sample of 135 companies in the Tehran Stock Exchange for a period of 10 years from 2003 to 2013. For testing the hypothesis, multiple regression models based on panel data analysis is used. The results indicate that when managers face incentive to avoid losses, they accelerate sliding adjustment of slack resources for sales decreases. These decisions diminish the degree of cost stickiness. &lt;br /&gt; </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر تأثیر مدیریت واقعی سود و انگیزه‌های مدیریت بر میزان چسبندگی هزینه‌ها را بررسی می‌کند. چسبندگی هزینه به این معنی است که نسبت کاهش هزینه‌ها در هنگام کاهش فروش کمتر از نسبت افزایش هزینه‌ها در هنگام افزایش فروش است. طبق نظریۀ‌ تصمیم‌های آگاهانه، چسبندگی هزینه‌ها نتیجۀ تصمیم‌های آگاهانۀ مدیران است. این مطالعه بر حالتی تمرکز می‌کند که در آن مدیران به هنگام کاهش فروش، با انگیزۀ پرهیز از زیان و کاهش سود، به تعدیل آگاهانۀ منابع اقدام می‌کنند. جامعۀ آماری این پژوهش، شامل نمونه‌ای از 135 شرکت حاضر در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران برای یک دورۀ 10 ساله از سال 1383 تا 1392 است. برای آزمون فرضیه‌ها از الگوی رگرسیونی چندمتغیره‌ استفاده شده است. نتایج نشان می‌دهد مدیران هنگام کاهش فروش یعنی زمانی که برای پرهیز از زیان انگیزه دارند، کنار‌گذاشتن منابع بدون استفاده را سرعت می‌بخشند و منابع را به‌طور آگاهانه تعدیل می‌کنند. این تصمیم آگاهانه، چسبندگی هزینه‌ها را کاهش می‌دهد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت واقعی سود</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انگیزههای مدیریت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">چسبندگی هزینه ها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظریۀ تصمیم‌های آگاهانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اهداف سود</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21149_e05e5fea6128b8eb0643b40e467fd454.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
