<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Business diversification effects on performance and value of listed companies in Tehran Stock Exchange</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر تنوع‌سازی کسب و کار بر عملکرد و ارزش شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران به تفکیک درجه تمرکز صنعتی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>65</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>86</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19882</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سمانه</FirstName>
					<LastName>شاهرضایی</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمزه</FirstName>
					<LastName>دیدار</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4651-7729</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>ایمانی برندق</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمزه</FirstName>
					<LastName>دیدار</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In recent years, the relationship between performance and firm diversification become as an important empirical matter. The diversity strategies in companyâs business are able to affect the competitive balance of an industry. The aim of this study, investigate the effect of business diversification on performance and value of accepted firms in Tehranâs Stock Exchange. To achieve this goal, the Herfindahl-Hryshmn index and TobinQ index were used to assess the business diversification and the companyâs value from the market value in each year, respectively. This sample includes 125 accepted firms in Tehranâs stock exchange within 7 industries, in the periods of 1381-1390. In order to verify the hypothesis, a multiple regression based on panel data by Estimated Generalized Least Square (EGLS) was used. The results from the study hypothesis indicate that there is significant and direst relationship between Herfindahl _ Hryshmn index and the performance of studied firms in comparative industries, in semi concentrated industries, there is a negative relationship between Herfindahl _ Hryshmn index and the performance of studied firms, but not significant. Also there is a negative relationship between Herfindahl _ Hryshmn index and the value of studied firms in competitive, concentrated and semi-concentrated industries, but are not significant. &lt;br /&gt;In conclusion we can say that the business diversification have an significant and positive effect of performance and have non-significant and negative effects on value of studied firms.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">درسال‌های اخیر، ارتباط بین عملکرد و تنوع شرکت موضوع مهم تجربی در مدیریت مالی شده است. استراتژی‌های تنوع در کسب و کار شرکت‌ها می‌توانند توازن رقابتی یک صنعت را تحت تأثیر قرار دهند. هدف این مقاله بررسی تأثیر تنوع‌سازی کسب‌وکار بر عملکرد و ارزش شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران است. برای دستیابی به این هدف از شاخص هرفیندال_هریشمن برای اندازه‌گیری تنوع‌سازی کسب‌وکار، برای ارزیابی عملکرد از شاخص کیوتوبین و برای ارزش شرکت از ارزش بازار هرسهم در پایان سال استفاده گردیده است. نمونه مورد بررسی شامل 125 شرکت در غالب 7 صنعت، در دوره زمانی 1381-1390 است. به منظور بررسی صحت فرضیه‌های پژوهش، از رگرسیون چندمتغیره مبتنی بر داده‌های تلفیقی به روش حداقل مربعات تعمیم یافته (EGLS) استفاده شده است. نتایج حاصل از آزمون فرضیه‌های پژوهش بیانگر این است که بین شاخص هرفیندال_هریشمن و عملکرد شرکت‌های مورد بررسی در صنایع رقابتی رابطه مستقیم و معنادار، در صنایع نیمه‌متمرکز رابطه معکوس و معنادار و در صنایع متمرکز رابطه معکوس و غیرمعناداری وجود دارد. و بین شاخص هرفیندال_هریشمن و ارزش شرکت‌های مورد بررسی در صنایع رقابتی، نیمه متمرکز و متمرکز رابطه معکوس و غیرمعناداری وجود دارد. در نتیجه می‌توان گفت که تنوع‌سازی کسب و کار، بر عملکرد شرکت‌های مورد پژوهش تأثیر مثبت و معنادار و بر ارزش شرکت‌های مورد پژوهش تأثیر منفی و غیرمعناداری داشته است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تنوع‌سازی کسب و کار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزش شرکت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شاخص هرفیندال_هریشمن</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_19882_a4d82102ff72bfbe5636a8d4b133e7e7.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
