<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The relationship between working capital management and criterions for value-based performance of the companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی رابطه بین مدیریت سرمایه در گردش و معیارهای عملکرد مبتنی بر ارزش شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>97</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>114</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19913</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدعلی</FirstName>
					<LastName>مرادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName>
					<LastName>نجار</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName>
					<LastName>ایزدپور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study aims at exploring relationship between Working Capital Management with criterions for value-based performance. Therefore, the information of 107 companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange between 2007-2011 (1386-1390) was studied and the effect of various variables for Working Capital Management (including Days Sales Outstanding, Days Sales of Inventory, Days Payable Outstanding, and Cash Conversion Cycle) on criterions for value-based performance (including Economic Value-Added (EVA), Market Value-Added (MVA), and Q Tobin index) was tested through employing 3 hypotheses and 9 sub-hypotheses all along with the main research question. Test of hypothesis was carried out by multiple regression analysis by Estimated generalized least square (EGLS). Findings of the study show that the increase of Days Sales Outstanding results in the increase of both Economic Value-Added (EVA) and Market Value-Added (MVA), and the increase of Days Sales of Inventory also results in the decrease of criterion for value-based performance of both Economic Value-Added (EVA) and Market Value-Added (MVA).</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی رابطه مدیریت سرمایه درگردش و معیارهای عملکرد مبتنی بر ارزش پایه‌گذاری شده است. از این‌رو، با مطالعه اطلاعات 107 شرکت پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران طی دوره زمانی 1386 الی 1390 و نیز با تدوین سه فرضیه اصلی و نه فرضیه فرعی در راستای پرسش اصلی پژوهش، اثر متغیرهای مختلف مدیریت سرمایه در گردش (شامل؛ متوسط دوره وصول مطالبات، دوره تبدیل موجودی کالا، متوسط دوره پرداخت بدهی و چرخه تبدیل وجه نقد) بر شاخص‌های عملکرد مبتنی بر ارزش (شامل؛ ارزش افزوده اقتصادی، ارزش افزوده بازار و Qتوبین) آزمون شده‌اند. برای تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها و آزمون فرضیه‌ها از الگوی رگرسیون خطی چندگانه به روش حداقل مربعات تعمیم یافته تخمینی (EGLS) استفاده شده است. نتایج حاصل از پژوهش نشان می‌دهد که افزایش دوره وصول مطالبات به افزایش ارزش افزوده اقتصادی و ارزش افزوده بازار و همچنین افزایش دوره تبدیل موجودی کالا موجب کاهش دو شاخص عملکرد مبتنی بر ارزش مزبور منجر می‌شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت سرمایه در گردش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">چرخه تبدیل وجه نقد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزش افزوده اقتصادی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزش افزوده بازار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شاخص Q توبین</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_19913_4fe125ceb4b36842ae31f4ec1fa4474d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
