<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Relationship between Earnings Management &amp; Earnings Forecast Error: an Emphasis on the End &amp; Interim Financial Statements</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رابطه مدیریت سود و خطای پیش‌بینی سود (با تأکید بر صورت‌های مالی میان‌دوره‌ای و پایان دوره‌ای)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>29</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>48</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">20638</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2016.20638</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهره</FirstName>
					<LastName>حاجیها</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه ازاد اسلامی واحد تهران شرق</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>چناری بوکت</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In this research, we aimed to study the relationship between earnings management and forecast error in earnings of listed companies in Tehran Stock Exchange (TSE). For the calculation of earnings management, we employed discretionary accruals using the Jones model. Hypotheses were tested in the both level of annual and interim financial statements. Therefore, the data of 75 firms for a five-year period (2009-2013) were studied. The multivariate panel regression model is used to test the hypotheses. The results show that there is no significant relationship between earnings management and earnings forecast error in the annual financial statements. This can reject the fundamental hypothesis that the optimistic predictions are associated with lower levels of forecast accuracy. Also in the interim financial statements, there is a negative significant relationship between earnings management and earnings forecast error as increased accruals leads to decreased forecast errors. It can be said that to compensate for the poor performance of the firms, managers do the earnings management through accruals increase which leads to decreased earnings forecast error.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف این پژوهش، مطالعه ارتباط بین مدیریت سود و خطای پیش‌بینی سود در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران است. برای محاسبه مدیریت سود از اقلام تعهدی اختیاری مدل جونز استفاده‌شده است. فرضیه مورد مطالعه هم در سطح صورت‌های مالی سالانه و هم میان‌دوره‌ای آزمون شده است. در راستای انجام پژوهش اطلاعات 5 ساله (1392-1388) هفتادوپنج شرکت مورد مطالعه قرار گرفت. برای آزمون فرضیه از رگرسیون چند متغیره، با داده‌های تابلویی استفاده‌شده است. یافته‌های حاصل از پژوهش نشان می‌دهد که بین مدیریت سود و خطای پیش‌بینی سود در صورت‌های مالی سالانه ارتباط وجود ندارد که این یافته فرضیه بنیادی را رد می‌کند؛ مبنی بر این‌که پیش‌بینی‌هایی خوش‌بینانه است که با سطح کمتری از دقت پیش‌بینی همراه است. هم‌چنین در صورت‌های مالی میان‌دوره‌ایبین مدیریت سود و خطای پیش‌بینی سود، ارتباط معکوس و معنی‌دار وجود دارد؛ به­طوری‌که افزایش اقلام تعهدی منتهی به کاهش خطای پیش‌بینی می‌شود.‌ به­عبارتی می‌توان گفت مدیریت برای جبران ضعف عملکرد واحد تجاری اقدام به مدیریت سود از طریق افزایش اقلام تعهدی می‌کند که منجر به کاهش خطای پیش‌بینی سود می‌شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت سود</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خطای پیش‌بینی سود</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">‌ صورت‌های مالی میان دوره‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل جونز</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_20638_c3dac55fb6d70a8a3d70a8497ea0e42d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
