<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Endogenous and Exogenous Relationship between Ownership and Dividend Policy: Evidence from Tehran Stock Exchange Using OLS, PSM, GMM Estimators</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی درون‌زائی و برون‏زائی مالکیت و خط‌مشی تقسیم سود: شواهدی از بورس اوراق بهادار تهران (بررسی مقایسه‌ای تخمین‌زن‏های GMM، PSM، OLS)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>63</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>82</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">22800</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.103080.1076</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>فیل سرائی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم انسانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، خوراسگان (اصفهان)، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>زارعی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم انسانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، خوراسگان (اصفهان)، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;Objective: &lt;/strong&gt;In this study, a new aspect of the relationship between ownership (The endogenous and exogenous) and dividend policy has been investigated.
&lt;strong&gt;Method: &lt;/strong&gt;For this purpose, data of 2080 firm-year were gathered in the period 2002 to 2016. The effect of ownership variable on dividend policy was firstly estimated as exogenous and endogenous as second. For the statistical analysis, the results were analyzed via R Software by using ordinary panel data, PSM and GMM. In both methods (OLS and PSM), the pooled logistic regression and panel logistic model model was fitted and Akaike&#039;s information criterion (AIC) were used for comparing the methods.
&lt;strong&gt;Results: &lt;/strong&gt;It was observed that the p-value of institutional investors (INS) and corporate investors (CORP) is less than 0.05, so these two variables have a significant effect on the variable dividend policy in the ordinary panel data and PSM. But in the GMM, there was a significant relationship between institutional ownership and dividend policy while no significant relationship between corporate ownership and dividend policy was observed. Finally, using PSM and matching of data in comparison with the other estimators can have a significant role in improving the fitted regression and its results are more significant and will lead to more accurate estimates.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;هدف: &lt;/strong&gt;در این مطالعه جنبۀ‏ جدیدی از رابطۀ مالکیت (رابطۀ ‏درون‏زا و برون‏زا) و خطی‌مشی تقسیم سود بررسی شده است. منظور از مالکیت در این پژوهش، مالکیت متمرکز نهادی و شرکتی است.
&lt;strong&gt;روش:&lt;/strong&gt; در راستای هدف فوق از داده‌های2080 سال - شرکت در فاصلۀ‏ زمانی 1382 تا 1394 استفاده شده است (دورۀ پژوهش 13 سال و هر سال 160 شرکت است). متغیر مالکیت یک‌بار به‌صورت برون‌زا و یک‌بار به‌صورت درون‌زا، در نظر گرفته شده است. داده‌ها به ‌روش‏های OLS، PSM و GMM تحلیل شده‌ است.
&lt;strong&gt;نتایج: &lt;/strong&gt;در به‌کارگیری OLS و PSM، متغیرهای سرمایه‌گذاران نهادی و شرکتی به‌ترتیب اثر معنادار مثبت و منفی بر تقسیم سود داشت. در GMM فقط متغیر سرمایه‌گذاران نهادی، اثر معنادار مثبتی بر تقسیم سود داشت. درنهایت اینکه استفاده از روش PSM و همسان‌سازی داده‌ها، نقش بسزایی در بهبود رگرسیون دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیاست تقسیم سود</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">درون‏زائی مالکیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">همسان‌سازی براساس نمرۀ گرایش (PSM)</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش گشتاورهای تعمیم‌یافته (GMM)</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_22800_a6e62942c7284bd973a3767e333b00cd.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
