<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An Investigation of the Effect of Exchange Rate on the Pharmaceutical Industry Stock Return in Tehran Stock Exchange: An Application of the Markov Switching Approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر نرخ ارز بر بازده سهام صنعت دارو در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران با استفاده از رهیافت مارکف سوئیچینگ</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>35</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>56</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">21420</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21420</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>حیدری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه اقتصاد، دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت، دانشگاه ارومیه، ارومیه، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>یوسف</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه اقتصاد، دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت، دانشگاه ارومیه، ارومیه، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آرش</FirstName>
					<LastName>رفاح کهریز</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد گروه اقتصاد، دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت، دانشگاه ارومیه، ارومیه، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>08</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Nowadays, the pharmaceutical industry in terms of its relationship with public health and also the special economic value is considered one of the most important industries in the capital market. Therefore, improvement of the health sector has always been the main objective of the authorities in various countries. Hence, this paper investigates the impact of exchange rate on the pharmaceutical industry stock return in Tehran Stock Exchange by using monthly data from 2005:4 to 2016:2 and applying Markov switching non-linear approach. For this purpose, among the various modes of Markov switching model, MSIH (3) -AR (2) has been selected. The results show that in an optimal model consists of three regimes, and the exchange rate has different impact on the return of the pharmaceutical industry in different regimes. As a result; coefficients exchange rate in the first regime has negative effect, but in regimes 2 and 3 positive effect on the pharmaceutical industry stock return in the Tehran Stock Exchange. Also, the inflation rate of the health sector in the regimes 1 and 2 have a positive effect, but in the regime 3 has a negative effect on the pharmaceutical industry stock return in Tehran Stock Exchange. In addition, the results show that the sustainability of the pharmaceutical industry return in the regime with the high returns (first regime) was more than that of the regime with the little low return (second regime) and that of the regime with the high low returns (third regime). But the volatility of the pharmaceutical industry return in the third regime was more than that of the first and second regimes.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه صنعت دارو به‌لحاظ ارتباط آن با سلامت عمومی و برخورداری از ارزش ویژه اقتصادی، یکی از مهم‌ترین صنایع در بازار سهام محسوب می‌شود؛ بنابراین بهبود شاخص‌های بخش سلامت همواره از اهداف اصلی دولتمردان در جوامع مختلف بوده است؛ از این‌رو، مطالعۀ حاضر می‌کوشد تأثیر نرخ ارز را در بازده سهام صنعت دارو در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، با استفاده از داده‌های ماهانۀ دوره 1384 تا 1394 و با بهره‌گیری از رهیافت غیرخطی مارکف سوئیچینگ بررسی کند. بدین‌منظور، از میان حالت‌های مختلف الگوی مارکف سوئیچینگ، الگوی MSIH(3)–AR (2) انتخاب شد. نتایج نشان داد در یک الگوی بهینه متشکل از سه رژیم، نرخ ارز، آثار متفاوتی در بازده صنعت دارو در رژیم‌های مختلف دارد؛ بدین‌صورت که ضرایب نرخ ارز در رژیم اول، تأثیر منفی ولی در رژیم‌های 2 و 3 در بازده صنعت دارو در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، اثر مثبت داشته است. اثر نرخ تورم بخش بهداشت و درمان در رژیم‌های 1 و2 نیز مثبت ولی در رژیم 3 منفی بوده است. علاوه بر این، نتایج نشان می‌دهد پایداری بازده صنعت دارو در رژیم 1 (رژیم با بازده زیاد) نسبت به دو رژیم 2 (رژیم با بازده پایین کم) و رژیم 3 (رژیم با بازده پایین زیاد) بیشتر بوده است؛ ولی نوسان‌های بازده صنعت دارو در رژیم 3 بیشتر از نوسان‌های رژیم‌های 1 و 2 بوده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوی مارکف سوئیچینگ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازار سهام</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پایداری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صنعت دارو</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نرخ ارز</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21420_41711cd1344a9e1a17871a7f868ca83a.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
