<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>13</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Time-varying long-term Memory in the Tehran Stock Exchange: the Generalized Hurst Exponents and the Rolling Window Approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی حافظه بلندمدت متغیر زمانی در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران: رویکرد نما‌های هرست تعمیم یافته و پنجره متحرک</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">24673</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2020.122453.1530</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>الهام</FirstName>
					<LastName>فرزانگان</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه مهندسی صنایع، دانشکده فنی و مهندسی، دانشگاه نهاوند، نهاوند، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3725-3189</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Objective: This study is the first one to examine the issue of time-varying long-term memory in the Tehran Stock Exchange, using a new efficiency index through a rolling window technique. To test the robustness of the results, this estimation technique is repeated with time windows with 5 day shifts. Furthermore, the wild bootstrap versions of the Automatic Portmanteau test (AQ) and the Automatic Variance Ratio test (AVR) have been performed with 14 and 5 day shifts.&lt;br&gt;Method: The sample employed in this paper consists of daily observations on the Tehran Stock Exchange Index (TEPIX), covering the period from December,13, 2008 to October,23, 2019, making up a total of 2621 observations. The TEPIX series are collected from the Rahavard Novin software. The hypotheses are analyzed by Excel, EViews, R and MATLAB software.&lt;br&gt;Results: The findings show that in the Tehran Stock Exchange the estimated values of the generalized Hurst exponents (GHE) for all windows with 14 day shifts are above the efficiency indicator 0/5. Therefore, long-term memory exists in the Tehran Stock Exchange. Moreover, the high degree of inefficiency ratio is observed in the market. Furthermore, the Tehran Stock Exchange does not become more efficient over time. Finally, the results from the time windows with 5 day shifts as well as wild bootstrap versions of the AQ and AVR tests with 14 and 5 day shifts indicate that the previous empirical results are robust. The findings from the study provide important implications for investors, portfolio managers and policy-makers.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">اهداف: در این مقاله برای نخستین‌‌بار موضوع حافظه بلندمدت متغیر زمانی در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران با بکارگیری یک شاخص کارآیی جدید از طریق یک رویکرد پنجره متحرک، مورد بررسی قرارگرفته است. به منظور بررسی و قوت نتایج، این روش تخمین برای پنجره‌‌های با تعداد روزهای انتقال 5 روز نیز انجام شده است. بعلاوه، از ورژن بوت‌‌استرپ ریسکی آزمون کلی‌‌نگر اتوماتیک (AQ) و آزمون نسبت واریانس اتوماتیک (AVR)، برای تعداد روزهای انتقال 14 و 5 روز، نیز استفاده شده است.&lt;br&gt;روش: مجموعه قیمت‌‌های p_t مورد استفاده در این مقاله شامل 2621 مشاهده روزانه از شاخص کل قیمت بورس اوراق بهادار تهران (TEPIX)، طی دوره زمانی23/9/1387 تا 1/8/1398 است که از نرم‌‌افزار ره‌‌آوردنوین گردآوری شده است. فرضیه‌‌ها با استفاده از نرم‌‌افزارهای Excel، EViews، R و MATLAB آزمون شده‌‌اند.&lt;br&gt;نتایج: نتایج نشان می‌‌دهد که در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، مقدار بدست آمده از نما‌‌های هرست تعمیم یافته (GHE) برای کلیه پنجره‌‌ها با روزهای انتقال 14 روز، بالای شاخص کارآیی یعنی مقدار 5/0 است. ازاینرو، حافظه بلندمدت در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران وجود دارد. همچنین، درجه بالایی از نسبت عدم کارآیی در این بازار مشاهده شده است. بعلاوه، بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در طی زمان کارآتر نشده است. در پایان، نتایج حاصل از تخمین پنجره‌‌های زمانی با روزهای انتقال 5 روز، و نتایج حاصل از تخمین ورژن بوت‌‌استرپ ریسکی آزمون‌‌های AQ و AVR برای روزهای انتقال 14 و 5 روز، دلالت بر صحت و قوت نتایج تجربی قبلی دارد. یافته‌‌های این مقاله دستاوردهایی نیز برای سرمایه‌‌گذاران، مدیران سبد و سیاست‌‌گذاران به همراه دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حافظه بلندمدت متغیر زمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رویکرد پنجره متحرک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارآیی بازار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نما‌های هرست تعمیم یافته (GHE)</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
