<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Ranking Of Selected Industries Of Tehran Stock Exchange Based On Fundamental Factors In Industry Using Data Envelopment Analysis</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رتبه‌بندی صنایع منتخب بورس اوراق بهادار تهران بر اساس عوامل بنیادی صنعت با استفاده از روش تحلیل پوششی داده‌ها</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>55</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>68</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19915</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعیده</FirstName>
					<LastName>کتابی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعید</FirstName>
					<LastName>فتحی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000000180672437</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ناهید</FirstName>
					<LastName>یوسفان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>One of the issues that always has been considered is selecting stocks for profitable investments in financial markets. If the investor decides reasonably in the stock selection, a return more than the market average could be achieved. Comparing different companies based on the industry which the company belongs to, and identifying the premier industries through analysis of their efficiency could be useful guideline for stakeholders of this field. The main purpose of this research is ranking the stock industry to help the efficiency of capital markets applying the data envelopment analysis. The nature of the model is constant return to scale and input-oriented that 67 companies in 16 industries were studied and finally 7 industries were introduced as efficient and 9 other as non-efficient. Then determining the efficiency boundary, the inefficient industries are ranking and to improve their performance, some units were introduced as reference units.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">انتخاب سهام مناسب برای سرمایه‌گذاری سودآور یکی از مسایلی است که همواره در بازارهای مالی مورد توجه بوده است. اگر سرمایه‌گذار در انتخاب سهام به طور منطقی تصمیم گیری نماید، می‌تواند به بازدهی بیش ازمیانگین بازار دست یابد. مقایسه شرکت‌های مختلف براساس صنعتی که شرکت به آن تعلق دارد و تشخیص صنایع برتر از طریق بررسی عملکرد آنها می‌تواند راهنمای مفیدی برای ذی‌نفعان این عرصه باشد. هدف اصلی این پژوهش، رتبه‌بندی صنایع بورس برای کمک به کارایی بازار سرمایه است و تکنیک مورد استفاده در این راستا، تحلیل پوششی داده‌هاست. ماهیت الگو بازده ثابت به مقیاس و ورودی محور است که با استفاده از آن 67 شرکت در قالب 16 صنعت مطالعه و در نهایت 7 صنعت کارا و 9 صنعت دیگر غیرکارا معرفی شدند، سپس برحسب مرز کارایی ایجاد شده صنایع ناکارا رتبه‌بندی و برای ارتقای سطح کارایی آنها واحدهایی به عنوان مرجع انتخاب شده‌اند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صنعت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل تکنیکال</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل بنیادی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رتبه بندی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_19915_14d5765d1aeb045d9fcfd729aae5cf98.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
