<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigating the Factors Influencing on the Stock Market Risk with the Emphasis on Financial Globalization in Dynamic Behavior of Stock Market</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر ریسک بازار سهام با تأکید بر جهانی‌شدن مالی در قالب رفتار پویای بازار سهام</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>87</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>100</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">20634</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2016.20634</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدکمال</FirstName>
					<LastName>صادقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تبریز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>باقرزاده آذر</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تبریز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سها</FirstName>
					<LastName>موسوی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تبریز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This paper examines equity market risk measured by beta-volatility of stock returns over 2002-2011 for Middle Eastern oil producing countries namely Iran, Bahrain, Qatar, Kuwait, Oman, Saudi Arabia and UAE. First, the paper examines whether the dynamic behavior of stock market returns has changed during the last decade. Using a Dynamic Conditional Correlation model we find that the stock market returns of the sampled countries are not definitely correlated in the short-term. So, international investors may get the short-term diversification benefits by diversifying their portfolios among the Middle Eastern equity markets. Second, in our dynamic panel data framework, after controlling for size and turnover, our results provide evidence in favor of the view that the broadening of the investor base by increasing degree of financial globalization doesn&#039;t reduce the total volatility of stock returns. Our results are important for Middle Eastern oil producing countries policy makers, portfolio managers, as well as academics.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">جهانی شدن مالی با ویژگی‌هایی همچون افزایش تحرک سرمایه در سطح بین­المللی، کاهش موانع در مسیر سرمایه‌گذاری­های مشترک و افزایش سرمایه­گذاری مستقیم خارجی و تأثیری که بر بازار اوراق بهادار دارد، توجه بسیاری از کشورهای در حال توسعه را به خود جلب نموده است. از اینرو، در این پژوهش با مطالعه پویایی رفتار بازارهای اوراق بهادار کشورهای تولید کننده نفت منطقه خاورمیانه شامل ایران، بحرین، امارات متحده عربی، عربستان، عمان، قطر و کویت، طی سال­های 2002- 2011 با استفاده ازمدل همبستگی شرطی پویا (DCC)، این نتیجه به‌دست آمد که بازارهای اوراق­ بهادار کشورهای مورد مطالعه همبستگی پایینی با یکدیگر دارند. در نتیجه می­توان با سرمایه‌گذاری‌های مشترک در طی فرآیند جهانی شدن مالی، از منافع متنوع­سازی سبد دارایی بین­المللی بهره برد. وجود این منافع بالقوه، انگیزه مطالعه تأثیر جهانی شدن مالی بر ریسک بازار اوراق بهادار را با استفاده از روش داده­های تابلویی پویا فراهم می­کند. نتایج نشان می­دهد جهانی شدن مالی در شرایط فعلی در کشورهای مورد مطالعه، به کاهش نوسان‌های بازار اوراق بهادار منجر نمی‌شود که دلیل این امر را می­توان در ساختار مالی ناکارا و شکننده کشورهای مذکور یافت، که ضرورت توسعه کیفی و کمی هر چه بیشتر زیرساخت­های بازارهای مالی کشورهای مذکور در تعامل با کشورهای دیگر را برجسته‌تر می­سازد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جهانی شدن بازارهای مالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ریسک بازار سهام</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل همبستگی شرطی پویا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">داده‌های تابلویی پویا</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_20634_3b8454dc1cfaa0799a768fcc52fc5591.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
