<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Anatomy of Asset Growth Anomaly Evidence from Tehran Stock Exchange</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>واکاوی خلاف قاعده‌ رشد دارایی؛ شواهدی از بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>14</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19851</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>رحمانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه الزهرا(س)</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>دولو</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The main purpose of this paper is analysis of total asset growth anomaly in Tehran Stock Exchange that emphasizes on the test of relation between total asset growth and net operating asset. On account Scrutiny in asset growth understanding, an anatomic approach is used to break down total asset growth to its three components and its effect on cross-section stock return is investigated using dual portfolio analysis and Fama-MacBeth (1973) two step regression from 1379 to 1389. The results confirm asset growth positive effect and reject the effect of net operating asset growth because the latter effect depending on weighting scheme and time horizon of subsequent stock return can be positive, negative or even statistically insignificant. The research Evidences indicate asset growth is self-inclusive and its explanatory power of is not appertained by anyone of its subcomponents. So, it cannot seek the reasons of the asset growth anomaly appearance in net operating asset anomaly. It seems that the source of asset growth financing (Criterion of asset growth decomposition) does not matter in asset growth anomaly occurrence.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف اصلی پژوهش حاضر، واکاوی اثر خلاف قاعده‌ رشد دارایی با تاکید بر آزمون رابطه اثر رشد دارایی و رشد خالص دارایی‌های عملیاتی در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران است. جهت تعمیق درک خلاف قاعده رشد دارایی طی سال‌های 1379 تا 1389 با استفاده از رویکردی تجزیه‌گرا، رشد دارایی به سه مولفه شاکله تجزیه گردیده و بر مبنای تحلیل پرتفوی دوگانه و مدل‌ رگرسیون دو مرحله‌ای فاما و مک‌بث (1973) اثر آن بر بازده مقطعی سهام منفرد آزمون می‌گردد. نتایج حاصله ضمن تایید اثر مثبت رشد دارایی، اثرگذاری رشد خالص دارایی‌های عملیاتی را مردود می‌داند به نحوی‌که اثر یادشده متاثر از الگوی وزنی بازده سهم و افق زمانی بازده آتی سهام، می‌تواند مثبت، منفی و یا حتی فاقد معناداری آماری باشد. شواهد به دست آمده دال بر شمولیت اثر رشد دارایی بوده و توان توضیحی رشد دارایی را منحصر به هیچ‌یک از ریزمولفه‌های آن نمی‌داند. بدین نحو نمی‌توان دلایل بروز خلاف قاعده رشد دارایی را در رشد خالص دارایی عملیاتی جستجو نمود. به نظر می‌رسد منبع تامین مالی رشد دارایی (ملاک تجزیه رشد دارایی) در وقوع خلاف قاعده دارایی حائز اهمیت نیست.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خلاف قاعده‌های رشد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رشد کل دارایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رشد خالص دارایی عملیاتی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_19851_f12edd63c7c2a94e6d0cd9b80a76b781.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
