<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Capital Structure on Profit Efficiency of Companies Listed in Automotive and Parts Manufacturing Industry of Tehran Stock Exchange</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر ساختار سرمایه بر کارایی سود شرکت های پذیرفته شده صنعت خودرو و ساخت قطعات بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>91</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>106</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19903</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>غیوری مقدم</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه خلیج فارس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمید رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>حاجب</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه خلیج فارس</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The aim of current research is to investigate the possible effect of capital structure on profit efficiency (comprehensive indicator of financial performance). This paper uses the Jensen and Meckling (1976) theory to assess the effect of financial leverage on agency costs and performance. Therefore, this study examines the effect of nonlinear effect of financial leverage on profit efficiency. The sample consists of 28 automotive and parts manufacturing companies listed on the Tehran Stock Exchange for the period of eight years from 1384 to 1391. Data envelopment analysis (DEA) method is used to calculate the profit efficiency and panel data regression is used to test the effect of financial leverage on profit efficiency. The results indicated that financial leverage has a nonlinear (inverted U-Shaped) impact on profit efficiency. Thus, in this industry, financial leverage growth plays a positive role in performance improvement because a reduction in the free cash flow in hands of manager and consequently, decreases agency costs. On the other hand, an increase of bankruptcy risk increases the agency costs of debt and consequently has a negative effect on performance. The findings also revealed that fixed assets have a negative and significant effect on profit efficiency, but firm size, intangible assets and growth ratio donât have any effect on profit efficiency.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف پژوهش حاضر بررسی تأثیر ساختار سرمایه بر کارایی سود به عنوان معیاری جامع از عملکرد مالی است. در بررسی این تأثیر، نظریه ارائه شده توسط جنسن و مکلین (1976) در باب تأثیر اهرم مالی بر هزینه‌های نمایندگی و متعاقباً بر عملکرد واحد تجاری مد نظر قرار گرفت. لذا در این پژوهش تأثیر غیر خطی اهرم مالی بر کارایی سود مورد توجه است. نمونه مورد بررسی شامل 28 شرکت فعال در صنعت خودرو و ساخت قطعات در دوره زمانی 1391-1384 است. به منظور محاسبه کارایی سود از روش تحلیل پوششی داده‌ها و به منظور بررسی تأثیر اهرم مالی بر کارایی سود از رگرسیون داده‌های ترکیبی استفاده شد. نتایج بدست آمده تأثیر غیر خطی (به شکل U وارونه) اهرم مالی را بر کارایی سود مورد تأیید قرار داد. لذا می-توان چنین گفت که در واحدهای مورد بررسی، افزایش اهرم مالی از طرفی با کاهش وجوه نقد آزاد در دسترس مدیر، هزینه‌های نمایندگی را کاهش و باعث بهبود عملکرد می‌شود و از طرفی دیگر می‌تواند با افزایش ریسک ورشکستگی، هزینه‌های نمایندگی بدهی را افزایش و عملکرد را تضعیف نماید. از دیگر یافته‌های پژوهش می‌توان به تأثیر منفی و معنادار دارایی‌های ثابت، عدم تأثیر اندازه واحد تجاری، دارایی‌های نامشهود و نرخ رشد بر کارایی سود اشاره کرد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساختار سرمایه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارایی سود</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل پوششی داده ها و داده های ترکیبی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_19903_ff2743ddb437b570b884d09fb893d289.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
