<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Comparative Analysis of Proxies for an Optimal Leverage Ratio</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیلی مقایسه‌ای بر سنجه‌های اهرم بهینه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>119</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>138</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">23537</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2019.114562.1353</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>منیژه</FirstName>
					<LastName>رامشه</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه حسابداری، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه قم، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;Objective: &lt;/strong&gt;Optimal leverage is one of the anchors of capital structure studies. These studies have used a wide range of debt ratios as the optimal ratio; however, the choice of the proxy can influence the results of the studies.
&lt;strong&gt;Method: &lt;/strong&gt;This paper aims to scrutinize the best optimal leverage between the firm’s mean leverage, moving average leverage, industry mean leverage and predicted leverage ratio based on regressions. Choice of the best proxy is based on the speed of adjustment, financing decisions and firm’s market value.
&lt;strong&gt;Results: &lt;/strong&gt;The results show that the change in market value is similar for all proxies when leverage deviates away from its optimum. It means as the firm&#039;s leverage ratio deviates away from its optimum, its market value declines in the firms whose leverage ratio is above the proxy. But the study of the speed of adjustment and financial decision shows that these alternative proxies yield results that are significantly different from each other. In other words, the conclusions drawn from the findings are sensitive to the model&#039;s proxy. Of the proxies in this study, the moving average debt measure exhibits characteristics that are most consistent with the theoretical optimal leverage ratio.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;هدف: &lt;/strong&gt;اهرم بهینه، مرکز ثقل مطالعات ساختار سرمایه است؛ این مطالعات از نسبت‌های اهرمی متفاوت به‌منزلۀ اهرم بهینه استفاده کرده‌اند. به‌کارگیری نسبت‌های متفاوت ممکن است بر نتایج مطالعات تأثیر بگذارد.
&lt;strong&gt;روش: &lt;/strong&gt;پژوهش حاضر سنجه‌های مختلف اهرم بهینه و انتخاب مناسب‌ترین سنجه از بین سنجه‌های میانگین اهرم شرکت، میانگین متحرک اهرم شرکت، میانگین اهرم صنعت و اهرم پیش‌بینی با رگرسیون را تحلیل می‌کند. انتخاب سنجۀ مناسب با بررسی سرعت تعدیل اهرم، تصمیمات تأمین مالی و ارزش بازار شرکت انجام شده است.
&lt;strong&gt;نتایج: &lt;/strong&gt;نتایج نشان داد تغییرات ارزش بازار شرکت‌ها با فاصله‌گرفتن اهرم از هر یک از چهار سنجۀ اهرم بهینه مشابه است؛ بدین معنی که در شرکت‌های با اهرم بالاتر از اهرم بهینه، دورشدن اهرم از اهرم بهینه سبب کاهش ارزش بازار خواهد شد؛ اما مطالعۀ سرعت تعدیل و تصمیمات تأمین مالی نشان می‌دهد استفاده از سنجه‌های مختلف سبب رسیدن به نتایج متفاوتی خواهد شد؛ به‌عبارتی، نتایج به سنجه‌های اهرم بهینه حساس است. از بین سنجه‌های مطالعه‌شده، ویژگی‌های سنجۀ میانگین متحرک بیشترین سازگاری را با تعریف اهرم بهینه در مبانی نظری دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اهرم بهینه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظریه توازن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرعت تعدیل اهرم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تصمیمات تامین مالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزش بازار شرکت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_23537_84f730e466b3a569e840c27a77fb42a2.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
