<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Simulating the effect of financial leverage model on company value via system dynamics approach (Case study: National Iranian copper industries company)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شبیه‏سازی الگوی تاثیر اهرم مالی بر ارزش شرکت با رویکرد پویایی‏شناسی سیستمی (مطالعه موردی: شرکت ملی صنایع مس ایران)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>83</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>104</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19920</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد هاشم</FirstName>
					<LastName>موسوی حقیقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>مرکز تحقیقات کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی استان فارس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجتبی</FirstName>
					<LastName>خلیفه</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Financing of companies investments are usually done by some various financing tools that each of them have their own specifications. In Iran, most of these tools are limited to loans and common stocks. This study considers and simulates the role of financial leverage on intrinsic value and stock price of national Iranian copper industries company via heuristic approach and by using system dynamics method and the relations of financial and capital market data. Research systemic model has been simulated and analyzed by this approach and applying Vensim DSS software. The overall results shows, increase of financial leverage has little role on company value however increase of equity has an influential role on the decrease of stock expected return rate and increase of company value so that at the end of study horizon capital cost rate decrease till seven percent and at the late of the period the stock price will experience close to eight thousand rial.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">تأمین وجوه مورد نیاز برای سرمایه‏گذاری شرکت‏ها معمولاً از طریق ابزارهای متنوع تأمین مالی صورت می‏گیرد که هر یک ویژگی‏های خاص خود را داراست. در ایران این ابزارها بیشتر به وام و سهام عادی محدود می‏شوند. این پژوهش با رویکردی ابتکاری و با استفاده از روش پویایی‏شناسی سیستمی و ارتباط داده‏های مالی و بازار سرمایه، به بررسی و شبیه‏سازی نقش اهرم مالی بر ارزش شرکت و قیمت سهام شرکت ملی صنایع مس ایران پرداخته است. الگوی سیستمی پژوهش با استفاده از این رویکرد و با نرم‏افزار Vensim DSS شبیه‏سازی و تحلیل شده است. نتایج حاکی از آن است که افزایش اهرم مالی نقش چندانی در ارزش شرکت نداشته، اما افزایش حقوق‏صاحبان‏سهام به نسبت بدهی‏ها، تأثیر بسزایی در کاهش نرخ بازده مورد انتظار سهامداران و افزایش ارزش شرکت ایفا می‏کند؛ به ‌طوری ‌که در پایان افق پژوهش نرخ هزینه سرمایه تا 7% کاهش یافته و در اواخر دوره قیمت سهام نیز تا نزدیک 8000 ریال را تجربه خواهد کرد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پویایی‌های سیستم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساختار سرمایه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اهرم مالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزش ذاتی شرکت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازار سرمایه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_19920_2f2e70f47f7143951db09997b991cd51.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
