<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identification of the Causes of Timely Availability of Working Capital Problem for Small and Medium Size Enterprises in Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی علل مشکلات تأمین سرمایۀ درگردش در شرکت‌های کوچک و متوسط کشور</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>16</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">20644</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2016.20644</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>روح الله</FirstName>
					<LastName>نوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعید</FirstName>
					<LastName>فتحی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000000180672437</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>لیلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>یگانه</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه خوارزمی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Small and medium size enterprises play and important role in the economic development of Iran. However, they face difficulties such as timely availability of working capital problem. As a result, the main purpose of this study is to investigate causes of this problem as one of the most challenging problems of such enterprises. This applied and descriptive study uses a qualitative data collection method and a sample of selected managers in small and medium size enterprises located in the provinces of Tehran, Qazvin, Alborz and Mazandaran. To test our hypotheses, we first study characteristics of small and medium size enterprises as well as the principles and theoretical concepts of their working capital. Second, causes of timely availability of working capital problem in small and medium size enterprises are determined. Finally, based on semi-structured interviews, the opinion of selected company&#039;s managers regarding the timely availability of working capital problem is recognized. According to the Top ten method, the results of this study indicate that the roots and causes of timely availability of working capital problem in small and medium size enterprises can be investigated in two internal and external aspects i.e. the supply and the demand sides.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">شرکت‌های کوچک و متوسط نقش مهمی در اقتصاد ملی و توسعۀ کشورها ایفا می‌کنند. با وجود این، با مشکلات زیادی از قبیل نداشتن دسترسی کافی و بموقع به سرمایۀ درگردش مواجه هستند. هدف اصلی پژوهش حاضر، بررسی مسئلۀ دسترسی بموقع و کافی به تأمین مالی سرمایۀ درگردش است که یکی ازمشکلاتاساسی شرکت­های کوچک و متوسط به شمار می­آید؛ بنابراین این پژوهش کاربردی و توصیفی با استفاده از روش‌های جمع‌آوری‌ داده‌های کیفی از مدیران منتخب شرکت­های کوچک و متوسط مستقر در شهرک­های صنعتی تهران، قزوین، البرز و مازندران انجام شده است. به همین منظور، ابتدا ویژگی­های بنگاه‌های کوچک و متوسط و مبانی و مفاهیم نظری سرمایۀ درگردش بررسی شد. در ادامه، ریشه­ها و دلایل دسترسی نداشتن بموقع و کافی به منابع سرمایۀ درگردش در شرکت­های کوچک و متوسط در مبانی نظری و پژوهش­های پیشین شناسایی شد. درنهایت، با استفاده از مصاحبۀ هدفمند و عمیق با مدیران بنگاه‌های منتخب، نظرات آنان در خصوص موانع و مشکلات تأمین سرمایۀ درگردش بر مبنای پرسش‌های نیمه‌ساختاریافته مستخرج از مبانی نظری،‌ دریافت شد. نتایج حاصل از پژوهش به روش Top Ten نشان داد، موانع و مشکلات تأمین بموقع سرمایۀ درگردش در شرکت‌های کوچک و متوسط در دو حوزۀ بیرونی و درونی،‌ یعنی طرف عرضه و طرف تقاضای منابع مالی، درخور بررسی است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تأمین مالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایۀ درگردش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بنگاه‌های کوچک و متوسط (SMEs)</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شرکت شهرک‌های صنعتی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_20644_1623d45a0186ca557705c319ddb1daa2.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
