<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Behavioral Preferences of Investors in Reaction to the Fundamental Variables Based on Sochastic Dominance</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ترجیح های رفتاری سرمایه‌گذاران در واکنش به متغیرهای بنیادی بر مبنای نظریه غلبه تصادفی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>23</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>40</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19905</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>بدری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عبدالمجید</FirstName>
					<LastName>عبدالباقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شیخ بهایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In this article, the fundamental signal analysis to evaluate the relative dominance of the winner-losser stocks based on investorâs preferences has been investigated.Therefore, based on factors related to the profitability , growth and variability the signals of information content of seven financial ratios are identified and based on winner-loser stock related to investrâs preferences identified. In this study, all the financial data of listed companies in TSE for the period 1380 to 1390 are used. The results indicated that the higher current and future return of winner stock related to losser stock one Period after portfolio formation. Also the further results indicate the second and third order of stochastic dominance of winner stocks relate to losser stocks and second and third order of stochastic dominance of losser stocks relate to winner stocks in the negative market conditions.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این مقاله با استفاده از تجزیه و تحلیل مبتنی بر سیگنالهای بنیادی به بررسی برتری نسبی سهام برنده-بازنده بر اساس عملکرد فعلی و آتی از منظر ترجیحات رفتاری سرمایه‌گذاران پرداخته شده است. بنابراین بر اساس عوامل مربوط به سودآوری، تغییرپذیری عایدات و رشد، سیگنالهای بنیادی (F-Score) مربوط به محتوای اطلاعاتی 7 شاخص مالی شناسایی و بر مبنای آن سهام برنده-بازنده، تعیین و رفتار آتی بازده آنها بر مبنای ترجیحات ریسک‌گریزانه سرمایه-گذاران مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. در این تحقیق از اطلاعات مالی تمامی شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در بازه زمانی1380 الی 1390 استفاده شده است. نتایج اولیه این تحقیق نشان دهنده وجود بازده بالاتر همزمان و آتی پرتفوی سهام برنده نسبت به سهام بازنده تا یک دوره زمانی پس از تشکیل پرتفوی و وجود رفتار مومنتومی و سپس رفتار معکوس بلندمدت آنهاست. همچنین نتایج تحقیق نشان دهنده وجود غلبه تصادفی بازده همزمان مرتبه‌های دوم و سوم سهام برنده نسبت به سهام بازنده و همچنین غلبه تصادفی مرتبه های دوم و سوم بازده دو دوره بعد سهام بازنده نسبت به سهام برنده در بازه های منفی بازار است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ترجیحات سرمایه‌گذاران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیگنالهای بنیادی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سهام برنده_بازنده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مومنتوم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">غلبه تصادفی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_19905_02da5fb15300609b968d59f8a78f81e1.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
