<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An Anatomic Study of the Relationship between Stock Return and Idiosyncratic Volatility Evidences from Tehran Stock Exchange</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی آناتومیک رابطه بازده سهام و نوسان‌پذیری غیرسیستماتیک؛ شواهدی از بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>37</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>48</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19922</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>دولو</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عظیم</FirstName>
					<LastName>رجبی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study is to explain the opposite of the idiosyncratic volatility based on breaking up the idiosyncratic volatility into expected idiosyncratic volatility (EIV) and unexpected idiosyncratic volatility (UIV) and analyzing its split effects on the explanation of cross-sectional changes of individual stock. This relationship is studied in a sample consisting of 95 companies approved in the Tehran Stock Exchange during the years 2002 and 2011 using Fama-Macbeth regression model (1973) and the portfolio approach. The evidences from the study show that EIV alone is not able to explain the return changes, so by taking both EIV and UIV simultaneously, the positive coefficient of UIV becomes meaningful in terms of the statistics. If size, book value to market value ratio, momentum, liquidity and dilatory effect are controlled, the results would remain the same. So it seems like the main source of the opposite of the idiosyncratic volatility in Tehran Stock Exchange is caused by the unexpected idiosyncratic volatility.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف پژوهش حاضر توضیح خلاف قاعده نوسان‌پذیری غیرسیستماتیک بر مبنای تجزیه‌ نوسان‌های غیرسیستماتیک به دو مؤلفه نوسان‌های غیرسیستماتیک مورد انتظار (EIV) و نوسان‌های غیرسیستماتیک غیرمنتظره (UIV) و بررسی اثر تفکیکی آن در توضیح تغییرات بازده مقطعی سهام منفرد است. رابطه اخیر در نمونه‌ای­ متشکل از 95 شرکت پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران طی سال­های 1381 تا 1390 با استفاده از مدل فاما-مک‌بث (1973) و رویکرد تحلیل سبد سرمایه گذاری بررسی می‌شود. شواهد به دست آمده حاکی از آن است که EIV به تنهایی قادر به تبیین تغییرات بازده نیست، لیکن با احتساب همزمان EIV و UIV، ضریب مثبت UIV به لحاظ آماری معنادار می­گردد. نتایج به دست آمده پس از احتساب تأثیر متغیرهای کنترل و نیز در صورت استفاده از رویکرد تحلیل سبد سرمایه گذاری، کماکان برقرار است. لذا به نظر می‌رسد منشأ بروز خلاف قاعده نوسان‌پذیری غیرسیستماتیک در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران ناشی از اثرگذاری نوسان‌پذیری غیرسیستماتیک غیرمنتظره است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوسان‌پذیری غیرسیستماتیک کل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوسان‌پذیری غیرسیستماتیک مورد انتظار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوسان‌پذیری غیرسیستماتیک غیرمنتظره</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازده مقطعی سهام</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_19922_fc8252df97af257abe6ea3201946300b.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
