<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Financing Decisions and Managerial Market Timing Evidence from Tehran Stock Exchange</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تصمیمات تامین مالی و زمان سنجی مدیریت، شواهدی از بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>21</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>36</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19923</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>داغانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>اعتمادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مسعود</FirstName>
					<LastName>عزیزخانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه ایلام</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی اصغر</FirstName>
					<LastName>انواری رستمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Managerial financing decisions seem to change the predictions of the financial model about how often and under what circumstances firms use financial resources. The financial accounting literature uses market timing hypothesis, pecking order theories to explain managementâs financing decision. We examine how market timing affects managementâs net financing decision using a sample of firms listed in Tehran Stock exchange over the period of 2002 to 2011. Our results do not provide support for the market timing hypothesis. We also find a negative association between net financing and firmsâ market return suggesting a negative impact of the net financing decision on firmsâ return. Our results show no association between initial public offering and firmsâ market return. This suggests that a suitable market return did not appear in initial public offerings. The findings also show that firms with an ability of using internal resources in its capital structure are more likely to perform well than expected in the capital market.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">از جمله عوامل برجسته در ادبیات مالی، پیگیری تصمیم‌های مدیریت هنگام تأمین منابع مورد نیاز و بررسی شرایط متفاوت مالی شرکت در هنگام این رویداد است. به­طوری که این پرسش مطرح شده است که آیا با پی­جویی تصمیم مدیریت در هنگام تأمین منابع مالی، می­توان وضعیت شرکت (از نظر ساختار مالی و عملکرد آن) را پی­گیری نمود. در این پژوهش با بررسی وضعیت تأمین مالی، برای توصیف شرایط شرکت­ها از مبانی نظری و ادبیات مالی نظیرزمان سنجی مدیریت و نظریه ترجیحی استفاده شده است. با استفاده از نمونه شامل بر1506 سال- شرکت طی دوره زمانی 1381 –1390 نتایج پژوهش­شواهدی را در مورد پذیرش فرضیه زمان سنجی مدیریت برای شرکت­های مورد مطالعه فراهم نکرده است. همچنین، نتایج نشان دهنده تأثیر منفی تأمین مالی بر بازده بازار، برای شرکت­های با خالص تأمین مالی منفی بود. در بررسی شرایط شرکت­ها در عرضه اولیه و کنترل آنها در مدل پژوهش، نتایج مشخص ساخته است که تأمین مالی خالص مثبت این شرکت­ها، تأثیر با اهمیتی بر بازده آنها داشته است. همچنین سایرنتایج پژوهش نشان داده است شرکت‌هایی که توانایی بهتری در استفاده از منابع داخلی دارند، عملکرد بهتری نیز در بازار داشته­اند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرضیه زمان سنجی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تامین مالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انتخاب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد شرکت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_19923_4a76979ea0003e1aabc8de8d6b5bc33f.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
