<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A comparative Analysis of Performance of Three-Factor and Five - Factor Fama and French Model to Estimate the Expected Rate of Return in Tehran Stock Exchange</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل مقایسه‌ای دربارۀ عملکرد مدل سه‌عاملی و پنج‌عاملی فاما و فرنچ در تخمین بازده موردانتظار</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>105</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>116</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">21419</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21419</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضایی دولت آبادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه مدیریت، دانشکدۀ علوم اداری و اقتصاد، دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ناهید</FirstName>
					<LastName>یوسفان</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‌ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی - مالی، گروه مدیریت، دانشکدۀ علوم اداری و اقتصاد، دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Accurately predict of stock returns is a key factor in investment decisions. The aim of this study is the test of five-factor Fama and French model and to comparison the performance of three-factor and five-factor model of Fama and French (2015) to estimate the expected return. This research is a correlation-descriptive research and its hypothesis is tested based on data collected from 40 companies listed on Tehran Stock Exchange in 2009 to 2014 years. Research hypothesis are tested by correlations synchronicity assessing in two phases of Alpha time series test to calculating intercept by GRS statistic and cross-sectional Fama-Macbeth (1973) test in pricing coefficient. The results show that five-factor model of Fama and French, with these explanatory variables: size, value, profitability and investment pattern, explains excess stock returns better than Fama and French three-factor model. Based on the results, in three-factor model value is the only factor that is significant, while the five-factor model price these two factors: value and investment.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پیش‌بینی صحیح بازده سهام، عامل کلیدی در تصمیم‌گیری‌های سرمایه‌گذاری است. هدف پژوهش حاضر، آزمون نظریۀ پنج‌عاملی فاما و فرنچ و مقایسۀ عملکرد الگوی سه‌عاملی و پنج‌عاملی در برآورد بازده موردانتظار است. این پژوهش از نوع توصیفی - همبستگی است و فرضیۀ آن براساس اطلاعات سال‌های 1393-1388 برای 40 شرکت پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران آزمون شده است. فرضیۀ پژوهش، با درنظرگرفتن همزمانی روابط، در دو مرحلۀ آزمون سری زمانی آلفا برای سنجش عرض از مبدأ با آمارۀ GRS و آزمون مقطعی فاما - مک‌بث در قیمت‌گذاری ضرایب بررسی شده است. نتایج به‌دست‌‎آمده نشان می‌دهد الگوی پنج‌عاملی فاما و فرنچ، با متغیر‌های توضیحی اندازه، ارزش، سودآوری و سرمایه‌گذاری، مازاد بازده سهام را با قدرت بیشتری نسبت به الگوی سه‌عاملی فاما و فرنچ توضیح می‌دهد. براساس نتایج در الگوی سه‌عاملی، تنها عامل ارزش معنادار است؛ در حالی که الگوی پنج‌عاملی دو عامل ارزش و سرمایه‌گذاری را قیمت‌گذاری می‌کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوی قیمت‌گذاری پنج‌‌عاملی فاما و فرنچ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آزمون الگوی قیمت‌گذاری دارایی سرمایه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوی سرمایه‌گذاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سودآوری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21419_7ba8b99aec7a1b93ef42d11e157d4a36.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
