<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The effect of Contractual Rewards on Non-Maturing Deposits and Bank Funding Stability (Case Study: Bank Mellat)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر پاداش‌های قراردادی بر سپرده‌های بدون سررسید مشخص و تأمین مالی باثبات در بانک مطالعۀ موردی: بانک ملت</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>45</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>62</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">23557</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2018.111350.1262</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>تهرانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه مدیریت مالی و بیمه؛ دانشکده مدیریت؛ دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید مجتبی</FirstName>
					<LastName>میرلوحی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مالی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه شاهرود. ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>مهرآرا</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد اقتصاد، دانشکده اقتصاد، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجید</FirstName>
					<LastName>لطفی قهرود</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری،‌ ﮔﺮوه علوم اجتماعی و رفتاری، مدیریت مالی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، پردیس بین‌الملل کیش دانشگاه تهران، کیش‌، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>24</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>There are four main sources for bank funding in Iran, including deposits, capital, borrowing from the Central Bank, and borrowing from other banks. Of all these sources, deposits are the main source of bank funding. During recent years, customers’ orientation to non-maturing deposits, possible to be withdrawn at any time by customers, has triggered a lot of problems for banks and financial institutions. This study examines the effect of contractual rewards on the behavior of 24107 depositors of the Mellat Bank, consisting of two groups of depositors as a sample, 10924 premier customers who received contractual rewards and 13183 normal customers who didn’t receive contractual rewards from 2010 to 2015. Most studies in this area have been encompassed on the interest rate and its effect on depositors. In this research, however, the effect of Contractual rewards on saving duration and cash inflow volatility, as two factors of bank funding stability, is considered. By definition, Contractual rewards involve special card and insurance, without interest of deposits. In conclusion, the results reveal that contractual rewards increase financial stability.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">تأمین مالی بانک‌‌ها در ایران چهار مسیر عمده دارد: سپرده‌ها، سرمایه، بدهی به بانک مرکزی یا سایر بانک‌ها و سپرده‌گذاری که یکی از منابع اصلی تأمین مالی است. در سال‌‌های اخیر گرایش مشتریان به سپرده‌‌های بدون سررسید مشخص که هر زمان قابل‌برداشت است، مشکلاتی را برای بانک‌ها و مؤسسه‌های مالی ایجاد کرده است. این پژوهش تأثیر پاداش‌‌های قراردادی بر رفتار 107/24 نفر از سپرده‌گذاران را - شامل 924/10 سپرده‌گذار ویژۀ بانک ملت که پاداش دریافت کرده‌اند و 183/13 سپرده‌گذار عادی این بانک که از این پاداش‌ها برخوردار نشده‌‌اند - از سال 1389 تا 1394 بررسی کرده است. بیشتر پژوهش‌های انجام‌شده در این حوزه، سود بانکی و تأثیر آن بر سپرده‌گذاران را بررسی کرده است. در این پژوهش پاداش‌‌های قراردادی شامل بیمه و کارت بانکی ویژه به‌استثنای سود سپرده است و اثر این پاداش‌‌ها بر طول دورۀ سپرده‌‌گذاری و نوسانات سپرده به‌منزلۀ عوامل تأمین مالی باثبات بررسی شده است. نتایج پژوهش نشان می‌‌دهد پاداش‌‌های قراردادی سبب افزایش ثبات تأمین مالی در بانک شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تأمین مالی باثبات</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفتار سپرده‌گذاران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سپردۀ بدون سررسید مشخص</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_23557_0a34292f7ae98fdb983777abc28a33fe.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
