<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Portfolio Optimization with Clustering Methods</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بهینه‌سازی سبد سرمایه‌گذاری با استفاده از روش‌های خوشه‌بندی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>16</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">21104</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2016.21104</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>سلطانی نژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه مدیریت مالی دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>دولو</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه مدیریت مالی دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>25</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The portfolio selection problem and optimizing it is an important issue in investment field. This process aims to create A portfolio that incur the minimum amount of risk to the investor in different levels of return. The existence of statistical uncertainty and noise in information, which is used in the process of optimization, would hamper the performance of optimized portfolios. The purpose of this article is to eliminate the noise of correlation coefficient matrix by using clustering method. In order to do so, two clustering methods, Single Linkage and Average Linkage, are applied, and the optimized portfolio based on the Tehran Stock Exchange information from March 2007 to March 2013 is obtained. The results show that such portfolio is more reliable and provides less risk to the capital owner. For analyzing the robustness of the results in a wide range of different investment horizons and numbers of assets, a Bootstrap analysis with resampling is performed and in most cases a significant improvement was observed.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مسألۀ انتخاب سبد سرمایه‌گذاری و بهینه‌سازی، یکی از موضوعات مهم در حوزۀ سرمایه‌گذاری است. در این فرایند سعی بر آن است که سرمایه‌گذار بازای هر نرخی از بازده، کمترین ریسک ممکن را متحمل شود. اگر اطلاعاتی که در جریان بهینه‌سازی سبد سرمایه‌گذاری استفاده شده‌اند، دچار عدم قطعیت‌های آماری و یا در معرض نویز باشند، به کارایی سبد سرمایه‌گذاری لطمه وارد می‌شود. هدف این مقاله، حذف نویز اطلاعات ماتریس ضرایب همبستگی از طریق روش‌های خوشه‌بندی است. برای این منظور، دو روش خوشه‌بندی اتصال واحد و اتصال میانگین به کار گرفته شد و براساس اطلاعات بازده روزانۀ 80 شرکت بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در بازه فروردین 1385 تا اسفند 1392، سبد سرمایه‌گذاری بهینه به دست آمد. نتایج نشان می‌دهد میزان اختلاف ریسک پیش‌بینی‌شده و ریسک مشاهده‌شده در این سبد سرمایه‌گذاری کمتر است و از طرفی درمجموع، ریسک کمتری را به سرمایه‌گذار تحمیل می‌کند. همچنین با هدف تحلیل حساسیت نتایج دو روش، یک مطالعۀ بوت استرپینگ در تعداد سهام و افق‌های زمانی مختلف انجام گرفت، در بیشتر حالت‌ها بهبود عملکرد سبد سرمایه‌گذاری مشاهده می‌شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بهینه‌سازی سبد سرمایه‌گذاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش‌های خوشه‌بندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ماتریس ضرایب همبستگی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21104_4c956a1af858de54a2f9194562e28cba.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
