<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Assessing the Impact of Financial Performance and Privatization on the Technical Efficiency of Transferred Firms in the Stock Exchange</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی تأثیر عملکرد مالی و خصوصی‌سازی بر کارایی فنی شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>93</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>108</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19891</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعید</FirstName>
					<LastName>میرزا محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسکندری عطا</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In recent decades, the privatization program by many developed and developing countries with different political systems has been followed. Financial and economic performance of the firms after privatization as one of the criteria for evaluating the mentioned policy, always has been one of the central issues in economic research in developing countries. In this paper, stochastic frontier analysis (SFA) is used to obtain the technical efficiency of transferred firms in Tehran Stock Exchange before and after entering to stock market. Then, panel data methods are used to measure financial performance on the technical efficiency. The sample consists of a panel data of 29 firms transferred during 1381 to 1388. The results indicate that technical efficiency for 28 firms decreased after entering the stock market and liquidity and return on equity ratios have a significant negative impact on the firmsâ technical inefficiency component.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در دهه‌های اخیر برنامه خصوصی‌سازی توسط بسیاری از کشورهای در حال توسعه و توسعه یافته با نظام‌های سیاسی مختلف دنبال شده است. عملکرد مالی و اقتصادی(کارایی) شرکت‌ها بعد از خصوصی‌سازی به عنوان یکی از ملاک‌های ارزیابی سیاست مذکور، همواره یکی از مسائل محوری در پژوهش‌های اقتصادی کشورهای در حال توسعه بوده است. در این پژوهش با استفاده از روش تحلیل مرزی تصادفی(SFA)، ابتدا کارایی فنی شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران قبل و بعد از ورود به بورس برآورد می‌شود و سپس با استفاده از روش پانل دیتا، تأثیر عملکرد مالی برکارایی، مورد سنجش قرار خواهد گرفت. نمونه‌های مورد بررسی داده‌های پانل 29 شرکت واگذار شده طی سال‌های 1381 تا 1388 است. نتایج پژوهش، کاهش کارایی فنی 28 شرکت را بعد از ورود به بورس نشان می‌دهد و نیز تأثیر منفی و معنادارِ نسبت‌های نقدینگی و بازده حقوق صاحبان سهام را بر جزء ناکارایی فنی شرکت‌ها تبیین می‌کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد مالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارایی فنی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خصوصی‌سازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل مرزی تصادفی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_19891_8bf2c45dba3ad530b976a6d340f65c7d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
