<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Solutions for Financial Restructuring in Iranian Banks</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>«راهکارهای بازسازی مالی بانک ها در ایران»</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">24588</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2020.119436.1473</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدصادق</FirstName>
					<LastName>عبداللهی پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه آموزشی مالی و بانکداری، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری ، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدهاشم</FirstName>
					<LastName>بت شکن</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، گروه آموزشی مالی و بانکی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Bank problems are due to mismatching in balance sheet, revenue and expense gap and uneconomical cash flow. The main aim of this research is investigating the executive solutions for solving those problems through the financial restructuring in Iranian banks. First, a big picture of the problems of banking system was presented via seeking the previous researches and the balance sheet of the banking system. After, having had an in-depth study in internal and international resources, the initial solutions are believed to be obtained. Next, by two-stage Delphi approach, the agreement about those solutions has been obtained. Half of experts have related Ph.D. degree and others have related MS degree, also the year average of their executive experiences is 18. Consequently, the final list of 21 solutions is extracted and classified in 5 sections which are named: clarifying the circumstances of unsafe banks which have considerable over draft from central bank of Iran, improving the bank regulatory and supervisory system of central bank, selling the excess assets of banks and improving their branch networks, lowering the long term liabilities of banks and enacting efficient rules and regulations.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">معضلات نظام بانکی ریشه در ناترازی ترازنامه، شکاف درآمد-هزینه و ناترازی نقدی دارد. هدف اصلی این پژوهش، بررسی راهکارهای اجرائی برای حل معضلات نظام بانکی در قالب بازسازی مالی بانک‌ها در ایران است. ابتدا با بررسی کلی مشکلات نظام بانکی بر اساس مطالعات صورت‌گرفته و اطلاعات ارائه شده توسط بانک مرکزی ایران ، تصویری کلی از مشکلات آن ارائه شد. در ادامه با مطالعه عمیق کتابخانه‌ای منابع داخلی و بین‌المللی، فهرست اولیه از راهکارهای بازسازی مالی نظام بانکی احصاء شد. در گام بعد با استفاده از روش دلفی دو مرحله‌ای، توافق راهکار‌های اجرائی حاصل شد. نیمی از خبرگان دارای مدرک دکتری مرتبط و نیم دیگر مدرک کارشناسی ارشد مرتبط هستند و میانگین سابقه اجرائی ایشان در سطح مدیریت ارشد نظام بانکی 18 سال است. بر این اساس، فهرست نهایی راهکارها شامل 21 مورد استخراج شد و در پنج طبقه‌بندی کلی قرار گرفت که عبارتند از: تعیین تکلیف بانک‌های ناسالم با اضافه برداشت بالا، ارتقای نظام نظارت بانک مرکزی بر بانک‌ها، تعیین تکلیف اموال مازاد بانک‌ها و بهینه‌سازی شبکه شعب، کاهش مطالبات غیرجاری بانک‌ها و دسته حاکمیتی، سیاست‌گذاری و مقرراتی.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بانک‌ها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازسازی مالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازبینی کیفیت دارایی ها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">برنامه گزیر</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
