<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Market Reaction to Tangible and Intangible Information in Tehran Stock Exchange</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>واکنش بازار به اطلاعات مشهود و نامشهود در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>19</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>36</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">20630</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2016.20630</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد اسماعیل</FirstName>
					<LastName>فدائی نژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجتبی</FirstName>
					<LastName>کامل نیا</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>There are two interpretations concerning the book to market ratio (B/M) effect. Financial economists believe that risk premium corresponding to high B/M stocks is due to high risk of these companies which are originated from previous weak performance. On the other hand, behaviorists believe “overreaction” as the main source of this phenomena. We investigate these two interpretations more deeply in this paper. We decompose past return into two components of tangible and intangible return and investigate the effect of each component on the future returns using panel regressions technique. Intangible return is the part of return which is not related to financial performance of the firm. Tangible return is the part of return which is caused by disclosure of accounting-based information. Our findings show there is no relation between future return and past financial performance of the firm, while there is a significant negative relation between future return and past intangible return. Therefore it seems that the main cause of the B/M effect is investors’ overreaction to intangible return.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در توجیه پدیده ضریب ارزش دفتری به ارزش بازار، دو دیدگاه موجود است. اقتصاددانان مالی معتقدند که این صرف بارده به دلیل ریسک زیاد سهام با ضریب B/M بالا است که منشأ این ریسک بازده ضعیف گذشته سهم است. در حالی که طرفداران مالی رفتاری معتقدند فراواکنشی سرمایه‌گذاران دلیل این پدیده است با تفکیک بازده گذشته به بازده مشهود و نامشهود و با استفاده از تکنیک رگرسیون‌ اثر هر بخش از بازده گذشته بر بازده آتی بررسی شد. بازده نامشهودآن بخش از بازده گذشته یک سهم است که ارتباطی به عملکرد مالی سهم ندارد، در حالی که بازده مشهود آن بخش از بازدهی یک سهم است که در اثر افشای اطلاعات مالی در قالب صورت‌های مالی به بازار ایجاد می‌شود. نتایج حاکی از آن است که بازدهی آتی سهم ارتباطی به عملکرد مالی شرکت ندارد، در حالی که بازده آتی به صورت بسیار قوی با بازده نامشهود گذشته ارتباط معکوس دارد.لذا دلیل واقعی پدیده ضریب B/M، فراواکنشی سرمایه‌گذاران روی بازده نامشهود است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ضریب ارزش دفتری به ارزش بازار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازده آتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اطلاعات مشهود و نامشهود</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_20630_0995de71a98fc6a8f8c4a427ad454be0.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
