<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>ProductMarket Power and Stock Market Liquidity</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>قدرت بازار محصول و نقد شوندگی بازار سهام</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>21</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>36</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">21571</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21571</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>رحمانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم اجتماعی و اقتصادی، دانشگاه الزهراء&amp;quot;س&amp;quot;</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">orcid.org/0000-0001</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حدیثه</FirstName>
					<LastName>حاجی مرادخانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای حسابداری، دانشکده علوم اجتماعی و اقتصادی دانشگاه الزهراء&amp;quot;س&amp;quot;</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>25</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>According topredictionsin the literature, sock price offirms with greater product market power is less sensitive to order flows which results in greater stock liquidity. This prediction was examined in a sample of 75 listed companies in Tehran Stock Exchange during 1388 to 1391 using three illiquidity measures (Amihud Ratio, Quoted Spread, Effective Spread) and two proxies for market power. The results of panel regressions showed that stock liquidity increases with market share (the first proxy of market power). Findings also showed the relationship between operational income ratio (second proxy of market power) and stock liquidity is not meaningful and consistent with theory. It seems that the reputation of firms in product market (respect to market share) results in higher stock market liquidity than their profitability. Other results confirmed that advertising in product market doesn’t influence stock market liquidity, directly.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">براساس پیش‌بینی‌های موجود در نوشتار،قیمت سهام شرکتیکهقدرتبازار محصول بیشتری دارد، حساسیت کمتری به جریان سفارش معاملات سهام نشان میدهد که این امر به نوبۀخود به نقدشوندگی بیشتر در بازار سهام منجر می­شود. در این مقاله پیش‌بینی فوق در یک نمونه از 75 شرکت پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در دورۀ 1388 تا 1391 و با استفاده از سه معیار مختلف نقدناشوندگی (معیار آمیهود، شکاف قیمت نسبی و شکاف قیمت مؤثر) آزموده شد. نتایج حاصل از رگرسیون­های ترکیبی (پنل) نشان داد نقدشوندگی سهام به تناسب سهم بازار (شاخص اول قدرت بازار محصول) افزایش می­یابد. یافته­ها همچنین نشان می‌دهد نسبت سود عملیاتی (شاخص دوم قدرت بازار محصول)، رابطۀ معنادار و منطبق با نظریه با نقدشوندگی بازار سهام ندارد. به­ نظر می­رسد نام­آوری شرکت­ها در بازار محصول (به‌لحاظ سهم بازار) بیش از سودآوری،  موجب افزایش  نقدشوندگی سهام آن‌ها می­شود. سایر نتایج نشان می‌دهد تبلیغات در بازار محصول تأثیری مستقیم در نقدشوندگی در بازار سهام ندارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نقد شوندگی سهام</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قدرت بازار محصول</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معیار آمیهود</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شکاف قیمت نسبی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شکاف قیمت مؤثر</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21571_d7457ac4a86722d3d90c31f954c21b66.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
