<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The effect of corporate governance mechanisms on the relationship between institutional investors and inventory management</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر سایر سازوکارهای حاکمیت شرکتی بر رابطه بین سرمایه‌گذاران نهادی و مدیریت موجودی کالا</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>75</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>90</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19907</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>علی نژاد ساروکلائی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه ازاد واحد تبریز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>بحرینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه ازاد واحد علوم و تحقیقات سیرجان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آرزو</FirstName>
					<LastName>طاهری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه ازاد واحد علوم و تحقیقات سیرجان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Presenting information which is useful for investors, creditors, and other current and potential users in decision makings related to investment and validating and other decisions is one of goals in financial reporting. The aim of this research is to study corporate governance mechanisms including managerial ownership, structure of board of directors, and board size on the relationship between institutional investors and inventory management in firms enlisted in Tehran Stock Exchange. To analyze data we have used a multiple variable regression by using generalized moments. Statistical sample in this research entails 47 companies which were enlisted in Stock Exchange during the time period between 2006 and 2011. Control variables in this research were firm growth, firm size, financial leverage, profitability, capital intensity, age, and private ownership. Results of analyzing data showed that managerial ownership affected the relationship between institutional investors and inventory management meaningfully. But structure and size of board of directors did not have any meaningful effects on the relationship between institutional investors and inventory management.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">یکی از اهداف گزارشگری مالی، ارائه‌ی اطلاعاتی است که برای سرمایه‌گذاران، اعتباردهندگان و دیگر کاربران فعلی و بالقوه در تصمیم‌گیری‌های مربوط به سرمایه‌گذاری و اعتبار دهی و سایر تصمیم‌ها، سود‌مند باشد. هدف از این پژوهش، بررسی تأثیر مکانیزم‌های حاکمیت شرکتی شامل مالکیت مدیریتی، ساختار هیئت مدیره و اندازه هیئت مدیره بر رابطه بین سرمایه گذاران نهادی و مدیریت موجودی کالا در شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران است. برای تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها از رگرسیون چند متغیره با استفاده از گشتاورهای تعمیم یافته استفاده شده است. نمونه آماری این پژوهش شامل 47 شرکت می‌باشد که طی سال‌های 1385 تا 1390 عضو بورس بوده‌اند. متغیرهای کنترلی که در این پژوهش مورد بررسی قرار گرفته‌اند رشد شرکت، اندازه شرکت، اهرم مالی، سودآوری، چگالی سرمایه، سن و مالکیت خصوصی می‌باشند. نتایج حاصل از تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها نشان داد که مالکیت مدیریتی بر رابطه بین سرمایه گذاران نهادی و مدیریت موجودی کالا تأثیر معنی داری دارد. ولی ساختار و اندازه هیئت مدیره بر رابطه بین سرمایه گذاران نهادی و مدیریت موجودی کالا تأثیر معناداری ندارند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه گذاران نهادی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مالکیت مدیریتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساختار هیئت مدیره</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اندازه هیئت مدیره</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت موجودی کالا</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_19907_d8e7bb66a089737d682f64e70ae91c51.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
