<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Analysis of big Shareholdersâ Perspective on Block Divestiture of Shares in Business Financing Through Matching Method (Tehran Stock Exchange as A Case Study)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل دیدگاه سهامداران بزرگ به عمل واگذاری بلوکی سهام برای تأمین مالی بنگاه به روش مچینگ (مورد مطالعه: شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>39</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>64</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19885</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>راضیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>صادق فلاح</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضایی دولت ابادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study is to investigate the big shareholdersâ perspective on block divestiture of shares in business financing through propensity score matching method in Tehran stock exchange. The statistical population of this study includes all of listed companies in Tehran stock exchange. 102 companies were examined from 2003 to 2012 and their data was collected through website of Tehran stock exchange and software of Novin Rahavard. In order to test the hypotheses, Logistic regression and matching based on the attitude score methods were used. The results of this study revealed that attitudes of big shareholders toward divestiture influence business policies negatively. As a result, shareholders seek to eliminate obstacles of appropriate divestiture opportunities.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف اصلی پژوهش حاضر، تحلیل دیدگاه سهامداران بزرگ به عمل واگذاری بلوکی سهام برای تأمین مالی بنگاه در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران است. برای این منظور، نمونه‌ای متشکل از 102 شرکت پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران طی سال‌های 1382 تا 1391 بررسی شده است. برای آزمون این دیدگاه از روش‌های همسان‌سازی بر اساس نمره گرایش (مچینگ) و رگرسیون لاجیت استفاده می‌گردد. نتایج به دست آمده ضمن تأیید دیدگاه مثبت و معنادار برخی از سهامداران بزرگ نسبت به واگذاری، بیانگر تأثیر منفی بزرگترین سهامدار، به دلیل محدودیت در فرصت‌های واگذاری، بر سیاست‌های بنگاه است. بنابراین، در صورت وجود فرصت‌های مناسب برای واگذاری، سهامداران از هر گونه ممانعت از این فعالیت، جلوگیری می‌نمایند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساختار مالکیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">واگذاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رگرسیون لاجیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نمره گرایش</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_19885_5174430a694c1102545b61442673034e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
