<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Robust Model with Adjustable Conservatism Level for Index Fund Construction in Tehran Stock Exchange</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارائۀ یک الگوی استوار با درجۀ محافظه‌کاری تنظیم‌شدنی برای تشکیل صندوق شاخصی در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>113</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>128</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">21576</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21576</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>بحرالعلوم</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، دانشکده مدیریت وحسابداری، گروه مالی و بانکداری</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مقصود</FirstName>
					<LastName>امیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، گروه مدیریت صنعتی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>میرفیض</FirstName>
					<LastName>فلاح شمس لیالستانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامیواحد تهران مرکزی، دانشکده مدیریت، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000000179898703</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In this study, the effective strategy of financial assets allocation under uncertainty is investigated with the aim of risk reduction, cost control, transaction volume reduction and favorable return realization. In order to implement this strategy, the formation of an index fund using robust optimization framework and considering cardinality constraint became the agenda. Although asset allocation through an index fund is the basis of all new investment strategies, it is less considered in Iran’s capital market and on the other hand, its robust attribute in terms of response to uncertainty in expected return on assets has not yet been studied. Filtering the listed companies based on market capitalization to determine the composition of the portfolio and also modeling the index tracking problem as minimizing the absolute deviation between the expected return of the index fund and that of the benchmark was performed in this study. The results of the analysis imply on the selection of 20 stocks as the index fund composition and the portfolio rebalancing after three months. The results also indicate good performance of the index tracking funds based on criteria such as correlation, root mean square error and the excess return using out of sample data.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این پژوهش، استراتژی تخصیص اثربخش دارایی‌های مالی در شرایط عدم اطمینان با هدف کاهش ریسک، کنترل هزینه، کاهش حجم معاملات و تحقق بازده مطلوب مطالعه شده است. برای پیاده‌سازی این استراتژی، تشکیل صندوق شاخصی با محدودیت عدد صحیح و در چارچوب بهینه‌سازی استوار مدّنظر قرار گرفت. با وجود اینکه تخصیص منابع با یک صندوق شاخصی، اساس تمامی راهبردهای نوین سرمایه‏گذاری است، در بازار سرمایۀ ایران کمتر به آن توجه شده و نیز ویژگی استواری آن به‌لحاظ پاسخگویی به عدم قطعیت در بازده مدّنظر دارایی‏ها تاکنون مطالعه نشده است. در این پژوهش، غربال‌گری سهام شرکت‌های پذیرش‌شده در بورس برمبنای ارزش بازار برای تعیین اقلام تشکیل‌دهندۀ صندوق و الگو‌سازی مسألۀ ردیابی شاخص به‌صورت کمینه‏سازی قدر مطلق انحراف بین بازده مدّنظر صندوق و شاخص بورس انجام شده است. نتایج حاصل از تجزیه و تحلیل داده‏ها بر انتخاب 20 سهم و بروزرسانی ترکیب صندوق بعد از سه ماه دلالت دارد. همچنین محاسبات انجام‌شده بر عملکرد مناسب صندوق‌های تشکیل‌شده در ردیابی شاخص مبتنی بر معیارهایی چون همبستگی، ریشۀ دوم میانگین مربعات خطا و بازده مازاد با بهره‌گیری از داده‌های خارج از نمونه تأکید دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صندوق شاخصی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ردیابی شاخص</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بهینه‌سازی استوار</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21576_58146174faf756111d166465c0955496.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
