<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1398</YEAR>
<VOL>7</VOL>
<NO>1</NO>
<MOSALSAL>24</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>0</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>درآمدی بر قوانین و مقررات تأمین مالی در طرح‌های زیرساختی حمل‌ونقل جاد‌ه‌ای ازطریق بازار سرمایۀ ایران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Rules and Regulations of Financing Infrastructure Road Transport Projects through the Capital Market of Iran</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: در حال حاضر استفاده از ظرفیت بخش خصوصی ازطریق بازار سرمایه به‌‌منزلۀ گزینه‌ای مهم در تأمین مالی دولت و پروژه‌های زیرساخت مطرح است که خود مستلزم وجود بستر مناسبی از قوانین و مقررات است. هدف از پژوهش‌ حاضر بررسی قوانین و مقررات مربوط به تأمین مالی طرح‌های زیرساختی حمل‌ونقل جاده‌ای، به‌‌منزلۀ یکی از مهم‌ترین بخش‌های زیرساخت، ازطریق بازار سرمایه است.
روش: با بهره‌گیری از روش پژوهش‌ آمیخته، ابتدا بررسی اسناد و مصاحبه‌های نیمه‌ساختاریافته انجام شد که براساس آن پیشنهادهای اولیه تدوین شد؛ سپس برای تأیید پیشنهادها، روش دلفی یا نظرسنجی از خبرگان با استفاده از پرسش‌نامه و مصاحبه به ‌کار گرفته شد. در حوزه‌های راه، بازار سرمایه و دانشگاه 42 پرسش‌نامه تکمیل‌ و 28 جلسۀ مصاحبه و 9 جلسۀ گروهی برگزار شد که نتایج کیفی و کمی آنها با رویکرد مثلث‌سازی مقایسه شد.
نتایج: درنهایت براساس اجماع خبرگان، پیشنهادهایی مبنی بر بازنگری در نگارش برخی قوانین و مقررات ازجمله قانون تشویق و حمایت سرمایه‌گذاری خارجی برای امکان استفاده از تضمین دولت یا بانک‌ها یا شرکت‌های دولتی، قانون احداث پروژه‌های عمرانی بخش راه و ترابری ازطریق مشارکت بانک‌ها و سایر منابع پولی و مالی کشور و آیین‌نامۀ اجرایی آن برای امکان استفاده از سایر ترتیبات قراردادی، قانون توسعۀ ابزارها و نهادهای مالی جدید برای رفع ابهام در وضعیت مالیاتی بانی و قانون رفع موانع تولید رقابت‌پذیر و ارتقای نظام مالی کشور برای شمول بخش راه در کنار سایر وزرات‌خانه‌ها در معافیت‌های مالیاتی مرتبط ارائه شد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: At the time, using the capital market capacities is assumed as an important choice to raise funds for government and infrastructure projects, which needs a good provision of rules and regulations. The main objective of this research is to study the rules and regulations related to the infrastructure road transport projects financing, as an important sectors of infrastructure, through the capital market.
Method: The methodology of this study is the mixed method. First, a systematic review was done and several half-structured interviews were undertaken with experts until the primary framework was designed. To approve the primary pattern and ensure its suitability, the Delphi technique was applied using questionnaires and interviews. In the fields of roads, capital market and university, 42 questionnaires were filled, 28 interviews were carried out and 9 group meetings were held.
Results: Subsequently, the qualitative and quantitative results were compared and concluded according to the triangulation method. Finally, some changes were proposed to facilitate the financing of road projects through the capital market.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>28</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدهاشم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بت‌شکن</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Hashem</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Botshekan</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه مالی و بانکداری، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه مالی و بانکداری، دانشکدۀ مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>dr.botshekan@atu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فرشته</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رحیمی الماسی</Family>
						<NameE>Fereshteh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rahimi Almasi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانش‌آموختۀ دکترا، گروه مالی و بانکداری، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانش‌آموختۀ دکترا، گروه مالی و بانکداری،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>fereshteh.rahimi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قوانین و مقررات</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تأمین مالی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>طرح زیرساخت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>حمل‌ونقل جاده‌ای</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بازار سرمایه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>امامی، ح. (۱۳۴۰). حقوق مدنی، 6 جلد، تهران: انتشارات اسلامیه.##پژوهشکده سیاست‌گذاری دانشگاه شریف، گروه سیاست‌گذاری در توسعۀ امور زیرساختی. (1394). شناخت و آسیب‌شناسی تأمین مالی و سرمایه‌گذاری در توسعۀ صنعت حمل‌و‌نقل [گزارش]، تهران: معاونت برنامه‌ریزی و اقتصاد حمل‌و‌نقل وزارت راه و شهرسازی##ترکان،  ا. و  شهبازی،  م. (1389). بررسی چگونگی جلب مشارکت بخش خصوصی در توسعۀ زیرساخت‌های حمل‌و‌نقل جاده‌ای؛ مسائل و راهکارها، فصلنامۀ راهبرد،  276-245:(57)19.##خانه ملت (خبرگزاری مجلس شورای اسلامی). (1395). گزارش کامل استیضاح وزیر راه در صحن علنی مجلس، قابل دسترس از آدرس: http://www.icana.ir/Fa/News/324358، تاریخ دسترسی: 31 خرداد 1396##دلاور، ع. و کوشکی، ش. (1394). روش تحقیق آمیخته، تهران: نشر ویرایش.##علی‌پور،  م. (1394). سود و زیان بلندپروازی‌های چین برای اقتصاد آسیا و جهان؛ از بانک توسعه زیرساخت‌های آسیا تا احیای جاده ابریشم، اقتصاد نیوز، کدخبر: ۱۲۰۹۱۰##کاتوزیان،  ن. (1386). اموال و مالکیت، چاپ بیستم، تهران: انتشارات بنیاد حقوقی میزان.##مجلس شورای اسلامی. (1393). مطالعات تطبیقی تجربه دیگر کشورها در تأمین مالی طرح‌های عمرانی - هند (گزارش 13857)، تهران: معاونت پژوهش‌های اقتصادی.##مجلس شورای اسلامی. (1393). مطالعات تطبیقی تجربه دیگر کشورها در تأمین مالی طرح‌های عمرانی - ترکیه (گزارش 14197)، تهران: معاونت پژوهش‌های اقتصادی.##موسویان، ع.  (1386الف). کتاب ابزارهای مالی اسلامی (صکوک)، تهران: انتشارات پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و اندیشۀ اسلامی.##[1] Alipoor, M. (2010). China&#039;s adventures profits and losses for Asia and world economy; from Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank to revival of Silk Road. Eghtesadnews News Code: 120910. (in persian).##[2] Allen &amp; Overy. (2016). Dubai embraces PPP again. Available at: http://www.allenovery.com/SiteCollectionDocuments, Accessed Feb 25, 2017.##[3] Amgad, T. H. (2013). Construction and projects in Saudi Arabia: Overview. published by Practical Law Company, USA.##[4] Braun, V., &amp; Clarke, V. (2006). Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qualitative Research in Psychology. 3 (2), 77-101. ISSN 1478-0887. Available at: http://eprints.uwe.ac.uk/11735. Publisher&#039;s URL: http://dx. Doi: org/10.1191/1478088706qp063oa.##[5] Delavar, A., &amp; Kooshki, S. (2010). Mixed Research Methodology. Tehran: Virayesh. (in persian).##[6] Dharish, D. (2010). Public Choice in National Highways Financing in India: The Scope for Financial Intermediation in Enhancing Infrastructure Investment. (Doctoral Dissertation) Waseda University, Tokyo, Japan.##[7] Emami, H. (1961). Civil Law. Tehran: Eslamieh. (in persian).##[8] Gatti, S. (2015). Infrastructure: The new crossover between industry and finance, Energy Infrastructures: Towards the Creation of a European Energy Union Bocconi.##[9] Grigg, N. S. (2010). Infrastructure Finance, The Business of Infrastructure for a Sustainable Future. United States of America: Wiley.##[10] Islamic Consultative Assembly. (2014a). Comparative studies of other counties in development projects- India [report code: 13857]. Economic Research Deputy. Iran.##[11] Islamic Consultative Assembly. (2014b). Comparative studies of other counties in development projects-Turkey [report code: 14197]. Economic Research Deputy. Iran.##[12] Johnson, R. B., &amp; Onwuegbuzie, A. J. (2004). Mixed methods research: A research paradigm whose time has come. Educational Researcher, 33(7), 14-26. https://doi.org/10.3102/0013189X033007014.##[13] Katoozian, N. (2007). Properties and Ownership. Tehran: Mizan. (in persian).##[14] KPMG. (2015). Public Private Partnerships; Emerging global trends and the implications for future infrastructure development in Australia. Available at: https://assets.kpmg.com/content/dam/kpmg/pdf/2015/06/public-private-partnerships-june-2015.pdf, Accessed Jan 28 2017.##[15] Litman, T. (2014). Local funding options for public transportation, victoria transport policy institute, a summary version of this report was published as: Evaluating public transportation local funding options. Journal of Public Transportation, 17, 43-74. Doi: 250-360-1560.##[16] Mussavian, A. (2007). Islamic Financial Tools. Tehran: Publishing Organization of Institute for Islamic Culture and Thought (in persian).##[17] Namey, E., Guest, G., Thairu, L., &amp; Johnson, L. (2007). Data reduction techniques for large qualitative data sets. In Guest, G. &amp; MacQueen, K. M. (Eds.). Handbook For Team-Based Qualitative Research. United Kingdom: AltaMira Press. 137-162.##[18] OECD With the financial assistance of the European Union. (2014). Public-Private Partnerships in the Middle East and North Africa. A Handbook for Policy Makers.##[19] Pakistan Policy on Public Private Partnership. (2010). Approved by the Economic Coordination Committee (ECC) of the Cabinet. available at: http://www.ipdf.gov.pk/prod_img/PPP%20Policy%20FINAL%2014-May-2010.pdf, Accessed 30 march 2017.##[20] Public-Private Partnership Guideline. (2009). Public-Private Partnership Unit; Prime Minister Department, Malaysia, Available at: http://www.ukas.gov.my/c/document_library/get_file?uuid=02f1ea81-8075-4387-8b69-ebb2120292f1&amp;groupId=15223, Accessed March 30, 2017.##[21] Raisbeck, P. (2010). A Methodology to Assess the Performance of PPPs Compared to Other Procurement Methods in Australia, The University of Melbourne, Transformation through Construction (28th volume), Australia Transformation through Construction: Joint 2008 CIB WO65/WO55 Symposium Proceedings.##[22] Rashid, K., Farihah Hasan S., Fauzi, P., Aripin, S., &amp; Sharkawi, A. (2016). A review on the Malaysian public private partnership (PPP). Journal of Scientific Research and Development, 3 (4), 112-117. Available at: www.jsrad.org. ISSN 1115-7569.##[23] Research Institute of Policy Making at Sharif University of Technology, Group of Policy Making in Infrastructure Development. (2015). Diagnosis and pathology of finance and investment intransportation development [Report], Resource Planning and Management at Ministry of Roads and Urban Development. Islamic Republic of Iran.##[24] Rodrigue. J. (2013). The Geography of Transport System. New York USA: Hofstra University.##[25] Skulmoski, G. J., Hartman, F. T., &amp; Krahn, J. (2007). The delphi method for graduate research. Journal of Information Technology Education, 6, 1-21. https://doi.org/10.28945/199.##[26] Somerville, J. A. (2008). Effective Use of the Delphi Process in Research: Its Characteristics, Strengths and Limitations. (Unpublished Doctoral Dissertation). Oregon State University. USA.##[27] The Clearing House (tch). (2016). The Custody Services of Banks (white paper). Available at: https://www.theclearinghouse.org/./media/tch/documents/research/articles/2016/07/20160728_tch_white_paper_the_custody_services_of_banks.pdf?la=en, Accessed April 1, 2017.##[28] Torkan, A., &amp; Shahbazi, M. (2010). How to attract private sector participation in road transportation infrastructure; problems and solutions. Rahbord Quarterly. 57, 245-276. ISSN: 3102-1028. (in persian).##[29] Turkey Country Report. (2011). Transportation in Turkey, Ministry of Transportation and Cmmunication.##[30] Werneck, B., &amp; Saadi, M. (2015). The Public-Private Partnership Law Review. London: Published by Law Business Research Ltd. United Kingdom.##[31] World Bank Group. (2017). Public-Private Partnerships Laws/Concession Laws, Public-Private-Partnership in Infrastructure Resource (PPPIRC), Available from: https://ppp.worldbank.org/public-private-partnership/legislation-regulation/laws/ppp-and-concession-laws#OECD_basic_elements, Accessed 30 March 2017.##[32] http://www. Icana.ir/Fa/News/324358.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر رقابت در بازار محصول بر عملکرد مالی با تعدیل‌کنندگی کیفیت افشای اطلاعات: شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigating the Effect of Product Market Competition on Financial Performance by Moderating Role of Information Disclosure Quality: The Companies Listed in Tehran Stock Exchange</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: در دنیای پرتلاطم رقابتی امروز، کسب و حفظ مزیت رقابتی شرط بقا و عملکرد بالای شرکت‌های مختلف تولیدی و خدماتی است. در این زمینه اطلاعات افشاشده به‌‌منزلۀ بخشی از سازوکارهای کنترلی، مدیران شرکت‌ها را ترغیب می‌کند تا در مسیر منافع سهامداران و بهبود عملکرد شرکت گام بردارند. هدف از این پژوهش بررسی تأثیر رقابت در بازار محصول بر عملکرد مالی با تعدیل‌گری کیفیت افشای اطلاعات در شرکت‌‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار است.
روش: برای حصول به هدف اطلاعات مالی 117 شرکت پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران طی دورۀ زمانی 1390 تا 1395 جمع‌‌آوری شد. در این پژوهش دو متغیر نرخ بازده دارایی‌‌ها و نرخ بازده حقوق صاحبان سهام به‌‌منزلۀ شاخص‌‌های اندازه‌‌گیری عملکرد مالی در نظر گرفته شد. برای سنجش رقابت بازاری محصول، از شاخص هریشمن - هرفیندال استفاده شد.
نتایج: نتایج به‌دست‌آمده نشان می‌‌دهد رقابت در بازار محصول بر عملکرد مالی تأثیر می‌گذارد. همچنین کیفیت افشای اطلاعات رابطۀ بین رقابت در بازار محصول و عملکرد مالی را تعدیل می‌کند؛ به‌طوری ‌که با ورود متغیر تعدیل‌کننده میزان توضیح‌دهندگی متغیر وابسته توسط متغیرهای توضیحی افزایش می‌یابد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: The purpose of this research is to investigate the effect of product market competition on financial performance with moderating role of information disclosure quality. In this regard, disclosed information, as a control tool, persuades managers to move toward stockholders&#039; interests and firms&#039; competitive objectives, in today&#039;s competitive environment.
Method: For this purpose, companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange during the period from 2010 to 2015 were considered. In this research, two variables of return on assets and return on equity were considered as indicators of financial performance. The Herfindahl-Hirschman index (HHI) is used to measure product market competition.
Results:
Results: The results show that product market competition has a significant effect on financial performance. Also, the results indicate that the information disclosure quality has moderated the relationship between product market competition and financial performance, so that with the introduction of the moderating variable the effect of independent variable increases on the dependent variable.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>29</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>44</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>اکبری</Family>
						<NameE>Mohsen</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Akbari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه مدیریت، دانشکدۀ ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه گیلان، رشت، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه مدیریت، دانشکدۀ ادبیات و علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.akbari@guilan.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهسا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فرخنده</Family>
						<NameE>Mahsa</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Farkhondeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس‌ارشد، گروه مدیریت، دانشکدۀ ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه گیلان، رشت، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس‌ارشد، گروه مدیریت، دانشکدۀ ادبیات</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mahsa.farkhondeh85@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>زهرا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ایاغ</Family>
						<NameE>Zahra</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ayagh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس‌ارشد، گروه مدیریت، دانشکدۀ ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه گیلان، رشت، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس‌ارشد، گروه مدیریت، دانشکدۀ ادبیات</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>zahra.ayagh@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رقابت در بازار محصول</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عملکرد مالی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کیفیت افشای اطلاعات</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شاخص هرفیندال - هیرشمن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>بادآور نهندی، ی.؛ قادری، ص. و بهشتی نهندی، ر. (1392). تاثیر شفافیت اطلاعات حسابداری بر ناکارایی سرمایه گذاری در شرکت­های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران،  فصلنامه پژوهش­ها و سیاست­های اقتصادی، 21(68)، 65-82.##باقری، آ. (1392). تجزیه و تحلیل تاثیر ارزش برند و رقابت بازار محصول بر عملکرد مالی شرکت­ها، (پایان­نامه کارشناسی ارشد)، دانشکده اقتصاد و علوم اداری، دانشگاه اصفهان.##پورحیدری، ا.؛ سروستانی، ا. و هوشمند، ر. (1391). تاثیر رقابتی بودن بازار محصول بر هزینه‌های نمایندگی، دانش مالی تحلیل اوراق بهادار، 5(4)، 13-28.##ثقفی، ع. و ابراهیمی، ا. (1388). رابطه تدوین استانداردهای حسابداری با کیفیت اطلاعات حسابداری. بررسی‌های حسابداری و حسابرسی، 57، 33-50.##حسینی راد،  د.؛ رضایی، غ.؛ محسنی فرد، غ. و خواجوی، ش. (1392). بررسی اثرات رقابت در بازار محصول بر مدیریت سود شرکت­های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، مدیریت دارایی و تامین مالی، 1(3)، 119-134.##خدادادی، و.و آقاجری، و. (1388). ارزیابی رابطه بین ساختار مالکیت شرکت و سیاست­های سود سهام در ایران، حسابداری مالی، 1(2)، 106-126.##خدامی پور، ا. و برزایی، ی. (1392). بررسی رابطه رقابت بازار محصول با ساختار هیئت مدیره و کیفیت افشا، دانش حسابداری، 4(14)، 51-66.##رضایی دولت آبادی، ح.؛ امیری عقدایی، فه.؛ رفعت، ب.و ایزدی، ف. (1393). تاثیرپذیری رابطه ساختار سرمایه و عملکرد مالی شرکت­ها از رقابت بازار محصول و نوع استراتژی کسب­و­کار شرکت­ها، راهبرد مدیریت مالی، 2(1)، 39-58.##سپاسی، س.؛ کاظم­پور، م. و شعبانی مازوئی، م. (1396). رقابت در بازار محصول و تاثیر آن بر سه معیار در تصمیم­گیری: هزینه نمایندگی، ساختار سرمایه و هزینه سرمایه، پژوهش حسابداری، 6(4)، 67-84.##سرلک، ن. و میرزایی، ف. (1395). رابطه رقابت در بازار و سیاست تقسیم سود، مدیریت دارایی و تامین مالی، 4(4)، 45-60.##طوروسیان، آ. (1390). بررسی تاثیر رقابت بازار محصول بر ساختار سرمایه شرکت­های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، (پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد)، دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصاد، دانشگاه اصفهان.##عباس زاده، م. (1393). رقابت محصول و معیارهای مختلف کیفیت سود مبتنی بر اصول فعالیت بازار، سومین کنفرانس ملی حسابداری و مدیریت، تهران.##قاسمیه، ر.؛ غیوری مقدم. ع. و حاجب، ح. (1393). بررسی تاثیر رقابت بازار محصول بر رابطه بین ساختار سرمایه و عملکرد واحد تجاری، پیشرفت­های حسابداری، 6(2)، 107-129.##قربانی، س.؛ موحد مجد، م.و منفرد مهارلویی، م. (1392). رقابت در بازار محصول، ترکیب هیئت مدیره و کیفیت افشای اطلاعات: شواهدی از بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، تحقیقات حسابداری و حسابرسی، 4(92)، 92-105.##نمازی، م.و رضایی، غ. (1393). رقابت در بازار محصول و کیفیت اطلاعات حسابداری، پیشرفت­های حسابداری، 6(2)، 131-166.##[1] Abbas Zadeh, M. (2014). Product market competition and different indexes market based earning quality, The Third National Conference Accounting and Management, Tehran. (In Persian).##[2] Abdoh H., &amp; Varela, O. (2017). Product market competition, idiosyncratic and systematic volatility. Journal of Corporate Finance, 43, 500-513. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcorpfin.2017.02.009.##[3] Allen, F., &amp; Gale, D. (2000). Corporate Governance: Theoretical and EmpiricalPerspectives.Cambridge: CambridgeUniversity.##[4] Badavarnahandi, Y., Ghaderi, S. &amp; Beheshtinahandi, R. (2013). The impact of accounting information accounting information disclosure on inefficiency investment. Journal of Economic Policies &amp; Researches, 21(6), 65-82.(In Persian). DOI: 10.1109/ICMTMA.2013.287.##[5] Bagheri, A. (2013). Analysis Effect of Brand Value and Product Market Competition on Firms Financial Performance. (Master Thesis), Faculty of Economics and Administrative Sciences, Esfahan University.(In Persian).##[6] Brockman, P., &amp; Unlu, E. (2011). Earned contributed capital, dividend policy and disclosure quality: An international study. Journal of Banking and Finance, 35, 1610-1625. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1016/ j.jbankfin.2010.11.014.##[7] Caves, R. (1980). Industrial organization, corporate strategy and structure. Journal of Economic Literature, 18, 64-92. DOI: https://www.jstor.org/stable/2723892.##[8] Chen, C., Li, L., &amp; Mary, L. Z. M. (2014). Product market competition and the cost of equity capital: Evidence from China. Asia-Pacific Journal of Accounting &amp; Economics. 21(3), 227-261. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1080/16081625.2014.893197.##[9] Cheng, P., Man, P., &amp; Yi, C. H. (2013). The impact of product market competition on earnings quality. Accounting and Finance, 53, 137-162. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-629X. 2011. 00457.x.##[10] Fama, E. F., &amp; French, K. R. (1992). The cross‐section of expected stock returns. Journal of Finance, 47(2), 427-465. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-6261.1992.tb04398.x.##[11] Fosu, S. (2013). Capital structure, product market competition and firm performance: Evidence from South Africa. The Quarterly Review of Economics and Finance, 53(2), 140–151. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1016/ j.qref.2013.02.004.##[12] Ghasemiyeh, R., Ghayori Moghadam, A., &amp; Hajeb, H. (2014). The effect of competition in product market on the degree of relationship between capital structure and business enterprise performance. Journal of Accounting Advances, 6(2), 107-129. (In Persian)DOI: 10.22099/jaa.2015.2857.##[13] Ghorbani, S., Movahed, M., &amp; Monfared Maharluyi, M. (2013). Product market competition, board combination and disclosure quality: Tehran Stock Exchange. Auditing and Accounting, 4(19), 92-105. (In Persian). DOI: http://discovery.ucl.ac.uk/ id/eprint/3840.##[14] Griffith, R. (2001). Product market competition, efficiency and agency cost: An empirical analysis. Working Paper and Institute for Fiscal Studies. DOI: https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/99d1/18eb80a8ddf14701d2e1b2d0f067f8ffd782.##[15] Hosseini Rad, S. D., Rezaee, G., Mohsenifard, G., &amp; Khajavi, S. (2013). The impact of product market competition on earning management of the companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. Asset Management &amp; Financing, 1(3), 119-134. (In Persian)DOI:http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_19853.html.##[16] Khodadadi, V., &amp; Aghajari, V. (2009). Investigating the relationship between ownership structure and company dividend policies in Iran. Financial Accounting, 1, 106-126. DOI: https://www.sid.ir/fa/journal/ViewPaper.aspx?id=113718.##[17] KhodamiPour, A., &amp; Bazri, Y. (2013). Investigation on the relationship between product market competition with board structure and disclosure quality. Journal of Accounting Knowledge, 4(14), 51-66. (In Persian). DOI: 10.22103/jak.2013.603.##[18] Li, X. (2010). The impact of product market competition on the quantity and quality of voluntary disclosure. Review of Accounting studies, 15, 663-711. DOI: 10.1007/s11142-010-9129-0.##[19] Lin, C., &amp; Wei, L. (2014). Product market competition and firms’ voluntary disclosure behavior: Evidence from a quasi-natural experiment. Working Paper.DOI:sfm.finance.nsysu.edu.tw/php/Papers/CompletePaper/042-485019745.##[20] Modigliani, F., &amp; Miller M. H. (1958). The cost of capital, corporation finance and the theory of investment. American Economic Review, 48, 261-297. DOI: http://www.jstor.org/stable/1809766.##[21] Musyoka, M. (2017). Effect of voluntary disclosure on financial performance of firms listed at Nairobi securities exchange. (Master&#039;s Thesis), in the School of Business and public Management at kca University.##[22] Namazi, M., Rezaei, G., &amp; Momtazian, A. (2014). Product market competition and accounting information quality. Journal of Accounting Advances, 6(2), 131-166. (In Persian). DOI: 10.22099/jaa.2015.2858.##[23] Nickell, S. (1996). Competition and corporate performance. Journal of Political Economy, 104, 724-746. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1086/262040.##[24] Ojeka, S., Mukoro, D., &amp; Kanu, C. (2015). Does financial reporting disclosures enhance firm financial performance in the Nigerian manufacturing companies? Mediterranean Journal of Social Sciences, 6(6), 338-332. DOI: 10.5901/mjss.2015. v6n6p332.##[25] Pourheidari, O., Sarvestani, A., &amp; Hooshmand, R. (2012). The effects of product market competition on agency costs, Financial Knowledge of Securities Analysis, 5(4), 13-28. (In Persian). DOI: http://jfksa.srbiau.ac.ir/article_3031.html.##[26] Raith, M. (2003). Competition, risk and managerial incentives. The American Economic Review, 93(4), 1425-1436. DOI: https://ssrn.com/abstract=486262.## [27] Rezaeidolatabadi, H., Amiriaghayi, S.F., Rafat, B., &amp; Izadi, F. (2014). The impacts of product market competition and business strategy on the relationship between capital structure and financial performance of the companies. Journal of financial management strategy, 2(1), 39-58. (In Persian). DOI: 10.22051/jfm.2015.975.##[28] Saghafi, A., &amp; Ebrahimi, E. (2008). The association of accounting standard setting with accounting information quality. Journal of the Accounting and Auditing Review, 57, 33-50. (In Persian). DOI: https://acctgrev.ut.ac.ir/article_20398.html.##[29] Sarlak, N., &amp; Mirzaie, F. (2016). The relation between market competition and dividend policies. Asset Management &amp; Financing, 4(4), 45-60. (In Persian). DOI:10.22108/amf.2016.21111.##[30] Sepassi, S., Kazempour, M., &amp; Shabanimazoei, M. (2017). Product market competition and its effect on three important criteria in decision making, agency cost, capital structure and the cost of capital. Journal of Accounting Research, 6(4), 67-84. (In Persian). DOI:10.22051/ijar. 2017.7722.1028.##[31] Shleifer, A., &amp; Vishny, R. (1997). A survey of corporate governance. Journal of Finance, 52, 737-783. DOI: https://doi.org/ 10.1111/j.1540-6261.1997.tb04820.x.##[32] Soleymankhan, A., &amp; Pourzamani, Z. (2017). Comparison the effect of competition risk in product market on relationship between cash holding level in firms with and without constraints in financing based on KZ index. Journal of Management System, 6(22), 53-62. (In Persian). DOI: http://jmaak.srbiau.ac.ir/ article_10801.html.##[33] Symeonidis, G. (2017). Does product market competition increase strike activity? Evidence from the UK. European Economic Review, 97, 42-56. DOI: https://doi.org/ 10.1016/j.euroecorev.2017.05.008.##[34] Teng, M., &amp; Li, C. (2011). Product market competition, board structure and disclosure quality. Frontiers of Business Research in China, 5 (2), 291-316. DOI: https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11782-011-0132-5.##[35] Turoosiyan, A. (2009). Investigating the effect of product market competition on capital structure of the companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. (Master thesis), Faculty of Economics and Administrative Sciences, Esfahan University.(In Persian)##[36] Valizade Larijani, A., Hejazi, R., &amp; Mojtahedzadeh, V. (2013). The effect of disclosure quality the value relevance of financial statements items. Asset Management &amp; Financing, 1(1), 13-26. (In Persian). DOI: http://amf.ui.ac.ir/ article_19830.html.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تأثیر پاداش‌های قراردادی بر سپرده‌های بدون سررسید مشخص و تأمین مالی باثبات در بانک مطالعۀ موردی: بانک ملت</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The effect of Contractual Rewards on Non-Maturing Deposits and Bank Funding Stability (Case Study: Bank Mellat)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>تأمین مالی بانک‌‌ها در ایران چهار مسیر عمده دارد: سپرده‌ها، سرمایه، بدهی به بانک مرکزی یا سایر بانک‌ها و سپرده‌گذاری که یکی از منابع اصلی تأمین مالی است. در سال‌‌های اخیر گرایش مشتریان به سپرده‌‌های بدون سررسید مشخص که هر زمان قابل‌برداشت است، مشکلاتی را برای بانک‌ها و مؤسسه‌های مالی ایجاد کرده است. این پژوهش تأثیر پاداش‌‌های قراردادی بر رفتار 107/24 نفر از سپرده‌گذاران را - شامل 924/10 سپرده‌گذار ویژۀ بانک ملت که پاداش دریافت کرده‌اند و 183/13 سپرده‌گذار عادی این بانک که از این پاداش‌ها برخوردار نشده‌‌اند - از سال 1389 تا 1394 بررسی کرده است. بیشتر پژوهش‌های انجام‌شده در این حوزه، سود بانکی و تأثیر آن بر سپرده‌گذاران را بررسی کرده است. در این پژوهش پاداش‌‌های قراردادی شامل بیمه و کارت بانکی ویژه به‌استثنای سود سپرده است و اثر این پاداش‌‌ها بر طول دورۀ سپرده‌‌گذاری و نوسانات سپرده به‌منزلۀ عوامل تأمین مالی باثبات بررسی شده است. نتایج پژوهش نشان می‌‌دهد پاداش‌‌های قراردادی سبب افزایش ثبات تأمین مالی در بانک شده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>There are four main sources for bank funding in Iran, including deposits, capital, borrowing from the Central Bank, and borrowing from other banks. Of all these sources, deposits are the main source of bank funding. During recent years, customers’ orientation to non-maturing deposits, possible to be withdrawn at any time by customers, has triggered a lot of problems for banks and financial institutions. This study examines the effect of contractual rewards on the behavior of 24107 depositors of the Mellat Bank, consisting of two groups of depositors as a sample, 10924 premier customers who received contractual rewards and 13183 normal customers who didn’t receive contractual rewards from 2010 to 2015. Most studies in this area have been encompassed on the interest rate and its effect on depositors. In this research, however, the effect of Contractual rewards on saving duration and cash inflow volatility, as two factors of bank funding stability, is considered. By definition, Contractual rewards involve special card and insurance, without interest of deposits. In conclusion, the results reveal that contractual rewards increase financial stability.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>45</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>62</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>تهرانی</Family>
						<NameE>Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Tehrani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه مدیریت مالی و بیمه؛ دانشکده مدیریت؛ دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه مدیریت مالی و بیمه؛ دانشکده مدیریت؛</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>rtehrani@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید مجتبی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>میرلوحی</Family>
						<NameE>Seyed Mojtaba</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mirlohi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه مالی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه شاهرود. ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه مالی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mirlohism@shahroodut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مهرآرا</Family>
						<NameE>Mohsen</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mehrara</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد اقتصاد، دانشکده اقتصاد، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد اقتصاد، دانشکده اقتصاد، دانشگاه تهران،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mmehrara@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مجید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>لطفی قهرود</Family>
						<NameE>Majid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Lotfi Ghahroud</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری،‌ ﮔﺮوه علوم اجتماعی و رفتاری، مدیریت مالی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، پردیس بین‌الملل کیش دانشگاه تهران، کیش‌، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری،‌ ﮔﺮوه علوم اجتماعی و رفتاری،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>majidlotfi@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تأمین مالی باثبات</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رفتار سپرده‌گذاران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سپردۀ بدون سررسید مشخص</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>ابزری، م. و درخشیده، ح. (1392). تاثیر شفاف سازی اطلاعات مالی بر رفتار سرمایه گذاران در بورس اوراق بهادار، فصلنامه علمی و پژوهشی تحقیقات مالی، 11: 59-75.##احمدیان، ا. (1394). مدلسازی هجوم بانکی در چارچوب مدل تعادل عمومی پویای تصادفی برای ایران، مجله علمی- پژوهشی سیاستگذاری اقتصادی، (14)7: 77-103.##احمدیان، ا. و کیانوند، م. (1391). اثر سیاست پولی بر قدرت تامین مالی بخش تولید توسط بانکها، فصلنامه پژوهش های پولی و بانکی، 9:27-50.##احمدیان، ا. و کیانوند، م. (1394). تحلیل نقش بانک مرکزی در کاهش احتمال رخداد ریسک نقدینگی در شبکه بانکی کشور، فصلنامه پژوهش های پولی و بانکی، 13:57-94..##اژدهاکش پور، ر. و سلطانی، ح. (1393). «مالی رفتاری»، انتشارات رازنهان، تهران.##اسلامی بیدگلی، غ. و کردلـویی، ح. (1389). مـالی رفتـاری، مرحلـه ای گذر از مالی استاندارد تـا نوروفاینـانس، فصـلنامه علمـی – پژوهشـی مهندسـی مـالی و مدیریت پرتفوی، 19-36: 1(1).##بابایی، ا. (1380). بررسی عوامل موثر بر مانده سپرده‌های بانک‌های تجاری با تاکید بر سپرده‌های بانک ملی ایران، نشریه پژوهش‌های اقتصادی، 159-184: 2.##بهشتی، س. (1385). مطالعه عوامل موثر بر بهبود مدیریت سپرده و حفظ سپرده های بانک ( مطالعه موردی، اصفهان)، مجله مدیریت استراتژیک دانشگاه آزاد، 119-129: 36.##جعفری، ا. و دولتی، ن. (1386). مقدمه ای بر مالی و اقتصاد رفتـاری، ماهنامـه بورس، 10-17: 68.##حقیقی، م. و مومنی نژاد، ن. (1395). تحلیل و رتبه‌بندی روش‌های تأمین مالی بانک‌ها با استفاده از ابزارهای تأمین مالی بازار سرمایه؛ با رویکرد تحلیل سلسله مراتبی، فصلنامه علمی _ترویجی اقتصاد و بانکداری اسلامی، 77-96: 17.##خواجــوی، ش. و قاســمی، م.  (1385). فرضــیه بــازار کــارا و مــالی رفتــاری، دوفصلنامه پژوهش ها مالی، 49-69: 20. خوش طینت، م. و نادی قمی، و. (1388). چارچوب رابطه رفتار اطمینان بیش از حد سرمایه گذاران با بازده سهام، مجله مطالعات تجربی حسابداری مالی، 198-214: (25)2. وکیلی فرد، ح.؛ فروغ نژاد، ح. و خوشنود، م. (1392). ارزیابی رفتارهای سرمایه گذاران در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران با روش فرایند تحلیل شبکه ای، نشریه مدیریت دارایی و تامین مالی، 34-19: (2)1.##دارابی، ر. (1394). ابعاد و رویکردهای نظریه مالی رفتاری، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی، پرتال جامع منابع انسانی.##رهنمای رودپشتی، ف. و زندیه، و. (1391). مالی رفتاری و مالی عصبی (پارادایم نوین مالی) از تئوری تا عمل، تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی.##عبده تبریزی، ح. و رادپور، م. (1391). جایگاه بازار سرمایه و نقش آن در تعامل با صنعت بانکداری، نخستین کنفرانس بین المللی صنعت بانکداری و اقتصاد جهانی.##فلاح پور، س. و عبـداللهی، غ. (1390). شناسـایی و وزن دهـی تـورش هـای رفتاری سرمایه گذاران در بازار بورس اوراق بهادار تهران : رویکرد AHP فازی، دوفصلنامه ی پژوهش ها مالی، 99: (31)13.##گرجی زاده، د. و خانمحمدی، م. (1396). بررسی اثرات عوامل مالی رفتاری بر تصمیمات سرمایه گذاران انفرادی، مجله دانش سرمایه گذاری، 275-292: 24.##References##[1] Abedifar, P., Hasan, I., &amp; Tarazi, A. (2016). Finance-Growth nexus and dual banking system: Relative importance of islamic banks. Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization, 132, 198-215. (in Persian).##[2] Abdeh Tabrizi, H., &amp; Radpoor, M. (2011). the position of the capital market and its role in interacting with the banking industry. International conference on banking and the world economy, Third Conference, Tehran, Iran. (in Persian).##[3] Abzari, M., &amp; Derakhshideh, H. (2013). the effect of transparency of financial information on investors’ behavior in Isfahan Stock Exchange. Journal of Financial Research, 11, 59-75. (in Persian).##[4] Ahmadian, A. (2015). Modeling of bank invasion in framework of dynamic random equilibrium model for Iran. Journal of Economic Policy, 14, 77-103. (in Persian).##[5] Ahmadian, A., &amp; Kianvand, M. (2012). Effect of monetary policy on the power of financing Production sector by banks. Journal of Monetary and Banking, 9, 27-50. (in Persian).##[6] Ahmadian, A., &amp; Kianvand, M. (2015). Analyze the role of central bank in decrease of probability of liquidity risk in banks of Iran. Journal of Monetary and Banking, 13, 57-94. (in Persian).##[7] Amidu, M. (2013). the effects of the structure of banking market and funding strategy on risk and return. International Review of Financial Analysis, 28, 143-155. DOI: 10.1016/j.irfa.2013.03.001.##[8] Arkes, H. R., Hirshleifer, D., Danling, J., &amp; Lim, S. (2008). Reference point adaptation: Tests in the domain of security trading, organization behavior and human decision processes. Journal of Organizational Behavior, 105, 67-81.##[9] Babaei, E. (2008). the study of the factors affecting deposits of commercial banks (case study: Melli Bank). Journal of Economic Researches, 2, 159-184. (in persian).##[10] Baker, K., &amp; Riccardi, V. (2014). Investment Behavior. Canada:Wiley.##[11] Basel Committee. (2011). Basel III: A global regulatory framework for more resilient banks and banking systems. Bank for international settlements.##[12] Beheshti, S. (2005). the study of effective factors on improvement of deposit management and maintain of bank deposits (case study: Isfahan). Journal of Strategic Management of Azad University, 36, 119-129. (in Persian).##[13] Bengtsson, E. (2013). Shadow banking and financial stability: European money market funds in the global financial crisis. Journal of International Money and Finance, 32, 579-594. DOI: 10.1016/j.jimonfin.2012. 05.027.##[14] Breuer, W., &amp; Perst, A. (2007). Retail banking and behavioral financial engineering: the case of structured products. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, 31 (3), 827-844. ISSN 0378-4266. Doi: 10.1016/j. jbankfin.2006.06.011.##[15] Craig, B. R., &amp; Dinger, V. (2013). Deposit market competition, wholesale funding and bank risk. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, 37 (9), 3605-3622. DOI: 10.1016/j.jbankfin.2013.05.010.##[16] Darabi, R. (2015). Dimensions and approaches of behavioral finance. Journal of Human Resource, 34, 78-85. (in Persian).##[17] Ejdehakosh, R., &amp; Soltani, H. (2014). Behavioral Finance. Tehran: Razenahan. (in Persian).##[18] Eslami Bidgoli, G., &amp; Kordloei, H. (2011). Behavioral finance, the process of pass through financial standard to neuro finance. Journal of Financial Engineering and Portfolio Management, 1, 19-36. (in Persian).##[19] Fallahpour, S., &amp; Abdollahi, G. (2011). Identification and weighting behavioral biases of investors in Tehran Stock Market. Journal of Financial Research, 31, 99-120. (in Persian).##[20] Fathi, S., Konjkave Monfared, A. R., &amp; Ranjbarian, B. (2016). Role of psychological factors and awareness on the intention to invest with emphasis on the mediate role of perceived risk of customers of investment services. Financial Knowledge of Security Analysis, 9 (30),##1-15. (in Persian).##[21] Flynn, S. (2008). Behavioral finance. Journal of Research Starters Business, 1, 1-13.##[22] Gorji zade, D., &amp; khanmohammadi, M. (2017). Investigating the effects of behavioral finance factors on individual investors&#039; decisions. Journal of Management System, 24, 275-292. (in Persian).##[23] Haghighi, M., &amp; Momeni Nejad, N. (2016). Analyzing and ranking of banks&#039; financing methods using capital market financing derivatives with hierarchical analysis approach. Journal of Economy and Islamic Banking, 17, 77-96. (in persian).##[24] Jafari, A., &amp; Dolati, N. (2007). Introduction of behavioral finance and behavioral economy. Journal of Bourse, 69, 10-17. (in persian).##[25] Jalilvand, A. (2009). Sequence of Asset Bubbles and the Global Financial Crisis, Lessons from the Financial Crisis: Insights and Analysis from Today&#039;s Leading Minds. United Stated of America: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc. (in persian).##[26] Khajavi, S., &amp; Ghasemi, M. (2007). Effective market and behavioral finance hypothesis. Journal of Financial Research, 20, 49-69. (in persian).##[27] Khosh Tinat, M., &amp; Nadi Ghomi, V. (2010). the framework of relation of investors overconfidence behavior with stock return. Journal of Empirical Studies in Financial Accounting, 2 (25), 198-214. (in persian).##[28] Pompian, M. (2006). Behavioral Finance and Wealth Management. Translated by: Ahmad Badri. Tehran: Keyhan.##[29] Rahnamay Roodposhti, F., &amp; Zandieh, V. (2011). Behavioral Finance and Neuro Finance (New Paradigm in Finance). Tehran: Azad University. (in Persian).##[30] Rodriguez, I., J. Kiss, H., &amp; Garcia, A. (2018). Panic bank runs. Economics Letters, 162, 146-149. https://doi.org/10.1016/ j.econlet.2017.11.014.##[31] Schlueter, T., &amp; Sievers, S. Wendels, T. H. (2015). Bank funding stability, pricing strategies and the guidance of depositors. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, 51, 43-61. ISSN 0378-4266. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/ j.jbankfin.2014.10.007.##[32] Shahchera, M. (2016). Deposit funding and loan volatility in iranian banking system. Iranian Journal of Economic Studies, 5 (2), 223-234.##[33] Shahmiri, A. (2014). Study of effective factors on deposits and forcasting deposits byartificial neural networks. Journal of Money and Banking Research, 15, 25-30. (in persian).##[34] Taleblo, R. (2011). the analysis of banking regulation on competition in iranian banking industry. Journal of Financial Knowledge of Securities Analysis, 5, 13-40. (in persian).##[35] Uysal, P., Gerlach, J. R., &amp; Mora, N. (2018). Bank funding costs in a rising interest rate environment. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, 87, 164-186. DOI: 10.1016/j.jbankfin.2017.09.011.##[36] Vakilifard, H., Foroughnejad, H., &amp; Khoshnood, M. (2013). Evaluation investor&#039;s behavior in Tehran Stock Exchange with analytic network process (ANP). Journal of Asset Management and Financing, 1 (2) , 19-34. (in persian).##[37] Vazquez, F., &amp; Federico, P. (2015). Bank funding structures and risk: Evidence from the global financial crisis. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, 61, 1-14.##[38] Xuan, V. O. (2018). Bank lending behavior in emerging markets. Journal of Finance Research Letters, 27, 129-134. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.frl.2018.02.011.##[39] Zakrajšek, E., English, W. B., &amp; Van Den Heuvel, S. J. (2018). Interest rate risk and bank equity valuations. Journal of Monetary Economics, 98, 80-97. DOI: 10.1016/j.jmoneco.2018.04.010.##[40] https://www.cbi.ir/##[41] http://tse.ir##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی درون‌زائی و برون‏زائی مالکیت و خط‌مشی تقسیم سود: شواهدی از بورس اوراق بهادار تهران (بررسی مقایسه‌ای تخمین‌زن‏های GMM، PSM، OLS)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Endogenous and Exogenous Relationship between Ownership and Dividend Policy: Evidence from Tehran Stock Exchange Using OLS, PSM, GMM Estimators</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: در این مطالعه جنبۀ‏ جدیدی از رابطۀ مالکیت (رابطۀ ‏درون‏زا و برون‏زا) و خطی‌مشی تقسیم سود بررسی شده است. منظور از مالکیت در این پژوهش، مالکیت متمرکز نهادی و شرکتی است.
روش: در راستای هدف فوق از داده‌های2080 سال - شرکت در فاصلۀ‏ زمانی 1382 تا 1394 استفاده شده است (دورۀ پژوهش 13 سال و هر سال 160 شرکت است). متغیر مالکیت یک‌بار به‌صورت برون‌زا و یک‌بار به‌صورت درون‌زا، در نظر گرفته شده است. داده‌ها به ‌روش‏های OLS، PSM و GMM تحلیل شده‌ است.
نتایج: در به‌کارگیری OLS و PSM، متغیرهای سرمایه‌گذاران نهادی و شرکتی به‌ترتیب اثر معنادار مثبت و منفی بر تقسیم سود داشت. در GMM فقط متغیر سرمایه‌گذاران نهادی، اثر معنادار مثبتی بر تقسیم سود داشت. درنهایت اینکه استفاده از روش PSM و همسان‌سازی داده‌ها، نقش بسزایی در بهبود رگرسیون دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: In this study, a new aspect of the relationship between ownership (The endogenous and exogenous) and dividend policy has been investigated.
Method: For this purpose, data of 2080 firm-year were gathered in the period 2002 to 2016. The effect of ownership variable on dividend policy was firstly estimated as exogenous and endogenous as second. For the statistical analysis, the results were analyzed via R Software by using ordinary panel data, PSM and GMM. In both methods (OLS and PSM), the pooled logistic regression and panel logistic model model was fitted and Akaike&#039;s information criterion (AIC) were used for comparing the methods.
Results: It was observed that the p-value of institutional investors (INS) and corporate investors (CORP) is less than 0.05, so these two variables have a significant effect on the variable dividend policy in the ordinary panel data and PSM. But in the GMM, there was a significant relationship between institutional ownership and dividend policy while no significant relationship between corporate ownership and dividend policy was observed. Finally, using PSM and matching of data in comparison with the other estimators can have a significant role in improving the fitted regression and its results are more significant and will lead to more accurate estimates.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>63</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>82</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فیل سرائی</Family>
						<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Filsaraei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم انسانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، خوراسگان (اصفهان)، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>filsaraei@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>زارعی</Family>
						<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Zarei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم انسانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، خوراسگان (اصفهان)، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم انسانی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>f8545091@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سیاست تقسیم سود</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>درون‏زائی مالکیت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>همسان‌سازی براساس نمرۀ گرایش (PSM)</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>روش گشتاورهای تعمیم‌یافته (GMM)</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>منابع فارسی##آقایی، م. و احمدیان، و. (1392). بررسی تاثیر نوع بزرگ ترین سهامدار بر سیاست های تقسیم سود شرکت های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی، 1 (3)، 66-49.##اسلامی بیدگلی، غ. (1370). مروری بر تئوری ها، سیاست ها و خط مشی تقسیم سود (1)، دانش مدیریت، 14، 29-14.##اعتمادی، ح. و انواری رستمی، ع. و احمدیان، و. (1393). آزمون نظریه های اصلی تقسیم سود با تأکید بر نقش سهامداران نهادی در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، پژوهشهایحسابداریمالی، 6 (3)، 20-1.##بنی مهد، ب. و اصغری، ع. (1390). بررسی اثر اهرم شرکت بر سیاست تقسیم سود شرکت های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، مجلهدانشمالی تحلیلاوراقبهادار، 4: (2)10، 18-1.##جهانخانی، ع. و قربانی، س. (1384). شناسایی و تبیین عوامل تعیین کننده سیاست تقسیم سود شرکتهای پذیرفته شده در سازمان بورس اوارق بهادار تهران، فصلنامهتحقیقاتمالی، 7 (2)، 48-27.##دموری، د. و دهقانی فیروزآبادی، ا. (1393). بررسی ارتباط بین عدم تقارن اطلاعاتی و سیاست تقسیم سود با به کارگیری مدل لاجیت. فصلنامه راهبردمدیریتمالی، 2 (1)، 38-21.##رجبی، ر.؛ آقاجانی، م. و اصلانی، ز. (1392). بررسی رابطه بین مکانیزم های نظام راهبری شرکت ها و سیاست های تقسیم سود در شرکت های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، فصلنامه تحقیقات حسابداری و حسابرسی، 5 (19)، 143-132.##ستایش، م. و کاظم نژاد، م. (1389). بررسی تأثیر ساختار مالکیت و ترکیب هیئت مدیره بر سیاست تقسیم سود شرکتهای پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، مجلهدانشحسابداری، 1 (1)، 51-29.##سوری، ع. (1392). اقتصاد سنجی (پیشرفته)، همراه با کاربرد Eviews8 و Stata12، تهران: نشر فرهنگ شناسی.##قالیباف اصل، ح. و بابالویان، ش. (1393). مدیریت مالی پیشرفته، چاپ نخست، انتشارت دانشگاه الزهرا (ناشر مشترک: انتشارات بورس).##مشایخ، ش. و عبداللهی، م. (1390). بررسی رابطه بین تمرکز مالکیت، عملکرد شرکت و سیاست تقسیم سود در شرکتهای پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، مجلهپژوهشهایحسابداریمالی، 3 (4)، 86-71.## References##[1] Aghaei, M. A., Ahmadian, V. (2013). Largest shareholder type and its effect on dividend policy in listed companies in Tehran Stock Exchange, Asset Management and Financing, 1(3): 49-66. (in pershian).##[2] Agresti, A. (2015). Foundations of Linear and Generalized Linear Models. New York, United Stetes:Wiley Series in Probability and Statistics.##[3] Ahmadian, V. (2014). Main dividend theories test stressing the role of institutional shareholders in Tehran Stock Exchange, Journal of Financial Accounting Researches, 6(3): 1-20.##[4] Al-Najjar, B., Kilincarslan, E. (2016). The effect of ownership structure on dividend policy: Evidence from Turkey, Corporate Governance, 16(1): 135–161.##[5] Balachandran, B., Khan, A., Mather, P., &amp; Theobald, M. (2017). Insider ownership and dividend policy in an imputation tax environment, Journal of Corporate Finance, In Press, Corrected Proof. https://www.sciencedirect.com/search?authors=Balachandran%2C&amp;pub=Journal%20of%20Corporate%20Finance&amp;show=25&amp;sortBy=relevance&amp;origin=jrnl_issue&amp;zone=search&amp;publicationTitles=271687.##[6] Banimahd, B., Asghari, A. (2011). An investigation of leverage effect on dividend policy in companies listed on the Tehran Stock Exchange, Quarterly Financial Knowledge of Security Analysis (Financial Studies), 4(10): 1-18. (in pershian).##[7] Björn, L., Lantz C. E. (2016). Ownership Structure&#039;s Effect on Dividend Policy: Evidence From Publicly Listed Swedish Firms. Master thesis. Umeå School of Business and Economics (USBE). Sweden: Umeå University, Faculty of Social Sciences.##[8] Bremberger, F., Cambini, C., Gugler, K. P., &amp; Rondi, L. (2013). Dividend policy in regulated firms, University Library of Munich, Germany, Available at SSRN: http://ssrn.com/abstract =2277595 orhttp://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.2277595.##[9] Chaabouni, I. (2017). Impact of dividend announcement on stock return: a study on listed companies in the Saudi Arabia financial markets, International Journal of Information, Business and Management, 9(1): 37-52.##[10] Clarke, R. M. (2012). The effect of substantial holdings on capital structure and dividend policy, Master thesis: The University of Western Australia.##[11] Crane, A. D., Michenaud, S., &amp; Weston, J. P. (2012). The effect of institutional ownership on payout policy: A regression discontinuity design approach. SSRN Electronic Journal, 12: 1-45.##[12] Damoori, D., Dehghani Firouzabadi, A. (2014). Examining the relationship between information asymmetry and dividend policy by using logit model. Journal of Financial Management Strategy, 2(1): 21-38.##[13] De Jong, A., DeJong, D. V., Hege, U., &amp; Mertens, G. (2013). Blockholders and leverage: When debt leads to higher dividends (April 4, 2013). ECGI - Finance Working Paper No. 261/2009. Available at SSRN: http://ssrn.com/abstract=1461492.##[14] Demsetz, H., Lehn, K. (1985). The structure of corporate ownership: Causes and consequences, Journal of Political Economy, 93(2): 1155-1177.##[15] Desai, M. A., Jin, L. (2011). Institutional tax clienteles and payout policy, Journal of Financial Economics 100: 68–84. Available at: http://www.sciencedirect.com /science/article/pii /S0304405 X10002497.##[16] Elston, J. A., Hofler, R., &amp; Lee, J. (2011). Dividend policy and institutional ownership: Empirical evidence using a propensity score matching estimator, Journal of Accounting and Finance, 11(3): 89-102.##[17] EslamiBidgoli, GH. (2002). An overview of the dividend theories and policies, Knowledge Management, 25(14): 14-29. (in pershian).##[18] Fischer, B. (1976). The Dividend Puzzle, Journal of Portfolio Management, 2(3): 5-8.##[19] Ghalibaf Asl, H., Babaloyan, S. (2014). Advanced Financial Management, Alzahra University: Securities Publications. (in pershian).##[20] Gonzalez, M., Molina, C. A., Pablo, E., &amp; Rosso, J. W. (2017). The effect of ownership concentration and composition on dividends: Evidence from Latin America, Emerging Markets Review, 30(4): 1–18.##[21] Gusni, T. (2016), Dividend policy, corporate governance mechnism, profitability, systematic risk, and firm size: A panel data analysis, 4th Gadjah Mada International Conference on Economics and Business, 2016, Fakultas Ekonomi &amp; Bisnis Universitas Gadjah Mada, 1-14.##[22] Harada, K., Nguyen, P. (2011). Ownership concentration and dividend policy in Japan, Managerial Finance, 37(4): 362-379.##[23] Himmelberg, C. P., Hubbard, R. G., &amp; Love, I. (2004). Investor protection, ownership, and the cost of capital, World Bank Policy Research Working Paper No: 2834. Available at SSRN: http://ssrn.com/abstract=303969.##[24] Jahankhani, A., Ghorbani, S. (2006). Identifying and understanding the determinants of dividend policy of companies listed on the Tehran Stock Exchange, Journal of Financial Research, 7(2): 27-48. (in pershian).##[25] Jensen, M., Meckling, W. (1976). Theory of the firm: Managerial behavior, agency costs, and ownership structure, Journal of Financial Economics, 48: 831-880.##[26] Kutner, M. H., Nachtsheim, C. J., Neter, J., &amp; Li, W. (2005). Applied Linear Statistical Models, New York Sanfrancisco: The McGraw·HiII Companies.##[27] Mashayekh, S., Abdollahi, M. (2012). Investigating the relation between ownership concentration, firm performanceand dividend policy in the companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange, Journal of Financial Accounting Research, 4 (10): 71-86. (in pershian).##[28] Pan, R., Shi, J., &amp; Zhu, Q. (2015). Dividend policy, corporate governance and stock liquidity. Asian Finance Association (AsianFA) 2015 Conference Paper. Available at SSRN: http://ssrn.com/abstract = 2570868 or http://dx.doi.org/ 10.2139/ ssrn.2570868.##[29] Rajabi, R., Aghajani, M., &amp; Aslani, Z. (2013). The relationship between corporate governance mechanisms and dividend policies of companies listed on the Tehran Stock Exchange, Quarterly Journal of Accounting and Auditing, 5(19): 132-143. (in pershian).##[30] Setayesh, M. H., Kazemnezhad, M. (2010). The effects of ownership structure and board composition on the dividend policy of the listed firms in Tehran Stock Exchange (TSE), Quarterly Journal of Accounting Knowledge, 1(1): 29-51. (in pershian).##[31] Souri, A. (2014). Econometrics, Tehran: Farhang shenasi. (in pershian).##[32] Thanatawee, Y. (2013). Ownership structure and dividend policy: Evidence from Thailand, International Journal of Economics and Finance, 5(1): 121-132.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر همزمان حاکمیت شرکتی و کیفیت حسابرسی بر کیفیت سود با نقش میانجی ساختار سرمایه و عملکرد مالی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigating the Simultaneous Effect of Corporate Governance and Audit Quality on Earnings Quality with the Mediating Role of Capital Structure and Financial Performance</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: کیفیت سود از ویژگی‌‌های مهم گزارش‌‌های مالی است که بر تخصیص بهینۀ منابع تأثیر می‌‎گذارد؛ زیرا سود یکی از ورودی‌‌های اصلی الگو‌‌های ارزیابی سرمایه‌‌گذاران و تحلیلگران محسوب می‌شود. هدف این پژوهش، بررسی تأثیر همزمان حاکمیت شرکتی و کیفیت حسابرسی بر کیفیت سود حسابداری با استفاده از الگویابی ساختاری است.
روش: به این منظور اطلاعات شرکت‌ها در فاصلۀ زمانی ده‌ساله از 1385 تا 1394 بررسی و 700 سال - شرکت انتخاب شد. برای تحلیل داده‌‌ها از الگویابی معادلات ساختاری با رویکرد حداقل مربعات جزئی (PLS) و نرم‌‌افزار Smart-PLS استفاده شده است.
نتایج: نتایج پژوهش نشان می‌‌دهد حاکمیت شرکتی و کیفیت حسابرسی به‌طور مستقیم و غیرمستقیم (ازطریق متغیر میانجی عملکرد مالی) بر کیفیت سود تأثیر مثبت معنادار دارند؛ اما ازطریق متغیر میانجی ساختار سرمایه، به‌‌طور معناداری تأثیر منفی می‌‌گذارند. به‌علاوه یافته‌‌ها نشان‌دهندۀ این است که تأثیر مستقیم حاکمیت شرکتی و کیفیت حسابرسی بر کیفیت سود، قوی‌‌تر از تأثیر غیرمستقیم آنهاست.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: Earnings quality is one of the most substantial features of financial reporting, influencing the optimal capital structure. This substantiality probably results from the fact that earning is generally considered as one of the main inputs of valuation models for both financial investors and analysts. This research aims to investigate the simultaneous effect of corporate governance and audit quality on accounting earnings quality, using structural modeling.
Method: With a sample of 2006 to 2015 and 700 firm-years, to analyze the data of the research period, structural equation modeling with partial least squares (PLS) approach and Smart-PLS software have been applied.
Results: The results of this research indicate that corporate governance and audit quality, directly and indirectly, through the mediating variable of financial performance, have a significant positive effect on the earnings quality; while, through the mediating variable of capital structure, the effect is significantly negative. Furthermore, our findings reveal that the direct impact of corporate governance and audit quality on earnings quality is stronger than their indirect effect.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>83</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>102</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رمضان احمدی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ramazan Ahmadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه حسابداری، دانشکدۀ اقتصاد و علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، اهواز، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه حسابداری، دانشکدۀ اقتصاد و</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ahamadi_m@scu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عبدالمجید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>آهنگری</Family>
						<NameE>Abdolmajid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Abdolmajid Ahangari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار، گروه اقتصاد، دانشکدۀ اقتصاد و علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، اهواز، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار، گروه اقتصاد، دانشکدۀ اقتصاد و علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>a_m_ahangari@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حمیدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حاجب</Family>
						<NameE>Hamid Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hajeb</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه حسابداری، دانشکدۀ اقتصاد و علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، اهواز، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه حسابداری، دانشکدۀ اقتصاد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hrhajeb@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کیفیت سود</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>حاکمیت شرکتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کیفیت حسابرسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ساختار سرمایه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>معادلات ساختاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] آگهی‌اسکویی، الف.، و ملکی، م. (1393). بررسی رابطۀ حاکمیت شرکتی و ارزش افزودۀ اقتصادی در شرکت‌های تولیدی پذیرفته‌‎شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی، 2 (4)، 75-96.##[2] امیری، هـ.، و محمدی‌خورزوقی، هـ. (1391). تحلیل ارتباط بین تأمین مالی ازطریق بدهی و کیفیت سود شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. فصلنامۀ حسابداری مالی، 4 (16)، 81-61.##[3] انصاری، ع.، و نداپور، غ.، و شیرزاد، ع. (1392). بررسی عملکرد شرکت بر مدیریت واقعی سود و سطح کلی مدیریت سود در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. دومین همایش بررسی راهکارهای ارتقای مباحث مدیریت، حسابداری، مهندسی صنایع در سازمان‌ها.##[4] بادآور نهندی، ی.، و تقی‌زاده‌خانقاه، و. (1392). بررسی ارتباط بین کیفیت حسابرسی و کارآیی سرمایه‌گذاری. بررسی‌های حسابداری و حسابرسی، 20 (2)، 42-19.##[5] بذرافشان، آ.، و عارف‌منش، ز. (1393). رفتار سود در شرکت‌های ورشکسته: نقش حسابرس. مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی، 2 (4)، 1-14.##[6] بندریان، الف.، و وحیدی‌الیزئی، الف.، و مقصودی، ف. (1397). تأثیر تعدیل‌کنندگی کیفیت و تداوم حسابرسی بر رابطۀ بین ساختار مالکیت و مدیریت سود. پژوهش‌‎های حسابداری مالی و حسابرسی، 10 (37)، 214-195.##[7] بولو، ق. (1385). نظام راهبری شرکت و تأثیر آن بر کیفیت سود. مجله بورس، 52، 11-8.##[8] داوری، ع.، و رضازاده، آ. (1393). مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری با نرم‌افزار PLS. تهران: جهاد دانشگاهی.##[9] رضایی، ش.، و محمدزاده، الف. (1397). بررسی تأثیر حاکمیت شرکتی بر عملکرد مالی و بحران مالی در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. مجلۀ مدیریت توسعه و تحول، 32، 88-81.##[10] رهنمای‌رودپشتی، ف.، و اصلانی، ع. (1387). بررسی ارتباط بین حاکمیت شرکتی و روش‌های تأمین مالی و سودآوری در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. مجلۀ مدیریت، 78، 53-45.##[11] صالحی، الف.، بزرگمهریان، ش.، و امینی، الف. (1395). بررسی تأثیر کیفیت حسابرسی بر پایداری سود (مطالعۀ موردی: شرکت‌های درماندۀ مالی نسبت به دیگر شرکت‌های بورس اوراق بهادار تهران). فصلنامۀ علمی - پژوهشی حسابداری و حسابرسی مدیریت، 5 (20)، 59-47.##[12] صالحی، م.، موسوی‌شبیری، م.، و سدیرنوغانی، ح. (1392). بررسی رابطۀ بین حق‌الزحمۀ حسابرسی و عملکرد شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. فصلنامۀ حسابداری مالی، 5 (20)، 21-1.##[13] علوی‌طبری، ح.، و هاشمیان، م. (1390). تأثیر کیفیت حسابرسی بر تصمیمات تأمین مالی در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. پژوهش حسابداری، 1 (1)، 17-1.##[14] محسنین، ش.، و اسفیدانی، م. (1393). معادلات ساختاری مبتنی بر رویکرد حداقل مربعات جزئی به کمک نر‌م‌افزار Smart-PLS. تهران: مهربان.##[15] نمازی، م.، و بایزیدی، الف.، و جبازاده‌کنگرلویی، س. (1390). بررسی رابطۀ بین کیفیت حسابرسی و مدیریت سود شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. تحقیقات حسابداری و حسابرسی، 3 (9)، 21-4.##[16] نوروش، الف.، مشایخی، ب.، و برقعی، ز. (1388). بررسی تأثیر اقلام تعهدی بر کیفیت سود در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار. فصلنامۀ حسابداری مالی، 1 (3)، 53-31.##References##[17] Agahi Oskuei, A., &amp; Maleki, M. (2014). Investigating the relationship between corporate governance and economic value added in manufacturing companies accepted in Tehran Stock Exchange. Asset Management and Financing, 2 (4), 75-96. (in persian).##[18] Alavi Tabari, S. H., &amp; Hashemian, S. M. (2011). Effect of audit quality on financing decisions in companies acquired in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Accounting Research, 1 (1), 1-17. (in persian). Doi: 10.22051/ijar.2013.426.##[19] Alzoubi, E. S. S. (2018). Audit quality, debt financing and earnings management: Evidence from Jordan. Journal of International Accounting, Auditing and Taxation, 30, 69-84. https://doi.org/10.1016/ j.intaccaudtax.2017.12.001.##[20] Amiri, H., &amp; Mohammadi Khorzughi, H. (2013). Analysis of the relationship between debt financing and earnings quality of listed companies in Tehran Stock Exchange. Quarterly Financial Accounting Journal, 4 (16), 61-81. (in persian).##[21] Ansari, A., Nedapour, G., &amp; Shirzad, A. (2013). Investigating the company&#039;s performance on the real earning management and the overall level of earnings management in companies admitted to Tehran Stock Exchange. second conference on reviewing solutions for management Issues, accounting, industrial engineering in organizations. (in persian).##[22] Anuar, H., &amp; Chin, O. (2016). the development of debt to equity ratio in capital structure model: A case of micro franchising. Procedia Economic and Finance, 35, 274-280. https://Doi.org/10.1016/S2212-5671(16)00034-4.##[23] Badavar Nahandi, Y., &amp; Taghizadeh Khanghah, V. (2014). Investigating the relationship between audit quality and investment efficiency. Accounting and Audit Reviews, 20 (2), 19-42. (in persian).##[24] Bae, G. S., &amp; Choi, S. U. (2012). Do industry specialist auditors improve investment efficiency? http:// www.ssrn.com. http://dx. Doi.org/10.2139/ ssrn.2145191.##[25] Bandarian, A., Vahidi Elizooei, A., &amp; Maghsudi, F. (2018). the effect of quality moderation and continuity of audit on the relationship between ownership structure and profit management. the Financial Accounting and Auditing Researches, 10 (37), 195-213. (in persian).##[26] Bartov, E. (1993). the timing of asset sales and earnings manipulation. Accounting Review, 68 (4), 840-855.##[27] Bartov, E., Radhakrishnan, S., &amp; Krinsky, I. (2000). Investor sophistication and patterns in stock returns after earnings announcements. the Accounting Review, 75 (1), 43-63. https://doi.org/10.2308/accr. 2000.75.1.43.##[28] Bassiouny, S. W., Soliman, M. M., &amp; Ragab, A. (2016). the impact of firm characteristics on earnings management: An empirical study on the listed firms in Egypt. the Business and Management Review, 7 (2), 91-101.##[29] Bazr afshan, A., &amp; Aref manesh, Z. (2014). Profit behavior in bankrupt companies: the role of an auditor. Asset Management and Financing, 2 (4), 1-14. (in persian).##[30] Beatty, A., &amp; Weber, J. (2003). the effects of debt contracting on voluntary accounting method changes. the Accounting Review, 78 (1), 119-142.##[31] Bhatia, A., Ali, M. J., Balachandran, B., &amp; Jurdi, D. (2015). Audit fees and capital structure decision. http:// www.ssrn.com.##[32] Black, B. S. (1992). Institutional investors and corporate governance: the case for institutional voice. Journal of Applied Corporate Finance, 5 (3), 19-32. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1745 6622.1992.tb00223.x##[33] Bolu, G. (2007). Corporate governance and its impact on the earning quality. Exchange Magazine, 52, 8-11. (in persian).##[34] Brailsford, T. J., Oliver, B. R., &amp; Pua, S. L. (2002). on the relation between ownership structure and capital structure. Accounting &amp; Finance, 42 (1), 1-26. https://Doi.org/10.1111/1467-629X.00001.##[35] Brown, L. D., &amp; Caylor, M. L. (2006). Corporate governance and firm valuation. Journal of Accounting and Public Policy, 25, 409-434. https://Doi.org/10.1016/ j.jaccpubpol.2006.05.005.##[36] Broye, G., &amp; Weill, L. (2008). Does leverage influence auditor choice? a cross-country analysis. Applied Financial Economics, 18 (9), 715-731. Doi: 10.1080/09603100701222325.##[37] Burgstahler, D., &amp; Dichev, I. (1997). Earnings management to avoid earnings decreases and losses. Journal of Accounting And Economics, 24 (1), 99-126. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0165-4101(97)00017-7.##[38] Bushee, B. J. (1998). the influence of institutional investors on myopic R&amp;D investment behavior. Accounting Review, 73 (3), 305-333.##[39] Chan, K., Chan, L. K., Jegadeesh, N., &amp; Lakonishok, J. (2006). Earnings quality and stock returns. Journal of Business, 79 (3), 1-42. http://dx.doi.org/10.1086/500669.##[40] Parsa, S., Chong, G., &amp; Isimoya, E. (2007). Disclosure of governance information by small and medium-sized companies. Corporate Governance: the International Journal of Business in Society, 7 (5), 635-684. https://doi.org/10.1108/ 14720700710827211.##[41] Damodaran, A. (2002). Investment Valuation: Tools and Techniques for Determining the Value of any Asset. United States of America: Wiley.##[42] Das, S., &amp; Pandit, S. (2010). Audit quality, life-cycle stage and the investment efficiency of the firm. www.ssrn.com.##[43] Davari, A., &amp; Reza zadeh, A. (2014). Modeling Structural Equations with PLS Software. Tehran: Jahad University Press. (in persian).##[44] DeAngelo, H., DeAngelo, L., &amp; Skinner, D. J. (1994). Accounting choice in troubled companies. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 17 (1-2), 113-143. https://doi.org/10.1016/0165-4101(94)90007-8.##[45] Dechow, P. (1994). Accounting earnings and cash flows as measures of firm performance the role of accounting accruals. Journal of Accounting and Economic, 18 (1),3-42. https://doi.org/10.1016/0165-4101(94)90016-7.##[46] Dittmar, A., &amp; Mahrt-Smith, J. (2007). Corporate governance and the value of cash holdings. Journal Of Financial Economics, 83 (3), 599-634. https://doi.org/10.1016/ j.jfineco.2005.12.006.##[47] Doyle, J. T., Ge, W., &amp; McVay, S. (2007) Accruals quality and internal control over financial reporting. the Accounting Review, 82 (5), 1141-1170. https://doi.org/10.2308/ accr.2007.82.5.1141.##[48] Eshleman, J. D., &amp; Guo, P. (2014). Abnormal audit fees and audit quality: the importance of considering managerial incentives in tests of earnings management. Auditing: a Journal of Practice &amp; Theory, 33 (1), 117-138. https://doi.org/10.2308/ ajpt-50560.##[49] Financial Accounting Standards Board. (2003). Statement of Financial Accounting Standards.##[50] Fornell, C., &amp; Larcker, D. F. (1981). Evaluating structural equation models with unobservable variables and measurement error. Journal of Marketing Research, 18 (1), 39-50. https://doi.org/10.1177/ 002224378101800104.##[51] Francis, J., LaFond, R., Olsson, P., &amp; Schipper, K. (2004). Costs of equity and earnings attributes. the Accounting Review, 79, 967-1010. 10.2308/accr.2004.79.4.967.##[52] Gompers, P., Ishii, J., &amp; Metrick, A. (2003). Corporate governance and equity prices. the Quarterly Journal of Economics, 118 (1), 107-156. https://doi.org/10.1162/ 00335530360535162.##[53] Gul, F. A., Fung, S. Y. K., &amp; Jaggi, B. (2009). Earnings quality: Some evidence on the role of auditor tenure and auditors’ industry expertise. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 47 (3), 265-287. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacceco.2009.03.001.##[54] Henseler, J., Ringle, C. M., &amp; Sinkovics, R. R. (2009). The use of partial least squares path modeling in international marketing. Advances in International Marketing, 20, 277-320. https://doi.org/10.1108/S1474-7979(2009) 0000020014.##[55] Hulland, J. (1999). Use of partial least squares (PLS) in strategic management research: A review of four recent studies. Strategic Management Journal, 20, 195-204. Doi:10.1002/(SICI)1097-0266(199902)20:23.0.CO.2-7.##[56] Ittonen, K. (2010). A Theoretical Examination of the Role of Auditing and Relevance of Audit Reports. Business Administration 28, Accounting and Finance, University of Vaasa. http://www.uva.fi/material.##[57] Jung, K., &amp; Kwon, S. Y. (2002). Ownership structure and earnings informativeness: Evidence from Korea. the International Journal of Accounting, 37 (3), 301-325. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0020-7063(02)00173-5.##[58] Lin, J. W., &amp; Hwang, M. I. (2010). Audit quality, corporate governance and earnings management: A meta‐analysis. International Journal of Auditing, 14 (1), 57-77. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1099-1123.2009.00403.x.##[59] Matsumoto, D. A. (2002). Management&#039;s incentives to avoid negative earnings surprises. the Accounting Review, 77 (3), 483-514. https://Doi.org/10.2308/accr.2002.77.3.483.##[60] Mayhew, B., &amp; Wilkins, M. (2003). Audit firm industry specialization as a differentiation strategy: Evidence from fees charged to firms going public auditing. A Journal of Practice &amp; Theory, 22 (2), 33–52. https://doi.org/10.2308/aud.2003. 22.2.33.##[61] Mohsenin, S., &amp; Sfidani, M. R. (2014). Structural equations based on partial least squares approach using Smart-PLS software. Tehran: Book Publishing Institute. (in persian).##[62] Namazi, M., Bayazidi, A., &amp; Jabbar Zadeh Kangarluei, S. (2011). Investigating the relationship between audit quality and earnings management of companies accepted in Tehran Stock Exchange. Accounting and Auditing Research, 3 (9), 4-21. (in persian).##[63] Noe, T. (2002). Institutional activism and financial market structure. Review of Financial Studies, 15, 289-315. https://doi.org/10.1093/rfs/15.1.289.##[64] Nowravesh, I., Mashayekhi, B., &amp; Baraghei, Z. (2009). Investigating the effect of accruals on earnings quality in companies admitted to the stock exchange. Quarterly Financial Accounting, 1 (3), 31-53.##(in persian).##[65] Peasnell, K. V., Pope, P. F., &amp; Young, S. (2005). Board monitoring and earnings management: Do outside Directors influence abnormal accruals? Journal of Business Finance &amp; Accounting, 32 (7‐8), 1311-1346. https://Doi.org/10.1111/j.0306-686X.2005.00630.x.##[66] Rahnamaye Roudposhti, F., &amp; Aslani, A. (2008). Investigating the relationship between corporate governance and financing methods and profitability in the companies acquired in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal Management System, 78, 45-53. (in persian).##[67] Rezaei, Sh. &amp; Mohammadzadeh, A. (2018). Investigating the effect of corporate governance on financial performance and financial crisis in companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Development Evolution Management, 32, 81-88. (in persian).##[68] Salehi, A., Bozorgmehrian, S., &amp; Amini, A. (2016). Investigating the effect of audit quality on earnest stability. case study: Helpless financial companies compared to other Tehran Stock Exchange companies. Journal of Management Accounting and Auditing, 5 (20), 47-59. (in persian).##[69] Salehi, M., Mousavi Shabiri, M., &amp; Sadir Noghani, H. (2014). Investigating the relationship between auditor fees and the performance of listed companies in Tehran Stock Exchange. Quarterly Financial Accounting Journal, 5 (20), 1-21. (in persian).##[70] Schipper, K., &amp; Vincent, L. (2003). Earnings quality. Accounting Horizons, 17, 97-110.##[71] Wang, S. F., Jou, Y. J., Chang, K. C., &amp; Wu, K. W. (2014). Industry competition, agency problem and firm performance. Romanian Journal of Economic Forecasting, 17 (4), 76-93.##[72] Watts, R. L., &amp; Zimmerman, J. L. (1978). Towards a positive theory of the determination of accounting standards. Accounting Review, 53 (1), 112-134.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی مطابقت داده‌های بورس اوراق بهادار تهران با قانون بنفورد</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Checking conformity of Tehran Stock Exchange Data with Benford’s Law</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: در بحث داده‌ها و اطلاعاتی که افراد، به‌خصوص سرمایه‌گذاران در بازار اوراق بهادار استفاده می‌کنند، کیفیت داده‌ها، اهمیت خاصی دارد. دستکاری اطلاعات بازار و شرایط آن ازجمله عوامل دخیل در کیفیت اطلاعات است. چنانچه بازار در شرایط عادی و نرمال فعالیت کند، داده‌های موجود در آن، توزیعی لگاریتمی به نام قانون بنفورد دارد. این قانون، احتمال وقوع ارقام مختلف را در یک مجموعه اعداد نشان می‌دهد.
روش: در این پژوهش برای بررسی شرایط بازار، همسانی توزیع اطلاعات مربوط به بازده روزانۀ سهام شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در سال‌های 1384 تا 1393 با این قانون بررسی شده است.
نتایج: نتایج پژوهش نشان می‌دهد اطلاعات مربوط به بازده روزانۀ سهام شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران، در دورۀ پژوهش از این قانون تبعیت نمی‌کند که دلایل مختلفی مانند تبدیلاتی که بر اطلاعات و داده‌ها انجام می‌شود و یا شرایط و وقایع تأثیرگذار در بازار بورس اوراق بهادار دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: In general, when a financial market works ordinarily, the probability distribution of the first significant digit of the returns of the assets listed therein follows Benford’s law, but does not necessarily follow this distribution in the case of anomalous events. This law shows the contingency of various digits in a set of numbers thus it can be used for assessing data sets that occur naturally.
Method: The present study applied Benford law in order to investigate the empirical probability distribution of the first and the second digit of daily stocks return in listed companies in the Tehran Stock Exchange during 1384 – 1393.
Results: The findings show that the data of daily stocks return in listed companies in the Tehran Stock Exchange that used in the present study do not obey the Benford law. This can be due to some reasons such as different data transformation or influential conditions in the Iran stock market.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>103</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>112</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سمیه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>پورحسین</Family>
						<NameE>Somayeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Poorhossein</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>مربی، گروه حسابداری، دانشکده حسابداری، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد مبارکه، اصفهان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>مربی، گروه حسابداری، دانشکده حسابداری، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>s.poorhossein@mau.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بازده سهام</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قانون بنفورد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کیفیت داده‌ها</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1- آذر، ع. و مومنی، م. (1377). آمار و کاربرد آن در مدیریت. تهران: انتشارات سمت.##2- رستمی، م. جعفری درگیری، ا. (1392). «بررسی قانون بنفورد در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران»، پژوهشهای مدیریت در ایران، (1)17: 95-109.##3- رنجبری شرف آبادی، ع. (1391). «قانون بنفورد و کاربردهای آن در حسابرسی»، ماهنامه حسابرس، (14)63: 110- 117.##4- فلاح، ا. دانش‌زاد، م. (1392). قانون بنفورد و کاربردهای آن، اندیشه آماری، (35)1، 18:71-84.##5- محمدی، ح. صالحی‌راد، م. و حاجی­زاده، س. (1390). شناسایی مدیریت آرایشی سود با استفاده از قانون بنفورد، دانش حسابرسی، (45)11: 51- 67.##References##]1[ Azar, A., &amp; Momeny, M. (2003). Statistics and its Application in Management. Tehran: SAMT publication. (in Persian).##]2[ Amiram, D., Bozanic, Z., &amp; Rouen, E. (2015). Financial Statement Errors: Evidence from the Distributional Properties of Financial Statement Numbers. Springer Science + Business Media. New York.##]3[ Barte, R. H. (2016). Foreign trust and confidence in Philippine stocks using Benford`s law. International Journal of Research in Business Management (IMPACT). 4(6): 67-74.##[4] Benford, F. (1938). The law of anomalous numbers. Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society. 78(4): 551-572.##[5] Boyle, J. (1994). An application of Fourier series to the most significant digit problem. American Mathematical Monthly. 101(9): 879-886.##]6[ Corazza, M., Ellero, A., &amp; Zorazi, A. (2008). Checking financial markets via Benford’s law. Mathematical and Statistical Methods for Actuarial Sciences and Finance. Springer- Verlag Italia. 93-103.##[7] De Ceuster, M. J. K., Dhaene, G., &amp; Schatteman, T. (1998). On the hypothesis of psychological barriers in stock markets and Benford’s law. Journal of. Empirical Finance 5: 263-279.##]8[ Fallah, A., &amp; Daneshzad, M. (2013). Benford distribution and its applications. Andishe- ye Amari. 18(1): 71-84. (in Persian).##[9] Hill, T. P. (1995). A statistical derivation of the significant digit law. Statistical Science. 10(4): 354-363.##]10[ Ley, E. (1996). On the peculiar distribution of the U.S indexes’ digits. American Statistician. 50(4).##]11[ Mohammadi, H., Salehirad, M., &amp; Hajizadeh, S. (2012). Detecting cosmetic earnings management using benford’s law. Journal of Auditing Science. 11(45):51-67. (in Persian).##[12] Newcomb, S. (1881). Note on the frequency of use of the different digits in natural numbers. American Journal of Mathematics. 4: 39-40.##]13[ Nigrini, J. M. (2005). An assessment of the change in the incidence of earnings management around the Enrone-Anderson episode. Review of Accounting and Finance 4(1).##[14] Pietronero, L., Tossati, E., Tossati, V., &amp; Vespignani, A. (2001). Explaining the uneven distribution of numbers in nature: The laws of Benford and Zipf. Physica A. 239: 297-304.##]15[ Ranjbarisharafabadi, A. (2012). Benford law and its application in auditing. Hesabras. 14(63): 110-117. (in Persian).##]16[ Rostami, M., &amp; Jafaridargiri, A. (2013). A Survey on Benford law in Tehran Stock Exchange. Management Researches in Iran. 17(1): 95-109. (in Persian).##[17] Tota, I., Aliaj, A., &amp; Lamcja, J. (2016). The use of Benford’s law as a tool for detecting fraud in accounting data. Interdisplinary Journal of Research and Development. 3(1).##[18] Zhipeng, L., Lin, C., &amp; Huajia, W. (2004). Discussion on Benford’s law and its applications. In: Cornell University Library. Available at: www.arxiv.org/abs/math.ST/ 0408057##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مدل پویای ارزشیابی سهام بانک‏ها؛ مورد مطالعه: بانک‏های ملت، تجارت، اقتصاد نوین و کارآفرین</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Dynamic Model of Valuation for the Bank Stocks (Case Study of Banks of Mellat, Tejarat, Eghtesad-e-Novin, and Karafarin)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: وجود ابهام در شفافیت گزارش‌های مالی بانک‌‎ها، ارزشیابی آنها را برای تحلیلگران و سهامداران با مشکلات زیادی روبه‌رو کرده است. در این پژوهش الگوی پویای ارزشیابی سهام بانک‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران با استفاده از الگوی ARDL ارزیابی شده است. روش: بدین منظور، داده‌های فصلی 4 بانک پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران تجزیه‌وتحلیل شدند؛ داده‌هایی که با توجه به دردسترس‌بودنشان به شیوۀ غربالگری طی سال‌های 1395-1388 انتخاب شدند. نوآوری‌ دیگر، انتخاب الگویی رقیب به‌صورت الگوی خودرگرسیونی ARIMA برای ارزیابی میزان دقت الگوی ARDL و بررسی اثر ریسک سیاسی کشور بر قیمت سهام بانک‌هاست که اثر تحریم بانک مرکزی ایران در قالب متغیر مجازی وارد الگو شد. نتایج: نتایج نشان داد هر دو الگو قابلیت بالایی در پیش‌بینی نسبت قیمت به ارزش دفتری بانک دارند؛ ولی میزان دقت الگوی ARDL بالاتر است. به‌علاوه، تحریم بانک مرکزی در بلندمدت اثر معناداری بر نسبت PB نداشته است. در نهایت براساس اثرات بلندمدت متغیرهای بنیادین، متغیر ارزشیابی سهام بانک تعریف شد که مثبت و منفی‌بودن آن نشان‌دهندۀ گران یا ارزان‌‌بودن قیمت سهم است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: The opacity in many banks’ financial reports has brought some difficulties for the analysts and shareholders who are to grasp them. In this research, using ARDL model, we assess the dynamic model of valuation of the shares of the banks listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. Method: For this purpose and subject to the availability of the data, the seasonal data of the four listed banks in Tehran Stock Exchange- which has been extracted by screening method in the years of 2009-2016- has been analyzed. The other contribution of this paper is to choose a competitor model as an auto-regressive ARIMA model in order to assess the accuracy of the ARDL model, and to investigate the effects of political risk of the country on the stock prices while the effects of the sanctions on the Iranian central bank entered the model in the form of a dummy variable. Results: The results show that both of the models have a high capability of prediction of price-to-book (PB) ratio of stocks but the accuracy of the ARDL model is higher In addition, the sanction on the central bank has no significant effect on PB ratio in the long-run term. Finally, depending on the long-term effects of fundamental variables, the “valuation” variable of bank stocks was defined so that its positivity (negativity) signifies overpriced (underpriced) stock.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>113</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>134</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>احسان</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>آقاسی</Family>
						<NameE>Ehsan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Aghasi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس‌ارشد، گروه مالی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و مالی، دانشگاه خاتم، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس‌ارشد، گروه مالی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>aghasiehsan@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نادر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مهرگان</Family>
						<NameE>Nader</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mehregan</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه اقتصاد، دانشکدۀ اقتصاد و علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، همدان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه اقتصاد، دانشکدۀ اقتصاد و علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mehregannader@buas.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>آسیما</Family>
						<NameE>Mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Asima</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکترای مالی، بانکداری، گروه مدیریت مالی و بیمه، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکترای مالی، بانکداری، گروه مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>asima1366@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الگوی پویای ارزشیابی سهام</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الگوی ARDL</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الگوی ARIMA</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الگوی ارزشیابی DDM</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] احمدزاده، ع.، یاوری، ک.، عیسائی‌تفرشی، م.، و صالح‌آبادی، ع. (۱۳۹۳). تحلیلی بر روش‌های ارزیابی کارآیی بازار سرمایه در ایران. فصلنامۀ تحقیقات مدلسازی اقتصادی، ۵(۱۷)، 28-1.##[2] اسلامی‌بیدگلی، س.، باجلان، س.، و محمودی، و. (1387). ارزیابی عملکرد مدل‌های ارزشگذاری در بورس اوراق بهادار. فصلنامۀ تحقیقات مالی، 10(26)، 21-40.##[3] اعتمادی، ح.، و فتحی، ز. (1391). مقایسۀ توانایی تبیین ارزش بازار شرکت با استفاده از دو متغیر سود خالص عملیاتی پس از کسر مالیات و ارزش افزودۀ اقتصادی. پژوهش‌های حسابداری مالی و حسابرسی، 4(16)، 67-45.##[4] باقی، م.، ابراهیمی، م.، و نیکزادچالشتری، ق. (1393). مقایسۀ مدل‌های تنزیلی سود تقسیمی، جریان نقد آزاد و سود باقیمانده در ارزشیابی سهام شرکت‌های تولیدی پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. فصلنامۀ حسابداری مالی، 6(22)، 113-89.##[5] بشیری‌جویباری، م.، و پاکیزه، ک. (1392). تأثیر ارزشیابی نادرست بر تصیمات سرمایه‌‎گذاری شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران. مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی، 1(3)، 98-81.##[6] ترقی‌جاه، ز.، و نیکومرام، هـ. (1394). بررسی مدل‌های ارزشگذاری سهام با رویکرد دست‌یابی به مدل بهینه در صنعت بانکداری ایران. دانش مالی تحلیل اوراق بهادار، 8(28)، 56-41.##[7] تشکینی، الف. (1395). اقتصادسنجی کاربردی به کمک مایکروفیت. تهران: نورعلم.##[8] حسینی‌نسب، الف.، و ایزانلو، ق. (1387). تأثیر ریسک سیاسی بر نوسان بازدهی سهام در ایران. فصلنامۀ پژوهشنامۀ اقتصادی، 8(2)، 62-41.##[9] عباسیان، ع.، و ذوالفقاری، م. (۱۳۹۲). تحلیل پویای کارآیی سطح ضعیف در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران توسط فیلتر کالمن. فصلنامۀ پژوهش‌ها و سیاست‌های اقتصادی، ۲۱(۶۵)، 254-231.##[10] قالیباف‌اصل، ح.، و بابالویان، ش. (1393). بررسی مدل‌های ارزشگذاری سهام بانک‌ها. فصلنامۀ روند، 21(68)، 178-151.##[11] قلی‌زاده، م.، و وحیدپور، ق. (1387). پیش‌بینی قیمت سهام با استفاده از روش خودرگرسیون با وقفۀ توزیعی (ARDL). فصلنامۀ تحقیقات مالی، 9(2)، 60-49.##[12] محمودی‌آذر، م.، و راعی، ر. (1393). پیش‌بینی بازده آتی بازار سهام با استفاده از مدل‌های آریما، شبکۀ عصبی و نویززدایی موجک. مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی، 2(2)، 16-1.##[13] مهرانی، ک.، و مهرانی، ک. (1392). ارزشیابی سهام (روش‌‎ها و مدل‌‎ها). تهران: مهربان.##[14] نادمی، ی.، و سالم، ع. (1395). بررسی فرضیۀ کارآیی ضعیف در دو رژیم پرنوسان و کم‌نوسان بازدهی بازار سهام تهران. فصلنامۀ پژوهش‌ها و سیاست‌های اقتصادی، 24(77)، 162-139.##References##[15] Abbasian, E., &amp; Zolfaghari. M. (2013). Dynamic analysis of weak efficiency in the Tehran Stock Exchange, using the kalman filter. Quarterly Journal of Economic Research and Policies, 21 (65), 231-254. (in persian). DOI: http://qjerp.ir/article-622-1-fa.html.##[16] Ahmadzadeh, A., Yavari., K., Isaee Tafreshi, M., &amp; Salehabadi. A. (2014). An analysis on methods of market efficiency evaluation in Iran. Journal of Research in Economic Modeling, 5(17), 1-28. (in persian). DOI: http://jemr.khu.ac.ir/article-896-1-fa.html.##[17] Baghi, M., Ebrahimi, M. &amp; Nikzad, G. (2014). Comparison of dividend dividend, free cash and residual profit in valuation of shares of the manufacturing companies accepted in Tehran Stock Exchange. Quarterly Financial Accounting Journal, 6(22), 89-113. (in persian). DOI: http://qfaj.ir/article-78-1-fa.html.##[18] Bashirijoibari, M. &amp; pakizeh, K. (2014). The impact Stock market misvaluation on firmâ™s investment decisions. Asset Management and Financing, 1 (3), 81-98. (in persian). DOI: http://amf.ui.ac.ir/ article_19862.htm.##[19] Bernard, V. L. (1995). The feltham‐ohlson framework: Implications for empiricists. Contemporary Accounting Research, 11, 733-747. Doi:10.1111/j.1911-3846.1995. tb00463.x.##[20] Bertsatos, G., &amp; Sakellaris, P. (2016). A dynamicmodel of bank valuation. Economics Letters, 145, 15-18. DOI: 10.1016/j.econlet.2016.05.014.##[21] Bertsatos, G., Sakellaris, P., &amp; Tsionas, M. G. (2017). Did the financial crisis affect the marketvaluation of large systemic US banks? Journal of Financial Stability, 32, 115-123. DOI: 10.1016/j.jfs.2017.09.002.##[22] Collins, D. W., Maydew, E. L., &amp; Weiss, I. S. (1997). Changes in the value-relevance of earnings and book values over the past forty years. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 24(1), 39-67. DOI: 10.1016/S0165-4101(97)00015-3.##[23] Eslami-Bidgoli, G., Bajalan, S., &amp; Mahmoodi, V. (2010). Performance assessment of valuation models in Tehran Stock Exchange. Financial Research, 10 (26), 21-40. (in persian). DOI: https://jfr.ut.ac.ir/article_20030.html.##[24] Etemadi, H., &amp; Fathi, Z. (2013). Comparison of ability to explain market value of a companyusing two variables of net operating profit after tax deduction and economic value added. Financial Accounting Research and Audit, 4(16), 45-67. (in persian). DOI: http://faar.iauctb.ac.ir/ article_510561.html.##[25] Ghalibaf Asl, H., &amp; Babaloyan, S. (2014). Reviewing the models of stock valuation of banks. Ravand, 68 (21), 151-178. (in persian). DOI: https://www.cbi.ir/page/ 13521.aspx.##[26] Golizadeh, M., &amp; Vahidpoor, G. (2008). Forecasting stock price with ARDL method ofone equationcumulative regression methods. Financial Research Journal, 9(2), 49-60. (in persian). DOI: https://jfr.ut.ac.ir/ article_27213.html.##[27] Hamadi, H., &amp; Hamadeh. M. (2012). Equity valuation: a comparison between the discounted cash flow models and the residual income models. International Journal of Business, Accounting &amp; Finance, 6 (2), 104-115. http://www.iabpad.com.##[28] Hosseiny Nasab, E., &amp; Izanlo, G. (2008). The effect of political risk on the fluctuation of stock returns in Iran. Economics Research, 8(2), 41-62. (in persian). http://joer.atu.ac.ir.##[29] Lazzati, N., &amp; Menichini, A. A. (2016). A Dynamic model of firm valuation. Financial Review, 53 (3), 499-531. DOI: 10.2139/ssrn. 2435328.##[30] Mahmoudiazar, M., &amp; Raei, R. (2014). Prediction of stock market returns with out of sampledata: evaluating out of sample methods (Regression method and wavelet neural network). Asset Management and Financing, 2(2), 1-16. (in persian). http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_19880.html.##[31] Mehrani, K., Mehrani, K., &amp; Mirsaneie, R. (2016). Stock Valuation (Methods and Models). Tehran: Mehraban. (in persian).##[32] Nademi, Y., &amp; Salem, A. (2016). An investigation of the hypothesis of weak form of efficiency in two regimes of high &amp; amp; poor volatility in Tehran stock exchange. Quarterly Journal of Economic Research and Policies, 24(77), 139-162. (in persian). http://qjerp.ir/article-1-1198-fa.html.##[33] Pesaran, M. H., Shin, Y., &amp; Smith, R. J. (2001). Bounds testing approaches to the analysis of level relationships. Journal of Applied Econometrics, 16 (3), 289-326. DOI: 10.1002/jae.616.##[34] Rees, W. P. (1997). The impact of dividends, debt and investment on valuation models. Journal of Business Finance and Accounting, 24 (7), 1111 -1140. DOI: 10.1111/1468-5957.00154.##[35] Taraghi Jah, Z., &amp; Nikoomaram, H. (2015). Stock valuation models with a view to achievingoptimal model in the banking industry of Iran. Financial Knowledge of Securities Analysis, 28 (8), 41-56. (in persian). http://jfksa.srbiau.ac.ir/article_8252.html.##[36] Tashkini, A. (2016). Applied Econometrics with Micropyte. Tehran: Noor e Elm. (in persian).##[37] www. Codal.ir.##[38] www.fipiran.com##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				