<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1397</YEAR>
<VOL>6</VOL>
<NO>1</NO>
<MOSALSAL>20</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>0</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی ارتباط ریسک سیستماتیک سهام وچولگی بازده سهام</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Examination of Relationship between Stock Systematic Risk and Skewness of Returns</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>چولگی بازده سهام یکی از پدیده‌های مشاهده‌شده در بازارهای مالی است که سوگیری‌های روان‌شناسی یا گرایش به اعداد خاص را در بازار نشان می‌دهد. پژوهش حاضر، ارتباط ریسک  سیستماتیک و چولگی بازده سهام را بررسی می‌کند. برای دستیابی به این هدف، دو فرضیه تدوین و برای آزمون فرضیه‌ها، 98 شرکت از بین شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار در سالهای 1392-1387 انتخاب شد. برای آزمون فرضیه‌ها از رگرسیون چندمتغیره با داده‌های تابلویی استفاده شده است. نتایج حاصل از فرضیۀ نخست پژوهش نشان می‌دهد بین ریسک  سیستماتیک سهام با چولگی مثبت بازده سهام، ارتباط مستقیم و معنی‌دار وجود دارد. نتایج حاصل از فرضیۀ‌ دوم پژوهش نیز نشان می‌دهد بین ریسک  سیستماتیک سهام با چولگی منفی سهام، ارتباط مستقیم و معنی‌دار وجود دارد؛ به عبارت بهتر، هرچه ریسک  سیستماتیک بیشتر باشد، چولگی بازده سهام بیشتر است و برعکس؛ به‌عبارتی، اصل ثابت‌شدۀ ارتباط مستقیم ریسک و بازده تأیید می‌شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Skewness of stock return is one of the phenomena observed in the financial markets, indicating psychological bias or tendencies to specific numbers in the market. This study examined the association between systematic risk and skewness in stock&#039;s return. To this end, two hypotheses were developed and the data of 98 companies listed on Tehran Stock Exchange, during 2008-2013 and multiple regression with panel data was used to test the hypotheses. The results of the first study suggest that there was a significant correlation between systematic risk of stocks and positive skewness of stock returns. The results of the study also suggest that there was a significant and direct correlation between negative skewness and systematic risk of stock. In other words, the higher the systematic risk, the higher the skewness of stock returns and vice versa. Therefore, the direct relationship between risk and return is confirmed.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>10</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>زهره</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حاجیها</Family>
						<NameE>Zohreh hajiha</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hajiha</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم انسانی، واحد تهران شرق، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم انسانی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>drzhajiha@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فاطمه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صفری</Family>
						<NameE>Fatemeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Safari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد گروه حسابداری، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد الکترونیکی ، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد گروه حسابداری، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>safari13610225@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بازارهای مالی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>چولگی بازده سهام</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ریسک سیستماتیک سهام</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Abbasi, E., Shohrati, A., &amp; Ghadak Frooshan, M. (2015). The rrelationship between accounting conservatism and risk of stock price crash in information asymmetry condition in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Accounting Knowledge. 5(19): 141-162. (in Persian).##[2] Alavi, S. M., Haghighat, H. (2013). The relationship between accounting transparency and abnormal stock returns. Financial Accounting Researches. 5(1): 1-12. (in Persian).##[3] Ang, A., Hodrick, R. J., Xing, Y., &amp; Zhang, X. (2006). The cross-section of volatility and expected return. The Journal of Finance. 61: 259-299.##[4] Bali, T. G., Cakici, N., &amp; Whitelaw, R. F. (2010). Systematic risk and skewness of expected returns. Electronic copy available at: http://ssrn.com/abstract=1262416##[5] Berk, J. (1995). A critique of size related anomalies. Review of Finance Studies, 8: 275-286.##[6] Boyer, B., Mitton, T., &amp; Vorkink, K. (2010). Expected idiosyncratic skewness. The Review of Financial Studies. 23(1): 148-159.##[7] Callen, J. L., Fang, X. (2013). Institutional investors and crash risk: Monitoring or expropriation? Rotman School of Management Working Paper No.1804697.Available at SSRN:https://ssrn.com/abstract=1804697##[8] Diyanati Deylami, Z., Lotfi, M., &amp; Azadbakhsh, K. (2013). The impact of working capital management is based on the cash conversion cycle &quot;Gytman&quot; to reduce the risk of fall (loss) stock price. Journal of Accounting &amp; Auditing Knowledge, 1(4): 55-64. (in Persian).##[9] Diyanati Deylami, Z., Moradzadeh Fard, M., &amp; Mahmoodi, S. (2011). The effect of institutional investors to reduce the risk of fall (loss) shares. Journal of Investment Knowledge. 1(2): 1-18. (in Persian)##[10] Eslami Bidgoli, G., &amp; Khojasteh, M. A. (2009). Improving the risk-adjusted return of the portfolio by implementing ccapital productivity in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Financial Research. 9(4): 55-64. (in Persian).##[11] Fama, E., &amp; MacBech, J. (1973). Risk, return and equilibrium: Empirical tests. Journal of Political Economy. 81: 607-636.##[12] Fama, E., &amp; French, K. (1992). The cross – section of expected stock returns. Journal of Finance. 47: 427-465.##[13] Harvey, C. R., &amp; Siddique, A. (2000). Conditional skewness in asset pricing tests. The Journal of Finance. LV (3): 1263-1295.##[14] Hutton, A. P., Marcus, A. J., &amp; Tehranian, H. (2009). Opaque financial reports, R2, and crash risk. Journal of Financial Economics. 94: 67-86.##[15] Jahankhani, A., &amp; Parsayian, A. (2002). Financial Management. Tehran: Samt Pub. (in Persian).##[16] Kapadia, N. (2007). Skewness, Idiosyncratic Volatility and Expected Returns. Working Paper. University of North Carolina: Chapel Hill.##[17] Kousenidis, D. V., Ladas, A. C., &amp; Negakis, C, I. (2014). Accounting conservatism quality of accounting information and crash risk of stock prices. The Journal of Economic Asymmetries. 11: 120-137.##[18] Mitton, T., &amp; Vorkink, K. (2007). Equilibrium under diversification and the preference for skewness. Review of Financial Studies. 20(4): 1-47.##[19] Moharrami, M., &amp; Axon, A. (2013). The relationship between refined economic value and stock returns adjusted by risk. Studies of Accounting and Auditing. 1(4): 74-89. (in Persian).##[20] Pettengill, G. N., Sundaram, S., &amp; Mathur, I. (1995). The conditional relation between beta and returns. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis. 30: 101-116.##[21] Rezayi, F., Ghaderi, H., Mohammadi, T. (2010). Accounting variables affecting the cost of capital in companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Researcher, Special Issue: 1-19. (in Persian)##[22] Robin, A., &amp; Zhang, H. (2015). Do industry-specialist auditors influence stock price crash risk? Forthcoming in auditing. A Journal of Practice &amp; Theory (AJPT). 34(3):47-79.##[23] Tehrani, R., Balghoorian, M., &amp; Nabizadeh, A. (2009). Examination of the effect of skewness and excess kurtosis on stock returns description through capital asset pricing model. Quarterly Journal of Securities Exchange, 1(4): 35-52. (in Persian).##[24] Tversky, A., &amp; Kahnemann D. (1979). Prospect theory: An analysis of decision under risk. Econometric a. 47(2): 263-291.##[25] Zhang, X-J. (2013). Book-to-market ratio and skewness of stock returns. The Accounting Review. 88 (6): 2213–2240.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تأثیر سرمایه‌گذاری در دارایی نامشهود در توضیح دهندگی تأثیر سلامت مالی و مشکلات نمایندگی در ارزش بازار شرکت</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Effect of Investments in Intangible Assets in the Explanatory Impact of Financial Health and Agency Problems on the Market Value Company&#039;s</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف این پژوهش، بررسی تأثیر سرمایه‌گذاری در دارایی نامشهود در توضیح‏‌دهندگی تأثیر سلامت مالی و مشکلات نمایندگی در ارزش بازار شرکت در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران است. بدین‌منظور، پنج فرضیه برای بررسی این موضوع تدوین و داده‌های مربوط به 120 شرکت عضو بورس اوراق بهادار برای دورۀ زمانی بین سال‎های 1387 تا 1392 تجزیه و تحلیل شد. الگوی رگرسیون پژوهش با استفاده از روش داده­های تابلویی با رویکرد آثار ثابت، بررسی و آزمون شد. نتایج نشان داد دارایی نامشهود مناسب، به شرکت برای دستیابی موفقیت­‌آمیز به ریشه­های خلق ارزش کمک می‎کند؛ به عبارت دیگر، دارایی­های نامشهود، محرک اصلی رشد و ایجاد ارزش در بسیاری از بخش‏های اقتصادی است. افزون بر این، نتایج نشان داد دارایی نامشهود در توضیح‌دهندگی ارتباط بین سلامت مالی شرکت (متغیر عملکرد شرکت) و هزینۀ نمایندگی (سیاست توزیع سود) در ارزش بازار شرکت، تأثیر معناداری دارد. همچنین نتایج نشان داد دارایی نامشهود بر توضیح‌دهندگی تأثیر دو متغیر دیگر (قدرت پرداخت بدهی و نسبت بدهی) در ارزش بازار شرکت، تأثیر معناداری ندارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The aim of this study is to investigate the effect of investments in intangible assets in the explanatory impact of financial health and agency problems on the market value company&#039;s in the company at listed in the Tehran Stock Exchange. For this purpose five hypotheses are developed and data on the 120 companies in Tehran Stock Exchange for the period between the years 2009 to 2014 were analyzed. This regression model using panel data with fixed effects approach, reviews and tests. The results showed that the intangible asset helps to companies to create value. In other words, the results confirm that intangible assets the major driver for growth and value creation in many sectors of the economy. In addition, the results showed that intangible assets has a significant effect on the explanatory relationship between financial health of the company&#039;s (variable performance) and agency costs (profit distribution policy) on the company&#039;s market value. Also, the results indicate that the intangible asset on the explanatory impact other two variables (the solvency and debt) No significant effect on the market value of the company.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>11</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>28</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>جواد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نیک کار</Family>
						<NameE>Javad Nikkar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nikkar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکترای حسابداری، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکترای حسابداری، دانشگاه شهید چمران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>j.nickar@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>همت فر</Family>
						<NameE>Mahmod</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hemat far</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه حسابداری دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد بروجرد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه حسابداری دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>dr.hematfar@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مریم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>اعصامی</Family>
						<NameE>Maryam</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Esami</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد دانشگاه ازاد اسلامی واحد بروجرد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد دانشگاه ازاد اسلامی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mari2010esami.ma@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ارزش بازار شرکت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دارایی نامشهود</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سلامت مالی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مشکلات نمایندگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Aflatoni, A., &amp; Nikbakht, L. (2011). Econometrics application of Accounting Research, Financial Management and Economic Sciences, Tehran, Publications Termeh. (in Persian).##[2] Alves, S., &amp; Martins, J. (2010). The Impact of intangible assets on financial and governance policies: UK Evidence. International Research Journal of Finance &amp; Economics. (36): 147-169.##[3] Aulia, H., Fanani, Z., Prasetyo, K., &amp; Mardijuwono, W. (2013). The impact of intangible asset on firm’s competitive advantage and market value: Empirical Examination from Emerging Market. www.ssrn.com.##[4] Castro, W.B. (2014). The impact of intangible assets on the company&#039;s market value: A comparative analysis in the listed companies on Latin America and USA, http://ssrn.com/abstract=2496118.##[5] Chen, M.Y., Lin, J.Y., Hsiao, T.Y., &amp; Thomas, W.L. (2008). Censoring model for evaluating intellectual capital value drivers. Journal of Intellectual Capital. 9(4): 639-654.##[6] Esmailzadeh Mqry, A., Hematfar, M., &amp; Zamanian, A. (2010). The relationship between intellectual capital and indicators evaluating the performance of companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. Management Accounting. 3(6): 1-12. (in persian).##[7] Foster, B.P., Fletcher, R., &amp; Stout, W. D. (2003). Valuing intangible assets. The CPA Journal. October.PP.217-233.##[8] Garanina, T., &amp; Pavlova, Y. (2011). Intangible assets and value creation of a company: Russian and UK Evidence. Proceedings of the European Conference on Intellectual Capital. 165-175.##[9] Ghahraman Ezady, M., &amp; Behnameh, M. (2013). The relationship between intangible assets and market value of companies, the pharmaceutical industry Case Study of Tehran Stock Exchange, National Conference Accounting and Management. Institute of InternationalEducation and ResearchKharazmiSafashahr. (in persian).##[10] Holmstrom. (1989). Agency costs and innovation. Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization. 12(4): 305-327.##[11] Husnah., subroto, B., Aisjah, S., &amp; Djumahir. (2013). Intangible assets, competitive strategy and financial performance: Study On Rattan SMEs In Palu City Of Central Sulawesi (Indonesia). IOSR Journal of Business and Management, e-ISSN: 2278-487X. 7(4):14-27.##[12] Jensen, M.C., &amp; Meckling, W. (1976). Theory of the firm: Managerial behavior, agency costs and capital structure. Journal of FinancialEconomics. 3: 305–360.##[13] Kritsonis , A.(2005). Assessing a firms future financial health. International Journal of Scholarly Academic Intellectual Diversity. 8(1):##[14] Lev, B. (2001). Intangibles: Management, Measurement, and Reporting. Washington, D.C.: Brookings Institution Press.##[15] Lim, S,C., &amp; Macias, A,J. (2015). Intangible assets and capital structure. http://ssrn.com/abstract=2514551.##[16] Madhoshi, M., &amp; AsgharneJad Amiry, M. (2009). Measuring intellectual capital and assess its relationship with financial return companies, Reviews of Accounting and Auditing. 57: 101-116. (in persian).##[17] Russell, M. (2014). Capitalization of intangible assets and firm performance. The University of Queensland, pp.1-67.##[18] Martins, J., &amp; Alves, S. (2010). The impact of intangible assete on financial and governance policies: A Literature Review. Portuguese Journal of Management Studies. 15(1): 87-107.##[19] Matolcsy, Z., &amp; Wyatt, A. (2006). Capitalized intangibles and financial analysts. Accounting and Finance. 46: 457–479.##[20] McKnight, F., &amp; Weir, C. (2008). Agency costs, corporate governance mechanisms and ownership structure in large UK publicly quoted companies: A panel data analysis. The Quarterly Review of Economics and Finance.##[21] Nasif, F. (2013). The impact of value added intellectual coefficient components on financial health. Review of International Comparative Management. 14(3): 459-472.##[22] Noravesh, E., Karami, Gh., &amp; Vafi Sani, J. (2009). Examine the mechanisms of corporate governance on Agency Costs, Accounting Research. 1:1-27. (in persian).##[23] Oliveira, L., Rodrigues, L.L., &amp; Craig, R. (2010). Intangible assets and value relevance: evidence from the portuguese stock exchange. The BritishAccounting Review. 42(4): 241-252.##[24] Penman, S.H. (2009). Accounting for intangible assets: There is also an income statement. ABACUS. 45(3): 358-371.##[25] Petkov, R.R. (2011). The current financial crisis and its potential impact on internally generated intangible assets. International Journal of Business &amp; Management. 6(3): 37-44.##[26] Shams, Sh., &amp; Khalili, M. (2011). Relationship between intellectual capital and financial performance of companies listed on the stock exchange. PerspectiveFinancial Management and Accounting. 1: 51-65. (in Persian).##[27] Taghavi, M., &amp; Porali, M.R. (2010). Analysis of financial ratios in determining the different levels of the financial health of manufacturing units in Iran. Journal of Financial Studies. 8: 23-51. (in Persian).##[28] Whitwell, S. (2008). Intangible assets. Financial Management. 50-51.##[29] Widiantoro, D.M. (2012). Measuring the impact of intangible asset investment toward company financial health and company agency problem. ACRN Journal of Finance and Risk Perspectives. 1(2): 2224-9729.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>عوامل مؤثر در بازده سهام شرکت‏های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران: رویکرد فراتحلیل</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Factors Affecting Stock Return of Firms Listed in Tehran Stock Exchange: Meta-analysis Approach</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف این پژوهش، بررسی عوامل مؤثر در بازده سهام شرکت‏ها با به‌کارگیری روش فراتحلیل است. جامعۀ آماری پژوهش شامل مطالعاتی است که عوامل مؤثر در بازده سهام شرکت را در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران  بررسی کرده است. براساس این، درمجموع، 89 پژوهش مختلف انتخاب شد. براساس پیشینۀ پژوهش، عوامل مؤثر شامل نسبت‏های نقدینگی، اهرمی، فعالیت، سودآوری، بازار، جریان‏های نقدی، شاخص‏های ریسک، مدیریت سود، پیش‌بینی سود، سرمایه‌گذاری واقعی و ویژگی‏های شرکت در نظر گرفته شد. نتایج نشان داد نسبت‏های نقدینگی، اهرمی، فعالیت، مدیریت سود و ویژگی‏های شرکت در بازده سهام شرکت‏ها تأثیر نداشته است؛ اما تأثیر مثبت سایر عوامل یعنی نسبت‏های سودآوری شامل نرخ بازده حقوق صاحبان سهام، میزان سود و حاشیۀ سود، نسبت‏های بازار شامل بازده بازار، نسبت‏های جریان‏های نقدی شامل جریان‏های نقدی ناشی از عملیات، شاخص‏های ریسک شامل صرف ریسک، شاخص‏های پیش‌بینی سود شامل افق زمانی پیش‌بینی سود و در‌نهایت، سرمایه‌گذاری واقعی در بازده سهام تأیید شد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The purpose of this study is to investigate the factors influencing firms &#039;stock return using meta-analysis approach. The study population consists of studies that had examined factors affecting stock returns of listed firms in Tehran Stock Exchange. Accordingly, a total of 89 different research are selected. Based on the literature review, the following factors are considered; liquidity ratios, leverage ratios, activity ratios, profitability ratios, multiple ratios cash flow ratios, risk indicators, earning management indicator, earning forecast, real investment and firm characteristics. The results show that the effect of liquidity ratios, leverage ratios, activity ratios, earning management indicator and firm characteristics on stock return are not significant. But the positive effect of profitability ratios consists of return on equity, profit and profit margin, market-based ratios consist of market return, cash flow ratios consist of cash flow based on operations, risk indicators including market risk premium, indices of earning forecast including the time horizon of profit forecasts and eventually real investment are confirmed.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>29</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>50</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>باقر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عسگرنژاد نوری</Family>
						<NameE>Bagher</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Asgarnezhad Nouri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار مدیریت بازرگانی، گروه مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشکدۀ ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی، اردبیل، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار مدیریت بازرگانی، گروه مدیریت و اقتصاد،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>asgarnezhad.research@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بازده سهام</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>روش فراتحلیل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایه‏گذاری مالی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Abdoli, M. R., (2000). The relationship between dividends and stock return. Master Thesis. Faculty of Accounting and Management, University of Allameh Tabatabaei, Tehran.##[2] Abzari, M., Kabiri Pour, V., &amp; Soheili, S. (2013). Analyzing the effect of liquidity on stock return with control of investment styles: A new approach with multidimensional criteria. Journal of Accounting Knowledge. 4(15): 79-103.##[3] Ansari. A. M., Yousef Zadeh, N. &amp; Zare, Z. (2015). A parallel study of factors affecting capital structure and stock return in companies listed on the Tehran Stock Exchange. Accounting Research. 7(25): 28-41.##[4] Asgarnezhd Nouri, B., Moradi, M. &amp; Khaleghi, N. (2016). Product market power, industry structure, and corporate earnings management: Evidence from Tehran Stock Exchange. Asset Management and Financing. 4(2): 1-14.##[5] Asgarnezhad Nouri, B., Sanayei, A., Fathi, S., &amp; Kazemi, A. (2014). Meta-analysis of the mediating role of sample characteristics in the relationship between marketing activities and organizational performance. Management Research in Iran. 18(1): 151-169.##[6] Asgarnezhad, B., Sanayei, A., Fathi, S., &amp; Kazemi, A. (2015). The effect of marketing tactical capabilities on the financial performance of the firms: Meta-analysis approach. Iranian Journal of Management Studies. 8 (1): 73-96.##[7] Asgarnezhad Nouri, B. &amp; Soltani, M. (2016). Designing a bankruptcy prediction model based on account, market and macroeconomic variables (Case study: Cyprus Stock Exchange). Iranian Journal of Management Studies. 9(1): 125-147.##[8] Bagher Zadeh, S., (2005). Determinants of stock return in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Financial Research. 19: 25-64.##[9] Banze, R. W. (1981). The relationship between return and market value of common stocks. Journal of Financial Economics. 9: 3-18.##[10] Bazr Afshan, A., Hejazi, R., Rahmani, A. &amp; Bastani, S. (2015). Meta-analysis of auditing committee independency and financial reporting quality. Management Accounting. 8 (25): 101-117.##[11] Bildik, R., &amp; Gulay, G. (2000). Profitability of contrarian vs. momentum strategies: Evidence from the Istanbul Stock Exchange. International Review of Finance. 7(1-2): 61-87.##[12] Bronestein, M., Hedges, L., Higgins, J., &amp; Rothstein, H. (2004). Comprehensive meta-analysis manual. Available at: www.meta-analysis.com /downloads/meta-analysis-manual.pdf.##[13] Capon, N., &amp; Farley, J. U. (1990), Determinants of financial performance: A meta-analysis. Management Science, 36 (10): 1143-1159.##[14] Dastghir, M., &amp; Sharifi Mobarake, R., (2011). Examining relationship between cash flows with stock return. Journal of Auditing. 52: 1-5.##[15] Dostian, S. (2006). A comparison of net income and operating cash flow changes with changes in stock returns of companies listed on the Tehran Stock Exchange. Master Thesis. Faculty of Social Sciences and Economics, University of Al-Zahra, Tehran.##[16] Fama, E. F., &amp; French, K. R. (1992). The cross-section of expected stock returns. The Journal of Finance, 47 (2): 427-465.##[17] Fatehi, S. (2016). Examining the effect of financial reporting quality on abnormal stock return fluctuations in companies listed on the Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Management and Accounting Studies. 2(1): 111-119.##[18] Fathi, S. (2007). Explaining a model of determinants of relationship between information technology and financial performance of business firms: A meta-analysis approach. PhD Thesis. Faculty of Humanities, University of Tarbiat Modares, Tehran.##[19] Fathi, S., Abzari, M., &amp; Habibi, S. (2014). Mata-analysis of capital structure determinants in firm level. Asset Management and Finacing. 2(4): 55-74.##[20] Fujimoto, A., &amp; Masahiro W. (2006). Time-varying liquidity risk and the cross section of stock returns. Available at: http://papers.ssrn.com/id=906327.##[21] Ghaemi, M. H., Livani, A. J., &amp; Dehbozorghi, S. (2008). Earning quality and stock return of firms. Journal of The Accounting and Auditing Review. 52: 71-88.##[22] Ghoudarzi, A. (2005). Analytical review of the relationship between financial ratios and stock returns of companies listed on the Tehran Stock Exchange. Master Thesis. Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch, Tehran.##[23] Ghrobani Zadeh, V. A., &amp; Hassan Nanghir, S. T. (2013). Practical guide of meta-analysiswith CMA2 software. Tehran: Sociologists Publications.##[24] Graham, J. R., &amp; Harvey, C. R. (2001). The theory and practice of corporate finance: Evidence from the field. Journal of Financial Economics 60: 187-243.##[25] Habib, A. (2008). The role of accruals and cash flows in explaining security returns. Journal of International Accounting, Auditing and Taxation, 17: 51-66.##[26] Hirshleifer, D., Kewei, H.. &amp; Siew, H. T. (2009). Accruals, cash flows, and aggregate stock returns. Journal of Financial Economics, 91 (3): 389-406.##[27] Hsieh, S. (2014). The causal relationships between stock returns, trading volume, and volatility. International Journal of Managerial Finance. 10(2): 218 – 240.##[28] Hunter, J., &amp; Schmidt, F. (2004), Methods of meta-analysis: Correcting error and bias in research findings. Beverly Hills CA: Sage.##[29] Inaam, Z. &amp; Khamoussi, H. (2016). Audit committee effectiveness, audit quality and earnings management: a meta-analysis. International Journal of Law and Management, 58 (2): 179 – 196.##[30] Khodadad Hosseini, S. H., Fathi. S., &amp; Elahi, S. (2006). Explaining a model of information technology effect on financial performance criteria with meta-analysis approach. Journal of The Accounting and Auditing Review. 46: 61-70.##[31] Lam, K. S. K. (2002). The relationship between size, book-to-market equity ratio. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, 31 (2): 455-475.##[32] Li, G. (2016). Growth options, dividend payout ratios and stock returns. Studies in Economics and Finance. 33(4): 638 – 659.##[33] Lonkani, R., &amp; Firth, M. (2005). The accuracy of IPO earnings forecasts in Thailand and their relationships with stock market valuation. Journal of Accounting and Business Research, 35: 269-286.##[34] Mazuruse, P. (2014). Canonical correlation analysis. Journal of Financial Economic Policy, 6 (2): 179-196.##[35] Mehrani, S., Mehrani, K., &amp; Karami, G. R. (2004). Using of historical financial and nonfinancial information to distinguish successful and unsuccessful firms. Journal of The Accounting and Auditing Review. 38: 77-92.##[36] Mosavi Zadeh, M. (2014). Factors affecting stock returns after the initial release in Tehran Stock Exchange by aggregate looking to variables and emphasis on Fama and French Three-Factor Model. Master Thesis. Shahrood University of Technology. Semnan.##[37] Reza Zadeh, J., &amp; Ashtab, A. (2010). The relationship between the accuracy of earnings forecasts and stock returns of newly listed firms in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Economics Science. 9(1): 55-76.##[38] Rosenberg, B., Reid, K., &amp; Lanstein, R. (1985). Persuasive evidence of market inefficiency. Journal of Portfolio Management, 11: 9-17.##[39] Rosenthal, R., &amp; Dematteo, M. R. (2001). Meta-analysis: Recent developments in quantitative cumulation methods. Advances in Measurement and Data Analysis, San Francisco: Jossey-Bass.##[40] Safdar, R. &amp; Yan, C. (2016). Information risk, stock returns, and the cost of capital in China. China Finance Review International. 6(1): 77 - 95.##[41] Shawn, M. F., Phillip, D., &amp; Rumrill, J. R. (2003). Meta-analysis as a tool for understanding existing research literature. Journal: Work, 21 (1): 97–103.##[42] Souissi, M., &amp; Khlif , H. (2012). Meta-analytic review of disclosure level and cost of equity capital. International Journal of Accounting &amp; Information Management, 20(1), 49 – 62.##[43] Zamari, R., (2007). The relationship between financial ratios based on cash flows and stock returns in Tehran Stock Exchange. Master Thesis. Faculty of Accounting and Management, University of Allameh Tabatabaei, Tehran.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>الگوسازی عملکرد سیستم مالی با استفاده از رویکرد پویایی‌شناسی سیستمی (شرکت تولیدکنندۀ شن و ماسه)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Modeling Performance of Financial System Using System Dynamics Approach: A Case Study on a Sand and Gravel Firm</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>سنجش عملکرد مالی، ابزار مهمی برای ارزیابی و هدایت راهبردها، پروژه‌ها و تصمیم‌های راهبردی سازمان‌ها شناخته شده است. از آنجا که ارزیابی عملکرد مالی، ابعادی چندگانه و ماهیتی پویا و وابسته به زمان دارد، این پژوهش با استفاده از رویکرد پویایی‌شناسی سیستمی و به‌کارگیری نرم‌افزار Vensim DSS در یک افق 15ساله، عملکرد سیستم مالی شرکت تولیدکنندۀ شن و ماسه‌ای (سهامی خاص) را الگوسازی و شبیه‌سازی می‌کند که قصد افزایش ظرفیت تولیدی را دارد. درواقع، هدف اصلی پژوهش، ارزیابی مقرون به صرفه بودن افزایش ظرفیت تولیدی نسبت به ظرفیت فعلی شرکت و شناخت سناریوهای مناسب برای بهبود عملکرد سیستم مالی است. نتایج پژوهش نشان داد پروژۀ افزایش ظرفیت تولیدی مقرون به صرفه است. سناریوهای جسورانه و میانه‌روی مدیریت حساب‌های دریافتنی و پرداختنی در وضعیت فعلی و سناریوهای محافظه‌کار و میانه‌رو در وضعیت افزایش ظرفیت تولیدی، به روند افزایشی متغیرهای سیستم مالی منجر می‌شود. کارشناسان مالی می‌توانند از الگوی مدّنظر به‌عنوان ابزاری برای حمایت و پشتیبانی از برنامه‌های توسعۀ شرکت و مدیریت عملکرد سیستم مالی استفاده کنند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Financial performance measurement has been known as an important tool for assessing and guiding strategies, projects, and strategic decisions of organizations. Since assessment of financial performance is multidimensional, dynamic, and time-dependent, system dynamics approach is used in this study. Considering a 15-year horizon, this study, using this approach and application Vensim DSS software models and simulates the performance of the financial system of a sand and gravel firm (private joint stock company) which is going to increase its productive capacity. The main purpose of this study is to assess and analyze the investment project for increasing productive capacity and its cost effectiveness. On the other hand, receivable and payable accounts are analyzed and assessed to improve the performance of the financial system. The results suggest that increasing the productive capacity is affordable project. Further, aggressive and moderate scenarios for management of receivable and payable accounts in current situation and conservative and moderate scenarios in increasing productive capacity situation lead to an increase in the financial system variables. Financial experts can use this model as a tool for supporting the company’s development programs and for managing the performance of its financial system.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>51</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>72</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علینقی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مصلح شیرازی</Family>
						<NameE>Alinaghi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mosleh Shirazi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت، دانشکده اقتصاد، علوم اجتماعی و مدیریت، دانشگاه شیراز، شیراز، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت، دانشکده اقتصاد، علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>an_mosleh@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>بهاره</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ملکی</Family>
						<NameE>Bahareh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Maleki</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت سیستم ها، بخش مدیریت ، دانشکده اقتصاد، علوم اجتماعی و مدیریت دانشگاه شیراز، شیراز، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت سیستم ها، بخش مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>itm.maleki@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مجتبی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خلیفه</Family>
						<NameE>Mojtaba</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khalifeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت سیستم ها،  بخش مدیریت دانشکده مدیریت اقتصاد، علوم اجتماعی و مدیریت دانشگاه شیراز، شیراز، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت سیستم ها،  بخش مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m_khalifeh@shirazu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>امیر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رمضانی مقدم</Family>
						<NameE>Amir</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ramezani Moghadam</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد حسابداری،  گروه حسابداری، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، قائنات، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد حسابداری،  گروه حسابداری، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>amirram97@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ارزش فعلی خالص</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پویایی‌شناسی سیستمی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جریان نقدی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خالص سرمایه در گردش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Abor, J. Y. (2017). Evaluating Capital Investment Decision, Capital Budgeting. In Entrepreneurial Finance for MSMEs. Springer International Publishing.‌##[2] Alborzi, M., Porzarandi, M. A., &amp; Shariari, M. (2010). Management of resources and expenditure in banks with a dynamic systems approach. Journal of Financial Engineering and Management of Exchange. 2(6): 41-59. (In Persian).##[3] Alborzi, M., Dadras, K., &amp; Gharakhani, D. (2005). Developing a system dynamics model for cash management in firms. Journal of Management and Development. 23: 53-62. (In Persian).##[4] Alshatti, A. S. (2015). The effect of the liquidity management on profitability in the Jordanian commercial banks. International Journal of Business and Management.10 (1): 62-72.##[5] Azhar, S. (2015). Impact of liquidity and management efficiency on profitability: a study of selected power distribution utilities in India. Journal of Entrepreneurship, Business and Economics. 3(1): 31-49.##[6] Chaim, R. M. (2007). Dynamic stochasticity in the control of liquidity in asset and liability management (ALM) for pension funds. Boston, Massachusetts, USA, www.systemdynamics.org.##[7] Chen, L., Liaw, S., &amp; Shin Chen, Y. (2001). Using financial factors to investigate productivity: An empirical study in Taiwan. Industrial Management &amp; Data Systems. 101(7): 378–384.##[8] Eljelly, A. M. (2004). Liquidity-profitability tradeoff: An empirical investigation in an emerging market. International Journal of Commerce and Management. 14(2): 48-61.##[9] Forrester, J. W., &amp; Brink, H. M. (1999). Industrial Dynamics.Students edition, MIT Press.##[10] Ghodratiyan Kashan, J., &amp; Anvari Rostami, A. (2004). Model for performance assessment and ranking. Journal of Human Sciences Modares. 8(36): 109-134. (In Persian).##[11] Gouws, D. G., &amp; Lucouw, P. (2000). A dynamic balance model for analysts and managers, Meditari Accountancy Research. 8(1): 25–45.##[12] Halawa, W. S., Abdelalim, A. M., &amp; Elrashed, I. A. (2013). Financial evaluation program for construction projects at the pre-investment phase in developing countries: A case study. International Journal of Project Management. 31(6): 912-923.##[13] Hou W., Liu X., &amp; Chen D. (2011). Payment problems, cash flow and profitability of construction project: A system dynamics model. World Academy of Science, Engineering and Technology. 5(10): 10-23.##[14] Khalili O. S. (2003). Assessing the financial performance strategies of Stock Exchange companies of Tehran applying multi-criteria decision-making techniques in a fuzzy environment. Development of Monetary and Banking Management Quarterly. 1(1): 36-53. (In Persian).##[15] Malekijafariyan. M., &amp; Mohseni, M. R. (2015). Financial and economic evaluation of wastewater projects for producing usable sewage in irrigation and industry. Journal of Water and Sustainable Development. 1(3): 1-8. (In Persian).##[16] Mansori, A., &amp; Bagheri, A. (2005). Assessing financial performances and rankings of pharmaceutical companies listed in the Stock Exchange of Tehran using a hybrid model of fuzzy and VIKOR analytic hierarchy processes. Health Accounting Quarterly. 4(3): 86-107. (In Persian).##[17] Mousavi Haghighi, M. H., &amp; Khalifeh, M. (2015). Simulating the effect of financial leverage model on company value via system dynamics approach. Asset Management and Financing. 3: 83-104. (In Persian).##[18] Mousavi Haghighi, M. H., Khalifeh, M., Safaei, B., &amp; Saberi, H. (2015). Simulating of stock price from the point of effective internal and external factors via system dynamics approach. Asset Management and Financing. 4(4): 79-98. (In Persian).##[19] Mobaraki A., Fadayehosseini Maleki, M., &amp; Kholafazadeh Asetmal, S. (2013). Relationship between working capital management and financial performance (Tehran Stock Exchange). Journal of Basic and Applied Scientific Research. 3(9): 201-207. (In Persian).##[20] Nair, G. K., &amp; Rodrigues, L. (2013). Dynamics of financial system: A system dynamic approach. International Journal of Economics and Financial Issues. 3(1): 14-26.##[21] Nobanee, H., &amp; Hajar M. A. (2009). Working capital management, operating cash flow and corporate performance. International Journal of Strategic Management. 10(1): 84-88.##[22] Paul, F., &amp; Jim, B. (2005). A review of performance measurement: Towards performance management. Computers Industry. 56: 663-680.##[23] Pedram, M., Shirin Bakhsh, Sh., &amp; Zavarian, Z. (2007). Forecast bank&#039;s cash flow to determine the liquidity gap. Journal of Financial Studies. 1(2): 1-36. (In Persian).##[24] Peterson, D. W., &amp; Blanc, M. (2012). Money Multiplier Dynamics and Banking Liquidity Cycles##St. Gallen, Switzerland, www.system dynamics.org.##[25] Roy, K. R., &amp; Saroj, K. (1997). Financial performance appraisal of a Steel Planet. A SD model, ed proceeding by Yaman B et al. 15th International System Dynamics Conference. Istanbul, August.19-22.##[26] Savolainen, J., Collan, M., &amp; Luukka, P. (2016). Combining system dynamic modeling and the datar–mathews method for analyzing metal mine investments. Acta Universitatis Palackianae Olomucensis. Facultas Rerum Naturalium. Mathematica. 55(1): 95-110.##[27] Shehata, H. (1977). Systems dynamics and cash flow planning: A model for accountants. Management Decision. 15 (1): 19 – 35.##[28] Sheikh Khozani, Z., Hosseiny, K., &amp; Rahimian, M. (2010). System dynamic modeling of multipurpose reservoir operation to estimate the optimal height of the dam. Journal of Modeling in Engineering. 8(21): 57-66. (In Persian).##[29] Sobel, M. J., Szmerekovsky, J.G., &amp; Tilson, V. (2009). Scheduling projects with stochastic activity duration to maximize expected net present value. European Journal of Operational Research. 198: 697–705.##[30] Srijariya, W., Riewpaiboon, A., &amp; Chaikledkaew, U. (2008). System dynamic modeling: an alternative method for budgeting. Value in Health.11(s1): S115-S123.##[31] Sterman. J. (2000). Business Dynamics: Systems Thinking and Modeling for A Complex World. NY, McGraw-Hill publication.##[32] Trebuňa, P., Petriková, A., Pekarčíková, M., Petrik, M., &amp; Popovič, R. (2017). Economic evaluation of investment project in the area of sheet metal processing. Metalurgija. 56(1-2): 245-248.##[33] Theil, H. (1966). Applied Economic Forecasting. Amsterdam, North Holland Publishing.##[34] Uzma, S. H., Singh, J. P., &amp; Kumar, N. (2010). Discounted cash flow and its implication on intangible valuation. Global Business Review. 11(3): 365-377.##[35] Wang, Y. J. (2002). Liquidity management operating performance and corporate value: evidence from Japan and Taiwan. Journal of Multinational Financial Management. 12(12): 159-169.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر ساختار سرمایه بر نرخ بازده دارایی‌ها و ارزش افزودۀ اقتصادی با توجه به شدت رقابت در بازار محصول در صنعت (مطالعه موردی شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Examination of Relationship between Stock Systematic Risk and Skewness of Returns Studying the Effect of Capital Structure on the Return on Assets and Economic Value Added by Attention to Intensity of Product Market Competition in the Industry (Case Study of Companies Listed in Tehran Stock Exchange)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>ایجاد ارزش برای سهامداران از اهداف مهم شرکت­ها است و هنگامی محقق می­شود که شرکت­ها سلامت مالی داشته باشند. ساختار تأمین مالی که یکی از مهم‌ترین تصمیم‌های مدیران است، در رفتار شرکت­ها در بازار محصول، تلاش آنها برای رقابت و درنهایت، در بازده­‌های رقابتی تأثیر می­گذارد. توجه به بازار رقابت در تعیین روش تأمین مالی مناسب در افزایش بازده شرکت­ها اهمیت دارد. در این پژوهش، رابطۀ ساختار سرمایه و عملکرد شرکت­ها بررسی و توجه ویژه‌ای به رقابت در بازار محصول در صنایع شده است. نتایج بررسی داده­های مالی برگرفته از صورت­های مالی 81 شرکت تولیدی در بازده زمانی 1388 – 1393 با به‌کارگیری نرم افزار استتا 11 نشان‌دهندۀ تأثیر منفی اهرم مالی در نرخ بازده دارایی­ها است. اثر تعدیل‌کنندگی رقابت بازار محصول در رابطۀ اهرم مالی و نرخ بازده دارایی­ها، منفی و معنادار است؛ اما اثر تعدیل‌کنندگی رقابت در بازار محصول در رابطۀ منفی بین اهرم مالی و ارزش افزودۀ اقتصادی، مثبت و معنادار است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Creating value for stockholders is one of the important objectives of the companies, and will be realized when the firm enjoy financial health. Financing structure –as one of the important managerial decisions, affect the firms` behavior in product market, their efforts to compete, and finally their competitive return. In financing decisions, it’s important to concern about market competition to achieve target return. In this study we examined the effect of capital structure on firm performance concerning product market competition. The sample includes 81 manufacturing companies listed in Tehran Stock Eschnage, and the time period includes 2009-2014. The results show negative effect of financial leverage on ROA. Also the mediation role of capital market competition is negative and significant. But this mediation role is significantlye positive when the dependent variable is economic value added.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>73</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>88</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سعید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سعیدا اردکانی</Family>
						<NameE>Saeid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Saeida Ardakani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشکده اقتصاد، مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه یزد، یزد، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشکده اقتصاد،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>dr.saeida@yazd.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مینو</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ایزدی</Family>
						<NameE>Minoo</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Izadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی- مالی، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشکده اقتصاد، مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه یزد، یزد، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی- مالی، گروه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.ezadi67@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فاطمه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ایزدی</Family>
						<NameE>Fatemeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Izadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی- مالی، گروه مدیریت، دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصاد، دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی- مالی، گروه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.ezadi90@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ارزش افزودۀ اقتصادی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رقابت بازار محصول</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ساختار سرمایه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عملکرد شرکت‌ها</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Ali Shah٫ S. Z., &amp; Ali Butt٫ S. (2011). Impact of leverage on performance of firms: Evidence from Pakistan. The Busines Review Cambridge. 19: 187-194.##[2] Anvary Rostamy, A. A., Tehrani,R., &amp; Seraji, H. ( 2004). The investigation the relationship between the economic value added, earning before interest and taxes (ebit) , cash from operation (ceo) with share market value (mv) of the listed companies in Tehran Stock Exchange .Journal of The Accounting And Auditing Review. 11(3): 65-91. (in persian).##[3] Asadi , M., &amp; Sadriani , M .( 2015). The effect of firm size, beta and financial leverage on the performance of selected companies in tehran stock exchange (the breakdown of industrial groups). Journal of Economic Modeling  Research . 5( 19):149-174. (in persian).##[4] Balakrishnane, S., &amp; Fox, I. (1993). Asset specificity, firm heterogeneity and financial leverage.Strategic Management Journal. 14(1):3-16.##[5] Bandyopadhya, A., &amp; Malini Barua, N. (2016). Factors determining capital structure and corporate performance in India: Studying the business cycle effects. The Quarterly Review of Economics and Finance. 61: 160–172.## [6] Boone, J., Van Ours, J. C. &amp; Van der Wiel, H. (2007). How (Not) To Measure Competition (Tilec Discussion Paper No. 2007-014.##[7] Campelllo, M. (2003).Capital structure and product market interaction: Evidence from business cycles. Journal of Financial Economics. 68: 353-378.## [8] Daghani, R., Etemadi, H., Azizkhani, M., &amp; Anvary Rostamy, A. (2015).The financing decisions and managerial market timing evidence from tehran stock exchange. Journal of Asses Management And Financing. 3(3):21-36. (in persian).##[9] Fosu, S. (2013). Capital structure, product market competition and firm performance: Evidence from south Africa. The Quarterly Review of Economics and Finance, 53(2): 140-151.##[10] Goel, U., Chadha, S., &amp; Sharma, A. (2015). Operating liquidity and financial leverage: Evidences from indian machinery industryoriginal research article .Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences.189: 344-350.##[11] González, V. M. (2013). Leverage and corporate performance: international evidence, International Review of Economics and Finance. 25: 169–184.##[12] Googerdchian, A., Hassan Heidary Soltanabadi, H., &amp; Mtofares, Z. (2017). Theoretical and Empirical Analysis of the Effect of Comparative Influence of Market Production on Stock Returns of Companies Listed in the Tehran Stock Exchange. The Quarterly Journal  Of Asset Management And Financing. 5(1): 31-44. (in persian).##[13] Gord, A., Vaghfi, H., &amp; Fakouri, M . (2015). Examine relationsheep between measures of financial leverage (capital structure) and measure of performance. Journal of Accounting Research. 4(4): 1-18. (in persian).##[14] Gu, L. (2016). Product market competition, R &amp; D investment, and stock returns,Journal of Financial Economics. 119(2): 441–455.##[15] Guiarati, D. (2008). Basic Econometrics. Translated by Abrishami. H. Univercity of Tehran Press, 10th edition .##[16] Guney, Y., Li, L., &amp; Fairchild, R. (2011). The relationship between product market competition and capital structure in Chines listed firms. International Review of Financial Analysis. 20: 41-51.##[17] Haushalter, D., Klasa, S., &amp;Mamaxwel, W. F. (2007). The influence of product market dynamics on a firm cash holdings and heding behavior. Jurnal of Financial Economics, 84: 797- 825.##[18] HekmatiFarid, S., Mohammadzadeh, Y., &amp; Khazali, D. (2016).The impact of business regulatory reforms and intellectual property rightsgrowth in upper middle income countries on economics, Quarterly Journal of Economic Growth and Development Research. 6(22):119-130. (in persian).##[19] Horngren, C. T., Datar, S. M., &amp; Foster , G. (2006). Cost Accounting: A Managerial Emphasis. 12 th Edition, New Jersey: Prentice-Hall, Inc.##[20] Istaitieh, A., &amp; Rodriguez, J. M. (2006) .Factor- product markets and firm’s capital structure: A literature review.Review of Financia Economics. 15: 49-75.##[21] Jensen, M. G., &amp; Meckling, W. H. (1976 (.Theory of the firm: Managerial behavior, agency costs, and ownership structure. Journal of Financial Economics. 3(4(:305- 360.##[22] Jermias٫ J. (2008). The relative influence of competitive intensity and business strategy on the relationship between financial leverage and performance.The British Accounting Review. 40: 71-86.##[23] Kashani, M., &amp; Rasaiian, A. (2010). The relationship between tobin&#039;s Q and criteria for evaluating the performance of companies in Iran. Quarterly Financial Accounting.3: 131-146. (in persian).##[24] Khodamipoor, A., &amp; Esmaeili, A. (2011). Value-relevance of changes in financial leverage for explaining operating performance. Journal  of Accounting Knowledge. 2(6): 65-91. (in persian).##[25] Lousuth, S. (2008). The Strategic Use of Corporate Debt Under Product Market Competition, Theory And Evidence. A thesis submitted to the degree of doctor of Philosophy University of Bath School of Management.##[26] Lubatkin, M., &amp; Chatterjee, S.(1994). Extending modern portfolio theory into the domain of corporate diversification: Dose it apply?, Academy of Management Journal. 37:109- 136.##[27] Margariti, D. &amp; Psillaki, M. (2010). Capital structure, equity ownership and firm performance. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance. 34: 621–632.##[28] Mashayekh, S., &amp; Abdollahi, M. (2013). Investigating the relation between ownership concentration, firm performance and dividend policy in the companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. Financial Accounting Researches. 3(4):71-86. (in persian).##[29] Nikbakht, M. R., &amp; Paykani, M. (2010). Review the relationship between capital structure and accounting and market performance assessment companies accepted in Stock Exchange.Journal of Financial Research. 11( 28): 89-104. (in persian).##[30] O٫ Brien٫ J. P. (2003). The financial leverage implications of pursuing a strategy of innovation. Strategic Management Journal. 24: 415-431.##[31] Pandy, I. M. (2004) . Capital stracture , profitability and market structure: evidence from Malasia, Asia Pacific Journal of Economics and Business. 8(2): 78- 91.##[32] Rajnoha, R., Sujova, A., &amp; Dobrovic, J. (2012). Management and economics of business processes added value. Procedia – Social and Behavioral Sciences. 62: 1292 – 129.##[33] Rathinasami , R . S., Krishnaswamy , C. R., &amp; Mantripragada, K. G. ( 2000) . Capital structure and product market interaction: An international perspective. Global Business and Finance Review. 5(2): 51- 63.##[34] Rezaee Panderi, A. (2009). The Relationship Between Economic Value And Risks of Listed Companies In Tehran Stock Exchange. M. A thesis at University of Isfahan.##[35] Salim, M., &amp; Yadav, R. (2012). Capital structure and firm performance: Evidence from Malaysian listed companies,Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences. 65: 156 – 166.##[36] Sarlak, N., &amp; Mirzaie, F. (2017). The relation between market competition and dividend policies. The Quarterly Journal  Of Asset Management And Financing. 4(40): 45-60. (in persian).## [37] Wet, J., &amp; Hall, J. H. (2004). The relationship between EVA, MVA and leverage, Meditari Accountancy Research. 12(1): 39- 59.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر بیش ‌اطمینانی مدیریت در ساختار سررسید بدهی در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Effect of Managerial Overconfidence on Debt Maturity Structure in Listed Companies in Tehran Stock Exchange</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>سیاست‌های تأمین مالی که مدیران اتخاذ می‌کنند، نقش مهمی در ریسک و ایجاد ثروت برای سهامداران دارد؛ بنابراین شناخت عوامل مؤثر در تصمیم‌های تأمین مالی مدیران، اهمیت بسیاری دارد. بیش­اطمینانی از مهم‌ترین ویژگی­های شخصیتی مدیران است که در ریسک­پذیری تأثیر دارد. مدیران بیش­اطمینان به‌دلیل اعتماد به نفس کاذب، بازده­های آتی پروژه­های واحد تجاری را بیشتر برآورد می­کنند؛ از این‌رو، ممکن است احتمال وقوع و تأثیر شوک­های مثبت جریان­های نقدی آتی حاصل از این پروژه­ها را بیشتر برآورد کنند و درمقابل، برآورد کمتری از شوک­های منفی داشته باشند. آنان معتقدند واحدهای تجاری تحت مدیریتشان در بازار سرمایه، کمتر از واقع ارزش­گذاری شده‌اند و با انتخاب بدهی با سررسید کوتا‌­تر، ثروت سهامداران را افزایش می‌دهند. هدف پژوهش حاضر، بررسی تأثیر یک عامل روان‌شناسی (بیش­اطمینانی مدیریت) در ساختار سررسید بدهی است. جامعة آماری پژوهش را شرکت­های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در سال­های 1386 تا 1393 تشکیل می­دهد. در این پژوهش برای اندازه­گیری بیش­اطمینانی مدیریت از دو سنجه مبتنی بر سوگیری مدیران در پیش­بینی سود و تصمیم‌های سرمایه­گذاری مدیران استفاده شده است. نتایج پژوهش نشان می­دهد بیش­اطمینانی مدیریت، تأثیر مثبت معناداری در ساختار سررسید بدهی دارد و شرکت‌های با مدیران بیش­اطمینان، با انتخاب درصد بیشتری از بدهی کوتاه­مدت، ساختار سررسید بدهی کوتاه­تری اتخاذ می­کنند و ریسک نقدشوندگی مربوط به این سیاست تأمین مالی، آنان را از این رفتار باز نمی­دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Financing policies made by managers can play a key role in the risk and wealth creation for stochkholders. However, identifying effective factors in managers` financing decisions is of great importance. Overconfidence is one of the most important personality traits of managers. Overconfidence is effective in risk taking. Overconfident managers overestimate future returns of business projects due to false confidence. Therefore, they might overestimate the likelihood and impact of positive shocks of future cash flows for these projects. Meanwhile, they may underestimate the negative shocks. They believe that their business entities have been undervalued in the capital market and can choose shorter maturity debt and increase shareholder wealth. They prefer to issue bonds rather than stocks. This study aims to examine the effect of a psychological factor (managerial overconfidence) on debt maturity structure. The sample consisted of selected companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange from 2007 to 2014. Two scales which are based on managers` bias to forecast earnings and investment decisions are employed to measure the managerial overconfidence. The results show that managerial overconfidence has a positive and significant effect on debt maturity structure. Overconfident managers take shorter debt maturity structure by applying higher percentage of short-term debt. Liquidity risk related to this financing policy would not prevent them from such behavior.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>89</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>106</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مسعود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حسنی القار</Family>
						<NameE>Masoud</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hasani Alghar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>مربی گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم انسانی، دانشگاه بزرگمهر قائنات، قائن، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>مربی گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم انسانی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>acc.hasani@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نظام الدین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رحیمیان</Family>
						<NameE>Nezamoddin</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rahimian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه حسابرسی، دانشکده علوم انسانی، دانشگاه خاتم، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه حسابرسی، دانشکده علوم انسانی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>norahimian@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بیش‌اطمینانی مدیریت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ریسک نقدشوندگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ساختار سررسید بدهی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قیمت‌گذاری نادرست</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Abor, J. (2007). Agency theories determinants of debt levels: Evidence from Ghana. Review of Accounting and Finance. 7(2): 183-192.##[2] Ahmed, A. S., &amp; Duellman, S. (2013). Managerial overconfidence and accounting conservatism. Journal of Accounting Research. 51(1): 1-30.##[3] Alcock, J., Finn F. C., &amp; Kelvin J. T. (2010). The determinants of debt maturity in Australian firms, Accounting &amp; Finance, Forthcoming, available at: http://ssrn.com/abstract=1728565.##[4] Ben-David, I. Graham, J., &amp; Harvey, C. (2010). Managerial miscalibration. National Bureau of Economic Research. Working Paper Series No. 16215. Available in: http://www.nber.org/papers/w16215.##[5] Bertrand, M., &amp; Schoar, A. (2003). Managing with style: The effect of managers on firm policies. Quarterly Journal of Economics. 118(4): 301–330.##[6] Blue, G., &amp; Hasani Alghar, M. (2015). Examining managerial overconfidence effect on earnings smoothing in companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange, Journal of Accounting Knowledge. 6(21): 33-56 [in Persian].##[7] Campbell, T. C., Gallmeyer, M., Johnson, S. A., Rutherford, J., &amp; Stanley, B. W. (2011). CEO optimism and forced turnover. Journal of Financial Economics, 101(3): 695-712.##[8] Chavoshi, K., Rastegar, M., &amp; Mirzaee, M. (2015). Examination of the relation between managerial overconfidence and financing policies in Tehran stock exchange. Financial Knowledge of Securities Analysis. 8(25): 1-136 (in Persian).##[9] Chen, S., Lai, S., Liu, C., &amp; McVay, S. (2014). Overconfident managers and internal controls. Working paper. National Taiwan University and University of Washington, Available at SSRN: https://ssrn.com/abstract=2510137 or http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.2510137##[10] Chen, I. Ju., &amp; Lin, S. (2012). Will managerial optimism affect the investment efficiency of a firm? 2nd Annual International Conference on Accounting and Finance (AF 2012). Procedia Economics and Finance. 2:73 – 80.##[11] Duellman, S., Hurwitz, H., &amp; Sun, Y. (2015). Managerial overconfidence and audit fees. Journal of Contemporary Accounting &amp; Economics. 11(2): 148-165.##[12] Fallahshams, M., Ghalibaf Asl, H., &amp; Nobakht Saraei, S. (2010). The impact of experience on risktaking, overconfidence and herding of investment companies’ managers. Journal of Securities Exchange, 12: 25-42 (in Persian).##[13] Fan, JP.H. Titman, S., &amp; Twite, G. (2010). An international comparison of capital structure and debt maturity choices. NBER working paper series, Working Paper 16445, available at: http://www.nber.org/papers/w16445,National Bureau of Economic Research.##[14] Gomariz, M, C., &amp; Ballesta, J, P. (2013). Financial reporting quality, debt maturity and investment efficiency. Journal of Banking and Finance, 40: 494-506.##[15] Greene, W. (2011). Econometric Analysis. Seventh ED. United states of America: Prentice-hall publication.##[16] Gujarati, D. N., &amp; Porter, D. C. (2009). Basic Econometrics. McGraw-Hill International student edition.##[17] Hackbarth, D. (2008). Managerial traits and capital structure decisions. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis. 43 (4): 843–882.##[18] Hajiha, Z., &amp; Akhlaghi, H. (2013). The Investigation of the board characteristics&#039; effect on firm debt maturity structure. Management Accounting. 17(2): 59-74 [in Persian].##[19] Hashemi, S. A., Samadi, S., &amp; Hadian, R. (2014). The effect of financial reporting quality and maturity of debt on investment efficiency. Empirical Studies in Financial Accounting Quarterly. 11: 117-143. (in Persian).##[20] Hay, D. C., Knechel, W. R., &amp; Wong, N. (2006). Audit fees: a meta-analysis of the effect of supply and demand attributes. Contemporary Accounting Research. 23 (1), 141-191.##[21] Heaton, J. (2002). Managerial optimism and corporate finance. Financial Management. 31(2): 33– 45.##[22] Hsieh, T., Bedard, J. C., &amp; Johnstone, K. M. (2014). CEO overconfidence and earnings management during shifting regulatory regimes. Journal of Business Finance &amp; Accounting. 41(9)(10): 1243-1268.##[23] Huang, R., Tan, K., &amp; Faff, R. W. (2016). CEO overconfidence and corporate debt maturity. Journal of Corporate Finance. (36): 93-110.##[24] Ishikawa, H., &amp; Takahashi, K. (2010). Overconfident managers and external financing choice. Review of behavioral finance. 2(1): 37–58.##[25] Kim, J. B., Wang, Z., &amp; Zhang, L. (2014). CEO overconfidence and stock price crash risk. Working Paper, Availble: Http://www.ssrn.com.##[26] Kirch, G., &amp; Terra, P.R. (2012). Determinants of corporate debt maturity in South America: Do institutional quality and financial development matter? Journal of Corporate Finance. 18(4): 980-993.##[27] Korner, P. (2007). The determinants of corporate debt maturity structure: evidence from czech firms, finance an úver - Czech Journal of Economics and Finance. 57(3-4): 142-158.##[28] Libby, R., &amp; Rennekamp, K. (2012). Self-serving attribution bias, overconfidence, and the issuance of management forecasts. Journal of Accounting Research. 50(1): 197-231.##[29] Lin, Y. H., Hu, S. Y., &amp; Chen, M. S. (2005). Managerial optimism and corporate investment: Some empirical evidence from Taiwan. Pacific-Basin Finance Journal. 13(5): 523-546.##[30] Madan, K. (2007). An analysis of the debt-equity structure of leading hotel chains in India. International Journal of Contemporary Hospitality Management. 19(5): 397-414.##[31] Malmendier, U. &amp; Tate, G. (2005). CEO overconfidence and corporate investment. European Financial Management. 11(5): 649-659.##[32] Malmendier, U. Tate, G., &amp; Yan, J. (2011). Overconfidence and early-life experiences: The effect of managerial traits on corporate financial policies. The Journal of Finance, 66(5): 1687-1733.##[33] Mashayekh, S., &amp; Behzadpur, S. (2015). The effect of managers&#039; overconfidence on dividend policy in the firms listed in Tehran Stock Exchange, The Iranian Accounting and Auditing Review. 21(4): 485-504. ( in Persian).##[34] Moradi, J., Ahmadi, G. (2011). Determinates of corporation investment behavior in the imperfect capital markets, Financial Accounting Researches. 3(2): 125-136. (in Persian).##[35] Muradoglu, Y. G., Onay, C., &amp; Phylaktis, K. (2011). Capital structure and debt maturity in Europe. Online Available at SSRN: http: //ssrn.com (accessed 7 December 2012).##[36] Ortiz, M. H., &amp; Penas, M. F. (2008). Lending to small businesses: The role of the loan maturity in addressing information problems. Small Business Economics. 30(4): 361-383.##[37] Pompian, Michel M. (2006). Behavioral Finance and Wealth Management, Translated by: Ahmad Badri. Kayhan Publishing.##[38] Presley, T. J., &amp; Abbott, L. J. (2013). CEO overconfidence and the incidence of financial restatement. Advances in Accounting. 29 (1): 74-84.##[39] Rahimian, N., Tavakolnia, E., &amp; Karamlou, M. (2013). Adjusted auditor&#039;s opinion and debt maturity structure. The Financial Accounting and Auditing Researches. 20(5): 157-180. (in Persian).##[40] Scherand, C. M., &amp; Zechman, S. L. (2012). Executive overconfidence and the slippery slope to financial misreporting. Journal of Accounting and Economics. 53:311–29.##[41] Stephan, A., Talavera, O., &amp; Tsapin, A. (2011). Corporate debt maturity choice in emerging financial markets, The Quartly Review of Economics and Finance, 51: 141-151.##[42] Terra, P. R.  S. (2010). Determinants of corporate debt maturity in Latin America. European Business Review. 23(1): 45-70.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر حالت‌های روحی در ریسک‌پذیری سرمایه‌گذاران بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Assessing the impact of investors mental status on risk taking behavior of Tehran Stock Exchange Investors</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>این پژوهش با توجه به اهمیت تصمیم‌گیری‌های مالی در زندگی افراد، تأثیر حالت‌های روحی را در ریسک‌پذیری سرمایه‌گذاران فعال در بورس اوراق‌ بهادار تهران بررسی کرده ‌است. ریسک‌پذیری صفتی است که افراد براساس آن تشویق می‌شوند به ابتکار عمل روی آورند و کارهای مخاطره‌آمیز انجام دهند. درواقع، ریسک‌پذیری تمایل فرد به قرارگرفتن در سناریوی تصمیم‌گیری است. حالت روحی، مجموعه‌ای از احساسات پایدار و با نمود خارجی است که در افراد مختلف، شدت و مدت استمرار متفاوتی دارد. جامعۀ آماری این پژوهش شامل کلیّۀ سرمایه‌گذاران بورس اوراق بهادار تهران است که از این میان، 386 نمونه انتخاب شد. برای جمع‌آوری داده‌های لازم در زمینۀ حالت‌های روحی و ریسک، به‌ترتیب از پرسشنامۀ استاندارد پاناس و پرسشنامۀ ریسک‌پذیری و برای آزمودن فرضیه‌های پژوهش از روش الگوسازی معادلات ساختاری با رویکرد حداقل مربعات جزئی استفاده‌ شد. نتایج نشان داد ریسک‌پذیری سرمایه‌گذاران تحت‌ تأثیر چهار حالت روحی عاطفۀ مثبت زیاد، عاطفۀ مثبت کم، عاطفۀ منفی زیاد و عاطفۀ منفی کم است؛ به‌گونه‌ای که با عاطفۀ مثبت زیاد و عاطفۀ منفی کم، رابطۀ مستقیم و با عاطفۀ مثبت کم و عاطفۀ منفی زیاد، رابطۀ عکس دارد. همچنین عاطفۀ مثبت زیاد، بیشترین و عاطفۀ مثبت کم،کمترین تأثیر را در میزان ریسک‌پذیری سرمایه‌گذار دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>With respect to financial decisions in daily life of investors, in this research we assess the mental state of investors on their risk taking behavior in Tehran stock exchange. Risk taking is the degree of encouragement investors has in order to take innovation and do extraordinary jobs. Mental state is composed of sustainable emotions with external expression in different degrees and continuity for kinds of investors. All Tehran stock exchange investors were among the study and 386 samples were selected. For mental state and risk taking behavior data gathered on the basis of PANAS and risk taking standard questioners in turn. Hypothesis tested by structural equation modeling with partial least square approach. Results show risk taking is positively affected by high positive affection and low negative affection besides negatively affected by low positive affection and high negative affection. High positive affection has the highest impact and low positive affection has the lowest impact on risk taking behavior.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>107</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>120</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>بهروز</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>لاری سمنانی</Family>
						<NameE>Behrouz</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Larisemnani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه پیام نور</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه پیام</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>bls@pnu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الگوی پاناس</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>حالت‌های روحی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ریسک‌پذیری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عاطفۀ مثبت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عاطفۀ منفی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Bakhshipour, A., &amp; Dezhkam, M. (2005). A Confirmatory factor analysis of the positive affect negative affect scales (PANAS). Journal of Psychology, 9(4): 351-365.) in persian)##[2] Borge, D. (2011). The Book of risk, c2001 (K. S. Dashti, Trans.). Tehran: Insurance Of Institute.##[3] Bozkurt, I. (2016). Role of negative mood on turkish stock market: suicides. Journal of Yasar University, 11(43): 185-197.##[4] David Cesarini Dawes C T., Johannesson M., Lichtenstein P., &amp; Wallace B. (2009). Genetic variation in preferences for giving and risk-taking. Quarterly Journal of Economics, 124(2): 809-842.##[5] Eslamibidgoli, G., &amp; kordlouie, H. (2010). Behavioral finance as an over – pass between standard finance and neurofinance. Journal of Financial Engineering and Portfolio Management, 1(1): 19-36.##[6] Fama, E. (1998). Market efficiency، long terms returns and behavioral finance. Jornal of Financial Economics, 49: 283-306.##[7] Grable, J. E., &amp; Lytton, R. H. (1999). Financial risk tolerance revisited the development of a risk assessment instrument. Financial Services Review, 8: 163-181.##[8] Hu, T., Xie, X., &amp; Li, J. (2013). Negative or positive? The effect of emotion and mood on risky driving. Transportation Research Part F, 16: 29-40.##[9] Kannadhasan, M. (2015). Retail investors financial risk tolerance and their risk-taking behaviour: the role of demographics as differentiating and classifying factors. IIMB Management Review, 27: 175-184.##[10]      Karimzadeh, M. (2007). Investigate and Determine the Relationship between Systemic Risk and Efficiency, Profits and Sales in the Investment Companies Listed on the Tehran Stock Exchange. Master&#039;s Thesis, Azad University. ) in persian)##[11] Khataee, M., &amp; Khavarinezhad, A. (2002). The expansion of financial markets and economic development. the Monetary and Banking Research Institute, 449-482.) in persian)##[12] Kuesten, C., Choprab, P., Bic, J., &amp; Meiselmand, H. L. (2014). A global study using PANAS (PA and NA) scales to measure consumer emotions associated with aromas of phytonutrient supplements .Food Quality and Preference, 33: 86-97.##[13] Kunju Sulaiman, E. (2012). An empirical analysis of financial risk tolerance and demographic features of individual investors. Procedia Economics and Finance, 2: 109-115.##[14] Lane, A., Weston, N. J. V., &amp; Thelwell, R. C. (2005). Mood، self-set goals and examination performance: the moderating effect of depressed mood. Personality and Individual Differences, 39: 143-153.##[15] Lemaster, P., &amp; Strough, J. (2014). Beyond mars and venus: understanding gender differences in financial risk tolerance. Journal of Economic Psychology, 42: 148-160.##[16] Liciano, N., &amp; Soccorso, P. (2012). Assessing investor’s risk tolerance through a questionaire. Disussion Papers, 4: 5-40.##[17] Mackinnon A., Jorm, A, F., Christensen, H., Korten, A, E., Jacomb, P, A., &amp; Rodgers, B. (1999). A short form of the positive and negative affect schedule: evaluation of factorial validity and invariance across demographic variables in a community sample. Personality and Individual Diferences, 27(16): 405-416.##[18] Mohammadi, N. (2011). Factor structure, forms of state and trait positive affect and negative scales. Journal of Behavioral Sciences, 5(1):21-26.) in persian)##[19] Phung, T. T. M., &amp; Khuong, M. N. (Producer). (2016). The impact of the big five traits and mood on investment performance – a study of individual investors in Vietnam. Retrieved from https://ssrn.com/abstract=2883425 or http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.2883425.##[20] Pompian, M. (2009). Behavioral Finance and Wealth Management (A. Badri, Trans.). Tehran: Kayhan.##[21] Rezaghoolizadeh, M. (2013). Assess the Impact of Risk on Capital Market of Iran (Case Study: Tehran Stock Exchange). Ph.D. Thesis, Tarbiat modares university.##[22] Riviere, C. (2009). International a l&#039;anthropologie. N. Fakoohi, Trans. Tehran: nashre Nei.##[23] Stephen P, R. (1998). Essentials of Organizational Behavior. A. Parsaeian &amp; M. Aarabi, Trans. Tehran: Office of Cultural Research.##[24] Statman, M. (2014). Behavioral finance: Finance with normal people. Borsa Istanbul Review, 14(2): 65-73.##[25] Tellegen, A. (1985). Structure of Mood and Personality and Their Relevance to Assessing Anxiety, with and Emphasis on self Report in A.H.Tuma and P. Maser (Eds) ، Anxiety and Anxiety Disorder. Hills Dole: Nj: Erlbaum##[26] Thelwell, R., Lane, A., &amp; Weston, N. (2007). Mood states، self-set goals, self-efficacy and performance in academic examinations. Personality and Individual Differences, 42: 573-583.##[27] Tran, Q. N. (2017). The behavior patterns of investors in Thailand stock market. Asian Journal of Finance &amp; Accounting, 9(1): 155-165##[28] Tuyon, J., &amp; Ahmad, Z. (2016). Behavioural finance perspectives on Malaysian stock market efficiency. Borsa Istanbul Review, 16(1): 43-61.##[29] Van De Venter , G., Michayluk, D., &amp; Davey, G. (2012). A longitudinal study of financial risk tolerance. Journal of Economic Psychology, 33: 794-800.##[30] Watson, D., Clarke, L., &amp; A., T. (1988). Development and validation of brief measures of positive and negative affect - the panas scales. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 54(6): 1063-1070.##[31] Zhang, Y., Shen, D., &amp; Zhang, W. (2017). Investor sentiment and stock returns: evidence from provincial TV audience rating in china. Physica A: Statistical Mechanics and its Applications, (15): 288-294.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تأثیر کیفیت حسابرسی در رابطۀ ارزش وثیقه‏‌ای دارایی‏‌ها با سطح تأمین‌ مالی و سرمایه‌گذاری شرکت‏‌ها</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Effect of Audit Quality on the Relationship of Collateral Assets with Financing and Investment</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>این پژوهش، تأثیر کیفیت حسابرسی را در رابطۀ تأمین ‌مالی و سرمایه‌گذاری با ارزش وثیقۀ دارایی‌های ملکی بررسی می‏کند که معیار ظرفیت تأمین ‏مالی در نظر گرفته شده است. از طرفی تأثیر تغییر ارزش وثیقۀ دارایی‌های ملکی در انتخاب حسابرس نیز مطالعه می‏شود. برای سنجش کیفیت حسابرسی از رتبه‌بندی مؤسسات حسابرسی استفاده شده‏ است که جامعۀ حسابداران رسمی ایران انجام داده است. از نوسان‌های قیمت املاک برای برآورد ارزش وثیقۀ دارایی‏های ملکی 126 شرکت پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در دورۀ زمانی 1386 تا 1393، مشتمل بر 1003 مشاهدۀ شرکت-سال بهره گرفته شده‏ است. فرضیه‏های پژوهش با استفاده از رگرسیون چندمتغیره، با به‌کارگیری داده‌های تابلویی و نرم‌افزار ایویوز آزمون شده ‏است. یافته‏های پژوهش نشان می‏دهد کیفیت حسابرسی از حساسیت مخارج سرمایه‌ای و تأمین ‌مالی به ظرفیت تأمین ‌مالی می‌کاهد و تغییر در ظرفیت ‌تأمین ‌مالی در انتخاب حسابرس مؤثر است. علاوه بر این نتایج نشان می‏دهد در ‏‏شرکت‏هایی‏که احتمال کم‌سرمایه‌گذاری در آنها بیشتر است، تغییرات در ارزش وثیقه‏ای دارایی‏ها، رابطۀ منفی و معناداری با سرمایه‌گذاری دارد. کیفیت حسابرسی نیز در این رابطه، نقش تعدیل‌گر خود را دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>This research investigates the effect of audit quality on the relationship of collateral value of assets with the firm&#039;s financing and investment decisions. Moreover, the firms&#039; audit quality responses to the change in firm&#039;s real estate assets were examined. We used changes in a firm’s collateral values caused by changes in real estate prices as an exogenous change to the financing capacity of a firm. The audit firms ranks (carried out by Iranian Association of Certified Public Accountant (IACPA)) were used as a proxy of audit quality. A sample consists of 126 firms listed in the Tehran Stock Exchange for the period 2007 to 2014, 1003 firm-year observations, and multivariate regressions in panel data mode were used to test the hypotheses. The results show that financing and investment by firms with higher audit quality is less affected by changes in real estate values than are financing and investment by firms with lower audit quality. Further, firms select auditors with higher quality in response to decreases in financing capacity. The results also show that changes in collateral value have a significant negative effect on the investment of firms that are more likely to under-investment and audit quality plays decreasing role in this relation.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>121</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>136</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فرج زاده دهکردی</Family>
						<NameE>Hassan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Farahzadeh Dehkordi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم مالی، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم مالی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ha.farajzadeh@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رضازاده</Family>
						<NameE>Mohsen</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rezazadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد، گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم مالی، دانشگاه رجاء، قزوین، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد، گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>msn.rezazadeh@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ارزش وثیقه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تأمین‌مالی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایه‌گذاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کیفیت حسابرسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1]   Abel, A. (1983). Optimal investment under uncertainty. American Economic Review. 73(1): 228–233.##[2]   Aflatooni, A. (2016). Investigating the effect of financial reporting quality on the relation among collateral assets, financing and investment. Journal of Asset Management and Financing. 4(3): 109-124. )In Persian(.##[3]   Badavar Nahandi, V., &amp; Taghizadeh Khangah. V. (2013). The relationship between audit quality and investment efficiency. The Iranian Accounting and Auditing Review. 20(2): 19-42 (In Persian).##[4]   Balakrishnan, K., Core, J. E., &amp; Verdi. R. S. (2014). The relation between reporting quality and financing and investment: Evidence from changes in financing capacity. Journal of Accounting Research. 52(1): 1-36.##[5]   Benmelech, E., &amp; Bergman. N. (2009). Collateral pricing. Journal of Financial Economics. 91: 339–360.##[6]   Biddle, G., Hilary, G., &amp; Verdi. R. S. (2009). How does financial reporting quality relate to investment efficiency? Journal of Accounting and Economics. 48: 112–131.##[7]   Chaney, T., Sraer, D., &amp; Thesmar. D. (2012). The collateral channel: How real estate shocks affect corporate investment? American Economic Review. 102: 2381–409.##[8]   Chang, X., Dasgupta, S., &amp; Hilary. G. (2009). The effect of auditor quality on financing decisions. The Accounting Review. 84: 1085–1117.##[9]   Clarkson, P. M., Ferguson, C., &amp; Hall. J. (2003). Auditor conservatism and voluntary disclosure: Evidence from the year 2000 system issue. Accounting and Finance. 43: 21-40.##[10]    Fazzari, S., Hubbard, R. G., &amp; Petersen. B. (1988). Financing constraints and corporate investment. Brookings Papers on Economic Activities. 1: 141-206.##[11]    Hubbard, R. G. (1998). Capital market imperfections and investment. Journal of Economic Literature. 36: 193–227.##[12]              Kausar, A., Shroff, N., &amp; White. H. (2015). Real effect of the audit choice. Journal of Accounting and Economics. 62 (1): 157-181.##[13]    Lenard, M., &amp; Yu. B. (2012). Do earnings management and audit quality influence over-investment by Chinese companies? International Journal of Economics and Finance. 4(2): 21-30.##[14]    Leuz, C., &amp; R. Verrecchia. (2000). The economic consequences of increased disclosure. Journal of Accounting Research. 38: 91–124.##[15]    Li, C., Xie, Y., &amp; Zhou. J. (2010). National level, city level auditor industry specialization and cost of debt. Accounting Horizons. 24(3): 395-417.##[16]    Lou, Y., &amp; Vasvari. F. P. (2009). Auditor specialization and the cost of public debt. Working Paper, London Business School.##[17]    Moradi, M., Eskandar, H., &amp; Elhaeisahar. M. (2015). Sensitivity of external finance resources to cash flow under financial constraints: Replacement role of tangible fixed assets. Journal of Asset Management and Financing. 2(4): 111-126. (In Persian).##[18]    Modarres, A., &amp; Hasarzadeh. R. (2008). Financial reporting quality and investment efficiency.##Journal of Securities Exchange. 1(2): 85-116.(In Persian).##[19]    Modigliani, F., &amp; Miller. M. H. (1959). The cost of capital, corporation finance, and the theory of investment. American Economic Review. 49(4): 261-297.##[20]    Myers, S., &amp; Majluf. N. (1984). Corporate financing and investment decisions when firms have information that investors do not have. Journal of Financial Economics. 13(2): 187–222.##[21]    Palmer, P. D. (2008). Disclosure of the impacts of adopting Australian equivalents of international financial reporting standards. Accounting and Finance. 48(5): 847–870.##[22]    Richardson, S. (2006). Over-investment of free cash flow. Review of Accounting Studies. 11(2): 159–89.##[23]    Safari Gerayoli, M., &amp; Ranaei. F. (2017). Investigating the relation between financial reporting quality and Investment efficiency and the role of debt maturity in such relation among the companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Asset Management and Financing. 5(1): 83-98. (In Persian).##[24]    Saghafi, A., &amp; Motamedi Fazel. M. (2012). Relation between audit quality and investment efficiency in firms with high investment opportunities. Journal of Financial Accounting Research. 3(4): 1-14. (In Persian).##[25]    Stein, J. (2003). Agency, information and corporate investment. In Handbook of the Economics of Finance, edited by G. Constantinides, M. Harris, and R. Stulz. North Holland: Elsevier, 111–65.##[26]    Stiglitz, J., &amp; Weiss. A. (1981). Credit rationing in markets with imperfect information. American Economic Review. 71: 393–410.##[27]    Verrecchia, R. (2001). Essays on disclosure. Journal of Accounting and Economics. 32: 97–180.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارائۀ الگوی جامع پشتیبان تصمیم برای ساختارسرمایۀ شرکتی (شرکت‌های شیمیایی بورس اوراق بهادار تهران)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>An Integrated Decision Support Model For Firms&#039; Capital Structure (Case Study: Chemical Companies In Tehran Stock Exchange)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>تصمیم‌های تأمین مالی شرکت‌ها یکی از وظایف مهم مدیریت سازمان است که با توجه به ماهیت خود، نوعی از مسائل چندمعیاره محسوب می‌شود. در این پژوهش، الگوی جامعی برای کمک به تصمیم‌های تأمین مالی برون‌سازمانی ارائه ‌شده است. بدین‌منظور، ضمن مرور نظریه‌های ساختار سرمایه و عوامل مؤثر بر آن، تأثیر این عوامل در سه سطح سازمانی، صنعت و اقتصاد کلان در اهرم مالی شرکت‌های مدّنظر بررسی ‌شده‌ است. در این راستا، از الگو‌های اقتصادسنجی گام‌به‌گام و میانگین گروهی تلفیقی استفاده ‌شده است. با افزایش متغیرهای مستقل در اینگونه مسائل، معمولاً مشکلات هم‌خطی در تخمین الگوی رگرسیونی افزایش می‌یابد؛ بنابراین از قابلیت اطمینان الگو کاسته می‌شود و الگو به‌تنهایی، نمی‌تواند الگوی مطمئنی برای کمک به تصمیم‌های ساختار سرمایه شرکتی باشد؛ بنابراین از نتایج الگوی اقتصادسنجی در طراحی یک الگوی تصمیم‌گیری چندمعیارۀ ترکیبی برای تأمین مالی شرکتی استفاده شد. نتایج نهایی، استفادۀ بیشتر از دو منبع اوراق اجارۀ اسلامی و وام‌های کوتاه‌مدت بانکی را توصیه می‌کنند. دلیل آن، وجود مجدودیت‌های کنترل ریسک در الگو است. نتایج الگو، تطابق مطلوبی با عملکرد واقعی نمونۀ مطالعه‌شده نیز داشت.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Financing decisions of the firms are one of important tasks for management and according to its nature, it is considered as a Multi-Criteria Decision problem. In this research, a comprehensive review on capital structure theories and its determinants has been made, then the effect of this determinants on the financial leverage of the firms is investigated in three levels: firm specific, industry and economy. In this regard, stepwise regression and pooled mean group model are used. This models specified both short-term and long-term effects of detected factors on capital structure. In this models, as the number of independent variables increase, the co-linearity in the model increases. So, the reliability of model declines and the model can&#039;t be a good pattern for financing decisions. In the next step, the identified factors were employed as decision criteria in a hybrid MCDM model that combining DEMATEL and ANP. The ANP weights of the model were used in a Goal programing model and a satisfactory solution for the case study was obtained. By using this model, decision makers can systemically structure a multi-criteria network framework and derive priority weights of those criteria, and then deal with the quantitative financial constraints for a satisfactory solution.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>137</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>158</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کیمیاگری</Family>
						<NameE>Ali mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Kimiagari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار دانشکدۀ مهندسی صنایع و سیستم‌های مدیریت، دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار دانشکدۀ مهندسی صنایع و سیستم‌های</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>kimiagar@aut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مجتبی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نبوی</Family>
						<NameE>Mojtaba</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nabavi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مهندسی مالی، دانشکدۀ مهندسی صنایع و سیستم های مدیریت، دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مهندسی مالی، دانشکدۀ</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>moj.nabavi@aut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>برنامه‌ریزی آرمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دیماتل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ساختار سرمایه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فرایند تحلیل شبکه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1]       Adrian, T., &amp; Shin, H. S. (2010). Liquidity and leverage. Journal of Financial Intermediation. 19(3): 418–437.##[2]       Agarwal, Y., Iyer, K. C., &amp; Yadav, S. S. (2012). Multiobjective capital structure modeling. Journal of Accounting, Auditing &amp; Finance. 27(3): 359–385.##[3]       Al-shammari, M., &amp; Masri, H. (2015). Multiple Criteria Decision Making in Finance, Insurance and Investment. Springer.##[4]       Baker, H. K., &amp; Martin, G. S. (2011). Capital Structure and Corporate Financing Decisions: Theory, Evidence, and Practice. New Jersey: Wiley.##[5]       Bandyopadhyay, A., &amp; Barua, N. M. (2016). Factors determining capital structure and corporate performance in India: Studying the business cycle effects. Quarterly Review of Economics and Finance. 61:160–172.##[6]       Beck, T., Demirgüç-Kunt, A., &amp; Maksimovic, V. (2008). Financing patterns around the world: Are small firms different? Journal of Financial Economics. 89(3): 467–487.##[7]       De Jong, A., Kabir, R., &amp; Nguyen, T. (2008). Capital structure around the world: The roles of firm- and country-specific determinants. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance. 32(9): 1954–1969.##[8]       Doumpos, M., &amp; Zopounidis, C. (2014). Multicriteria Analysis in Finance. New York: Springer.##[9]       Draper, N. R., &amp; Smith, H. (2014). Chapter 15- Selecting the Best Regression Equation, in Applied Regression Analysis. New York: Wiley.##[10]    Dufour, J. M., &amp; Taamouti, A. (2010). Short and long run causality measures: Theory and inference. Journal of Econometrics. 154(1): 42–58.##[11]    Fathi, S., Abzari, M., &amp; Habibi, S. (2014). Determinants of Capital Structure: Meta-analysis. Asset Management and Financing 4(4): 55-74. (in Persian).##[12]    Fazli, S., Kiani Mavi, R., &amp; Vosooghidizaji, M. (2015). Crude oil supply chain risk management with DEMATEL–ANP. Operational Research. 15(3): 453:480. (in Persian).##[13]    Frank, M. Z., &amp; Goyal, V. K. (2008). Handbook of Empirical Corporate Finance.##[14]    Gölcük, I., &amp; Baykasoʇlu, A. (2016). An analysis of DEMATEL approaches for criteria interaction handling within ANP. Expert Systems with Applications. 46: 346–366.##[15]    Ho, W. J., Tsai, C., Tzeng, G., &amp; Fang, S. (2011). Combined DEMATEL technique with a novel MCDM model for exploring portfolio selection based on CAPM. Expert Systems with Applications. 38(1): 16–25.##[16]    Khanna, S., Srivastava, A., &amp; Medury, Y. (2015). The effect of macroeconomic variables on the capital structure decisions of Indian firms: A vector error correction model/vector autoregressive approach. International Journal of Economics and Financial Issues. 5(4): 968–978.##[17]    Mehregan, M. R., Hashemi, S. H., Karimi, A., &amp; Merikhi, B. (2014). Analysis of interactions among sustainability supplier selection criteria using ISM and fuzzy DEMATEL. International Journal of Applied Decision Sciences. 7(3): 270–294. (in Persian).##[18]    Pesaran, M. H., Shin, Y., &amp; Smith, R. P. (1999). Pooled mean group estimation of dynamic heterogeneous panels. Journal of the American Statistical Association. 94(446): 621–634.##[19]    Saaty, T. L. (1996). Decision Making with Dependence and Feedback, The Analytic Network Process. Pittsburgh: Rws Publications.##[20]    Saaty, T. L., &amp; Vargas, L. G. (2013). Decision Making with The Analytic Network Process. Springer.##[21]    Tsai, W., Yang, C., Leu, J., Lee, Y., &amp; Yang, C. (2013). An integrated group decision making support model for corporate financing decisions. Group Decision and Negotiation. 22(6): 1103–1127.##[22]    Yu, R., &amp; Tzeng, G. H. (2006). A soft computing method for multi-criteria decision making with dependence and feedback. Applied Mathematics and Computation. 180(1): 63–75.## [1]      Adrian, T., &amp; Shin, H. S. (2010). Liquidity and leverage. Journal of Financial Intermediation. 19(3): 418–437.##[2]       Agarwal, Y., Iyer, K. C., &amp; Yadav, S. S. (2012). Multiobjective capital structure modeling. Journal of Accounting, Auditing &amp; Finance. 27(3): 359–385.##[3]       Al-shammari, M., &amp; Masri, H. (2015). Multiple Criteria Decision Making in Finance, Insurance and Investment. Springer.##[4]       Baker, H. K., &amp; Martin, G. S. (2011). Capital Structure and Corporate Financing Decisions: Theory, Evidence, and Practice. New Jersey: Wiley.##[5]       Bandyopadhyay, A., &amp; Barua, N. M. (2016). Factors determining capital structure and corporate performance in India: Studying the business cycle effects. Quarterly Review of Economics and Finance. 61:160–172.##[6]       Beck, T., Demirgüç-Kunt, A., &amp; Maksimovic, V. (2008). Financing patterns around the world: Are small firms different? Journal of Financial Economics. 89(3): 467–487.##[7]       De Jong, A., Kabir, R., &amp; Nguyen, T. (2008). Capital structure around the world: The roles of firm- and country-specific determinants. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance. 32(9): 1954–1969.##[8]       Doumpos, M., &amp; Zopounidis, C. (2014). Multicriteria Analysis in Finance. New York: Springer.##[9]       Draper, N. R., &amp; Smith, H. (2014). Chapter 15- Selecting the Best Regression Equation, in Applied Regression Analysis. New York: Wiley.##[10]    Dufour, J. M., &amp; Taamouti, A. (2010). Short and long run causality measures: Theory and inference. Journal of Econometrics. 154(1): 42–58.##[11]    Fathi, S., Abzari, M., &amp; Habibi, S. (2014). Determinants of Capital Structure: Meta-analysis. Asset Management and Financing 4(4): 55-74. (in Persian).##[12]    Fazli, S., Kiani Mavi, R., &amp; Vosooghidizaji, M. (2015). Crude oil supply chain risk management with DEMATEL–ANP. Operational Research. 15(3): 453:480. (in Persian).##[13]    Frank, M. Z., &amp; Goyal, V. K. (2008). Handbook of Empirical Corporate Finance.##[14]    Gölcük, I., &amp; Baykasoʇlu, A. (2016). An analysis of DEMATEL approaches for criteria interaction handling within ANP. Expert Systems with Applications. 46: 346–366.##[15]    Ho, W. J., Tsai, C., Tzeng, G., &amp; Fang, S. (2011). Combined DEMATEL technique with a novel MCDM model for exploring portfolio selection based on CAPM. Expert Systems with Applications. 38(1): 16–25.##[16]    Khanna, S., Srivastava, A., &amp; Medury, Y. (2015). The effect of macroeconomic variables on the capital structure decisions of Indian firms: A vector error correction model/vector autoregressive approach. International Journal of Economics and Financial Issues. 5(4): 968–978.##[17]    Mehregan, M. R., Hashemi, S. H., Karimi, A., &amp; Merikhi, B. (2014). Analysis of interactions among sustainability supplier selection criteria using ISM and fuzzy DEMATEL. International Journal of Applied Decision Sciences. 7(3): 270–294. (in Persian).##[18]    Pesaran, M. H., Shin, Y., &amp; Smith, R. P. (1999). Pooled mean group estimation of dynamic heterogeneous panels. Journal of the American Statistical Association. 94(446): 621–634.##[19]    Saaty, T. L. (1996). Decision Making with Dependence and Feedback, The Analytic Network Process. Pittsburgh: Rws Publications.##[20]    Saaty, T. L., &amp; Vargas, L. G. (2013). Decision Making with The Analytic Network Process. Springer.##[21]    Tsai, W., Yang, C., Leu, J., Lee, Y., &amp; Yang, C. (2013). An integrated group decision making support model for corporate financing decisions. Group Decision and Negotiation. 22(6): 1103–1127.##[22]    Yu, R., &amp; Tzeng, G. H. (2006). A soft computing method for multi-criteria decision making with dependence and feedback. Applied Mathematics and Computation. 180(1): 63–75.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>انتخاب روش بهینۀ محاسبۀ ارزش در معرض خطر صندوق‌های سرمایه‌گذاری</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Best Methodology of Estimation of Value-at-Risk in Iranian Mutual Funds</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در چند سال گذشته، تجربۀ انفجار خارق­العاده ناشی از صندوق‌های سرمایه‌گذاری که به خرید سهام سایر شرکت­ها اقدام می‌کنند، سبب شد سازمان­های مسئول برای کنترل و نظارت بر این سرمایه­گذاری­ها، برخی دستورالعمل­های مدیریتی براساس ارزش در معرض خطر اعمال کنند؛ اما انعطاف­پذیری روش مذکور، پرسش‌های زیادی را دربارۀ انتخاب دقیق‌ترین و مناسب‌تر‌ین الگوی تخمین ایجاد کرد. هدف این مقاله، انتخاب روش بهینه از بین سه روش پارامتریک، شبیه‌سازی تاریخی و شبیه‌سازی مونت‌کارلو در سطوح اطمینان 99، 5/97 و 95 درصد است تا بهترین روش پیش‌بینی ضررهای احتمالی صندوق­های سرمایه­گذاری ایران مشخص شود. بدین‌منظور، ابتدا نتایج ناشی از روش‌های مختلف تخمین ارائه شد؛ سپس در هر روش محاسبه، صندوق­هایی مشخص شد که بیشترین وکمترین ارزش در معرض خطر را داشت. در این پژوهش، هر سه روش پارامتریک، شبیه­سازی تاریخی و شبیه­سازی مونت‌کارلو با آزمون کوپیک تأیید شد؛ اما بیشترین سطوح اطمینانی که با آزمون­های اعتبارسنجی تأیید شد، سطح اطمینان 99 درصد بود؛ به عبارت دیگر، مشخص شد سطح اطمینان 99 درصد، کمترین انحراف را نسبت به میانگین ایجاد می‌کند و بهترین سطح برای استفاده در روش‌های مختلف محاسبۀ ارزش در معرض خطر است. این مورد نشان می‌دهد در محاسبۀ خطر صندوق­های سرمایه‌گذاری در ایران، سطح اطمینان مدّنظر، مهم­تر از روش محاسبۀ ارزش در معرض خطر است که این موضوع دقیقاً با گزارش کمیتۀ بال در سال 2016 دربارۀ محاسبۀ ارزش در معرض خطر و کفایت سرمایۀ بانک­ها همخوانی دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The considerable increase of mutual funds in recent years drove supervising and controlling organizations of these funds to impose some risk management directives based on value-at-risk. However the concept’s flexibility raises many questions concerning the choice of the most accurate and suitable estimation model which can be used for risk management.The purpose of this study consists of selecting between the three esimation methods, namely, parametric, historical, and Monte Carlo simulation method, to determine the most accurate method for providing the prediction of potential losses which confront Iranian mutual funds. For this purpose, we tried firstly to present the different estimation’s approached of VaR. Secondly, we analyzed the statistical descriptive characteristics of mutual funds, the subject of this study. After that, empirical study’s results have been exposed, and therefore, allowed us to highlight that there is no significant difference between different methods and 99 percent confidence level is the best level for estimation.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>159</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>180</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نادری نورعینی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Naderi Nooreini</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه حسابداری، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه حسابداری، دانشکده مدیریت و</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mehdinadery@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ارزش در معرض خطر</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>روش پارامتریک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شبیه‌سازی مونت‌کارلو</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شبیه‌سازی تاریخی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>صندوق‌های سرمایه‌گذاری مشترک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF> [1] Azizi, S., &amp; Shariffar, A. (2013). Mutual fund selection determinants: a mixed method approach, Asset Management &amp; Financing.1(2): 35-50. (in Persian).##[2] Basel Committee on Banking Supervision. (2016). Minimum capital requirements for market risk.##[3] Cifter, A. (2011). Value-at-risk estimation with wavelet-based extreme value theory: Evidence from emerging markets. Physica A: Statistical Mechanics and its Applications, 390(12): 2356-2367.##[4] Christoffersen, P. (1998), Evaluating internal forecasts. International Economic review. 39: 841-862.##[5] Dornbusch, R. (1998). Capital controls: An idea whose time is past. Essays in International Finance. 7(2): 19-25.##[6] Gallsli, M. I., &amp; Guesmi, A. (2008). Value-at-risk in mutual funds which methodology of estimation. 2ème Conférence Euro-Africaine en Finance et Economie (CEAFE). Tunis.##[8] Hanifi, F. (2001). Investigate Amaunt of Risk Taking of Listed Companies in Tehran Stock Exchange Through Measures of Value at Risk. PHD Thesis, Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch, Tehran. (in persian).##[10] Hendricks, D. (1996). Evaluation of value-at-risk models using historical data. Economic Policy Review. 2(1): 39-70.##[10] Jorion, P. (2007). Financial risk manager handbook (Vol. 406). John Wiley &amp; Sons.##[11] Kupiec, P. (1995), Techniques for verifying the accuracy of risk measurement models. Journal of Derivatives. 3: 73-84.##[12] Poor-agha, M., Nownahalenahr, A. A., &amp; Zinali, M. (2014). Determination relation between value at risk (VaR) and monthly returns of exchange portfolios of investor companies in stock of Tehran Exchange Companies. 1st International coferance on Economic, Management, Accounting &amp; Social Sinces. (in Persian).## [13] Sahabi, B., Sadeghi, H., &amp; khorsandi, V. (2015). The calculation of var of metal ores and pharmaceutical industries in Tehran Stock Exchange by using wavelet analysis and GARCH models. The Economic Research. 15(1): 105-122. (in Persian).##[14] Shahmoradi, A., &amp; Zanganeh, M. (2007). The parameric methods for estimating the value at risk for Tehran Stock Exchange, Tahghighat-E- Eghtesadi. 42(79): 121-149. (in Persian).##[15] Shahiki Tash, M. N., Zamanian, J. R., &amp; Shayeganmehr, A. (2016). Performance evaluation of mutual funds by stochastic dominance criteria and compare with sharp ratio and sortino ratio. Asset Management &amp; Financing, 3(4): 67-84. (in persian).##[16] The Development of New Financial Instrument and Institutions (approved 2012). Available At: http://rc.majlis.ir/fa/law/show/810412.##[17] The Investment Company Act of 1940. AvailableAt:https://www.sec.gov/about/laws/ica40.pdf.##[18] The Securities Market Act of Islamic Republic of Iran, (approved 2005). Available At: http://rc.majlis.ir/fa/law/show/97786.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی رابطۀ محدودیت مالی، ساختار دارایی ها و تأمین مالی در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Relationship between Financial Constraints, the Structure of Assets and Financing in Companies Listed in Tehran Stock Exchange</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>پژوهش حاضر، اثر تعدیلی محدودیت ‌مالی با شاخص کاپلان و زینگالس (1997) را در رابطۀ ساختار دارایی‌های ‌وثیقه‌شدنی و ساختار‌ مالی شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار ‌تهران بررسی می‌کند. بدین‌منظور، 155 شرکت برای یک دورۀ 11 ساله (1393-1383) بررسی شده است. یافته‌ها نشان می‌دهد محدودیت مالی شرکت­ها در رابطۀ کل دارایی‌های ‌وثیقه‌شدنی با اهرم ‌مالی و اجزای دارایی‌های وثیقه‌شدنی (اموال، ماشین‌آلات و تجهیزات، موجودی‌کالا و حساب­های دریافتنی) با اهرم ‌مالی شرکت، تأثیر مثبت و معناداری دارد؛ به عبارت دیگر، با وجود محدودیت­های مالی در شرکت­ها، این رابطه تقویت می­شود. در تحلیل فرضیۀ سوم، متغیر تعدیلی محدودیت مالی در رابطۀ بین دارایی‌های بلندمدت وثیقه‌شدنی با اهرم ‌مالی بلندمدت تأثیری ندارد. متغیر تعدیلی محدودیت مالی در رابطۀ بین دارایی‌های کوتاه‌مدت وثیقه‌شدنی با اهرم مالی کوتاه‌مدت، نشان‌دهندۀ اثر مثبت و معناداری است. علاوه بر این اثر تعدیلی محدودیت‌ مالی در اجزای دارایی‌های کوتاه‌مدت‌ وثیقه‌شدنی (موجودی‌کالا و حساب­های دریافتنی) با اهرم ‌مالی کوتاه‌مدت به‌ترتیب، نشان‌دهندۀ رابطۀ مثبت و معنادار و نبود رابطه است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The main objective of this study was to investigate the moderating effect of financial constraints of Kaplan-Zingales Index (1997) on the relationship between the structure of collateral assets and financing structure of the companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange (TSE).  To this end, the study was carried out using systematic elimination skewed sample consists of 155 firms over the period of 11 years -from 2004 to 2015. The results show that moderating effect of financial constraints on the relationship between and the total collateral assets with financial leverage and components collateral assets (property, plant and equipment, inventory, accounts receivable) with the company&#039;s financial leverage is direct and significant. The test of the third hypothesis showed that there is no moderating effect of financial constraints on the relationship between long-term assets and long-term securities held by financial leverage. Furthermore, testing the moderating effect of financial constraints on the relationship between short-term bond funds with short-term financial leverage impose a direct and significant relationship; as well as the moderating effect of short-term financial constraints on components of collateral assets (inventory, accounts receivable) with short-term financial leverage denote that there is a direct and significant relationship and non-relationship for the aforementioned issues, respectively.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>181</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>196</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>لاری دشت بیاض</Family>
						<NameE>Mahmoud</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Lari Dashtbayaz</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه حسابداری دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصاد دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه حسابداری دانشکده علوم اداری</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.lari@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صالحی</Family>
						<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Salehi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه حسابداری دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصاد دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه حسابداری دانشکده علوم اداری</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mehdi.salehi@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مریم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سخاوت پور</Family>
						<NameE>Maryam</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sekhavatpoor</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناسی ارشد حسابداری، گروه حسابداری موسسه آموزش عالی عطار، مشهد، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناسی ارشد حسابداری، گروه حسابداری موسسه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sekhavat1391@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اهرم مالی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بورس اوراق بهادار‌تهران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>محدودیت مالی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ساختار دارایی‌ها</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>وثیقه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF> [1] Aflatooni, A. (2016). Investigating the effect of finansial Reporting quality on the relation among collateral assets, financing and investment. Asset Managenent &amp; Financing. 4(3): 109 – 124.##[2] Ahmed Sheikh, N., &amp; Wang, Z. (2011). Determinants of capital structure: An empirical study of firms in manufacturing industry of Pakistan. Managerial Finance. 37(2): 117 – 133.##[3] Almeida, H., &amp; Campello, M. (2007). Financial constraints, asset tangibility and corporate investment. Revieew of Financial Studies. 20(5): 1429-1460.##[4] Asadi, A. R., &amp; Abbaszadeh, M. R. (2014). An investiyation of determinants of capital stracture of affiliated and unaffiliated firms in Thran Stock Exehange. Financial Monetary Economics. 7(21): 210 -233. (in Persian).##[6] Balakrishnan, K., Core, J. E., &amp; Verdi, R. S. (2014). The relation between reporting quality and financing and investment: Evidence from changes in financing capacity. Journalof Accounting Research. 52(1): 1-36.## [8] Berger, A., Frame, S., &amp; Ioannidou, V. (2011). Tests of ex ante versus ex post theories of collateral using private and public information. Journal of Financial Economics. 100: 85-97.##[9] Berle, A., &amp; Means, G. (1932). The Modern Corporation and Private Property. Macmillan New York.## [10] Blve, G., Shariatpanahi, S. M., Abrahimi, S., &amp; Hosseini, S. H. (2014). The effective factors in the preference of short – term finance. Journal of Securities Exchange. (25): 21- 137.##[11] Campello, M., &amp; Giambona, E. (2013). Real assets and capital structure. Journal of Financial and Quontitative Analysis. 48 (5): 1333–1370.##[12] Chaney, T., Srawr, D., &amp; Thesmar, D. (2012). The collateral channel: How rael estate shocks affect corporate investment. American Economic Review. 102(6): 2381-2409.##[13] Chang, C., Lee A. C., &amp; Lee, C. F. (2009). Determinants of capital structure choice: A structural equation modeling approach. The Quartery Review of Economics and finance. 49: 197-213.##[14] Chung, K. H., &amp; Pruitt, S. W. (1994). A simple approximation of Tobin’s q. Financial Management. 23(3): 70-4.##[15] Deari, F., &amp; Deari, M. (2010). Determinants. of capital structure: Case of companies listed on zargreb stock exchange. International Review of Econamies &amp; Business. 13(1): 65–82.##[16] Drobetz, W., &amp; Fix, R. (2003). What are the determinants of the capital structure? Some evidence for Switzerland. Swiss Journal of Economics and Statistics. WWZ/Department of Finance, Working Paper No. 4/03.##[17] Faulkender, M., &amp; Petersen, M. (2006). Does the source of capital affect capital structure? Review of Financial Studies. 19: 45–79.## [18] Fazzari, S., Hubbard, R., &amp; Petersen, B. (1988). Financing constraing and corporate investment. Brooking papers on Economic Activity. 1: 141- 195.##[19] Frank, M., &amp; Goyal, V. (2009). Capital structure decisions: Which factors are reliably important? Financial Management. 38: 1- 37.##[20] Gan, J. (2007). The real effects of asset market bubbles: Loan- and firm-level evidence of a lending channel. Review of Financial Studies. 20(6): 1941-1973.##[21] Gracia, J. L., &amp; Mirasogorb, F. (2014). Sensitivity of exrternal resources to cash flow under financial constraints. International Business Review, 3(5): 920-930.##[22] Guney. Y., Li, L., &amp; Farichild, R. (2011). The relationship between product market competition and capital structure in Chinese listed firms. International Rewiew of Financial Analysis. 20: 41 – 51.##[23] Hall, T. (2012). The collateral channel: Evidence on leverage and asset tangibility. Journal of Corporate Finance. 18: 570–583.##[24] Hubbard, R. (1998). Capital markets impetections and investment. Journal of Economic Literature. 36: 193- 227.##[25] Kanani Amiri, M. (2008). Financial constraints and stock returns in capital market. Daneshvar Raftar. 26: 29 – 48. (in Persian).##[26] Kaplan, S., &amp; Zingales, L. (1997). Do investment-cash flow sensivities provide useful measures of financin constraints? The Journal of Economics. 112: 169-215.##[27] Karadeniz. Kandir, S. Y., Balcilar, M., &amp; Onal, Y. B. (2009). Determinants of capital structure: Eridence from Turkish lodging companies. International Journal of Contemporary Hospitality Management. 21 (5): 594 – 609.##[28] Khajavi, S., Salhinia, M. (2015). Financing constraints and firm growth. Quarterly Financial Accounting Journal. 7(25): 29- 48.##[29] Korner, P. (2007). The Determinants of corporate debt maturity structure: Evidence from Czech firms. Czech Journal of Economics and Finance. 57(3 – 4): 142 – 158.##[30] Leary, M. (2009). Bank loan supply, lender choice, and corporate capital structure. Journal of Finance. 64: 1143–1185.##[31] Matemilola, B. T., &amp; Ahmad, R. (2015). Debt financing and importance of fixed assets and goodwill assets as collateral: Dynamic panel evidence. Journal of Business Economics and Management. 16(2): 407-421.##[32] Matinfard, M., &amp; Qvshayy Qujeq, D. (2015). The relationship between capital stractur and collateral value of assets and performance of the companies listed in Tehran Stock Exehange. The therd National Conference on Accoanting and Management.##[33] Moradi, M., Eskandar, H., &amp; Mehdi Elhaei, S. (2015). Sensitivity of external finance resources to cash flow under financial constraints: Replacement role of tangible fixed assets. Asset Management &amp; Financing. 2(4): 111- 126.##[34] Myers, S. C., &amp; Magluf, N. (1984). Corporarte financing and invesing and investment decision when firms have information investors do not have. Journal of financial Economics. 13 (2): 187– 221.##[35] Nankoo, P. K., &amp; Boateng, A. (2010). The empirical determinants of target capital structure and adjustment to long – run target: Evidence form Canadian firms. Applied Economics Letters. 17: 983 – 990.##[36] Norden, L., &amp; Kampen, S.V. (2013). Corporate leverage and collateral channel. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance. 37: 5062-5072.##[37] Qian, Y., Tian. Y. &amp; Wirjanto, T. S. (2007). An empirical investigation into the capital structure choice determinants of publicly listed Chinese companies. Unpublished ph.D. Thesis, Zhejiang University.##[38] Rajan, G., &amp; Zingales, L. (1995). What do we know about capital sfructure? Some evidence from international data. Journal of Finance. 50(5): 1421-1460.##[39] Richardson, S. (2006). Over- investment of free cash flow. Review of Accounting Studies. 11: 153- 189.##[40] Stiglitz, J., &amp; Weiss, A. (1981). Credit rationing in markets with imperfect information. American Economic Review. 71(3): 393-410.##[41] Stosh, M. H., &amp; Mauer, D. C. (1996). The determinants of corporate debt maturity structure. Journal of Business. 69(3): 279 – 312.##[42] Tehrani, R., &amp; Hesarzade, R. (2009). The effect of free cash flows and financial on over- investment and under – investment. Accounting Research. 1(3): 50-67.##[43] Titman, S., &amp; Wessels, R. (1988). The determinants of capital structure choice. Journal of Finance. 43(1): 1- 19.##[44] Verdi, R. (2006). Financial reporting quality and investment efficiency. Working paper, MIT University.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>قراردادهای آتی نفت، تعهد به بیع یا تعهد به انتقال روزانۀ وجه تضمین؟</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Oil futures contracts, obligation to selling or to daily settlement?</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>قراردادهای آتی نفت این امکان را برای کلیّۀ مشارکت‌کنندگان بازار فراهم می‌کند تا از نوسان‌های قیمتی نفت خام مصون بمانند. جمهوری اسلامی ایران به دو دلیل به ورود قراردادهای آتی نفت به بورس انرژی نیاز مبرم دارد: اولاً، درآمد کشور وابستگی شدیدی به قیمت نفت دارد و بی­ثباتی قیمت نفت به ناپایداری وضعیت اقتصادی منجر می­شود. دوماً، بازارهای آتی نفت، ابزارهای لازم را برای کاهش ریسک معاملات نفتی، کاهش بی‌ثباتی، افزایش انعطاف‌پذیری و فراهم‌کردن ابعاد وسیع­تر تجاری برای پالایشگران و سایر خریداران نفت و صنایع وابستۀ آن فراهم می‌کند؛ اما در حال حاضر، بورس انرژی، به‌دلیل موانع شرعی، از این ابزار قدرتمند پوشش ریسک نمی‌تواند استفاده کند و این مسأله با اجرای سیاست­های اقتصاد مقاومتی منافات دارد. این پژوهش با واکاوی ماهیت مالی قرارداد آتی نفت و با بررسی متعلَّق اصلی ارادۀ دو طرف قرارداد نشان می­دهد قراردادهای آتی به هیچ وجه از سنخ بیع نیست؛ زیرا تملیک و تحویل دارایی، مقصود معامله­گران نیست؛ بنابراین شبهات شرعی مطرح‌شده از اساس با این قراردادها برخورد نمی­کند و طرح آنها ناشی از ضعف در موضوع­شناسی بوده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Oil futures contracts make it possible for all market participants to remain safe against the crude oil price fluctuations. Islamic Republic of Iran needs to import oil futures contracts to energy exchange for two reasons: First, its national income is highly dependent on crude oil price and instability in oil price leads to unstable economic situation. Second, Oil futures markets provide necessary instruments to reduce risk of oil deals, reduce volatility, increase flexibility and provide broader commercial dimensions to refiners and other buyers of petroleum and related industries. But now, exchange energy, due to jurisprudential constraints, is not able to use this powerful instrument of hedging risk, and this is incompatible with the implementation of economic resistance and resilience policies. This study analyzes financial nature of oil futures contracts and investigates the intend of the parties to the contract and shows that oil futures contracts are not, in any way, type of selling or obligation to selling because the acquisition and consequently delivery of asset are not intended by parties. Therefore, all of those jurisprudential obstacles are wrong about these contracts and are caused by the poor in recognizing the issue.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>181</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>200</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صادقی شاهدانی</Family>
						<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sadeghi Shahdani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه اقتصاد انرژی، دانشکده معارف اسلامی و اقتصاد، دانشگاه امام صادق (ع)، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه اقتصاد انرژی، دانشکده معارف</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>shahdani@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>پاک ذات</Family>
						<NameE>Seyed Mahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Pakzat</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجویی دکتری مدیریت قراردادهای بین المللی نفت و گاز، دانشگاه امام صادق (ع)، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجویی دکتری مدیریت قراردادهای بین المللی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>pakzat@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ابزارهای مشتقه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قراردادهای آتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قراردادهای آتی نفت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت ریسک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] The Holy Quran##[2] Ansari, M. (1994). Al-Makaseb al-Moharramah, Qom, Majmaolfekr al-Islami. (in Persian)##[3] Aram, M. (2003). The Feasibility Study of the Establishment of Independent oil Futures Exchange in the Islamic Republic of Iran, M.A thesis, Tehran, Imam Sadiq University, Faculty of Islamic studies &amp; management. (in Persian)##[4] Bayat, M. (2008). Study of Deficiencies in Hedge Instruments (futures and options), Proposed Guidelines based on Sunni Jurisprudence and its Compatibility with the Comments of Some Shi&#039;a Jurists, M.A thesis, Tehran, Imam Sadiq University, Faculty of Islamic studies &amp; management. (in Persian)##]5] Board of Directors of Securities &amp; Exchange Organization (2007). Executive order of futures transactions on Iran Mercantile Exchange, Adopted on 2007 and Modified on 2009 and 2012.##[6] BotShekan, M. H. (1998). The Recognition of Futures and Options Contracts and Providing a Model for Establishment of its Market in Iran, Ph.D. thesis, University of Tehran, Faculty of Administrative Sciences and Business Administration. (in Persian)##[7] Derakhshan, M. (2011). Derivatives and Risk Management in the Oil Markets, Tehren, Institute for International Energy Studies. (in Persian)##[8] Fahim, Kh. (2000). Islamic Futures and their Markets, with Special Reference to their Role in Developing Rural Financial Market, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia, Islamic Development Bank, Islamic Research Training Institute, Research Paper. No. 32.##[9] Ghanimi fard, H &amp; Aram Bnyar, M. (2005). Jurisprudential feasibility Study of establishing oil futures exchange in Islamic Republic of Iran, Journal of Religion &amp; Communications, 25: (Especially in Islamic financial markets) 171–200. (in Persian)##[10] Haeri, K. (2002).Jurisprudence of Contracts, Qom, majmaolfekr al-islami. (in Persian)##[11] Hajeeian, M. M. (2011). TheLegal Status of Oil and Gas Futures Contracts, Ph.D. thesis, Tehran, Tarbiat Modares University, Faculty of Humanities. (in Persian)##[12] Hosseini, M. (2007). Jurisprudential and Economic Analysis of Derivatives, with Emphasis on Futures Contracts and Option Contracts, Ph.D. thesis, Tehran, Imam Sadiq University, Faculty of Islamic studies &amp; economic. (in Persian)##[13] Hosseini Chaloshtari, M. (1998). The Feasibility Study of Designing Futures Contracts in Islamic Financial System, M.A thesis, Tehran, Imam Sadiq University, Faculty of Islamic studies &amp; management. (in Persian)##[14] Hull, John C. (2014). Options Futures and Other Derivatives, 9th Edition, Prentice Hall.##[15] ICE Futures Europe (www.theice.com), report center – historical monthly volumes.##[16] Ismath Basha, O, Derivative Instruments and Islamic Finance: Some Thoughts for a Reconsideration, International Journal of Islamic Financial Services. 1(1).##[17] Jurisprudential Committee of Securities &amp; Exchange Organization (2007). Detailed discussions and proceedings, Securities &amp; Exchange Organization&#039;s Website (http://www.seo.ir).##[18] Katouzian, N. (2009). General Principles of Contracts, Tehran, Enteshar Company. (in Persian)##[19] Obaidullah, M. (2005). Islamic Financial Services, Islamic Economics Research Center.##[20] Ma&#039;asoumi nia, Gh. (2008). Derivatives; Jurisprudential and Economic Study, Qom, Islamic Research Institute for Culture and Thought. (in Persian)##[21] Mohseni, F. (2013). A Comparative Study of Jurisprudential Challenges in the Futures and Options Market on the Basis of the Ideas of Shia and Sunni Thinkers, thesis, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Faculty of Humanities. (in Persian)##[22] Motahari, M. (2007). The Problem of Usury and Banking Together with Insurance, Tehran, Sadra. (in Persian)##[23] Ne&#039;mati, M. (2005). Futures Contract in Islamic Economics, M.A thesis, Tehran, Imam Sadiq University, Faculty of Islamic studies &amp; economic. (in Persian)##[24] Oil &amp; Gas Authority (OGA) - Energy Group - UK Production Data Release (https://www.gov.uk/guidance/oil-and-gas-uk-field-data).##[25] Pakzat, S. M. (2011). The Separation between Constant and Variable Elements of Islamic Verdicts of Transactions, Case Study of Futures and Options in Capital Market, M.A thesis, Tehran, Imam Sadiq University, Faculty of Islamic studies &amp; economic. (in Persian)##[26] Pour Toroghi, H. Y. (2007). Futures Contract on the Mercantile Exchange, M.A thesis, University of Qom, Faculty of Law. (in Persian)##[27] Reza&#039;ee, M. (2003). Jurisprudence Study of derivatives, Qom, Journal of Islamic Economics,11: 35 – 48. (in Persian)##[28] Saleh Abadi, A. (2002). The Feasibility Study of Establishing Stock Futures Market for Listed Companies in Tehran Stock Exchange, M.A thesis, Tehran, Imam Sadiq University, Faculty of Islamic studies &amp; management. (in Persian)##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی رابطۀ شفافیت شرکتی و محدودیت در تأمین مالی در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شدۀ بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Examining the relationship between corporate transparency and financial constraints of Listed Companies in Tehran Stock Exchange</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف این پژوهش بررسی رابطۀ بین شفافیت شرکتی و محدودیت در تأمین مالی شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران است. در این زمینه، تعداد 118 شرکت در دورۀ زمانی 1383 تا 1394 انتخاب شد و فرضیه‌های پژوهش با تدوین الگو‌های رگرسیون لجستیک چندمتغیره و با استفاده از داده‌های تلفیقی بررسی شد؛ برای سنجش شفافیت شرکتی نیز از دو معیار شفافیت سود حسابداری و اقلام تعهدی اختیاری و برای تعیین شرکت‌هایی که محدودیت در تأمین مالی دارند، از شاخص بومی‌شدۀ KZ استفاده شد. یافته‌های پژوهش نشان می‌دهد شفافیت شرکتی با محدودیت در تأمین مالی رابطۀ معنی‌داری دارد که این نشان می‌دهد شرکت‌هایی که ازنظر شفافیت شرکتی وضعیت بهتری دارند، در زمینۀ تأمین مالی با محدودیت کمتری روبه‌رو خواهند بود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The purpose of this study is to examine the relationship between corporate transparency and financial constraints in the Tehran Stock Exchange. To this end, 118 companies, listed on the Tehran Stock Exchange, were selected as our sample in the period of 1383-1394 (2004-2015). Applying panel data in multivariate logistic regression models, we tested the hypotheses of the research. In the present study, accounting earning transparency and discretionary accruals criteria represent corporate transparency; furthermore, KZ criterion measures the financial constraints. The Findings of this research reveal that there exists a negative and significant relationship between corporate transparency and financial constraints. This means that companies with more transparent financial information would face fewer restrictions while financing.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>201</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>216</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>اسفندیار</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمدی</Family>
						<NameE>Esfandyar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mohammadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت، دانشکدۀ ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه ایلام، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت، دانشکدۀ ادبیات و علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>e.mohamadi@ilam.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فرشاد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سبزعلی پور</Family>
						<NameE>Farshad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sabzalipour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه حسابداری، دانشکدۀ ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه ایلام، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه حسابداری، دانشکدۀ ادبیات و</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>f.sabzalipour@ilam.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فاطمه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>دهقانی</Family>
						<NameE>Fatemeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Dehghani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانش‌آموختۀ کارشناسی‌ارشد، گروه مدیریت صنعتی، مؤسسۀ آموزش عالی باختر، ایلام، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانش‌آموختۀ کارشناسی‌ارشد، گروه مدیریت صنعتی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>fatemeh_dehghan93@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شفافیت شرکتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>محدودیت در تأمین مالی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>داده‌های تلفیقی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رگرسیون لجستیک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>[1] Aghaei, M., Ghaisari, Y., &amp; Peirozfar, Z. (2015).The effect of discretionary accruals onreducing financial constraints listed companies in firms listed at Tehran Stock Exchange. The First International Conference on Accounting, Auditing, Management and Economics. In Esfahan. (in Persian).##[2] BadavarNahandi, Y., Darkhor, S. (2013). The relationships among financial constraint, cash value and net investment of the firms listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Empirical Reaserch in Accounting, 2 (4): 167-189. (in Persian).##[3] BadavarNahandi, Y., Ghaderi, S., &amp; Beheshti-nahandi, R. (2014). Transparency of accounting information impact on investment inefficiency of the companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. Quarterly Journal of Economic Research and Policies, 21 (68): 49-64. (in Persian).##[4] Balakrishnan, K., Core, J. E., &amp; Verdi, R. S. (2011). The relation between reportingquality and financing and investment: Evidence from shocks to financing capacity. Journal ofAccounting Research, 52 (1): 1-36.##[5]Baradaran Hassanzadeh, R., BadavarNahandi, Y., &amp; Negahban, L. (2013). The impact of financial constraints and agency costs of investment efficiency. Journal of Financial Accounting Reaserch, 1 (13): 89-106. (in Persian).##[6] Barth, M. E., Konchitchki, Y., &amp; Landsman, W. R. (2008). Cost of capital and earnings transparency. Working Paper, Stanford University and the University Of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. Available At URL:http://www.ssrn.com.##[7] Beaty, A., Liao, S., &amp; Weber, J. (2010) .Financial reporting quality, private information, monitoring and the lease-versus-buy decision. The Accounting Review, 85 (4): 1215-1238.##[8] Biddle, G., Hilary, G., &amp; Verdi, R. (2009). How does financial reporting quality improve investment efficiency? Journal of Accounting and Economics, 48 (2-3): 112-131.##[9] Botosan, C. A. (1997). Disclosure level and the cost of equity capital. Accounting Review, 72 (3): 323-349.##[10] Bushman, R., Piotroski, J., &amp; Abble, S. (2001). What determines corporate transparency? Journal of Accounting Research, 42 (2): 207-252.##[11] Chan, K. S., Dang, W. Q. T., &amp; Yan, I. K. M. (2012). Chinese firms’ political connection, ownership and financing constraints. Economics Letters, 115 (2): 164-167.##[12] Chen, Y., Hua, X., &amp; Boateng, A. (2016). Effects of foreign acquisitions on financial constraints, dose the role of disclosure transparency matter? International Business Review, 25 (6): 218-235.##[13] DeBoskey, D. G., Gillett, P. R. (2014). The impact of multi-dimensional corporate transparency on us firms’ credit ratings and cost of capital. Rev Quant Finan Acc, 40 (1): 101–134.##[14] Dechow, P., Sloan, R., &amp; Sweeney, A. (2005). Detecting earning management. The Accounting Review, 70 (2): 193-225.##[15] Diamond, D. W. (1985). Optimal release of information by firms. Journal of Finance, 40 (4): 1071–1094.##[16] Diamond, D. W., Verrecchia, R. E. (1991). Verrecchia, disclosure, liquidity and the cost of capital. Journal of Finance. 46 (4): 1325-1359.##[17] Dongmei, L. (2009) Financial constraints, R&amp;D investment and stock returns: Theory and evidence. Working paper. The Wharton School, University of Pennsylvania.##[18]Easley, D., O&#039;Hara, M. (2004). Information and the cost of capital. Journal of Finance, 59 (4): 1553-1583.##[19] Ebrahimi, K., Ahmadi-Moghadam, M. (2016). The relationship between financing constraints and conditional and unconditional conservatism of the companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Financial Management Strategy, 3 (4): 73-88. (in Persian).##[20] Elliott, W. K., Brooke, D., &amp; Peecher, E. (2010). Expected mispricing:the joint influence of accounting transparency and investor base. Journal of Accounting Research, 48 (2): 343-381.##[21] Fama, E. F., Jensen, M. C. (1983). Jensen the separation of ownership and control. The Journal of Law and Economics, 26 (2): 25-31.##[22]Fatahi, R. (2016). The relationship between the level of financial constraints, companies with future stock returns. 5th International Conference on Accounting andManagement. Niroo Institute Conf Center.(in Persian).##[23] Francis, J. R., Lafond, P., &amp; Schipper, K. (2005). Schipper the market pricing of accruals quality. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 39: 295-327.##[24] Gautam,V., Vaidya, R. (2013). Growth and finance constraints in Indian manufacturing firms. Applied Financial Economics, 24 (1): 31-40.##[25] Guariglia, A., Yang, J. (2016). A balancing act: Managing financial constraints and agency costs to minimize investment inefficiency in the Chinese market. Journal of Corporate Finance, 36: 111-130.##[26] Hashemi, S., Sadeghei, M., &amp; Soroshyar, A. (2010). The earnings quality role on pattern, financing policy and investment efficiency of Tehran Security Exchange. Journal of Accounting Reaserch, 6 (2): 86-102.(in Persian).##[27] Hayashi, F. (1982). Tobin&#039;s marginal q and average q: A neoclassical interpretation. Econometrica, 50 (1): 213-224.##[28] Hope, O. K., Thomas, W. B., &amp; Vyas, D. (2009). Transparency, ownership and financing constraints in private firms. Available atSSRN:http://ssrn.com/abstract=1535644.##[29] Howell, A. (2016). FirmR&amp;Dinnovation and easing financial constraints in China: Does corporate tax reform matter? Research Policy, 45 (10):1996–2007.##[30] Irani, R. M., Oesch, D. (2015). Financial constraints and corporate disclosure: Evidence from a quasi-experiments. Journal of Financial Economics, 109: 398–418.##[31] Kalatzis, A. E. G., Pellicani, A., &amp; Moccellin, J. V. (2010). The impact of corporate governance on financial constraint: Evidence from Brazilian firms. International Conference on Applied Economics, ICOAE 2010.##[32]Kanani-Amiri, M. (2008). Financial constraints and stock return in capital market. Daneshvar Raftar Bimonthly, 4 (26): 17-31.(in Persian).##[33] Kaplan, S. N., Zingales, L. (1997). Do investment-cash flow sensitivities provide useful measures of financing constraints? The Quarterly Journal of Economics,. 112 (1): 169-215.##[34] Kasznik, R. (1999). On the association between voluntary disclosure and earnings management. Journal of Accounting Research, 37 (1): 57-81.##[35]Khashanipour, M., Rasekhi, S., Naghinejad, B., &amp; Rasaiian, A. .(2011). Financial constraints and investment-cash flow sensitivity in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Accounting Advances, 2 (2): 51-74. (in Persian).##[36] Kordestani, R., Alavei, M. (2010). The effect of accounting transparency on the cost of equity. Journal of Securities Exchange, 3 (12): 43-61. (in Persian).##[37] Lambert, R., Leuz, C. &amp; Verrecchia, R. E. (2007). Accounting information, disclosure, and the cost of capital. Journal of Accounting Research, 45 (2): 385-420.##[38] Lang, M. H., Lundholm. R. J. (2000). Voluntary disclosure and equity offerings: Reducing information asymmetry or hyping the stock? Contemporary Accounting Research, 17: 623-662.##[39] Leuz, C., Winsock, P. (2008). Economic consequences of financial reporting and disclosure regulation: A review and suggestions for future research. Working Paper, University of Chicago.##[40] Li-Chiu, C. (2009). Do transparency and disclosure predict firm performance? evidence from the taiwan market. Journal Homepage Elsevier, 36 (8): 11198-11203.##[41] Mashayekh, S., SadatNasiry, N. (2016). The impact of financial reporting transparency on value relevance of earning accounting. Journal of Empirical Research in Accounting, 5 (3): 127-154. (in Persian).##[42] Myers, S. C., Majluf. N. S. (1984). Corporate financing and investment decisions when firms have information that investors do not have. Journal of Financial Economics, 13: 187-221.##[43] Negintaji, Z., Hashemi Golsefidi. A. (2015). The effect of transparency profit on the capital cost and additional returns of companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange. Journal of Macro and Strategic Policy, 3 (11): 95-114. (in Persian).##[44] Ogneva, M., Raghunandan, K., &amp; Subramanian, K. R. (2006). Subramanian, internal control weakness and cost of equity: Evidence from SOX section 404 disclosures. AAA Financial Accounting and Reporting Section. (FARS) Meeting Paper. Available at SSRN: http://ssrn.com/abstract5766104.##[45] Rajan, R., Zingales, L. (1998). Finance dependence and growth. American Economic Review, 88: 559–586.##[46] Tehrani, R., Hasarzade, R.(2009) The effect of free cash flows and financial constraint on over-investment and under-investment. Journal of Accounting Research, 5 (3): 50-67. (in Persian).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				