<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه اصفهان</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دارایی و تأمین مالی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1170</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Comparative Investigation the Hazard Model and the Accounting Model Using Receive Operating Characteristic (ROC) Curve for Bankruptcy Predication</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تطبیقی الگوی خطر و الگوی حسابداری با استفاده از منحنی مشخصۀ عملکرد سیستم (ROC) برای پیش‌بینی ورشکستگی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>121</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>134</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">21386</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22108/amf.2017.21386</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نازنین</FirstName>
					<LastName>صالحی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد حسابداری، گروه حسابداری، دانشکده حسابداری مدیریت دانشگاه آزاد مبارکه، اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>هادی</FirstName>
					<LastName>امیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه اقتصاد، دانشکدۀ علوم اداری و اقتصاد، دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Bankruptcy prediction in economic corporations is one of the financial branches that has become more prominent in the last two decades, so that the bankruptcy models have been developed and included variables of the macroeconomic environment and market conditions along with accounting variables. Since accounting approach is frequently used in Iran, comparing different approaches is of great importance. This study mainly aims to investigate the hazard model proposed by Campbell et al. (2008) in Iran&#039;s economic environment and compare it with the accounting model consisting of variables of the Ohlson&#039;s model (1980) and the Shumway&#039;s hazard model (2001) in prediction of bankruptcy. Figures of 241 Iranian corporations, admitted in Tehran stock Exchange between 2003 and 2015 have been used. In order to test the models, the logistic regression method was used and to compare the power of the models in prediction of bankruptcy, Receiver Operating Characteristic (ROC) curve analysis method was employed. The results show that the hazard model developed by Campbell et al. (2008) significantly predicts bankruptcy of non-financial corporations and is more accurate than the Ohlson&#039;s (2010) accounting model in predicting bankruptcy, But its difference with the Shumway model (2001) was not significant in the dimension of accuracy.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پیش‌بینی ورشکستگی بنگاه‌های اقتصادی یکی از شاخه‌های رشتۀ مالی است که در دو دهۀ اخیر توجه بیشتری به آن شده است؛ به‌گونه‌ای که الگو‌های ورشکستگی توسعه‌یافته و متغیرهای محیط کلان اقتصادی و شرایط بازار را به همراه متغیرهای حسابداری در بر می‌گیرد. از آنجا که در ایران از رویکرد حسابداری استفادۀ بیشتری شده است، مقایسۀ رویکردهای مختلف اهمیت دارد. هدف اصلی پژوهش، بررسی الگوی خطر کمپبل و همکاران (2008) در محیط اقتصادی ایران و مقایسۀ آن با الگوی حسابداری متشکل از متغیرهای الگوی اُلسون (1980) و الگوی خطر شام‌وی (2001) در بُعد صحت پیش‌بینی ورشکستگی است. در این پژوهش از داده‌های 241 شرکت پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران بین1382 تا 1394 استفاده شده است. برای تخمین الگو‌ها از روش رگرسیون لجستیک و برای مقایسۀ قدرت الگو‌ها در پیش‌بینی ورشکستگی از روش تحلیل منحنی مشخصۀ عملکرد سیستم (ROC) استفاده شد. نتایج نشان می‌دهد الگوی خطر کمپبل و همکاران (2008) به‌طور معناداری، ورشکستگی شرکت‌های غیرمالی را پیش‌بینی می‌کند و دقت آن بیشتر از الگوی حسابداری اُلسون (1980) در پیش‌بینی ورشکستگی است؛ اما تفاوت آن با الگوی شام‌وی (2001) در بُعد دقت معنادار نشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوی حسابداری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوی خطر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیش‌بینی ورشکستگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">منحنی مشخصۀ عملکرد سیستم (ROC)</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://amf.ui.ac.ir/article_21386_b16e9c0096d6c01c7b6fcbd480a89a56.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
