@article{ 
author = {ShafieiKadkani, Mohammad Rez},  
title = {The evolution of an Image}, 
abstract ={This article intends to examine the processes of change in poetic images from simplicity to exaggeration. In so doing, the author , upon meticulous examination of the old sources, discusses the occupation of the society's mentality in Saadi's well-known poem KAZ SANG NALE KHIZAD ROOZ-E VEDA-E YARAN (The stone will moan upon the friends' farewell) and presents the evolutionary process of a poetic image across time. Perhaps, the earliest mental script of the Iranian society for FARYAD AZ JODAEI (yelling out at separation) should be traced back in an ancient proverb of the Sasanids age which associates the concept with tearing the canvas dress. This image has been recorded in literary and poetic texts of the fourth century. Several years later, the poets implied the same sense through the image of breaking the wood. Eventually, Saadi exaggerates the image and expresses it through stone's moaning.},  
Keywords = {Image, evolution, Saadi, Artistic occupation of the society.   },
volume = {16},
Number = {60}, 
pages = {7-12}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-928-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-928-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2008}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Payamani, Behnaz},  
title = {A study of economic evolution and Industry development in Shahname}, 
abstract ={Economic evaluation of various societies is a way to better understand the governments and people's life. A review of the economic system of societies in the very far past- through their famous literature records- will reveal their industry, sub-divisions and active associations in the related fields, and also some hidden layers of their past. This paper considers environmental and meteorological conditions of Shahname and tribe battles, along with the necessity of governmental attention to people's life, to discuss activities such as agriculture, veterinary, weaving, blacksmithing, shipbuilding, and their rate of development.},  
Keywords = {Shahname, society, industry, agriculture, veterinary, weaving, blacksmithing, shipbuilding},
volume = {16},
Number = {60}, 
pages = {13-33}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-929-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-929-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2008}  
}

@article{ 
author = {ZahiriNav, Bijan and Ebrahimpour, Mohamm},  
title = {Sa\'di’s rhetorical views based on his Qasidas (odes)}, 
abstract ={Sadi is one of the few Persian poets whose fame and eternal presence in the Persian culture rests mostly on the effect of his works. This study is an effort to investigate the relationship between his didactic, rhetorical, religious and ethical poems and the principles of the Ash'ari school of rhetorical thought. To this end, we will define the discipline of rhetoric and mention its characteristic features as well as the reasons for its emergence and development, and also the probable weaknesses and failure of the Mo'tazele and Ashare. The two dominant schools of rhetoric in the Islamic civilization will be given special treatment. However, in the final section of the project, entitled &#34;Sa'di's school of Rhetoric&#34; the historical background and the reasons for Sa'dis tendency toward Ash'ari school will be explained.&#160; Finally evidence for this tendency and reflections of his Ash'ari thought samples will be extracted from his poems and will be classified and explained under the common rhetorical topics such as &#34;divine sight&#34;, &#34;divine justice&#34;, and &#34;determinism and free will},  
Keywords = {Saadi, poems, Ashari, rhetorical topics},
volume = {16},
Number = {60}, 
pages = {35-64}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-930-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-930-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2008}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Forouzandeh, Masou},  
title = {A Structural analysis of Ayyuqi\'s Varaqeh - o - Golshah’s plot}, 
abstract ={Varaqeh-o- Golshah is a beautiful and charming story, which Ayyuqi has put into verse. The analysis of the components and the elements composing a story paves the way for the story to be known much better and reveals its merits and demerits. We have, therefore, had a structuralist look at the plot of the story as one of its basic elements. In the story Varaqeh, the protagonist, aims at marrying Golshah. To this end he faces the resistance of the opponent forces; so the conditions of his own balanced life and those of his tribe are disturbed. But later on the protagonist succeeds to overcome his opponents with the helpful forces and achieves his aim. He also succeeds to restore the balanced and organized conditions &#8211; which are the result of the story&#8217;s events &#8211; to his life and that of his tribe. The events that happen in the story form four Sequences in its plot. In this writing, as mentioned, the plots of the story and its consisting components have been analyzed from the viewpoint of structuralism.},  
Keywords = {Varaqeh - O - Golshah , Structuralism , story, plot},
volume = {16},
Number = {60}, 
pages = {65-81}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-931-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-931-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2008}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Fallah, Qolam Ali},  
title = {Dialogue in Shahname}, 
abstract ={This study explores dialogue, a dominant style in both traditional and contemporary poetry / prose&#160; narrative literature, in Shahname as a classical&#160; masterpiece. To this end, initially, the concept and terminology of dialogue is scrutinized from the viewpoint of narration and its position and functions are discussed. Then, a reasonably large number of various dialogues are extracted from Shahname and examined in terms of their different features, including their in/directness and the partners. Finally, to analyze the role of this literary element, a subset of the distinguished dialogues basically concerned with champions are analyzed further for their content and topic and how they correspond with the conditions and setting factors. It is concluded that the literary element under study is basically represented in the heroic section and the dominant theme is boastfulness.},  
Keywords = {Ferdowsi, Shahname, Dialogue, Narration},
volume = {16},
Number = {60}, 
pages = {83-105}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-932-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-932-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2008}  
}

@article{ 
author = {MohammadiAsiabadi, Ali},  
title = {The wind and wine (A structural analysis of a poem by Maolavi)}, 
abstract ={Maolavi known as Rumi, in a lyrical poem discussed in this essay, expresses some of his mystical points of view, not explicitly, but through the poem&#8217;s structure. This poem has an organic form and in its structure there is a sign that indicates &#34;wind&#34; in its own absence has become a symbol. This poem because of its special structure can show a part of stylistic distinctness of Rumi in poetry.},  
Keywords = {Lyrical poem, Structure, Wind, Maolavi},
volume = {16},
Number = {60}, 
pages = {107-130}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-933-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-933-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2008}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Nikoubakht, Naser and Ranjbaran, Abbas},  
title = {Criticizing and analyzing the method used by Saeed Nafisi for correcting Persian Classic Literary Texts}, 
abstract ={Revival of written works in a society is a way for a better understanding of the society&#8217;s culture and civilization. The knowledge of criticism and correction of the texts helps to study the past written works by removing the dust of distortion and time that sits on such works. Saeed Nafisi is a researcher who has entered into this area and corrected some texts in a critical manner for the first time. Most of his efforts were concentrated on reviving verse type texts. Considering the criteria required in correcting texts, this paper has dealt with his critical methods and views by studying 10 texts corrected by him, including 6 verse type works (Divan-e Anvari, Divan-e Attar, Divan-e Amaaq, Divan-e Rashidoddin-e Vatvat, Robaiyate Baba Afzal, Kkoliat-e Araqi) and four prose type works (Tarikh-e Beyhaqi, Goshayesh and Rahayesh, Lobab-al Albab, Reslaeye Fereydone Sepahsalar).},  
Keywords = {Literal Criticism, Texts Criticism, Text Correction, Saeed Nafisi. },
volume = {16},
Number = {60}, 
pages = {131-153}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-934-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-934-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2008}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Yahaqi, Mohammad Jafar and Adinekalat, Faramarz},  
title = {The Social backgrounds of the defeat of the Sasanian\'s Emperor}, 
abstract ={In the present paper, the analysis of the background and sociological reasons of the defeat of the Sasanian 's emperor&#160; has been examined by Ferdowsi's Shahname. Some of these factors have been pointed out by historiographers, like war for power by the Sasanian 's emperor. But Ferdowsi has new viewpoints about these problems like women&#8217;s reign. Some of the reasons have been recognized by Ferdowsi like national origin and women's reign. Although the selection of the starting point of the discussion very difficult but for some reasons, which are mentioned in the text of the research, Khosrow Parviz's reign is the starting point of this discussion.},  
Keywords = {Shahname, social analysis, Sasanian. },
volume = {16},
Number = {60}, 
pages = {155-176}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-935-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-935-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2008}  
}

@article{ 
author = {ShafiiKadkani, Mohammad Rez},  
title = {The prosodic Characteristics of Soltan Valad\'s Diwan}, 
abstract ={This article presents a new aspect of the poems of Soltan Valad, Jalaleddin Mohammad Moulawi's senior son.&#160; In his poetry, one may spot a new prosodic feature which is drastically different from all classical Persian poems. This difference is so significant that one can hardly attribute it to such typical errors made by scribes, typists or publishers. After highlighting this feature, the author presents two possible factors underlying this difference: The contrasts in the phonological system of the Persian words due to proximity with the Greek and Turkish languages in Qunieh, and the impact of the music dominating the House of Dervishes and the style of the story tellers and writers of that age.},  
Keywords = {Soltan Valad, Prosody, Phonological system},
volume = {16},
Number = {62}, 
pages = {7-15}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-936-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-936-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2008}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Fotoohi, Mahmoo},  
title = {The Significance of Ambiguity in literature}, 
abstract ={Unlike ancient rhetoricians who rejected ambiguity altogether, modern theorists consider it as a value. This article, initially, presents a historical survey as well as the modern approaches to ambiguity and highlights the modern aesthetic tendency toward ambiguity and polysemy. After the early years of 20th century, ambiguity was considered as the essential essence of literary texts by literary critics and theorists. Second, the article discusses the value of ambiguity in literary works and draws a borderline between difficulty and polysemy (i.e. pluralization and multiple meaning). Then, it introduces some kinds of ambiguity and elaborates on their distinct features. Meanwhile, this article pinpoints the basic deference between language and literature through emphasizing the value and function of ambiguity.&#160; The main purpose of the article, then, is to emphasis that &#34;ambiguity as inherent nature of literature&#34; and stresses the principle saying: &#34;the artistic value of a literary work and the secret of its eternality depend on the amount of its ambiguity&#34;. If one ignores the ambiguity in literary texts, he would lose its spirit and essential essence. Ambiguity causes an interaction between&#160;&#160; reader and text and fosters the ability of meaning creation by readers.&#160; Through persuading the readers to react to the content of text, ambiguity provides the opportunities for generations to engage in different dialogues with text across time and history.},  
Keywords = {Ambiguity, Difficulty, Polysemy (pluralization & multiple meaning), Literature},
volume = {16},
Number = {62}, 
pages = {17-36}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-937-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-937-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2008}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Pahlavannezhad, Mohammad Reza and Naseri, Nosrat Mashhadi},  
title = {A linguistic Analysis of a Letter from Beyhaqi}, 
abstract ={This article examines a letter from Beyhagi s history,&#160;based on pragmatic theories. Based on this approach, the context of situation, diexis, including: social, personal, time and spatial diexis are analyzed in the text. In other words, the communicative competence of the writer or his linguistic knowledge and his application of rules in different situations are taken into consideration. Since the communicative competence of the writer is interrelated with his attitude and motivation and in so far as the description of language functions in a text can illustrate some of the linguistic features, not explicitly cited in the text, such analyses may play an important role in our literature. To this end, the segmental elements like words, and sentences as well as&#160; some supra segmental features like stress and intonation are analyzed in the text.&#160;},  
Keywords = {Functional semantics, Context of situation, Speech act.},
volume = {16},
Number = {62}, 
pages = {37-58}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-938-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-938-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2008}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Heidari, Mahbubeh},  
title = {On the Role of Narrator and Audience in Suffi\'s Dreams}, 
abstract ={order to communicate with the celestial world. Also, it is a unique means to introduce and suggest many key thoughts of Sufism. Dreams are normally stated in a narrative style. All dreams of Sufi literature depict narrative themes. This paper examines the qualities of dream narration and the role of the two substantial elements: narrator and addressee in forming the narrative style of dream.},  
Keywords = {Narrative style, Narration, Dream, Narrator, Addressee.},
volume = {16},
Number = {62}, 
pages = {59-91}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-939-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-939-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2008}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Mousavi, Seyed Kazem and Khosrawi, Ashraf},  
title = {The Struggle between Shadow and Consciousness in Nezami\'s &#34;Kheir &#38; Shar&#34;}, 
abstract ={Nezami Ganjavi enjoys a worldwide reputation as a great poet. His story-telling is based on reality. Together with his indescribable imagination, this feature has made him a distinguished poet in the realm of humanism and psychiatry. It seems that his genius is best depicted in Haft Peykar (Seven Planets) especially in his seven tales containing the inner layer as well as the outside elements of the story. One can go from the surface structure of his poems to the deep structure of his human character and, hence, discover the hidden aspects of his human character. A remarkable story in Haft-Peykar is the story of &#34;Khair&#34; and &#34;shar&#34;. The theme of this story is a debate between two young people called Kheir (good) and Shar (evil/bad). This story can be interpreted in terms of psychology of the young. According to this classic psychological theory, the hidden aspects have a special status in manُ s spirit.These aspects sometimes manifest themselvessymbolically in humanُ's consciousness. In this story, good symbolizes humanُ s consciousness and bad/evil is the symbol of shadow and humanُ s subconscious. These two aspects finally reach a unity after a long debate with each other. The numerous archetypes such as anima, shadow, rebirth, journey, water and tree play significant roles in this struggle. The present paper is an attempt to shed some lights on these aspects.},  
Keywords = {Conciousness, shadow, journey, kheir, shar},
volume = {16},
Number = {62}, 
pages = {93-111}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-940-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-940-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2008}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Neqabi, Effat},  
title = {The Status of Heart in Mathnavi}, 
abstract ={Due to the significance of heart in mystical poem, in general, and in Mathnavi Maanavi, in particular, this article attempts to investigate the position and status of heart and probe the challenging question as to which heart deserves accommodation of the position of the Real. To this end, initially, the lexical origin and behavior of &#34;heart&#34; as well as its reason of appellation is provided and discussed. Then, the unique characteristics of Celestial hearts are presented and the barriers between the heart and the Divine Kingdom are discussed.},  
Keywords = {Heart, The mirror of the heart, Knowledge, Heart of the Saints, Moulawi, Mathnavi Maanavi},
volume = {16},
Number = {62}, 
pages = {113-134}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-941-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-941-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2008}  
}

@article{ 
author = {BahmaniMotlaq, Yadollah},  
title = {Simile in Sepehri\'s Poems}, 
abstract ={Simile is one of the main forms of imagination in any literature serving other forms of imagination because the principle in such images is of &#8220;the sameness&#8221; kind. Likewise, this figure is used in different forms of imagination such as metaphor, variety, expansion and freshness in the poems by Sepehri. This paper examines various views on the quantity and quality of his images, having or not having frames and classifies the allegories employed by him through reviewing a corpus of his well-known samples. The paper is based on different types of simile in terms of bases, sensibility and wisdom of the parties, variety of the parties, etc. in order to categorize the samples. Nevertheless, in his review of the samples, the author has not limited himself to the traditional views but has also studied the new European schools of thought. One way to recognize the ideas of poets and uncover the corners of their minds is to explore the images in their poems. Accordingly, the present research has tried to examine the underlying thoughts of the poet as well as his attitudes.},  
Keywords = {Sohrab Sepehri, Simile},
volume = {16},
Number = {62}, 
pages = {135-162}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-942-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-942-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2008}  
}

