<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Persian Language and Literature</title>
<title_fa>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبیات فارسی</title_fa>
<short_title>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبيات فارسی</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2476-6925</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2476-6941</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/jpll</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>11</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1385</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2007</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>14</volume>
<number>55</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>چرا نیما را شاعر «آی آدم‌ها» می‌نامند؟</title_fa>
	<title>Why is Nima called &quot;Ai Adamha&quot; Poet ?</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p&gt;اغلب بر این باورند، که ساختمان شعر، چیزی جدا و کم اهمیت&#8204;تر از معنا و پیام آن است؛ اما صورت شعر، اولین چیزی است که خـواننده را تحت تأثیر قرار می&#8204;دهد. نیما با حساسیت و تکیه بر بینشی مستقل، ارزش ساختمان شعر را، در ادب فارسی، احیا کرد. در شعر معاصر غالباً، نیما را شاعر &amp;laquo;آی آدم&#8204;ها&amp;raquo; می&#8204;دانند. سؤال این است، که راز اهمیت شعر &amp;laquo;آی آدم&#8204;ها&amp;raquo; در چیست؟ به نظر می&#8204;رسد آن&#8204;چه باعث برجستگی شعر &amp;laquo;آی آدم&#8204;ها&amp;raquo; و ساخت&#8204;&#8204;های مشابه در شعر معاصر است، ترفندها و انتظارات تعبیه&#8204;شده در فرم تازه آن&#8204;هاست، نه پیام و محتوای تکراری. تکــرار عنصر مسلط &amp;laquo;آی آدم&#8204;ها&amp;raquo; در ساختمان شعر مذکور، علاوه بر استحکام و اسکلت&#8204;بندی، توازن نحوی، تقویت موسیقی، واسازی ساختار و پایان&#8204;پذیری خلاق، به شعر وحدت اندیشه و احساس و یکپارچگی عاطفه و لحن، بخشیده است. این مقاله، با نقد شعر &amp;laquo;آی آدم&#8204;ها&amp;raquo; از منظر انتظارات و تنـظیمات فرمالیستی، سعی دارد تا علاوه بر تقویت حساسیت خوانندگان، آن&#8204;ها را مهیای کشف انواع اشارت&#8204;های کمتر آشنا، در ساختمان شعر معاصر کند.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Often readers and even critics believe that the ideology and message of poems are more important than their structures. However, it's impossible to draw a distinction between ideology and structure as the structure of a poem is the primary element that influences the readership. Nima ,as the architect of the contemporary poetry relying on his own sharp and independent insights, revived the significance of the structure in Persian literature. Many enthusiastic readers and even critics of the field of cotemporary poetry have considered Nima as the poet of 'Ai Adamha'. This paper attempts to explore why Nima has been called Ai Adfamha poet. Obviously, the significance of the poem 'Ai Adamha' and similar poetic structures lies in their literary figures and expectations embedded in their novel forms than their frequent content and message. The repetition&amp;nbsp; of the dominant element of Ai Adamha in the structure of the poem has, in addition to strengthening the skeleton of the poem, enhanced the syntactic integrity, musical system, coherence, and creative opening and ending of the poem. This article attempts to analyze 'Ai Adamha' from a formalistic perspective and in doing so it paves the way for the readership to delve into the less frequently uncovered senses of the contemporary poetry.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>نیما , شعر «آی آدم‌ها» , عنصر مسلط , فرم و معنا ,</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Nima's poem , contemporary poetry , dominant element , form and meaning </keyword>
	<start_page>19</start_page>
	<end_page>36</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-3-27&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Taghi </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Pournamdarian</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>تقی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>پورنامداریان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002501</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002501</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>تهران، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
