<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Persian Language and Literature</title>
<title_fa>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبیات فارسی</title_fa>
<short_title>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبيات فارسی</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2476-6925</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2476-6941</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/jpll</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>11</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1395</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>24</volume>
<number>81</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی انطباقی شعر پروین ‌اعتصامی و آثار یوسف اعتصام‌الملک</title_fa>
	<title>A Comparative Study of Parvin Etesami’s Poetry and Yousef Etesam al-Molk’s Works</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:1.0cm;&quot;&gt;پروین اعتصامی از شاعران صاحب&#8204;سبک و برجسته عصر مشروطه و فرزند یوسف اعتصامی است. اعتصام&#8204;الملک (1253-1316ش) نیز از جمله روشنفکران بزرگ اواخر دوره قاجار و از پیش&#8204;گامان ترجمه و آغازکنندگان رمانتیسم در ایران است که با ترجمه آثار مختلف و نگارش در زمینه&#8204;های گوناگون، نقشی مؤثر در رویکرد مدرن به ادبیات و البته زندگی در ایران داشته&#8204;است. شائبه تقلید و اقتباس کلی پروین از اعتصام&#8204;الملک از جمله مسائلی است که همواره محققان مختلف در دوره&#8204;های گوناگون به آن اشاره کرده&#8204;اند. این پژوهش با استفاده از شیوه آماری&#8204;ـ&#8204;تحلیلی، به بررسی میزان و چگونگی این تأثیرپذیری در زمینه&#8204;های مختلف (واژه، تصویر، محتوا و کنشگران روایت) پرداخته و به این نتیجه رسیده&#8204;است که اگرچه اعتصامی بسان هر شاعر دیگری از زمینه&amp;shy;های فکری گوناگون در شعر خود متأثر بوده&#8204;است، به&#8204;دلایل کاملاً روشن، از آثار پدر خویش بیش&#8204; از دیگران تأثیر پذیرفته و البته، تأثیرپذیری با تقلید و سرقت متفاوت است، اما آنچه حاصل این پژوهش است، نوآوری&#8204;های شاعر است در شکل و قالب، نوع نگاه و درمجموع سبک ویژه و نیز استقلال او در اندیشه و رویکردها ـ&#8204;به&#8204;خصوص در حوزه تفکرات مشترک&#8204;ـ که از او شاعری ماندگار و صاحب&#8204;نام آفریده است.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Parvin-e E`tesami, the daughter of Yousef E`tesami, was one of the eminent poets of the constitutional period. Her father, E`tesam al-Molk was a remarkable intellectual. He was one of the very first translators and one of the writers whose work started Romanticism in Iran in the last years of Qajar dynasty. He translated pieces from a vast range of topics and, thus, he had an undeniable role in the development of literature and also a modernist look towards life. As the time passed, the idea of Parvin imitating and taking from her father&amp;rsquo;s works became a widely cited view among the scholars. This research, by using a statistical-analytical method, has investigated the quality and quantity of this linkage in some points (such as diction, imagery, themes, characters) and shows that although Parvin, like any other poet, was influenced by many thoughts and ideas, for some clear reasons the strongest influence was that of her father. It is of course obvious that this influence does not mean mere imitation or plagiarism. The conclusion of this research is that the poet had some innovations in form, format and point of view that formed her special thought and style in poetry. This unique outlook, especially on the common issues of the day, is what indeed makes her a well-known and unforgettable poet.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>پروین اعتصامی, شعر, تأثیرپذیری, یوسف اعتصام‌الملک</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Parvin E'tesami, Poetry, Influence, Yousef Etesam al-Molk.</keyword>
	<start_page>179</start_page>
	<end_page>199</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-11-653-48&amp;slc_lang=other&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>قدسیه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رضوانیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Ghrezvan@umz.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846001627</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001627</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه مازندران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مریم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>محمودی نوسر</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>msmahmoodi_13@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001628</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001628</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه مازندران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
