<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Persian Language and Literature</title>
<title_fa>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبیات فارسی</title_fa>
<short_title>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبيات فارسی</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2476-6925</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2476-6941</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/jpll</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>11</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1392</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2013</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>21</volume>
<number>75</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>نقش یک نقطه در قرائت کلمه و تأثیر آن در سوق معنای شعر حافظ</title_fa>
	<title>The Role of Diacritical Point in Reading a Word and Its effect on Defining the Meaning of the Poems of Hafiz</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p&gt;بعضی کاتبان نسخه&#8204;های خطی دیوان حافظ و ازآن&#8204;جمله کاتبان سده نهم هجری در امر کتابت به سبب شتاب&#8204;کاری یا بی&#8204;اهمیت&#8204;دانستن نقطه درقالب کلمه، در قید نقطه در جای صحیح آن تسامح کرده&#8204;اند یا آن را از قلم انداخته&#8204;اند.&lt;br&gt;
برای مصحح دیوان حافظ به&#8204;ویژه هنگام استناد به ضبط نسخه&#8204;های خطی این اشکال پیش می&#8204;آید که کلمه&#8204;ای را که فرضاً نقطه حرف اول آن ساقط است نه می&#8204;توان در ردیف نسخه&#8204;هایی منظور کرد که در آن موضع یک فعل مثبت کتابت کرده&#8204;اند و نه جزء آن گروهی که آن کلمه در آن نسخه&#8204;ها معرف یک فعل منفی است.&lt;br&gt;
درضمنِ سه نمونه&amp;shy;ای که در این مقاله مطرح شده است، مشخص می&#8204;شود که مصححان دیوان حافظ نتوانسته&#8204;اند با پذیرش معنی و تفسیری معین از بعضی ابیات حافظ در کتابت آن کلمه محل اختلاف نیز به توافق برسند. مسئله انس و عادت با یک قرائت خاص یا جانبداری از متن یا یک چاپ ویژه، مانع از آن شده است که چنین توافقی ایجاد شود.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Some of the scribes of manuscripts of the poems of Hafiz, including the scribes of the ninth century AH, due to their haste or because they thought little of the importance of diacritical points in the words, did not care for the right position of point in writing or even sometimes omitted it.For the editor of the poetry of Hafiz, especially in his reference toand use of the manuscripts, the problem is that when a word whose first letter, for example, has no pointhe can neither put the word among those manuscripts that take the word as a positive verb nor among those where the word is written as a negative verb.The three examples given in this article show that the editors of the poetry of Hafiz could not come to an agreement regarding the writing of the word in question on the basis of a certain meaningor interpretation of some of the verses of Hafiz. Indeed interest in one reading or following one editionhave made this agreement impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>حافظ , دگرسانی‌های دیوان حافظ , نقطه محذوف در نسخ خطی ,</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Hafiz, Varience in the Poetry of Hafiz, omitted diacritical point in manuscripts</keyword>
	<start_page>7</start_page>
	<end_page>16</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-3-16&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Salim</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Neysari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سلیم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نیساری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001013</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001013</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>عضو پیوسته فرهنگستان زبان و ادب فارسی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
