<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Persian Language and Literature</title>
<title_fa>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبیات فارسی</title_fa>
<short_title>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبيات فارسی</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2476-6925</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2476-6941</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/jpll</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>11</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1390</year>
	<month>1</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2011</year>
	<month>4</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>19</volume>
<number>70</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی و مقایسه صورخیال در شعر حسین منزوی و قیصر امین‌پور</title_fa>
	<title>A Comparative Study of Figures of Speech in Poems by Hossein Monzavi and Gheisar Aminpour</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p&gt;تصرف ذهن شاعر در مفاهیم و امور عادی زندگی و ارتباط آن با طبیعت حاصل بینش و آگاهی او&amp;shy; از پدیده&amp;shy;های طبیعی و جهان بیرون است. مجموعه تصاویر حاصل از انواع صورخیال (استعاره، تشبیه، مجاز، کنایه) در دیوان هر &amp;shy;شاعری بیانگر لحظه&amp;shy;هایی&amp;shy; است که با درون و جهان درونی او سروکار دارد؛ در واقع، انعکاس روح، شخصیت و ویژگی&amp;shy;های درونی اوست. هدف این پژوهش بررسی عناصر خیال (استعاره، تشبیه، مجاز، کنایه) و بسامد هرکدام در شعر امین&#8204;پور و منزوی و دست&#8204;یافتن به نتایجی حاصل از اندیشه، عواطف، احساسات و نگرش آن&#8204;ها به جهان و زندگی است. تصاویر مشترک این دو شاعر یا تصویر مرکزی اشعار آن&#8204;ها مربوط به عشق و مسائل پیرامون آن است، هرچند بازتاب اجتماع و مسائل اجتماعی نیز کم&#8204;وبیش در اشعارشان به چشم می&amp;shy;خورد. تصاویر شعری دو شاعر، زنده، پویا و دیداری است. در شعر هرکدام از آن&#8204;ها تقلیدی اندک و ناچیز مشاهده می&amp;shy;شود، ولی حوزه تصاویر و صورخیال خویش را به تصاویر شعر سنتی منحصر نکرده&amp;shy;اند، بلکه نوآوری&amp;shy;هایی در شعر هر کدام مشاهده می&amp;shy;شود. تشبیهات، بیشتر فشرده و حاصل امور حسی ـ انتزاعی است.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The pertinence of a poet&amp;rsquo;s imagination in ordinary concepts of life and their relationship with nature is due to his or her insights and knowledge of natural phenomena as well as the outside world. In the collection of works of every poet, all various types of imagery being attributable to figures of speech (i.e., metaphor, simile, synecdoche, and irony) represent moments that deal with the poet&amp;rsquo;s inner world; in fact, they are the reflections of the poet&amp;rsquo;s soul, personality, and inner characteristics. The current study was an attempt to scrutinize figures of speech and their frequency of use in Aminpour&amp;rsquo;s and Monzavi&amp;rsquo;s poems to find out the poets&amp;rsquo; thoughts, emotions, and ideology towards the world and life. The common shared imageries or the central poetical imageries of these two poets were around love and the issues surrounding it. Although, more or less, a reflection of the society and the social issues could be seen in their writings, their subject was mostly about love. Their poetical imageries were vivid, dynamic, and visual. Although even little imitations could be discernible in their poems, their imageries and figures of speech domains were not just limited to the imageries of traditional poetry, but innovations could be observed in their poems. Similes were mostly intense and intuitive-intangible, and metaphor and simile were used more frequently than the other figures of speech.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>صورخیال , قیصر امین‌پور , منزوی , تصویر , استعاره , تشبیه ,</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Figures of speech, Gheisar Aminpour, Hossein Monzavi, Imagery, Metaphor, Simile</keyword>
	<start_page>167</start_page>
	<end_page>196</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-3-122&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Seyyed Jamaleddin </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mortazavi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سید جمال‌الدین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مرتضوی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002416</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002416</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>استادیار/دانشگاه شهر کرد</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Sajad</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Najafi Behzadi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سجاد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نجفی بهزادی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>najafi23ir@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846002417</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002417</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>کارشناسی ارشد/ دانشگاه شهر کرد</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
