<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Persian Language and Literature</title>
<title_fa>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبیات فارسی</title_fa>
<short_title>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبيات فارسی</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2476-6925</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2476-6941</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/jpll</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>11</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1395</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2016</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>24</volume>
<number>80</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>امیر داد: منصبی دیوانی در تعدادی از متون تاریخی و ادبی فارسی</title_fa>
	<title>“Amir-e- dad”: A Governmental Position in Some of Persian Literary and Historical Texts</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:1.0cm;&quot;&gt;نظام حکومتی و تشکیلات اداری ایران در طول تاریخ تغییر کرده و دگرگون شده است. یکی از مناصبی که در بعضی از اعصار دایر بود و جزو مشاغل مهم دیوانی به&#8204;شمار می&#8204;رفت منصب امیر دادی است. صاحب این سمت را امیر داد یا میر داد می&#8204;گفتند. فرهنگ&#8204;نویسان و اربابان لغت چندین وظیفه متفاوت را برای امیر داد برشمرده&#8204;اند. عده&#8204;ای او را همان قاضی&#8204;القضات می&#8204;دانند. برخی وی را مجری اوامر شاه در روز مظالم و بعضی دیگر متصدی رسیدگی به امور توده مردم تلقی کرده&#8204;اند. عده&#8204;ای نیز از او با عنوان وزیر یا سرپرست دیوان عدالت یاد کرده&#8204;اند. نگارنده در این مقاله به&#8204;دنبال پاسخ به این پرسش اساسی است: امیر داد در تشکیلات اداری قدیم چه جایگاهی داشته و چه وظایفی برعهده او بوده است؟ این مقاله در چهار بخش تدوین شده است: در بخش نخست، ساخت واژگانی امیر داد بررسی می&#8204;شود. بخش دوم، روزگار رواج این اصطلاح را می&#8204;کاود. در بخش سوم، با توجه به برخی شواهد ادبی و تاریخی موجود، وظایف امیر داد و جایگاه او در نظام&#8204;های حکومتی&#8204;ای شرح داده می&#8204;شود که این منصب را به رسمیت می&#8204;شناختند. سرانجام در بخش چهارم، نگارنده به ذکر چند نکته درباره آداب تفویض سمت امیر دادی پرداخته است.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Governmental systems and administrative organizations in Iran have been always in change throughout history. A position which was necessary in some centuries and was counted as an important governmental position was &amp;ldquo;Amirdadi&amp;rdquo;. The person who held this post was called Amir-e dad or Mirdad. Lexicographers have mentioned several different tasks for Amir-e dad. Some believe they are the same as chief judges. Some have considered them as the executers of the King&amp;rsquo;s commands in Mazalem (justice) days. And some others have assumed they are the administrators who were responsible for public affairs. Some also have mentioned them as ministers or administrators of the Ministry of Justice. In this article the researcher attempts to answer this essential question: What position did Amir-e dad have in old administrative organization and for which tasks he was responsible? This article consists of four sections: in section one, the word structure of Amir-e dad is studied. Section two analyzes the era in which this term was prevalent. Section three describes the tasks and positions of Amir-e dad in governmental systems in which this post had been officially recognized, on the basis of some available literary and historical evidences. Finally, in section four, some points are mentioned on the ceremony of Amirdadi empowering.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>امیر داد, شغل دیوانی, دیوان مظالم, مجلس مظالم, متون ادبی و تاریخی فارسی</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Amir-e-dad, Governmental Position, Mazalem Ministry, Mazalem Meeting, Persian Literary and Historical Texts</keyword>
	<start_page>91</start_page>
	<end_page>113</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-653-32&amp;slc_lang=other&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Maryam </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Seyedan</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مریم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سیدان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>seyedan@sharif.edu</email>
	<code>10031947532846002340</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002340</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
