<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Persian Language and Literature</title>
<title_fa>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبیات فارسی</title_fa>
<short_title>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبيات فارسی</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2476-6925</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2476-6941</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/jpll</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>11</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>11</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2019</year>
	<month>2</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>26</volume>
<number>85</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>رویکرد سنت‌گرای مجله یغما به شعر معاصر</title_fa>
	<title>The Classicist Approach of Yaghma Magazine toward Contemporary Poetry</title>
	<subject_fa>ادبیات غنایی</subject_fa>
	<subject>ادبیات غنایی</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;مجله ادبی &lt;em&gt;یغما&lt;/em&gt;، در حوزه شعر، با هدف حفظ دستاوردهای کهن و مبارزه با هرگونه بدعت و نوآوری فعالیت خود را آغاز کرد. این درحالی است که سال&#8204;ها از حیات شعر نو گذشته بود و شاعران برجسته&#8204;ای در شعر نیمایی ظهور کرده&#8204; بودند. مقاله حاضر، با بررسی مسائل نظری مطرح&#8204;شده در زمینه شعر در این مجله و تحلیل آماری، محتوایی شکل و مضمون اشعار آن و مشخص&#8204;کردن شاعرانی که در این مجله به آنان بیش از دیگران توجه شده است، تلاش می&#8204;کند دریابد &lt;em&gt;یغما&lt;/em&gt; چقدر در پی&#8204;گیری خط&#8204;مشی&#8204;ای که در اولین شماره&#8204;اش برای خود در زمینه شعر ترسیم کرده، موفق عمل کرده است. آیا توانسته، بی&#8204;اعتنا به جریان نوگرایی، راه سنت را در پیش گیرد یا اینکه از این جریان تأثیر پذیرفته است. نتایج این پژوهش، که با روش توصیفی&#8204;ـ&#8204;تحلیلی و تحلیل محتوا انجام گرفته است، نشان می&#8204;دهد با اینکه &lt;em&gt;یغما&lt;/em&gt; در چاپ اشعار به&#8204;سبک گذشته و همکاری با شاعران متعصب در این زمینه، اهتمام فراوان داشته است و درصد زیادی از اشعار آن را غزل (33 درصد) و قصیده (25 درصد) و مضامین شعری کهن و اخوانیات تشکیل می&#8204;دهد، نتوانسته است به مطالبه مردمی که در زمینه نوگرایی شکل &#8204;گرفته است بی&#8204;توجه بماند؛ به&#8204;گونه&#8204;ای که برای پاسخگویی به این نیاز روز، به نوآوری&#8204;های محتاطانه دست می&#8204;زند و گاه به&#8204;اقتضای موقعیت، مجبور می&#8204;شود شاعران نوگرا را بستاید و حتی از آنان شعر منتشر کند. بااین&#8204;حال، رعایت جانب کلاسیک&#8204;ها، که قاطبه مخاطبان &lt;em&gt;یغما &lt;/em&gt;را تشکیل می&#8204;دهند، باعث می&#8204;شود این کار هرگز در&lt;em&gt; یغما&lt;/em&gt; به رویه تبدیل نشود.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;em&gt;Yaghma&lt;/em&gt;, The literary magazine in the field of poetry, started its activity with the aim of preserving ancient achievements and countering every kind of unapproved innovations and novelty. This was in spite of the fact that many years had passed since the beginning of modern poetry and there have emerged famous figures in &lt;em&gt;Nimaei&lt;/em&gt; poetry. The present article intends to see how much &lt;em&gt;Yaghma&lt;/em&gt; was successful in following its initial policy in the field of poetry delineated in its very first number. This will be done through a review of the theories of poetry published in this magazine and also content-statistical analysis of forms and contents of the poems and identifying the poets who were considered and heeded more than others in &lt;em&gt;Yaghma&lt;/em&gt;. Had &lt;em&gt;Yaghma&lt;/em&gt; been successful in following classicism regardless of modernism, or had it been affected by modern trends in poetry? Results of the current study, which was done by content analysis and descriptive-analytic method, show that although &lt;em&gt;Yaghma&lt;/em&gt; had serious attempts to print and publish classic poems and had great cooperation with dogmatic poets, and much of it comprised of Ghazal (33 percent), Ghasideh (25 percent), classical contents and &lt;em&gt;Akhavaniat&lt;/em&gt;, yet it could not ignore public demands for modern trends in poetry and sometimes made cautious innovations to satisfy contemporary needs and occasionally eulogized and praised innovative (or modern) poets due to expediencies of the age, and even published some of their poems. However, to defend and respect its classic followers who form the main body of its audience, &lt;em&gt;Yaghma&lt;/em&gt; prevented this from becoming a regular approach in the magazine.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot; &gt;
&amp;nbsp;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>مجله یغما, شعر نو, شعر کلاسیک, نوگرایی, سنت‌گرایی</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Yagham Magazine, New Poetry, Classic Poetry, Modernism, Classicism</keyword>
	<start_page>279</start_page>
	<end_page>302</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1855-15&amp;slc_lang=other&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Morad Ali </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Vaezi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مرادعلی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>واعظی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>ma.vaezi@birjand.ac</email>
	<code>10031947532846004241</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004241</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>University of Birjand</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه بیرجند</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Safieh </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Jamali</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>صفیه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>جمالی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>safiejamali@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846004242</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004242</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>University of Birjand</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه بیرجند</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
