<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Persian Language and Literature</title>
<title_fa>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبیات فارسی</title_fa>
<short_title>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبيات فارسی</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2476-6925</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2476-6941</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/jpll</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>11</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1391</year>
	<month>7</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2012</year>
	<month>10</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>20</volume>
<number>73</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>حافظ و خلاف‌عادت در صورت و معنی غزل</title_fa>
	<title>Hafez and Norm-breaking in Form and Content of the Ghazal</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p&gt;خروج از عادت در حیطه ادبیات هم، همچون دیگر معارف انسانی، کار نوابغ است. خلاف&#8204;عادت&#8204;هایی که حافظ در غزل خود ایجاد کرد منشأ جریانی شد که مقلدان بسیاری را پدید آورد. این خلاف&#8204;عادت&#8204;ها در حوزه صورت، معنی، یا ارتباط&#8204;های ممکن در معنی و صورت رخ داده است. نقد اخلاق اجتماعی یکی از هنجارشکنی&#8204;&#8204;های معنایی بود. ابداع ظرایف&#8204; بلاغی که تازگی آن&#8204;ها بخصوص در حوزه ایهام مشهود بود، خلاف&#8204;آمد دیگری در ایجاد پیوندهای گوناگون نشانه&#8204;ها بر محور افقی شعر محسوب می&#8204;شود که حاصل توغل حافظ در شناخت بار معنوی کلمات در پیوند با جلوه&#8204;های مختلف فرهنگی بود. هماهنگی زمینه معنایی و عاطفی غزل با موسیقی عمومی حاکم بر آن، که از طریق وزن عروضی، همنشینی کلمات و قافیه پدید می&#8204;آید، یکی دیگر از ویژگی&#8204;های غزل حافظ&#8204; است که ارزش تأثیربخش آن و صمیمیت عاطفی&#8204;اش در غزل حافظ مشهود است. شاید برجسته&#8204;ترین خلاف&#8204;عادت در غزل حافظ شیوه ارتباط مخفی معانی پراکنده در طول یک غزل باشد که سبب شده است غالب کسانی که درباره غزل حافظ سخن گفته&#8204;اند، آن را چندمعنایی و فاقد پیوند منطقی میان ابیات بدانند، اما این ابیات با وجود تداعی&#8204;های دور از هم و فاصله&#8204;دار، در باطن عمیقاً به هم مربوط&#8204;اند. مقاله حاضر علاوه بر اشاره به خلاف&#8204;عادت&#8204;های بلاغی و هنری و معنایی نشان داده است که در آن سوی ظاهر پراکنده&#8204;نمونِ&#8204; ابیات که ناشی از تداعی&#8204;های دور و درازِ ذهن سرشار از بار فرهنگی و تجربی حافظ است، پیوندی باطنی وجود دارد که از طریق تبدیل گزاره&#8204;های عادت&#8204;گریز به گزاره&#8204;های عادت&#8204;پذیر دریافتنی است. برای روشن&#8204;شدن مطلب غزلی از سعدی با حافظ مقایسه شده است.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Norm-breaking in the field of literature, like other areas of human knowledge, is the province of the talented. Norm-breakings Hafiz undertook in his ghazals came to be the source of a movement with a good many imitators. His norm-breakings took place in form, meaning and/or in the possible relationships between the two. Critiquing the social mores was one of his trademark iconoclastic practices in the realm of content. Another norm-breaking was inventing rhetorical subtleties whose novelty was particularly conspicuous in the realm of pun. It was an innovation in creating varied links of signs on the horizontal axis of poetry&amp;mdash;an innovation resulted from Hafez&amp;rsquo;s contemplations on the emotional meanings of words conjured up in various cultural aspects. The harmony of meaning background and emotional background with the general music dominating them&amp;mdash;a linkage created by meter, rhyme and juxtaposition of words&amp;mdash;is another feature in Hafez&amp;rsquo;s poetry. The impressing value and emotional intimacy of these elements are palpable in his poetry. The most remarkable norm-breaking in Hafez&amp;rsquo;s ghazals may be the way in which the scattered meanings clandestinely interact through a ghazal; this has caused most scholars to regard it as polysemous and lacking in terms of logical relationship among couplets. These couplets, albeit distantly related with each other, are connected deep inside. Besides demonstrating Hafez&amp;rsquo;s rhetorical, artistic as well as semantic norms-breakings, the present paper shows that in spite of his poetry seeming scattered, which is a result of distant and far-reached associations in Hafez&amp;rsquo;s culturally and experientially loaded mind, there is an inner relationship among them that can be understood by transforming the norm-breaking propositions to norm-enforcing ones. A ghazal by Saadi is juxtaposed to one by Hafez to illustrate the issue at hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>حافظ , خلاف‌عادت , صورت , معنی , پیوند ابیات ,</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Hafez, Norm-breaking, Form, Meaning, Relationship among couplets.</keyword>
	<start_page>7</start_page>
	<end_page>32</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-3-4&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Taghi </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Pournamdarian</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>تقی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>پورنامداریان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>pournamdarian@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846002443</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002443</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>استاد پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
