<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Persian Language and Literature</title>
<title_fa>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبیات فارسی</title_fa>
<short_title>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبيات فارسی</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2476-6925</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2476-6941</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/jpll</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>11</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1394</year>
	<month>11</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2016</year>
	<month>2</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>23</volume>
<number>79</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>پرسش از پرسش گونه‌ها و کارکرد پرسش در دیوان حکیم ناصرخسرو</title_fa>
	<title>Question Types and Their Functions in Nasir-Khosrow’s Poetry</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:1.0cm;&quot;&gt;پرسش، علاوه&#8204;بر برخورداری از ویژگی&#8204;های بلاغی و زبانی، یکی از عوامل ایجاد تفکر خلاق است. هدف از طرح پرسش در تفکر خلاق را عواملی همچون کنترل غیرمستقیم مخاطب، کسب اطلاعات از او، بررسی و آزمون، بیدارکردن اندیشه، به&#8204;حرکت درآوردن و راهبری فکرها در جهتی معین و آشنایی با طرز فکر مخاطب می&#8204;توان برشمرد. در فضای غیرگفت&#8204;وگویی کمتر پرسشی عنوان می&#8204;شود اما در فضای گفت&#8204;وگو و دیالوگ، آنچه بیش&#8204;از همه در سلامت بنیان گفت&#8204;وگو تأثیر دارد، طرح سؤال است. هدف این مقاله، بررسی شیوه&#8204;های هدایت&#8204; ذهن ازطریق به&#8204;کارگیری پرسش در دیوان ناصرخسرو است. ازاین&#8204;رو، با روش کاربردشناسی تربیتی و زبانی و همچنین، با نگاهی به رویکرد علم معانی، انواع پرسش به دو گروه پرسش بلاغی و پرسش فلسفی&#8204;ـ شامل تمثیل، قیاس و استقراءـ تقسیم شده است. در پایان، ضمن اشاره به ویژگی&#8204; پرسش&#8204;های بلاغی به&#8204;عنوان پرسش بسته یا همگرا و پرسش&#8204;های فلسفی به&#8204;مثابه پرسش باز یا واگرا، این نتیجه حاصل شد که ناصرخسرو از پرسش به منظور ایجاد &amp;laquo;خودپنداری مثبت&amp;raquo; در مخاطب بهره برده است. بدین&#8204;معنی که با درنظرگرفتن تفاوت&#8204;های فردی میان یادگیرندگان، باورهای پیشین آنان را پوچ و بی&#8204;ارزش جلوه نمی&#8204;دهد، بلکه با یادآوری ارزش موضوع گفت&#8204;وگو، از مخاطب می&#8204;خواهد که به بازنگری درباره آن یا توجه به ابعاد دیگر موضوع بپردازد.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;In addition to possessing some rhetorical and linguistic characteristics, question is one of the elements in generating creative thinking. More notable objectives of asking questions in creative thinking are as follows: indirect control of audience, obtaining information from him, evaluating and testing him, provocation of the thought in audience, guiding the thoughts in a specific direction and understanding the idea of audience. The question is less likely to be asked in a non-dialogue context, but asking question is the most significant element in moving the conversation forward in a dialogue context. The aim of the present study is to investigate the methods of guiding thought through asking question in Nasir Khosrow&amp;rsquo;s poetry. By applying educational and linguistic pragmatics and considering a semantic approach, questions are divided into rhetorical and philosophical categories, consisting of analogy, induction, and deduction. Finally, by referring to rhetorical questions as close-ended or convergent and considering philosophical questions as open-ended or divergent ones, it was concluded that Nasir-Khosrow used questions to create &amp;ldquo;positive self-consciousness&amp;quot; in his audience. It means that by considering individual differences in his readers, he does not disvalue and nullifies their previous beliefs, but by highlighting the significance of dialogue, he makes the audience reconsider it or think about other aspects of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>ناصرخسرو, پرسش باز, پرسش بسته, نفوذ, قصد</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Nasir Khosrow, Open-Ended Question, Close-Ended Question, Penetration, Intention</keyword>
	<start_page>113</start_page>
	<end_page>139</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-653-15&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Razieh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Hojjatizadeh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>راضیه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حجتی زاده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>phdstudent1363000@gmail.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600958</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600958</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه اصفهان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
