<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<language>fa</language>
<journal_id_issn></journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi></journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_isnet></journal_id_isnet>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>11</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2019</year>
	<month>2</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>26</volume>
<number>85</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>سفینه، مجموعه، جُنگ  تحولاتِ تاریخیِ یک نوع ویژه ادبی</title_fa>
	<title>Safīne, Majmūʻe, and Jong
The Historical Transformations of a Literary Genre
</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>هریک از مصطلحات &#171;مجموعه&#187;، &#171;سفینه&#187; و &#171;جُنگ&#187; اکنون در معنایی به&#8204;کار می&#8204;رود که گاه با کاربرد آن در گذشته متفاوت است. هریک از این موارد، و نیز اصطلاحات دیگری مانند &#171;بیاض&#187;، &#171;جریده&#187; و حتی &#171;کرّاسه&#187;، &#171;دفتر&#187;، &#171;مفرد&#187; و &#171;جزو&#187; در زبان عربی و فارسی، برای مفاهیم ویژه&#8204;ای وضع شده است که درعین داشتن نوعی تمایز از یکدیگر، گاه به&#8204;شدت تعریف&#8204;گریزند. به&#8204;دست&#8204;آوردن شناختی نسبی، با درنظرگرفتن کاربردشناسی مصطلحات مزبور در متون و اسناد هر دوره، ضرورتی انکارناپذیر است. ازسوی &#8204;دیگر، برخی از این اصطلاحات، در ادواری به حوزه معنایی یکدیگر وارد شده یا معنای دقیق خویش را از دست داده است که در ترسیم مفهوم آنها، لازم است به این تطوّر معنایی توجه شود. در این پژوهش مقدماتی، به کهن&#8204;ترین شواهد و کاربردهای سه اصطلاح بنیادین &#171;مجموعه&#187;، &#171;سفینه&#187; و &#171;جُنگ&#187; در زبان فارسی، از آغاز تا پایان سده نهم هجری، با استناد به اشارات شاعران و ادیبان در متون، و نیز بررسی دقیق خود سفینه&#8204;ها و جُنگ&#8204;های کهن برجای&#8204;مانده، پرداخته خواهد شد تا تحولات معنایی و مصادیق هریک از آنها در ادوار مختلف تاحدودی روشن شود. همچنین، در هر بخش، به روابط بین این اصطلاحات با کاربردهای متداول در ادوار دیگر به&#8204;اختصار اشاره خواهد شد. 
&#160;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>The terms &#8220;majmūʻe&#8221;, &#8220;safīne&#8221;, and &#8220;jong&#8221; are presently used in the senses which may differ from their past meanings. Some related terms in Arabic and Persian languages, such as &#8220;bayāż&#8221;, &#8220;jarīde&#8221;, even &#8220;korrāse&#8221;, &#8220;daftar&#8221;, &#8220;mofrad&#8221;, and &#8220;jozv&#8221; have been coined for special concepts, which are hardly definable in some cases. Therefore, acquiring a relative perception of these terms, with regard to their application in the texts and documents of each period, is indispensably necessary. Some of these terms have been inserted into each other&#8217;s semantic fields or have lost their exact meanings in various periods; therefore, it is necessary to pay attention to their semantic evolution. In this paper, firstly the oldest uses of the three basic terms &#8220;majmūʻe&#8221;, &#8220;safīne&#8221;, and &#8220;jong&#8221; are studied in Persian texts up to the end of the ninth century A.H. For this purpose, the literati and poets&#8217; references in the texts, and the old anthologies (safīnes and jongs) are examined to clarify the meanings of the terms and their semantic changes during several periods. In addition, the relationship between the terms and their common uses in other eras are referred to in brief.
&#160;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>Safīne, Jong, Majmūʻe, Literary Anthologies, Literature.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>سفینه, جنگ, مجموعه, گلچین‌های ادبی, ادب</keyword>
	<start_page>7</start_page>
	<end_page>31</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-2003-4&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Afshinvafaie</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>University of Tehran</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>محمد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>افشین وفایی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>m.afshinvafaie@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>0031947532846004216</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004216</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Javad </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>bashary</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>University of Tehran</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>جواد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بشری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>m.afshinvafaie@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>0031947532846004217</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004217</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بدل بلاغی و انواع آن در غزلیات حافظ</title_fa>
	<title>Rhetorical Replica (Badal Bilaqi) and Its Variants in Hafez’s Sonnets</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>یکی از ویژگی&#173;های سبکی غزل حافظ تکرارِ بخشی از معنی مصراع نخست در مصراع دوم است. شناخت او از روابط بلاغی و معنایی واژگان به او این امکان را داده که بتواند، بدون گرفتارشدن در قید تکرار لفظی، معنی را تکرار کند. یکی از روش&#173;هایی که او را در رسیدن به این هدف یاری بخشیده&#173;، جانشین&#173;کردن مفاهیم در دو پاره از بیت، با توجه به روابط بلاغی بین آنهاست. مفهوم جایگزین&#8204;شده، علاوه&#8204;&#173;براینکه بر مفهوم نخست (مبدل&#8204;منه) یا قسمتی از معنی آن دلالت دارد، معنی اصلی خود را نیز حفظ می&#173;کند. این روش را اصطلاحاً &#34;بدل بلاغی&#34; &#173;نامیده&#8204;ایم. در این پژوهش، روابط مختلفی که میان طرفین جانشینی وجود دارد، با استناد به سه مبحث سنتی معانی، بیان و بدیع در علم بلاغت دسته&#173;بندی شده &#173;است. نحوه چینش بدل&#173;های بلاغی در ابیات حافظ متنوع است. گاهی چند مفهوم را در بیت جانشین یکدیگر کرده و چندین بدل بلاغی آفریده &#173;است. گاهی میان دو مفهوم چندین رابطه بلاغی ایجاد کرده و بر دامنه معنی افزوده &#173;است و گاهی نیز یک مفهوم را جایگزین چند مرجع کرده که این ارجاعات متعدد سبب ایهام و چندمعنایی شده&#173; است. در ادامه، تعدد و تنوع بدل&#173;های بلاغی در ابیات حافظ، با ذکر نمونه&#173;هایی، دسته&#8204;بندی و تشریح شده &#173;است. بسامد روابط بلاغی در طرفین جانشینی در سه حوزه علم بلاغت به این ترتیب است: معانی 3%، بیان 69% و بدیع 28%. حدود یک&#8204;سوم از ابیات حافظ دارای بدل بلاغی است. این بسامد بالا این شگرد را به&#8204;مثابه یکی از ویژگی&#173;های سبکی حافظ معرفی می&#173;کند.
&#160;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>One of the stylistic features of Hafez&#8217;s sonnets is the repetition of a part of the meaning of the first line in the second line. His knowledge of the rhetorical and semantic relations of vocabularies enabled him to repeat the meaning with the least verbal repetition. One of the ways that has helped him to achieve this goal is replicating the concepts in two parts of the couplet based on rhetorical relations between them. The replicated concept, in addition to referring to the first concept or a part of the meaning of that, retains its original meaning. We call this method &#34;Rhetorical Replica&#34; (Badal Bilaqi). In this research, based on the three traditional offices of rhetoric, we have categorized different relations existing between the two sides of the replica. In Hafez&#8217;s poetry, methods of arranging the &#8220;rhetorical replica&#8221; vary. Sometimes Hafez substitutes a few concepts for each other in a verse and creates several rhetorical replicas. Sometimes he creates several rhetorical relations between two concepts, and extents the domain of significance. Also, occasionally he replaces a concept with multiple references which generate numerous significance and ambiguity in the poem. In what follows, through examples from Hafez, the authors of this paper categorize and explain the multiplicity and diversity of rhetorical replicas in his poetry. The frequency of rhetorical relations on the two sides of the rhetorical replica in the three different offices of rhetoric is as follows: invention, 3%; arrangement, 69%; and style 28%. About one third of Hafez&#8217;s poetry contains rhetorical replica. And, the high frequency indicates that this is a stylistic feature in Hafez&#8217;s poetry.
&#160;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>Rhetorical Replica, Hafez's Sonnets, Substitution</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>بدل بلاغی, غزلیات حافظ, جانشینی</keyword>
	<start_page>33</start_page>
	<end_page>53</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1063-5&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Ali </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Heidari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Lorestan University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حیدری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Aheidary1348@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846004218</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004218</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه لرستان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Behnoush</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Rahimi-Harsini</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Lorestan University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>بهنوش</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رحیمی هرسینی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Rahimi.behnoosh@gmail.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846004219</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004219</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه لرستان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تحلیل و بررسی دلالت‌های ضمنی رمان تنگسیر</title_fa>
	<title>An Analytic Study of the Implicit Meanings in Tangsir</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>نشانه&#8204;شناسی یکی از نظریه&#8204;های خوانشِ متون ادبی است. این دانش به مطالعه نظام&#8204;مندِ علل و عواملی می&#8204;پردازد که در فرآیندِ تولید و تفسیر نشانه&#8204;ها دخیل&#8204;اند. یکی از مباحث مطرح&#8204;شده در نشانه&#8204;شناسی، دلالت ضمنی نشانه&#8204;هاست که به بررسی معانی تلویحی و غیرمستقیم نشانه می&#8204;پردازد. تنگسیر یکی از موفق&#8204;ترین رمان&#8204;های ادبیات معاصرِ ایران است. در این رمان بخش بزرگی از وقایع، شخصیت&#8204;ها، کنش&#8204;ها، صحنه&#8204;ها و نام&#8204;ها، علاوه&#8204;بر معنای صریح و مستقیم خود، معانی ضمنی و غیرمستقیمی &#8204;نیز دربردارند که با واکاوی آنها می&#8204;توان به لایه&#8204;های زیرین متن دست یافت و سویه&#8204;های پنهان آن را آشکار کرد. در این نوشتار، کوشیده&#8204;ایم به بررسی دلالت&#8204;های ضمنی این رمان بپردازیم. برای این منظور، ابتدا نشانه&#8204;شناسی و مبحث دلالت&#8204;های ضمنی به&#8204;اختصار معرفی شده و سپس دلالت&#8204;های ضمنی رمان تنگسیر، در سه دسته دلالت&#8204;های ضداستعماری، جامعه&#8204;شناختی و اسطوره&#8204;ای، بررسی شده است. یافته&#8204;های پژوهش نشان می&#8204;دهد که دلالت&#8204;های ضمنی ضداستعماری این رمان، بیشتر به توطئه&#8204;ها و دسیسه&#8204;های استعمارگران انگلیسی در منطقه جنوبِ ایران اشاره می&#8204;کند. دلالت&#8204;های ضمنی جامعه&#8204;شناختی رمان، جامعه&#8204;ای را به&#8204;تصویر می&#8204;کشد که در آن فقر و فلاکت و ستمگری و ستم&#8204;پذیری به اوج رسیده است و دلالت&#8204;های ضمنی اسطوره&#8204;ای رمان نیز رسم قربانی&#8204;کردن گاو در آیین میترائیسم و کهن&#8204;الگوی گذر از آب در اساطیر را تداعی می&#8204;کند.
&#160;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Semiotics is one of the theories of reading literary texts. &#160;This theory systematically studies the causes and factors involved in the process of production and interpretation of the signs. One of the main topics in semiotics deals with implicit meaning wherein the scholars examine the implied significance of the signs in addition to their explicit significance. Sadegh Chubak&#8217;s Tangsir is one of the most successful contemporary Iranian literary novels. Most of the events in this fiction, characters, actions, scenes, and names have implicit and connotative meanings that by analyzing them, the underlying layers of the texts will be discovered. This study attempts to investigate the implicit significance of the novel. To this end, first, a brief explanation of semiotics and implicit significance is put forth. Then the implicit significance of Tangsir will be presented in three categories of: the anticolonial, sociological and mythical. The results of this study indicate that the implicit anticolonial significance of the novel raises the issue of the conspiracies of British colonialism in the southern regions of Iran. The sociological significance of the novel portrays a community drowned in misery, poverty, suppression, and oppression. And the mythical significance of the novel indicates the ritual of sacrificing a cow in Mithraism and the archetype of crossing water in myths.
&#160;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>Semiotics, Implicit Meaning, Tangsir, Sadegh Chubak</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>نشانه‌شناسی, دلالت‌های ضمنی, تنگسیر, صادق چوبک</keyword>
	<start_page>55</start_page>
	<end_page>73</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-2298-5&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Gholamreza </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Salemian</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Razi University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>غلامرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سالمیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>salemian@razi.ac.ir</email>
	<code>0031947532846004220</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004220</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه رازی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Fatemeh </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Kolahchian</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Razi Unviersity</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>فاطمه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کلاهچیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>kolahchian@razi.ac.ir</email>
	<code>0031947532846004221</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004221</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه رازی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mohsen </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ahmadvandi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Razi University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>محسن</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>احمدوندی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>kolahchian@razi.ac.ir</email>
	<code>0031947532846004222</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004222</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه رازی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تاریخ جهانگشا به‌مثابه گفتمان قدرت چنگیز</title_fa>
	<title>Tārīkh-i Jahāngushāy: The Discourse of the Power of Genghiz</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>گفتمان قدرت چنگیز در بستر اجتماعی و سیاسی خاصی صورت&#8204;بندی شد که اگرچه مفصل&#8204;بندی آن در سده هفتم هجری انجام شد، ریشه&#8204;های آن را باید ماقبل حیات گفتمانی آن جست&#8204;وجو کرد، یعنی در دوره سلجوقیان، به&#8204;ویژه در حمله غزها به خراسان و دوره خوارزمشاهیان. در این جستار به بررسی چگونگی تکوین و چیرگی گفتمان قدرت چنگیز بربنیادِ روایت جوینی در تاریخ جهانگشا می&#8204;پردازیم. برای تحصیل این مهم از میان رهیافت&#8204;های مختلف، رویکرد گفتمان لاکلا و موف با توجه به مبانی و اصول آن کارآمدترین روش برای بررسی تکوین و تطور گفتمان است. از دیرباز، همواره ارتباط میان صاحبان قدرت با نویسندگان در کانون اهمیت بوده است. عطاملک جوینی نیز از این قاعده مستثنی نیست. جوینی در جایگاه ناظر و مورخ دربار مغول فجایع مغول را ثبت کرد، اما در این راه ناگزیر بود، در کنار بیان دَدمنشی&#8204;ها، به دربار مغول نیز وفادار بماند. مسئله اصلی این است که جوینی در پرداخت شخصیتِ محوری متن، چنگیز، رفتاری متفاوت با دیگر مورخان به&#8204;ویژه بیهقی در پیش گرفته است. کار اصلی مورخ انتخاب روایتی خاص از میان روایت&#8204;هاست. روش روایت&#8204;پردازی جوینی برای تثبیت معنای موردنظرش چه بوده است؟ آنچه از این تاریخ برمی&#8204;آید قدرت بی&#8204;بدیل چنگیز در مناطق تحت امر اوست که صدای متفاوتی از این رویداد هولناک از تاریخ جهانگشا به گوش می&#8204;رسد. درنهایت، به این نتیجه می&#8204;رسیم که طبق نظریه یادشده، متن تاریخ جهانگشا دارای یک نظام معنایی هم&#8204;سو است و این قابلیت در آن وجود دارد تا معنا در آن تثبیت شود. مجموعه این نظام هماهنگ برای تعدیل و توجیه خشونت ناشی از قدرت چنگیز پیش می&#8204;رود. 
&#160;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>The Discourse of the power of Genghiz was formulated in a specific social and political context. Although it was well articulated in the seventh century AH, its roots go back even before its discursive life, that is, to the Seljuk period, especially to the attack of the &#34;Ghoses&#34; to Khorasan and the &#34;Kharazmshahi&#34; period. In this article, we examine the development and dominance of discourse of the power of Genghiz based on Ata-Malik Jovayni&#8217;s historical narrative in Tārīkh-i Jahāngushāy. To this end and considering from among different approaches, Laclau and Mouffe&#8217;s discursive approach proved to be the most effective in examining the development and evolution of the discourse. The relationship between power holders and writers has always been central and Ata-malik Jovayni is no exception. In the position of an observer and historian, he recorded the adversities brought by the Mongols, while he remained loyal to the Mongol court. The point is that Jovayni adopted an approach different from other historians, especially Bayhaghi, in delineating the characteristics of Genghiz, the central figure of the text. The main task of the historian is to select a particular narrative from among available narratives. What is Jovayni&#8217;s method of narration for establishing the meaning of his text? What comes out of this history is the reverberation of Genghiz&#8217;s unparalleled power in the regions under his rule which is different from other voices narrating the horrible events in Tārīkh-i Jahāngushāy.&#160; In the end, we conclude that, according to the aforementioned theory, the text of Tārīkh-i Jahāngushāy has a consistent semantic system, and this ability helps to fixate the meaning of the text. This harmonious system functions to modify Genghiz&#8217;s image and justify his violence.
&#160;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>Jovayni, Tārīkh-i Jahāngushāy, Discourse of Power, Genghiz.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>جوینی, تاریخ جهانگشا, گفتمان قدرت, چنگیز.</keyword>
	<start_page>75</start_page>
	<end_page>93</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-2274-4&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Habibullah </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Abbasi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Kharazmi University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>حبیب‌الله</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عباسی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>habibabbasi45@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846004223</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004223</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه خوارزمی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Reza </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Gilaki</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Kharazmi University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>رضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>گیلکی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>habibabbasi45@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846004224</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004224</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه خوارزمی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>فرآیند فردیت در داستان خسرو و شیرین (با تکیه بر شخصیت خسرو)</title_fa>
	<title>The Process of Individuation in the Story of Khosrow and Shirin (With Special References to the Character of Khosrow)</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>خسرو و شیرین دومین منظومه از پنج&#8204;گنج نظامی و از زیباترین داستان&#8204;های عاشقانه ادب فارسی است. این داستان تاکنون از جنبه&#8204;های گوناگون و با رویکردهای متفاوت بررسی شده است. یکی از رویکردهایی که در تحلیل این داستان تاکنون مغفول مانده، تطبیق آن با نظریه فرآیند فردیت از دیدگاه یونگ است. ازاین&#8204;رو، هدف مقاله پیش&#8204;ِرو، واکاوی کنش&#8204;های شخصیت خسروپرویز و تحول شخصیت او و دیگر شخصیت&#8204;های تأثیرگذار این داستان، در طی این مسیر برپایه کهن&#8204;الگوهای آنیما و آنیموس، سایه، نقاب، خویشتن، پیر خردمند و... با روش تحلیلی&#8204;ـ توصیفی است. نتیجه بررسی حکایت از آن دارد که برای نیل به تفرد و یک&#8204;پارچه&#8204;سازی شخصیت خسرو، در جایگاه قهرمان داستان، ورود به عرصه ناخودآگاه الزامی است تا به&#8204;وسیله نمایه&#8204;های نمادین درون، قهرمان به خودشناسی دست یابد و تولدی دیگر در زندگی او حادث و مسیر دست&#8204;یابی به تاج و تخت و شیرین برایش هموار شود.
&#160;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Khosrow and Shirin is the second of five long narrative poems by Nezami and is one of the finest love stories in Persian literature. This story has been examined so far from different aspects and with different approaches. One of the approaches overlooked in the analysis of this story is the process of individuation from Carl Jung's point of view. Therefore the aim of the present paper is to psychoanalyze the development of the character of Khosrow Parviz and other central characters. This will be done through analytical-descriptive method while drawing upon the archetypes of anima and animus, shadow, persona, anima, wise old man, etc. The result&#160;of the study&#160;suggests&#160;that&#160;to&#160;achieve&#160;the individualism&#160;and&#160;unification&#160;of Khosrow's personality,&#160;as the hero of&#160;the&#160;story, it is&#160;necessary for him to enter&#160;the unconscious so that through the symbolic&#160;indexes&#160;of the inner&#160;self and&#160;the forces&#160;that&#160;produce consciousness, the hero would obtain self-knowledge, and his way to throne and Shirin is smoothed.
&#160;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>Nezami, Khosrow and Shirin, Carl Jung, Archetype, Individuation Process</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>نظامی, خسرو و شیرین, یونگ, کهن‌الگو, فرآیند فردیت.</keyword>
	<start_page>95</start_page>
	<end_page>114</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-925-4&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Zolfaghar </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Allami</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Alzahra University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>ذوالفقار</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>علامی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>zalami@alzahra.ac.ir</email>
	<code>0031947532846004225</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004225</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه الزهراء</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Roghayeh </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mousavi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Alzahra University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>رقیه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>موسوی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>nafisemousavi58@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846004226</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004226</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه الزهرا</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Afsane</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Akbarzadeh Moghadam</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Alzahra University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>افسانه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>اکبرزاده مقدم</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>moghaddamafsane@gmail.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846004227</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004227</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه الزهراء</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>اِتباع در زبان و ادب فارسی</title_fa>
	<title>Reduplication in Persian Language and Literature</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>مرکب&#173;های اِتباعی ترکیب&#173;هایی هستند که بر اثر تکرار قسمتی از واژه پایه ساخته می&#173;شوند. این بخش مکرر معنی ندارد و هیچ&#173;گاه به&#8204;تنهایی به&#8204;کار نمی&#173;رود. این واژگان در زبان گفتاری مردم متداول است و در دوران اخیر، در برخی متون نظم و نثر، به&#8204;ویژه داستان&#173;هایی که به زبان عامیانه نوشته شده، به&#8204;کار رفته است. این پژوهش با رویکردی تاریخی و روش تحلیلی&#8204;ـ&#8204;تبیینی، در کنار واکاوی پیشینه کاربرد مرکب&#173;های اِتباعی (اِتباع مهمل) در زبان و ادب فارسی، سه مسئله را بررسی می&#173;کند: 
تأثیر تغییر صورت و معنی واژگان کهن فارسی بر شکل&#173;گیری مرکب&#173;های اِتباعی در زبان و ادب فارسی؛ تأثیر نحو زبان عربی بر شکل&#173;گیری مرکب&#173;های اِتباعی در زبان و ادب فارسی؛ تأثیر رواج واژگان عربی و مترادف&#8204;نویسی بر شکل&#173;گیری مرکب&#173;های اِتباعی در زبان و ادب فارسی.
برطبق یافته&#173;های این پژوهش، پیشینه کاربرد مرکب&#173;های اِتباعی در زبان فارسی به قرن سیزدهم قمری می&#173;رسد. بیشتر ترکیب&#173;هایی که در فاصله سده&#173;های اول تا سیزدهم قمری در آثار منظوم و منثور دیده می&#173;شود و فرهنگ&#173;نویسان آنها را مصادیق مرکب&#173; اِتباعی برشمرده&#173;اند، ترکیب&#173;های عطفی و مترادف&#8204;اند که به&#8204;علت تغییر صورت و فراموشی معنی واژگان به&#8204;اشتباه مرکب اِتباعی خوانده شده&#173;اند. مرکب&#173;های اِتباعی از قرن سیزدهم و به&#8204;علت رواج واژگان عربی در زبان فارسی و عادت گفتاری مردم به مترادف&#173;گویی در محاورات کلامی متداول شد.&#160; با تحول در نثر فارسی و گرایش نویسندگان به ساده&#8204;نویسی و گفتاری&#8204;نویسی، این ترکیب&#173;ها به متون فارسی به&#8204;ویژه آثار داستانی با مایه&#173;های طنز و هزل وارد شد. &#160;
&#160;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>The Reduplications are made by repeating part of the base. The repeated part does not make sense and will never be used alone and is just popular in spoken language. In recent times, they have been used in some texts of poetry and prose, in particular, in stories written in vernacular. This research, with a historical approach, and with an analytical-explanatory method, examines the information obtained from literary and historical sources; and while analyzing the use of reduplication in Persian language and literature, it investigates three hypotheses: first, the effect of the changing of the face and meaning of the ancient Persian vocabulary on the formation of reduplication in Persian language; second, the effect of the Arabic syntax on the formation of reduplication in Persian language; and third, the effect of Arabic vocabulary and synonyms on the formation of reduplication in Persian language and literature
According to the findings of this research, the history of the use of reduplication dates back to the thirteenth century AH. Most of the compositions, from the first to the thirteenth century AH, are seen in poetic and prose works,&#160;and the writers of&#160;dictionaries have described them as examples of reduplication but in fact they are synonyms connected by conjunctives which due to a change of face and passage of time are mistakenly claimed to be reduplication. Reduplication has been introduced into Persian language since the thirteenth century AH. This was due to the prevalence of Arabic vocabulary in Persian language and also people&#8217;s habits of using synonyms in speaking. Along with developments in Persian prose and the tendency of writers to simplification and vernacularism, these compositions were introduced into Persian texts, especially satirical fictional works.&#160;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>Reduplication, Persian Language and Literature, Persian Prose and Poetry</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>مرکب اِتباعی, زبان و ادب فارسی, آثار منظوم و منثور فارسی.</keyword>
	<start_page>115</start_page>
	<end_page>134</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-2414-6&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mansoureh </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Karimi Ghahi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Alzahra University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>منصوره</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کریمی قهی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>karimighahi@gmail.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846004228</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004228</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه الزهراء</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تحلیل ساختاری رسالۀ‌العشق‌های منثور با تکیه بر مضامین غنایی آنها</title_fa>
	<title>A Structural Analysis of Musical Gnostic Prose works with an Emphasis on their Lyrical Contents</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>نثرهای عرفانی، ازنظر شمول، حوزه&#8204;های متفاوتی را، چه ازنظر موضوع و محتوا و چه ازنظر سبک، ساختار، زبان و اسلوب بیان، دربرمی&#8204;گیرند و نمی&#173;توان همه آنها را در یک مجموعه و ذیل یک نوع ادبی (ژانر) معرفی کرد. اطلاق عنوان کلی &#171;نثرهای عرفانی&#187; به این آثار ما را از هویت واقعی آنها دور می&#173;کند. بسیاری از نثرهای عرفانی، درعین تعلق&#8204;داشتن به حوزه عرفان، ویژگی&#173;هایی دارند که آنها را از دیگر متون عرفانی متمایز می&#173;سازد. در جستار حاضر، با بهره&#173;گیری از روش توصیفی&#8204;ـ&#8204;تحلیلی و استفاده از منابع کتابخانه&#173;ای، با تکیه بر موضوع کلیدی &#171;عشق&#187;، آثار عرفانی، اعم از کتاب و رساله (رسائل عشقی منثور) مطالعه&#173; شده&#173; و ضمن پرداختن به ویژگی&#173;های مشترک آنها، منطبق با ویژگی&#173;ها و معیارهایی که به&#8204;دست آمده &#173;است، آثار یادشده زیرمجموعه یک نوع ادبی دیگر (ژانر)، به&#8204;مثابه &#171;نثرهای عرفانی غنایی&#187; معرفی شده&#173; است. هدف جستار حاضر، تقسیم عرفان به عرفان عابدانه و عاشقانه نیست، بلکه مقصود این است که آثار عرفانی با توجه شیوه بیان، ساختار، زبان، صور خیال و موضوع ـ&#8204;به&#8204;گونه&#173;ای که نمایان&#8204;کننده هویت واقعی آن آثار باشدـ مطالعه شود. حاصل مطالعه نشان داد که سه مؤلفه اساسی 1. نثربودن و مباحث مرتبط با آن (تلفیق سنت مکتوب و سنت گفتار و تأویل&#8204;پذیری) 2. عرفانی&#8204;بودن و مصادیق آن (معرفت&#8204;شناسی و هستی&#173;شناسی، بی&#173;قاعدگی، عشق، حسن و جمال و تأثیرپذیری از آثار متقدم) 3. عاشقانه و غنایی&#8204;بودن و اسباب شاعرانگی (موسیقی، صور خیال و استفاده از منطق شعر) ویژگی&#173;های اساسی و مشترکِ این نوع ادبی است. 
&#160;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Gnostic prose works cover a wide range of subjects, contents, styles, structures, languages, and manners of expression. They might, therefore, be all categorized under one single literary genre. Applying the general term &#34;gnostic prose works&#34; to these oeuvres hinders our understanding of their true nature. Despite that many gnostic prose works belong to Gnosticism, they have special characteristics that make these works different from other gnostic texts. The present study has been done comparatively and analytically and with the help of library sources such as books and pamphlets on central topics, such as &#34;Love&#34;. While examining the common characteristics, this subset was introduced as another literary genre like theosophical and lyrical prose texts. The purpose of this study is not to divide Sufism into theosophical and romantic, but it intends to study theosophical works according to their ways of expression, structure, language, figures of thought and subject to exhibit their real identities. The study indicates that they are closely comparable on three grounds: 1. In being prose and related issues (mixing oral and written tradition and interpretation), 2. In being Gnostic and in issues related to epistemology, ontology, irregularity, love, beauty, and influence from earlier works, 3. In being romantic and poetical in expression regarding questions related to musicality, imagery, and poetic logic.
&#160;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>Gnostic Prose Works, Genres, Savaneh-Al-Oshag, Abhar-Al- Ashegin, Lamaat.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>نثر عرفانی, انواع ادبی, سوانح ­العشاق, عبهرالعاشقین, لمعات.</keyword>
	<start_page>135</start_page>
	<end_page>159</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1905-4&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mahbubeh </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mobasheri</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Alzahra University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>محبوبه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مباشری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>mobasheri2010@gmail.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846004229</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004229</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه الزهراء</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Masroureh </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mokhtari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Mohaghegh Ardabili University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>مسروره</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مختاری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>mmokhtari@uma.ac.ir</email>
	<code>0031947532846004230</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004230</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تحلیل داستان گل و نوروز خواجوی کرمانی با تأکید بر فرآیند فردیت یونگ</title_fa>
	<title>Analysis   of   “Gol  -o- Norooz”   by  Khwaju Kermani According to the Jungian Archetype of Individuation</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>کارل گوستاو یونگ، بنیان&#8204;گذار روان&#8204;شناسی تحلیلی در قرن بیستم، معتقد است در زیر سطح ظاهری آگاهی انسان&#8204;ها بخش دیگری به نام ناخودآگاه جمعی ازلی وجود دارد که به&#8204;صورت عامل روانی مشترک و موروثی خانواده بشری درآمده است. او موفق به کشف و معرفی کهن&#8204;الگوهای مشترک در اساطیر ملل شد و این موضوع، مکتب روان&#8204;کاوی او را شکل داد. در این پژوهش داستان گل و نوروز از این دیدگاه و با تأکید بر فردیت هدف تأمل و مداقه قرار می&#8204;گیرد. توجه به کهن&#8204;الگوها برای رمزگشایی داستان گل و نوروز ضرورت دارد؛ زیرا این مجموعه به&#8204;طورکلی برپایه این نمادهای کهن پی&#8204;ریزی شده است. نوروز نماد نیروهای ناخودآگاه پیروزشاه است و پیروزشاه نماینده بُعدِ فعلیت&#8204;یافته کهن&#8204;الگوی خود است. نوروز پس از سفرهای خطرناک فراوان، در انتها، به وصال محبوبش می&#8204;رسد و با متولدشدن فرزندش، چرخه فرآیند فردیت کامل می&#8204;شود.
&#160;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Carl Gustav Jung, the&#160;&#160; founder&#160;&#160; of&#160;&#160; the&#160;&#160; analytical&#160;&#160; psychology&#160;&#160; in the twentieth century&#160;&#160; believes&#160;&#160;&#160; that&#160;&#160; under&#160;&#160; the&#160;&#160; appearance&#160;&#160; of&#160;&#160; human&#160;&#160; consciousness&#160;&#160; exists&#160;&#160; an eternal collective unconscious&#160;&#160; which is&#160;&#160; part&#160;&#160; of&#160;&#160; the&#160;&#160; hereditary&#160;&#160; psychological&#160;&#160; factor&#160;&#160; common in the entire human race. He successfully introduced&#160;&#160; the common archetypes in the mythology of&#160;&#160; the different&#160;&#160; nations and opened up a new trend in psychology.&#160; This article intends to study &#34;Gol-o-Norooz&#34; in light of Jung&#8217;s archetype of individuation.&#160; Attention to archetypes for decoding &#34;Gol-o-Norooz&#34; is necessary because this collection is entirely explainable based on these archetypal symbols. Norooz&#160;&#160; is&#160;&#160; a symbol of&#160;&#160; Piroozshah&#8217;s unconscious&#160;&#160; forces and Piroozshah is in turn the activated representative of his own archetype. After many dangerous&#160;&#160; voyages, he finally reached his beloved, and by the birth of his children the cycle of individuation is completed.
&#160;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>Khwaju Kermani, Narrative, Gol-o-Norooz, Carl Jung, Archetypes, Collective Unconscious.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>خواجوی کرمانی, گل و نوروز, یونگ, کهن‌الگو, ناخودآگاه جمعی</keyword>
	<start_page>161</start_page>
	<end_page>176</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-584-3&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mohsen  </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mohamadi Fesharaki</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Isfahan University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>محسن</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>محمدی فشارکی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>fesharaki311@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846004231</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004231</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه اصفهان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Nasrin </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Setayesh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Isfahan University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>نسرین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>ستایش</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>beh_nasrin@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846004232</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004232</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه اصفهان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>فراواقع‌گرایی وهم‌انگیز در کشف‌الاسرار روزبهان بقلی</title_fa>
	<title>The Fantastic and Superrealism in Kashf-Al-Asrar by Ruzbehan Baqli</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>ادبیات وهمناک، شگفت و شگرف یکی از شاخه&#8204;های شناخته&#8204;شده در میان انواع ادبی جهان است که به&#8204;دلیل گستردگی آن، نظریه&#173;های متعددی در این حوزه ادبی مطرح شده است. ازسوی دیگر، بسیاری از متون ادب فارسی نیز از این ویژگی برخوردارند، اما چنان&#8204;که بایسته است هدف پژوهش واقع نشده&#8204;اند. در حوزه عرفان، به&#8204;دلیل ارتباط با امور ماوراءطبیعی، آثار متعددی به&#8204;قلم عرفا خلق شده که با موضوعات وهم&#8204;انگیز و فراواقعی گره خورده است. کشف&#173;الاسرار روزبهان بقلی از این زمره است که دربردارنده مکاشفات و سیر انفسی و روحانی نویسنده است. او در این سیر و سفر روحانی با موجودات فراطبیعی و مکان&#173;های شگفت&#173;انگیز روبه&#8204;رو شده و ازهمه&#8204;مهم&#8204;تر ملاقات&#173;ها و گفت&#8204;وگوهایی با خداوند داشته است. همین موضوع صبغه&#173;ای شگفت&#173;انگیز، ماورائی و وهم&#173;آفرین به اثر داده است. در این مقاله نویسندگان می&#8204;کوشند تا علاوه&#8204;بر تبیین ادبیات وهمناک و ماورائی، با استفاده از عناصر و ابزار مورد استفاده روزبهان ازجمله رمز، استعاره و...، به توصیف و شرح عناصر ادبیات وهم&#8204;آمیز و فضاسازی فراواقع&#173;گرایانه در کشف&#173;الاسرار بپردازند. گفتنی است روزبهان برای تبیین این سیر و تجربه روحانی، با بهره&#8204;گیری از ابزار متعدد، در سه ساحت عالم درونی، بیرونی و ماورائی، ارتباط خود را با عالم غیب و موجودات خارق&#8204;&#8204;العاده آن به&#8204;تصویر کشیده و این به کشف&#8204;الاسرار او رنگ&#8204;وبوی منحصربه&#8204;فردی داده است.
&#160;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Fantastic literature is one of the most popular genres in the world. Due to its wide scope, literary theoreticians have put forth numerous theories to explain its various dimensions. On the other hand, many Persian literary texts make use of these features, but they have not been sufficiently investigated yet. In the field of mysticism, due to the connection with supernatural affairs, numerous works have been created by the mystics, which are related to fantastic and supernatural issues. Kashf al-Asrar is of this kind, which includes the writer's revelations and spiritual journey. In this spiritual journey, he encounters super-real creatures and visits fantastic places, and most importantly, has meetings and talks with God; a range of events that gives a fantastic, super-real and phantasmagoric structure to the book. In this article, in addition to explaining the super-real and fantastic literature, using the elements and methods used by Ruzbehan Baqli, such as symbol, metaphor, etc., the authors describe and explain the elements of the fantastic literature in Kashf al-Asrar. It is said that, in order to explain this journey and spiritual experience, Ruzbehan uses various tools in three realms of the inner, outer, and super-real worlds to illustrate his connection with the unseen world and its extraordinary creatures.
&#160;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>Kashf-Al-Asrar, Tripartite Worlds (Inner, Outer, Super-Real Worlds), Fantastic, Phantasmagoria</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>کشف­الاسرار, عوالم سه­گانه (درونی, بیرونی, ماورائی), وهم­انگیز/ وهمناک, ابزار وهمناکی.</keyword>
	<start_page>177</start_page>
	<end_page>210</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-353-5&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Alireza </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Nabiloo</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>University of Qom</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>علیرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نبی لو</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>قم dr.ar_nabiloo@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846004233</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004233</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه قم</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mohaddeseh </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Hashemi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>University of Qom</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>محدثه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>هاشمی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Hmohaddese74@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846004234</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004234</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه قم</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>خوانش تحلیلی گفتمان «شاه‌زاده و یاران او» در کلیله و دمنه بر پایه نشانه ـ معناشناسی</title_fa>
	<title>A Discourse Analysis of “The Prince and His Companions” in Kelileh and Demneh 
Based On Semio-Semantics
</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>فرآیند معناسازی در گفتمان&#173; ادبی&#8204;ـ&#8204; روایی کلاسیک، برخلاف قالبی ساده و بیرونی، تابع عناصر و نظام&#173;های نشانه&#173;ای پیچیده است. برای درک چگونگی ابعاد حضور و نقش تعیین&#8204;کننده این عناصر، یکی از علمی&#173;ترین ابزارهای قابل اتکا، نشانه&#8204;ـ&#8204;معناشناسی است که باعث می&#173;شود روابط هم&#173;بسته و منسجم گزاره&#173;های نشانه&#173;ای متنی درون&#173;گفتمانی از حیث پدیدارشناختی و حتی معرفت&#173;شناختی با اتقانی علمی تحلیل شوند. با استناد به همین فهم، گفتمان روایی &#171;شاه&#8204;زاده و یاران او&#187;، با هدف استنباط قابلیت معناسازی عناصر دالی و چگونگی ظهور مؤثر آن عناصر در میزان تبیین اندیشه راوی و گستره&#173;بخشی گفتمان، تحت خوانش و تحلیل قرار گرفته است. این مقاله به&#8204;روش مطالعه کتابخانه&#173;ای و برای پی&#8204;جویی و پاسخ&#173;یابی این دو مسئله اصلی فراهم آمده است: الف) پیش&#8204;زمینه&#173;های زبانی و شاخص&#173;ها در کیفیت و سیالیت معنای گفتمانی هم&#173;سو با ذهنیت گفته&#173;پرداز چگونه وضع و نقشی دارند؟ ب) حضور نشانه&#8204;ـ&#8204;فردها در روند معناسازی و بُعد معرفت&#173;شناختی گفتمانی چگونه است؟ برآیند یافته&#173;ها در نگاهی کلی، مبین این است که گفته&#173;پرداز این گفتمان روایی را جهت&#173;دار و طراحی&#8204;شده تدوین کرده است. به&#173;&#8204;همین&#8204;رو، کوشیده است شاکله تمام عناصر و نظام&#173;های نشانه&#173;ای را در روند تبیین بازنمود ذهنی تقدیرگرایی گرد آورد. 
&#160;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Despite showing an overtly simple structure, the semantic process in classic literary-narrative discourse conforms to complicated semiotic systems. As a result, semio-semantics is deemed as one of the most scientific, reliable tools since it helps intradiscursive semio-textual propositions be phenomenologically, and even epistemologically, analyzed. Consequently, the narrative discourse in &#8220;The Prince and His Companions&#8221; is studied in order to find how much sign elements have semantic capability and how effective they have been in revealing the narrator&#8217;s thoughts and discourse.
This study is a library research, trying to address a) what situation and function linguistic backgrounds and parameters have in quality and fluidity of discursive meaning in line with narrator&#8217;s mindset; and b) how sign-individuals exist in the semantic process and epistemological discourse. In general, findings reveal that the narrator has intentionally formed this narrative discourse, compiling all semiotic systems and elements in an attempt to describe deterministic mental representation.
&#160;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>Kelileh and Demneh, Narrative Discourse, Semantic Process, Semiotics, Collective Mindset</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>کلیله و دمنه, گفتمان روایی, فرآیند معنایی, نشانه‌شناسی, ذهنیت جمعی</keyword>
	<start_page>211</start_page>
	<end_page>229</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-43-5&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Ismaeil </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Narmashiri</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Department of Velayat University of Iranshahr</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>اسماعیل</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نرماشیری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>toordan@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846004235</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004235</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه ولایت ایرانشهر</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>قرض‌گیریِ فعل «است» و گونه‌های آن در گویش عربی سراب</title_fa>
	<title>Borrowing the Verb “ast” and Its Varieties in Arabic Dialect of Sarab</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>قرض&#8204;گیری فرآیندی زبانی است که در زبان&#8204;شناسیِ درزمانی بررسی می&#8204;&#8204;شود. در این فرآیند، زبان عناصری را از زبان دیگر قرض می&#8204;گیرد. این فرآیند معمولاً در مناطقی رخ می&#8204;&#8204;دهد که دو زبان با یکدیگر برخورد می&#8204;کنند و به مدت طولانی تماس دارند. یکی از مناطق ایران که چنین موقعیتی دارد، جنوب خراسان است. در این منطقه، عرب&#8204;هایی زندگی می&#8204;کنند که احتمالاً تاریخ مهاجرت آنها به قرون نخست اسلامی بازمی&#8204;گردد. در این مقاله به بررسی فرآیند قرض&#8204;گیری فعل &#171;است&#187; و گونه&#8204;های آن در روستای عرب&#8204;نشین سراب می&#8204;پردازیم. فعل اسنادی فارسی به سه صورت est (با تحول آوایی، صرفی و معنایی)، hast (بدون تحول)&#160; و mest (به&#8204;مثابه اسم فاعل) در این گویش کاربرد دارد. در گویش عربی سراب، فعل &#171;است&#187; و گونه&#8204;های آن در سه وجه اخباری، التزامی و امری به&#8204;کار می&#8204;رود. کاربرد شناسه&#8204;های عربی در ساختار فعلِ &#171;است&#187; در این گویش و ساخت فارسی آن تفاوت دارد. 
&#160;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&#8220;Borrowing&#8221; is a lingual process that is studied in diachronic linguistics. In this process a language borrows elements from another language. This process usually occurs in areas that two languages make contact with each other. In a dialect spoken in South Khorasan the language borrowing happens. Arabs living in this part of Iran probably have immigrated in the early centuries of Islam. In this paper, the process of borrowing the verb &#8220;ast&#8221; and its varieties in &#8220;Sarab&#8221; village will be studied. In this village, this Farsi copular verb is used in three ways: est (with the phonetic, morphological and semantic transformation), hast (without any transformation) and mest (as a participle). In Arabic dialect of Sarab &#8220;ast&#8221; and its varieties are used in three modes of predictive, subjunctive and imperative. The use of Arabic identifiers in construction of &#8220;ast&#8221; is different in this dialect and its Farsi structure.
&#160;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>“ast” Copular Verb, Borrowing, Arabic Dialect, South Khorasan, Sarab Village</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>فعل اسنادی «است», قرض‌گیری, گویش عربی, جنوب خراسان, روستای سراب.</keyword>
	<start_page>231</start_page>
	<end_page>252</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-2090-4&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Hamed </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Norouzi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>University of Birjand</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>حامد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نوروزی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>hd_noruzi@birjand.ac.ir</email>
	<code>0031947532846004236</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004236</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه بیرجند</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Zeinab </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Salehi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Arabic language and literature, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>زینب</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>صالحی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>salehi.zeinab@um.ac.ir</email>
	<code>0031947532846004237</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004237</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>پیوندهای فکری مولانا جلال‌الدین و سلطان ولد در عرصه تأویل احادیث</title_fa>
	<title>Intellectual Links between Mawlānā Jalāl ad-Dīn and Sultan Walad in the Realm of Hadith Interpretation: A Case Study of Masanvi Manavi and Sultan Walad’s Masnavies</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>تأویل یکی از بنیادی&#173;ترین اصول منظومه فکری اهل عرفان است. ارباب ذوق با قدرت علمی و شهودی خود در آن&#173;سوی ظواهر الفاظ و عبارات، معانی بکر و عمیقی از آیات قرآن و احادیث ارائه می&#173;دهند که جز در خاطر فضلا و عرفای بزرگ نگنجد. مثنوی معنوی از آثاری است که دیدگاهی تأویلی به قرآن و حدیث دارد. غور در مثنوی آشکار می&#173;سازد که مولانا در بسیاری از موارد از پوسته ظاهری احادیث عبور کرده و معنای عمیق&#173;تری از آنها ارائه داده است. سلطان&#173;ولد نیز در جایگاه فرزند و مرید مولانا در مثنوی&#8204;های سه&#173;گانه خود رویکردی تأویل&#173;گرا به احادیث دارد. او، اگرچه در زمینه تفسیر و تأویل احادیث نوآوری&#8204;هایی دارد، در بیشتر موارد از منظومه فکری پدرش تأثیر پذیرفته است. 
نگارندگان در این جستار رویکرد تأویلی مولانا را به احادیث در مثنوی معنوی بررسی می&#8204;کنند و میزان و نحوه بازتاب این تأویل&#8204;ها را در مثنوی&#8204;های سلطان&#173;ولد آشکار می&#173;سازند. نتیجه پژوهش آشکار می&#173;کند که مولانا و به&#8204;تبع او سلطان&#173;ولد سطحی&#173;اندیشی و اتکا به ظواهر متون دینی را درخور ارباب احوال ندانسته&#8204;اند و معتقدند اولیای الهی، به&#8204;علت اینکه صفات بشری را در وجود خود فانی کرده و از عقیله انانیت گذشته&#173;اند، گفتارشان چونان وحی الهی از خطا مصون است و با قدرت شهودی و با استناد به تجربیات عرفانی خود می&#8204;توانند معانی ژرفی از معارف دین بیان کنند.&#160; 
&#160;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Interpretations are of the most fundamental principles of mysticism (Sufis). Masters of taste with their scientific and intuitive power go beyond the surface structures and present real and unfathomable meanings of the Quran and Hadith in ways that may not cross the mind of ordinary people. Masnavi Manavi is one the works that has an interpretation look toward the Quran and Hadith. Delving into this great work reveals that Mawlānā, in many cases, goes beyond the surface structures of Hadith and attaches a profound meaning to them. Sultan Walad, Mawlānā&#8217;s son and follower, in his Masnavies adopted an interpretative view toward Hadith. Though he has innovative views about the interpretations of the Quran and Hadith, in most of the cases he was influenced by his father&#8217;s work.
The authors in this study investigate Mawlānā&#8217;s interpretive approach in Masnavi Manavi and reveal how they affected Sultan Walad&#8217;s Masnavies. The results show that Mawlānā and Sultan Walad rejected superficial thinking and reliance on the surface of religious works. They believed that because of the fact that they overcome their humanistic desires and self-love, the true Allah lovers are infallible in their speech because Allah reveals to them the truth. And they can express the profound meaning of religion through their intuitive powers and based on their mystic experience.
Keywords:&#160;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>Hadith Interpretation, Mawlānā, Sultan Valad, Masnavi Manvie, Sultan Walad’s Masnavies</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>تأویل احادیث, مولوی, سلطان­ولد, مثنوی معنوی, مثنوی‌های سلطان­ولد.</keyword>
	<start_page>253</start_page>
	<end_page>277</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-2465-4&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Davood </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Vaseghi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Yazd University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>داود</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>واثقی خوندابی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>d.vaseqhi@gmail.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846004238</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004238</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه یزد</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mahdi </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Malek Sabet</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Yazd University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>مهدی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>ملک ثابت</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>mmaleksabet@yazd.ac.ir</email>
	<code>0031947532846004239</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004239</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه یزد</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad Kazem </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Kahdooyi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>Yazd University</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>محمدکاظم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کهدویی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>mkka35@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846004240</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004240</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه یزد</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>رویکرد سنت‌گرای مجله یغما به شعر معاصر</title_fa>
	<title>The Classicist Approach of Yaghma Magazine toward Contemporary Poetry</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>مجله ادبی یغما، در حوزه شعر، با هدف حفظ دستاوردهای کهن و مبارزه با هرگونه بدعت و نوآوری فعالیت خود را آغاز کرد. این درحالی است که سال&#8204;ها از حیات شعر نو گذشته بود و شاعران برجسته&#8204;ای در شعر نیمایی ظهور کرده&#8204; بودند. مقاله حاضر، با بررسی مسائل نظری مطرح&#8204;شده در زمینه شعر در این مجله و تحلیل آماری، محتوایی شکل و مضمون اشعار آن و مشخص&#8204;کردن شاعرانی که در این مجله به آنان بیش از دیگران توجه شده است، تلاش می&#8204;کند دریابد یغما چقدر در پی&#8204;گیری خط&#8204;مشی&#8204;ای که در اولین شماره&#8204;اش برای خود در زمینه شعر ترسیم کرده، موفق عمل کرده است. آیا توانسته، بی&#8204;اعتنا به جریان نوگرایی، راه سنت را در پیش گیرد یا اینکه از این جریان تأثیر پذیرفته است. نتایج این پژوهش، که با روش توصیفی&#8204;ـ&#8204;تحلیلی و تحلیل محتوا انجام گرفته است، نشان می&#8204;دهد با اینکه یغما در چاپ اشعار به&#8204;سبک گذشته و همکاری با شاعران متعصب در این زمینه، اهتمام فراوان داشته است و درصد زیادی از اشعار آن را غزل (33 درصد) و قصیده (25 درصد) و مضامین شعری کهن و اخوانیات تشکیل می&#8204;دهد، نتوانسته است به مطالبه مردمی که در زمینه نوگرایی شکل &#8204;گرفته است بی&#8204;توجه بماند؛ به&#8204;گونه&#8204;ای که برای پاسخگویی به این نیاز روز، به نوآوری&#8204;های محتاطانه دست می&#8204;زند و گاه به&#8204;اقتضای موقعیت، مجبور می&#8204;شود شاعران نوگرا را بستاید و حتی از آنان شعر منتشر کند. بااین&#8204;حال، رعایت جانب کلاسیک&#8204;ها، که قاطبه مخاطبان یغما را تشکیل می&#8204;دهند، باعث می&#8204;شود این کار هرگز در یغما به رویه تبدیل نشود.
&#160;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Yaghma, The literary magazine in the field of poetry, started its activity with the aim of preserving ancient achievements and countering every kind of unapproved innovations and novelty. This was in spite of the fact that many years had passed since the beginning of modern poetry and there have emerged famous figures in Nimaei poetry. The present article intends to see how much Yaghma was successful in following its initial policy in the field of poetry delineated in its very first number. This will be done through a review of the theories of poetry published in this magazine and also content-statistical analysis of forms and contents of the poems and identifying the poets who were considered and heeded more than others in Yaghma. Had Yaghma been successful in following classicism regardless of modernism, or had it been affected by modern trends in poetry? Results of the current study, which was done by content analysis and descriptive-analytic method, show that although Yaghma had serious attempts to print and publish classic poems and had great cooperation with dogmatic poets, and much of it comprised of Ghazal (33 percent), Ghasideh (25 percent), classical contents and Akhavaniat, yet it could not ignore public demands for modern trends in poetry and sometimes made cautious innovations to satisfy contemporary needs and occasionally eulogized and praised innovative (or modern) poets due to expediencies of the age, and even published some of their poems. However, to defend and respect its classic followers who form the main body of its audience, Yaghma prevented this from becoming a regular approach in the magazine.

&#160;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>Yagham Magazine, New Poetry, Classic Poetry, Modernism, Classicism</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>مجله یغما, شعر نو, شعر کلاسیک, نوگرایی, سنت‌گرایی</keyword>
	<start_page>279</start_page>
	<end_page>302</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1855-15&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


		<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Morad Ali </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Vaezi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>University of Birjand</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>مرادعلی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>واعظی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>ma.vaezi@birjand.ac</email>
	<code>0031947532846004241</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004241</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
Yes
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه بیرجند</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Safieh </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Jamali</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<affiliation>University of Birjand</affiliation>
	<first_name_fa>صفیه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>جمالی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>safiejamali@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>0031947532846004242</code>
	<orcid>0031947532846004242</orcid>
	<coreauthor>
No
	</coreauthor>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه بیرجند</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


		</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
