<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Persian Language and Literature</title>
<title_fa>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبیات فارسی</title_fa>
<short_title>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبيات فارسی</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2476-6925</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2476-6941</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/jpll</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>11</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1394</year>
	<month>11</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2016</year>
	<month>2</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>23</volume>
<number>79</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ریخت‌شناسی قصه حضرت یوسف(ع) در ترجمه تفسیر طبری</title_fa>
	<title>The Morphology of Joseph’s (pbuh) Tale in the Translation of Tafsir-e-Tabari</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:1.0cm;&quot;&gt;بایستگی استفاده از دانش&amp;shy;های نوین ادبی در ارزیابی متون قرآنی و نوشته&amp;shy;های برآمده از معارف قرآنی در جهان امروز بر پژوهشگران مسلمان آشکار و گریزناپذیر است. در پژوهش حاضر ساختار قصه حضرت یوسف(ع) در &lt;em&gt;ترجمه تفسیر طبری&lt;/em&gt; با استفاده از نظریه ریخت&#8204;شناسی پراپ تحت ارزیابی قرار گرفته است. برای رسیدن به نتیجه&amp;shy;ای مناسب&amp;shy;تر، این قصه به چهار داستان بخش شده و شخصیت&amp;shy;ها و خویش&amp;shy;کاری&amp;shy;های آنها در هر داستان هدف تحلیل انتقادی قرار گرفته است. شمارگان شخصیت&amp;shy;های قصه و چگونگی خویش&amp;shy;کاری&amp;shy;های آنها تطابق ساختاری این قصه را با نظریه پراپ و تبصره&amp;shy;های نظریه او به&amp;shy;روشنی نشان می&#8204;دهد. حرکت&amp;shy;های سه داستان از چهار داستانِ این قصه از الگوهای حرکتی شش&amp;shy;گانه پراپ پیروی کرده است؛ تنها در داستان دوم این قصه حرکتی دو&amp;shy;مقطعی دیده می&amp;shy;شود که با الگوهای حرکتی پراپ هم&#8204;خوانی ندارد و حرکت تازه&amp;shy;ای به&#8204;شمار می&amp;shy;رود. پراپ در آرای خود به ریشه&amp;shy;های دینی قصه&amp;shy;ها توجه زیادی داشته و نظریه ریخت&amp;shy;شناسی او در مطالعه قصه یوسف(ع) بسیار کار&amp;shy;گر افتاده است. ازآنجاکه پراپ به ساختار&amp;shy;ها توجه داشته نه روساخت&amp;shy;ها و جزئیات کمّیت&amp;shy;زای قصه&amp;shy;ها، آرای او در مطالعه قصه&amp;shy;هایی غیر از قصه&amp;shy;های پریان نیز کار&amp;shy;گشاست. نگارنده در پایان پیشنهاد می&amp;shy;کند، با بهره&amp;shy;گیری از آرای پراپ، همه قصه&amp;shy;های قرآنی و تفاسیر این قصه&amp;shy;ها ارزیابی ساختاری شوند تا ساختار بنیادین این قصه&amp;shy;ها به دست آید.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The necessity of using modern literary knowledge in evaluating the Quranic texts and the writings based on the Quranic teachings is clear and necessary for Muslim researchers in today's world. In this research, the structure of Joseph&amp;rsquo;s (pbuh) Tale in the translation of Tafsir-e-Tabari (the Persian translation of Tabari&amp;rsquo;s Commentary of the Quran) has been evaluated by using Propp&amp;rsquo;s morphology. To achieve a more appropriate conclusion, this tale has been divided into four stories and its characters and their functions have been critically analyzed in each story. The number of the characters and the manner of their functions clearly demonstrate the structure of this tale on the basis of Propp&amp;rsquo;s theory. The movements of three stories out of four in the mentioned tale have followed Propp&amp;rsquo;s sextuple movement pattern; only in the second story of this tale, a two cross-sectional movement is seen that is not adaptable to Propp&amp;rsquo;s movement patterns and is considered as a new movement. Propp in his ideas has considered the religious roots and his morphology theory has been very efficient in studying Joseph&amp;rsquo;s (pbuh) tale. Since Propp has paid attention to structures rather than superstructures and quantitative details, his ideas are also helpful in studying the other tales. Finally, the author suggests that all the Quranic tales can be evaluated from a structural perspective on the basis of Propp&amp;rsquo;s ideas to find out the fundamental structure of these tales.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>پراپ, ریخت‌شناسی, قصه, یوسف(ع), ترجمه تفسیر طبری</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Propp, Morphology, Tale, Joseph (pbuh), translation of Tafsir-e-Tabari.</keyword>
	<start_page>141</start_page>
	<end_page>168</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-653-16&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Morteza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Heydari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مرتضی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حیدری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>mortezaheydari.58@gmail.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600959</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600959</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه پیام نور</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
