<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Persian Language and Literature</title>
<title_fa>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبیات فارسی</title_fa>
<short_title>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبيات فارسی</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2476-6925</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2476-6941</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/jpll</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>11</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>26</volume>
<number>84</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>نقش جنسیت در ساخت و گزینش استعاره در اشعار شاملو و مشیری ازمنظر نظریه گفتمانی استعاره</title_fa>
	<title>The Role of Gender in Production and Selection of Metaphors in Poems by Shamloo and Moshiri based on Discourse Theory of Metaphor</title>
	<subject_fa>ادبیات غنایی</subject_fa>
	<subject>ادبیات غنایی</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;تاکنون پژوهش&amp;shy;های نسبتاً خوبی در زمینه روابط بین جنسیت، استعاره و گفتمان درباب متون سیاسی، رسانه&amp;shy;ای و ادبی انجام شده است. در پژوهش حاضر، سعی شده است روابط جنسیت و استعاره در شعر بررسی شود. پرسش&amp;shy;های اساسی پژوهش عبارت&#8204;اند از: نقش جنسیت در ساخت و گزینش استعاره در اشعار شاملو و مشیری چگونه است؟ آیا می&amp;shy;توان پذیرفت که استعاره ابزاری برای بازنمایی جنسیت&amp;shy;گرایی در اشعار ذکرشده است؟ در این پژوهش، داده&amp;shy;ها از مجموعه اشعار احمد شاملو و فریدون مشیری استخراج و با توجه به نظریه گفتمانی استعاره چارتریس&#8204;ـ&#8204;&#8204;بلک تجزیه و تحلیل شده&amp;shy;اند. نتایج پژوهش نشان می&#8204;دهد که جنسیت&amp;shy;گرایی در اشعار شاملو و مشیری وجود دارد، اما میزان جنسیت&amp;shy;گرایی در اشعار شاملو به&#8204;مراتب بیشتر از اشعار مشیری است؛ چراکه حوزه معنایی جنگ در استعاره&amp;shy;های مفهومی اشعار شاملو بیشتر از اشعار مشیری است. بنابراین، نتایج پژوهش حاکی از آن است که در ساخت و گزینش استعاره در اشعار جنسیت، نگرش و اندیشه شاعر، احساسات او و فضای اجتماعی حاکم بر روزگار شاعران مؤثرند و البته عامل جنسیت نقش مهمی در ساخت و گزینش استعاره ایفا می&amp;shy;کند.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Many noteworthy studies have been done to examine the discursive relationship between gender and metaphor in the context of politics, media and literature. In this research, however, I try to investigate the relationship between gender and metaphor specifically in poetical discourse. The main questions of this research are as follows: What is the role of gender in the production and selection of metaphors in the poems by Shamloo and Moshiri? And also can we claim that metaphor is an instrument for representation of sexism in given poems? Research data are extracted from poems by Shamloo and Moshiri and they are analyzed based on Charteris-Black&amp;rsquo;s discourse theory of metaphor. The results of research indicate that there are manifestations of sexism in these poems, but the degree of sexism in the poems of Shamloo is higher than Moshiri&amp;rsquo;s. The reason is that the semantic domain of war on conceptual metaphors in Shamloo&amp;rsquo;s poems is more than Moshiri&amp;rsquo;s. Therefore, the results of the research indicate that the production and selection of metaphors in poems are decided by gender, attitude and thought of poets, as well as their feelings and social atmosphere. Indeed, gender plays an important role in production and selection of metaphors in poems.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>جنسیت, استعاره, نظریه گفتمانی استعاره, شاملو, مشیری</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Gender, Metaphor, Discourse Theory of Metaphor, Shamloo, Moshiri</keyword>
	<start_page>133</start_page>
	<end_page>156</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-2114-2&amp;slc_lang=other&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Ebrahim </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Rezapour</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ابراهیم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رضاپور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>abrahim_rezapour@semnan.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846004253</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004253</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Semnan University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه سمنان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
