<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Persian Language and Literature</title>
<title_fa>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبیات فارسی</title_fa>
<short_title>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبيات فارسی</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2476-6925</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2476-6941</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/jpll</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>11</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1394</year>
	<month>11</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2016</year>
	<month>2</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>23</volume>
<number>79</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بازشناسی دگردیسی فکری ـ عاطفی قیصر امین‌پور در بستر گزاره‌های پرسشی</title_fa>
	<title>A Study of Qeysar Aminpour’s Intellectual-Emotional Metamorphosis in the Context of Interrogative Statemen</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:1.0cm;&quot;&gt;کاربردشناسی به کارکرد زبان در بافت مربوط است و هر جمله ثابت در بافت&#8204;های متغیر می&#8204;تواند کارکردهای متفاوتی داشته باشد؛ ازاین&#8204;رو، معنا همان کاربرد است و مستقل از بافت وجود ندارد، اما نوع جمله&#8204;ها از عوامل تعیین&#8204;کننده در استنباط معانی است. جمله پرسشی در زبان فارسی دارای دوگونه ایجابی و غیرایجابی است. هدف از گزاره&#8204;های پرسشی غیرایجابی یا بلاغی انتقال پیام به طرز غیرمستقیم و مؤثرتر است. قیصر امین&#8204;پور در دفترهای پنج&#8204;گانه شعری از گزاره&#8204;های پرسشی به صورت گسترده و گوناگون استفاده می&#8204;کند. پرسش&#8204;های هریک از دفترها محصول اوضاع اجتماعی و افق&#8204;های فکری ـ عاطفی شاعرند و هرچه از دوره اول به دوره سوم نزدیک&#8204;تر می&#8204;شویم، ازنظر کیفی و ژرف&#8204;اندیشی، خردمندانه&#8204;تر و واقع&#8204;گرایانه&#8204;تر می&#8204;شوند؛ به همین دلیل، با بررسی انگیزه&#8204;های گزاره&#8204;های پرسشی براساس فرایند زمانی می&#8204;توان به بازشناسی دگردیسی فکری ـ عاطفی شاعر دست یافت. مهم&#8204;&#8204;ترین این انگیزه&#8204;ها عبارت&#8204;اند از: 1) حیرت 2) تردید 3) انتقاد 4) امیدواری. حیرت در اشعار قیصر از یقین به آرمان&#8204;های انقلاب و جنگ، به حیرت در خودشناسی و دست&#8204;یابی به مقصود منجر می&#8204;شود و تردید امین&#8204;پور اساساً مربوط به دوره سوم و رهاورد حیرت&#8204;هایش است و ابعاد اعتقادی و عمل&#8204;گرایانه و واقع&#8204;گرایانه را دربرمی&#8204;گیرد. مهم&#8204;ترین دگردیسی&#8204;های فکری ـ عاطفی شاعر عبارت&#8204;اند از: 1) از یقین به تردید 2) از آرمان&#8204;شهر به شهر و زندگی واقعی مردم 3) از فردگرایی به جمع&#8204;گرایی 4) از نگرش به بینش یا از مشاهده به اندیشه 5) از پیروزی در جنگ به پیروزی بر جنگ 6) از نومیدی به امیدواری.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Pragmatics is related to language use in context. A single sentence can have different functions in different contexts. Hence, the meaning is the same as function and the function does not exist out of context; however, the type of sentence has a decisive role in inferring the right meaning. The interrogative sentence in Persian language has two types of rhetorical and non-rhetorical questions. The aim of rhetorical interrogative statement is to convey the message indirectly and more effectively. Qeysar Aminpour has employed interrogative statements in various and different ways in his five poetry books. The questions mentioned in each poetry book are the results of the poet&amp;rsquo;s social circumstances and his intellectual-emotional perceptions. By moving from the first period to the third one, the questions become more contemplative and realistic in terms of quality and intellectual aspects. Therefore, by investigating the intentions behind interrogatives based on time process, the intellectual-emotional metamorphosis of the poet can be recognized. Most of these intentions include: 1. Astonishment, 2. Doubt, 3. Criticizing, 4. Hope, and 5. Desperation. Astonishment in Qeysar&amp;rsquo;s poems moves from certainty in revolution and war goals to astonishment in self-discovery and achievement of the goals. His doubt is basically related to third period due to his astonishments including belief, pragmatic and realistic aspects. The most important intellectual-emotional metamorphoses of the poet include: 1. From certainty to uncertainty, 2. From utopia to real life, 3. From individualism to collectivism, 4. From attitude to insight or from observation to contemplation, 5. From winning the war to victory over the war, and 6. From despair to hope .&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>گزاره‌های پرسشی, کاربردشناسی, قیصر امین‌پور, حیرت, تردید, انتقاد</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Interrogatives, Amipour, Astonishment, Doubt, Criticism</keyword>
	<start_page>35</start_page>
	<end_page>58</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-653-12&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Ali Akbar</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Bagheri Khalili</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی اکبر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>باقری خلیلی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>aabagheri@umz.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600954</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600954</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه مازندران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Effat sadat</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Qafouri</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>عفت سادات</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>غفوری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>e.ghafoori@stu.umz.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600955</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600955</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه مازندران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
