<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Persian Language and Literature</title>
<title_fa>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبیات فارسی</title_fa>
<short_title>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبيات فارسی</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2476-6925</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2476-6941</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/jpll</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>11</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1393</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>22</volume>
<number>77</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تأملی بر سرگذشت سوفرا در شاهنامه فردوسی و منابع دوره اسلامی</title_fa>
	<title>A Study of the Story of Sufra in Ferdowsi's Shahnameh and the Sources of the Islamic Era</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p&gt;یکی از رویدادهای مهم دوره ساسانیان جنگ&#8204;های پیروز با هپتالیان است که با وجود تلاش&#8204;هایی که ایرانیان در این پیکار&#8204;ها از خود نشان دادند سرانجام شکست سختی از هپتالیان خوردند و ناچار پیامدهای زیادی را متحمل شدند. پیروز که پادشاهی خودکامه بود برای جبران نخستین شکست خویش، بار دیگر به نبرد هپتالیان رفت اما نه&#8204;تنها کاری از پیش نبرد، بلکه جان خود را نیز از دست داد. پس از این شکست&#8204;&#8204;ها هپتالیان مدت&#8204;های طولانی در امور سیاسی ایران دخالت &#8204;کردند تا اینکه سرانجام در دوره پادشاهی انوشیروان از میان رفتند. بااین&#8204;حال خاطرات تلخ این شکست&#8204;&#8204;ها هرگز از ذهن ایرانیان پاک نشد. بنابراین چندی بعد، ایرانیان برای حفظ آبرو برخی واقعیت&#8204;&#8204;ها را تغییر دادند و داستان&#8204;هایی از خود ساختند که برپایه یکی از مهم&#8204;ترین آنها، پهلوانی به نام سوفرا به جنگ هپتالیان رفت و سرانجام آنان را به&#8204;سختی شکست داد و آنچه را از ایرانیان نزد هپتالیان به غنیمت مانده بود بازگردانید. به احتمال زیاد این روایت&#8204;های ساختگی در بیشتر خدای&#8204;نامه&#8204;های دوران ساسانیان وجود داشته و ازآنجا به تاریخ&#8204;های دوران اسلا&#8204;می &#8204;&#8204;نیز راه یافته است.&lt;br&gt;
در این مقاله نخست به بررسی روایات&#8204; &lt;em&gt;شاهنامه&lt;/em&gt; درباره جنگ&#8204;های پیروز و سوفرا با هپتالیان و دیگر روایت&#8204;های تاریخی می&#8204;پردازیم؛ سپس اساسی&#8204;&#8204;ترین تحریفاتی را که در دوره ساسانیان وارد خدای&#8204;نامه&#8204;&#8204;ها شده است نشان می&#8204;دهیم.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;One of the main events of the Sassanid's period is the battles of Piruz against the Hephthalites, which despite the great efforts of the Iranians in these wars, they ended with their defeat and a huge tribute to be given to the Hephthalites. To compensate for his failure, Piruz the tyrant king waged another war against the Hephthalites. However, not only he achieved nothing, but he also lost his life. After these defeats, the Hephthalites used to intervene in the Iranians&amp;rsquo;affairs for a long time, until they finally disappeared during the reign of Anushiravan. Nonetheless, the bitter memories of these defeats never left the Persians' minds. So after these events, the Iranians manipulated some facts to maintain their dignity. They made some stories about those events and one of the stories was about a hero named Sufra who fought against the Hephthalites and eventually defeated them and brought back all that the Iranians had lost to them. These narratives most likely were present in the many Khodaynameh(s) of the Sassanid's period to enter then the history of the Islamic era. This article first examines Shahnameh and other historical narratives for Piruz's and Sufra's battles against the Hephthalites, and then shows the main distortions which entered Khodaynameh(s) in the Sassanid's period.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>پیروز , سوفرا , قباد , هپتالیان , ساسانیان , شاهنامه فردوسی , </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Piruz, Sufra, Ghobad, Hephthalites, Sassanid, Ferdowsi's Shahnameh.</keyword>
	<start_page>189</start_page>
	<end_page>213</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-3-141&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Reza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Qafouri</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>رضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>غفوری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>reza_ghafouri1360@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001891</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001891</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
