<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Persian Language and Literature</title>
<title_fa>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبیات فارسی</title_fa>
<short_title>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبيات فارسی</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2476-6925</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2476-6941</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/jpll</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>11</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>25</volume>
<number>83</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی چند روایت از  نبرد ایرانیان با دیوهای مازندران در متون پهلوانی پس از شاهنامه</title_fa>
	<title>The Study of Some Narratives about Iranian’s Battle with Mazandaran’s Demons in the Heroic Literature after Shahnameh</title>
	<subject_fa>شعر معاصر</subject_fa>
	<subject>شعر معاصر</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:tahoma;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;یکی از داستان&#8204;های مشهور &lt;em&gt;شاهنامه&lt;/em&gt; رفتن رستم به مازندران برای رهایی کاووس و سپاهیانش است که با کشته&#8204;شدن دیو سپید، رهایی کاووس از بند او و واگذاری مازندران به اولاد پایان می&#8204;یابد. این داستان، که به &amp;laquo;هفت&#8204;خان رستم&amp;raquo; نیز اشتهار دارد، نفوذ بسیاری در شماری از منظومه&#8204;های پهلوانی، طومارهای نقالی و روایت&#8204;های شفاهی/مردمی &lt;em&gt;شاهنامه &lt;/em&gt;داشته است. اثرپذیری این دسته آثار از روایت نبرد رستم با دیوان مازندران به دوگونه است: نخست، در بسیاری از این متون، روایات گوناگونی از رفتن رستم به مازندران و نبرد او با دیو سپید آمده یا اشاره&#8204;های بسیاری بدان شده است. دوم، در برخی متون حماسی ایران، خواه منظوم و خواه منثور، شماری دیوان و پتیارگان از نژاد دیو سپید حضور دارند که هریک از آنها، پس از آگاهی از نژاد خود و چگونگی کشته&#8204;شدن آن دیو، به کین&#8204;خواهی از رستم یا یکی از پهلوانان خاندان او می&#8204;پردازند، اما در همه این داستان&#8204;ها ناکام می&#8204;مانند و در نبرد با پهلوان کشته می&#8204;شوند. اگرچه این دسته روایات در بیشتر متون منثور عامیانه ایران به&#8204;اختصار آمده است، اما در شماری از متون، مانند &lt;em&gt;شبرنگ&#8204;نامه&lt;/em&gt;، &lt;em&gt;شهریارنامه&lt;/em&gt; و &lt;em&gt;برزونامه جدید&lt;/em&gt; با تفصیل بیشتری بیان شده است. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;در این مقاله، نخست به بررسی این دسته روایات در متون منظوم پهلوانی پس از &lt;em&gt;شاهنامه &lt;/em&gt;می&#8204;پردازیم. سپس، مضامین مشترک این داستان&#8204;ها یا موارد اختلاف آنها را با روایت &lt;em&gt;شاهنامه&lt;/em&gt; بررسی می&#8204;کنیم.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>One of the popular stories in Shahnamehis Rustam&amp;rsquo;squestto Mazandaran in order to rescue Kavoos and his soldiers, which led him into killingDivSepid (the white demon), rescuingKavoos from captivity, and also entrusting Mazandaran to his children. This story, which is known as Haft-khan Rustam, has influenced a number of heroic poems, manuscripts of rhapsodies and oral/public narrativesof Shahnameh. The influence that these works have from the narratives of Rustam&amp;rsquo;s battle with the demons of Mazandaran can be classified into two categories: first, in many of these texts, are various narratives about or references to Rustam&amp;rsquo;sjourney to Mazandaran and his battle with DivSepid. Second, in some Iranian epic texts, be it poetry or prose, a number of demons or descendants ofDivSepid are present that each try to take revenge on Rustam or one of the members of his family. But, in all of these stories, they either have failed or were killed by the hero. Although these types of narratives have briefly been expressed in most of Iranian public prose literature, they have been expressed in more details in a number of texts including ShabrangNameh, ShahriyarNameh, and TheNew BorzoNameh. In this paper, first, these types of narratives in some heroic pieces of poetry are addressed. Then, common grounds or differences of these stories with the narrative of Shahnameh are analyzed.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>نبرد مازندران, شاهنامه, شبرنگ‌نامه, شهریارنامه, برزونامه جدید</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Battle of Mazandaran, Shahnameh, Shahryarnameh, The New Borzoonameh.</keyword>
	<start_page>209</start_page>
	<end_page>230</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-800-2&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Reza </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ghafouri</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>رضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>غفوری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>reza_ghafouri1360@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846004281</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004281</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Hazrat Narjes University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه حضرت نرجس (س)</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
