@article{ 
author = {AsghariBayqut, Yousef and Dehrami, Mahdi},  
title = {The Necessity of a New Correction of Khaghani\'s Arabic Poems}, 
abstract ={A part of Khaghani's Divan includes his Arabic poems where one can be find a large number of errors which have not already been studied and discussed. In this paper, attempts are made to illustrate some of these errors and correct them. In so doing, the present researchers have studied these errors stemming from misreading (Tashif), distorting and miswriting, and considering Khaghani's other poems and Arab poets, the syntagmatic (metonymic) level of poems, Khaghani's poetical style, figures of speech, copies, meanings, etc,&#160; we have suggested the correct forms. These errors are so frequent; hence, it is highly necessary to correct them. Due to Khaghani's great status, his artistic skills and his powerful rhetoric in Persian and Arabic languages, it is highly necessary to study these poems more closely and precisely again.},  
Keywords = {Khaghani's Arabic poems, Correction, Misreading (Tashif). },
volume = {20},
Number = {72}, 
pages = {7-24}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-997-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-997-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2012}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Shamshirgarha, Mahbobeh},  
title = {The Addressing Factor in Saadi\'s Poetry}, 
abstract ={Saadi is undoubtedly the master of lyric poem in Persian literature. His Melodious and impressive speech in comparison with other poets' sonnets, is related to many cultural, linguistic, expressive, pictorial factors. Although many elegant points concerning his poems have already been investigated by Henri Masse, Gh.Yousefi, A.dashti, M.Ebadiyan, S.Hamidiyan, T. Poornamdariyan, Z.Movahhed etc., there are still many details about the unique techniques in his sonnets which await further research in order to understand the secret of his beautiful speech and extraordinary impulse. In this article, we have addressed ''addressing'' as a determining factor. The determinative appearance of this factor in Saadi's sonnets has a great role in motivational aspect of his poems. Following a quick introduction of addressing, we present the factors that amplify this sense in saadi's sonnets. He has made the addressing factors in his poems by utilizing artistic techniques and making a presence feeling. It is concluded that the most important effect of &#34;presence feeling&#34; and the &#34;addressing factor&#34; is the audience's excitation. Finally, the addressed factors of saadi's speech are analyzed and presented. In this research, we have used the document analysis method and in the last section we present the distribution of data and statistics of the addressed factors.},  
Keywords = {Lyric poem, Rethoric, Presence},
volume = {20},
Number = {72}, 
pages = {25-51}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-998-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-998-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2012}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Abdollahian, Hamid and Farahmand, Farnoush},  
title = {A Deconstructive Analysis of Two Stories by Bizhan Najdi}, 
abstract ={Najdi is one of the outstanding contemporary writers due to his specific style. He has a different attitude towards human life and cultural elements of Iran, which makes his stories a good subject for discussion and research. In this article, two stories of Najdi are analyzed in the light of Deconstruction: &#8220;The Day of Asb-rizi&#8221; and &#8220;The Night of Killing Sohrab&#8221;. Deconstruction is mostly based on Derrida&#8217;s theory. It originated and was initially used in Philosophy and then it spread to literary criticism. The aim of Deconstruction is to find the binary oppositions, to analyze them in order to reveal the contradictory points and to deny the accepted assumptions. The results of this process is to doubt those beliefs that have been considered as axiomatic up to that time. In Najdi&#8217;s stories, the binary oppositions include man/animal, man/nature and man and civilization. In &#8220;The Day of Asb-rizi&#8221;, the opposition between man and animal, and, freedom and slavery causes some contradictions in the major themes of the story. In &#8220;The Night of Killing Sohrab&#8221;, the binary opposition is that of harsh patriarchal world/ innocent childish world, or, experience/inexperience.},  
Keywords = {Literary criticism, Deconstruction, Contemporary short story,  Jacques Derrida, Bizhan Najdi},
volume = {20},
Number = {72}, 
pages = {53-71}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-999-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-999-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2012}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Gholamrezaei, Mohammad and Momeni, Seyedeh Narjes},  
title = {The Necessity of Re-correction of Terjemah Tafsir Tabari}, 
abstract ={The ancient&#160; translations and interpretations of the&#160; Holy Qur'an are among the less recognized capitals of the great treasures of the Persian language, consisting of the various&#160; words of&#160; the different&#160; domains and&#160; periods of this language and&#160; can be a rich&#160; treasure house in order to develop the&#160; Persian language. Terjemah&#160; Tafsir&#160; Tabari is one of the oldest and richest translations and interpretations which has been provided on the basis&#160; of&#160; the book&#160; of&#160; Tafsir&#160; Tabari&#160; and is of particular importance both from the point of&#160; view of the Persian language history and in terms of&#160; the&#160; history of religious texts. However, the edition which is available has some problems considering the regulations of the correction technique and conditions of the Persian language dialectology. In this article, attempts are made to refer to some typical cases and the necessity for re-correction of this valuable book based on another copy is highlighted.&#160;},  
Keywords = {Terjemah Tafsir Tabari,  Iasufis's  manuscript,  Transoxiana dialect,  Scientific correction.  },
volume = {20},
Number = {72}, 
pages = {73-92}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1000-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1000-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2012}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Mirbagherifard, Aliasghar and Aghahosaini, Hossein and NasrIsfahani, Mohammad Reza and Haghi, Maryam},  
title = {Forbidden Fruit in Contemporary Poetry (Twenty Outstanding Poets from Nima to the Present}, 
abstract ={Quranic tales have always been used by Persian poets in order to create beautiful and unique themes and images. One of these tales is the tale of Adam and Eve and their Fall from Heaven due to eating the Forbidden Fruit. Following most Islamic commentaries, wheat has been considered as this fruit in classic Persian poetry, but the reading of contemporary poets of this tale is different. Sometimes, their reading is similar to classic poets but in other times, following the Old Testament, they consider the apple or the tree of Knowledge of Good and Evil as this fruit, and still in other times they have a mixed reading of Islamic and Jewish traditions. Also, some contemporary poets have proposed a symbolic reading of this tale. This article, initially provides a history of the tale of Forbidden Tree in the Quran, Old Testament and their commentaries. Then, this issue is investigated in the poems of twenty outstanding contemporary poets (from Nima to the present time) and their poems are compared with Quranic and Biblical narratives. The results show that those contemporary poets which have traditional views, have paid attention to Islamic narratives whereas modern poets have often used Biblical narratives},  
Keywords = { The Quran, Old Testament, Symbol, Contemporary poetry, The tale of Adam and Eve, Forbidden Fruit. },
volume = {20},
Number = {72}, 
pages = {93-120}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1001-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1001-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2012}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Vazirizadeh, Mohammad Bagher and Khoeini, Esmat},  
title = {Historical Issues of Dependency Nominal Phrases in Tarikh-e-Balámi}, 
abstract ={Dependency nominal phrases are among the main kinds of nominal phrases. These phrases have spread in kinds and types. In this paper, we investigate these kinds of phrases in the whole text of Tarikh-e-Bal&#225;mi from the historical grammar perspective. This work is indeed one of the first remained Dari Persian manuscripts. More specifically, we study issues that have historical aspects or are semantical and considered as stylistic features. The method adopted in this study is based on the definitions and divisions that late professor Farshidvard who wrote extensively on these nominal groups. Also, we use other grammar books, whenever they are relevant to our discussion. The main goal of this article is providing an accurate historical recognition of dependency nominal phrases that are subtle issues in syntax and are considered as frequently used syntactic groups in discourse. It is assumed that the scientific investigation of grammatical subjects in a specific text may enrich the historical grammar and also may shed lights on old texts.},  
Keywords = {Phrase, Noun, Historical grammar, Tarikh-e-Balámi.},
volume = {20},
Number = {72}, 
pages = {121-140}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2395-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2395-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2012}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Pournamdarian, Taghi},  
title = {Hafez and Norm-breaking in Form and Content of the Ghazal}, 
abstract ={Norm-breaking in the field of literature, like other areas of human knowledge, is the province of the talented. Norm-breakings Hafiz undertook in his ghazals came to be the source of a movement with a good many imitators. His norm-breakings took place in form, meaning and/or in the possible relationships between the two. Critiquing the social mores was one of his trademark iconoclastic practices in the realm of content. Another norm-breaking was inventing rhetorical subtleties whose novelty was particularly conspicuous in the realm of pun. It was an innovation in creating varied links of signs on the horizontal axis of poetry&#8212;an innovation resulted from Hafez&#8217;s contemplations on the emotional meanings of words conjured up in various cultural aspects. The harmony of meaning background and emotional background with the general music dominating them&#8212;a linkage created by meter, rhyme and juxtaposition of words&#8212;is another feature in Hafez&#8217;s poetry. The impressing value and emotional intimacy of these elements are palpable in his poetry. The most remarkable norm-breaking in Hafez&#8217;s ghazals may be the way in which the scattered meanings clandestinely interact through a ghazal; this has caused most scholars to regard it as polysemous and lacking in terms of logical relationship among couplets. These couplets, albeit distantly related with each other, are connected deep inside. Besides demonstrating Hafez&#8217;s rhetorical, artistic as well as semantic norms-breakings, the present paper shows that in spite of his poetry seeming scattered, which is a result of distant and far-reached associations in Hafez&#8217;s culturally and experientially loaded mind, there is an inner relationship among them that can be understood by transforming the norm-breaking propositions to norm-enforcing ones. A ghazal by Saadi is juxtaposed to one by Hafez to illustrate the issue at hand.},  
Keywords = {Hafez, Norm-breaking, Form, Meaning, Relationship among couplets.},
volume = {20},
Number = {73}, 
pages = {7-32}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1537-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1537-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2012}  
}

@article{ 
author = {JafariKamangar, Fatemeh and Damavandi, Mojtab},  
title = {Modern Techniques of Intellectual Reaction in ShazdeEhtejab}, 
abstract ={The authors of modern stories for the deliverance from the deformity of the new civilization attend the inner world, which is more expanded than the external world. They disregard specific philosophies in art and life and try to display the subjective and psychological personalities. Moreover, instead of revealing social objective challenges of the characters, they aim at displaying the contents of the mind&#8217;s inner world. However, to describe the inner world and the mind with the same writing methods used formerly is not possible. Modern writers in order to show the twisted layers of the mind and its world have tried to introduce new ways of narration and story writing. Of course, using such methods may cause some complexity in the novel, but the writer does that deliberately to bring the structure of his novel close to the structure of the mind.This article is a library research highlighting the nature of the mind and presenting one of the first Persian modern subjective novelsShazdeEhtejab by HushangGolshiri. It attempts to discuss how this novel shows the hidden world of the characters and investigates in depth the basic techniques that reveal the mind and the innerworld of the characters.},  
Keywords = {ShazdeEhtejab, Golshiri, mentality, memento, fancy},
volume = {20},
Number = {73}, 
pages = {33-65}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1538-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1538-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2012}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Salemian, Qolam Reza and Arta, Sayyed Mohammad and Heydari, Dony},  
title = {Comparative Study of the Meaning of Symbols in Classical Literature and Ahmad Shamlu’s Poetry}, 
abstract ={Using indirect explanation and symbolism has a long history in Persian literature. Classic poets have used many symbols to explain mystical concepts. In contemporary periods, however, the insight of the poets is deeper than that of traditional poets as they pay more attention to political and social issues. Accordingly, the symbols have changed so that in contemporary poetry they are used for expressing political and social thoughts. Political and social symbolism is a new phenomenon in Persian poetry that begins with Nima and is developed by his followers, especially Ahmad Shamlu. Shamlu was not interested in explicit words, so in order to disseminate the clusters of meaning in his poems he used symbols and symbolism. In his deep and significant symbolism Shamluhas attempted to change the repeated and old symbols of classic poetry and to give them new meaning. This comparative study attempts to look at the different meanings of symbols in Shamlu&#8217;s poetry and to explain how the poet has used them.},  
Keywords = {Ahmad Shamlu, contemporary poetry, classical poetry, symbol, signification},
volume = {20},
Number = {73}, 
pages = {67-98}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1539-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1539-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2012}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Rouhani, Masoud and EnayatiGhadikolaee, Mohamm},  
title = {Aesthetic Analysis of the Phonetic Structure of QaysarAminpour’s poetry}, 
abstract ={Poetry is an event that happens in language. In fact, the poet in his poetry works with language and the reader understands the difference between his poetic language and the common language. The Purpose of the poem is to create harmony among its different elements and one way to establish this harmony is through the phonetic structure of poetry. The Formalists and structuralists believe that the basis of poetry is its structure and in their structural studies they give more importance to the phonetic structure.In this article attempt is made to investigate the phonetic structure and the classification of all methods of forming this structure in the poetry of QaysarAminpour as well as the literary devices that shape the phonetic structure. Aminpour is one of the contemporary poets that adopts a classical form and is one of the followers of Nima. He uses the multiple language possibilities to add to the music of his poetry. The phonetic construction in Aminpour&#8217;s poetry has three levels: phonetic balance, lexical balance and syntactic balance. He looks at the special features of different components forming the word&#8212;phoneme to sentence&#8212;and creates artistic beauty in his poetry. He applies various techniques, such as repetition, rhyme, and pun to add to the beauty of the phonetic structure of the poems},  
Keywords = {QaysarAminpour, aesthetic, phonetic structure, phonetic balance, lexical balance, syntactic balance},
volume = {20},
Number = {73}, 
pages = {99-128}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1540-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1540-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2012}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Fallah, Qolam Ali and PourakbarKasmaee, Seddigheh},  
title = {The Role of Additive, Adversative and Causative  Connectives in Text Cohesion}, 
abstract ={In Persian language and generally in all other languages connectives are considered among the most important devices in the coherence of texts. However, there are some other elements such as adverbs and prepositions that operate in the text and function like conjunctions. These are only a few of the elements that connect sentences in a text to each other. We can classify these elements from different perspectives. One of these perspectives isHalliday&#8217;s functional theory. In his theoryHalliday calls the semantic, verbal, syntactic and logical connections of the sentences in text coherence. From this point of view, in addition to connectives, the other factors that affect the coherence of the text are reference, displacement, elision, and lexical cohesion. Because of the extent of the subject, the researchers in this article study only one of these factors, namely connection. Among different factors of connection, only non-temporal connectives that include simple, compound, explicative and allegorical connectives; contrastive connection factors including simple and compound connectives; and causal connection factors such as the common and reverse will be studied.},  
Keywords = {Coherence, Holiday, Connectives, Language},
volume = {20},
Number = {73}, 
pages = {129-152}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1541-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1541-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2012}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Mirhashemi, Sayyed Mortez},  
title = {About “KabkShekastan”}, 
abstract ={Persian is a language that accepts combination.This tendency has made some of the poets and authors try to create new combinations. Nizami of Ganje is one of the poets in whose works hundreds of these new combinations are seen. On the one hand because of his high intelligence and talent and on the other hand because the people of his time looked for new subjects and new expressions, and also due to the natural evolvement of language, he has paid special attention to this issue. Although Nizami does not limit himself to certain combinations, on the whole the frequency of allusive combinations is high in his works. One of these combinations is that of&#34;kabkshekastan&#34;, which the narrator of Ganje has used in Khosro and Shirin and Sharafname three times. The meanings written for this allusive combination in dictionaries are as follows: &#34;to flirt&#34;, &#34;to efface the track&#34; and &#34;to hide secrets&#34;. Although on the construction of this combination no explanation has been given, we may offer a few conjectures. What we attempt to explain in this research concerns this combination and its meaning in dictionaries. The research is an endeavor&#160;to find out how much these meanings are reliable and if there is another possible meaning for this term.},  
Keywords = {partridge, combination, kabkshekastan, allusion, meaning, typographical error, Nizami},
volume = {20},
Number = {73}, 
pages = {153-172}, 
publisher = {Kharazmi University},
url = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1542-en.html},  
eprint = {http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-1542-en.pdf},  
journal = {Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature},  
issn = {2476-6925}, 
eissn = {2476-6941}, 
year = {2012}  
}

