<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Persian Language and Literature</title>
<title_fa>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبیات فارسی</title_fa>
<short_title>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبيات فارسی</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2476-6925</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2476-6941</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/jpll</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>11</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1394</year>
	<month>11</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2016</year>
	<month>2</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>23</volume>
<number>79</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ویلیام وردزورث و نیما یوشیج: پیوندهای زندگی، شعر و اندیشه دو شاعر رمانتیک</title_fa>
	<title>William Wordsworth and Nima Youshij: Life, poetry and Thought’s Affinities in Two Romantic Poets</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:1.0cm;&quot;&gt;زمانه، زندگی، اشعار و نظریه&#8204;های انتقادی و ادبی ویلیام وردزورث، طلایه&#8204;دار جنبش رمانتیک در ادبیات انگلستان، و نیما یوشیج، که در دوره&#8204;ای از زندگی شاعری رمانتیک شمرده می&#8204;شود، شباهت&#8204;های بسیاری دارند. هر دو شاعر در زمانه انقلاب و آشوب زیستند و به سهم خود بر سنت&#8204;های ادبی غالب در کشورشان شوریدند و تلاش&#8204;های آنان انقلابی در شعر و نظریه ادبی به &#8204;وجود آورد. این مقاله با نگاهی به اصول اثبات&#8204;شده جنبش رمانتیسم به مشخص&#8204;کردن پیش&#8204;زمینه&#8204;های مشابه زندگی&#8204;&#8204;نامه&#8204;ای، اجتماعی&#8204;ـ اقتصادی و فلسفی دو شاعر پرداخته و سپس به بررسی نزدیکی&#8204;های نوسازی دو شاعر در نظریه و عمل می&#8204;پردازد. در این کار رویکرد دو شاعر به مفاهیمی &#8204;مانند شعر و شاعری، محتوا، زبان، احساسات و عواطف و جامعه تحت بررسی قرار می&#8204;گیرد و مشخص می&#8204;شود که دو شاعر با تأثیرپذیری از زمانه خود و تحولات تاریخی در عصر انقلاب&#8204;های اجتماعی، فرهنگی و اقتصادی موفق به انقلاب در شعر و نظریه انتقادی کشورشان شدند. این انقلاب عبارت بود از درک مفاهیم نوین عصر و بیان آنها با شکلی تازه که سرآغاز شعر &amp;quot;مدرن&amp;quot; در انگلستان و شعر &amp;quot;نو&amp;quot; در ایران قلمداد می&#8204;شود.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The time, life, poetry, literary and critical theories of William Wordsworth, the pioneer of Romanticism in English literature, and Nima Youshij, who is often regarded as a Romantic in some part of his literary career, share many similarities. Both poets lived at a time of revolution and turmoil and both revolted against the dominant literary conventions of their time with their efforts accordingly leading to revolutions in the poetry and literary theory of their land. After delineating the accepted tenets of the Romantic Movement, this article highlights the analogous biographical, socio-economical and philosophical contexts of the two poets&amp;rsquo; career and studies the affinities of their attempts at modernizing the poetic theory and practice of their countries. To this aim, the two poets&amp;rsquo; attitude towards concepts such as poetry and the poet, content, language, feelings and emotions, and society are examined in detail. It is explained that by being influenced by their time and the historical evolutions in the age of social, cultural and economic revolutions, the two poets were able to bring the revolution into the poetry and critical theory and practice of their time. This revolution consists of realizing the novel concepts of the age and expressing them in a new form, which is considered as the commencement of &amp;ldquo;Modern&amp;rdquo; English poetry in England and &amp;ldquo;New&amp;rdquo; Persian poetry in Iran.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>رمانتیسم, انقلاب, شعر رمانتیک, شعر نو, ویلیام وردزورث, نیما یوشیج</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Romanticism, Revolution, Romantic Poetry, “New” Poetry, William Wordsworth, Nima Youshij.</keyword>
	<start_page>7</start_page>
	<end_page>34</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-653-11&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Kamran</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ahmadgoli</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>کامران</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>احمدگلی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>k.ahmadgoli@gmail.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600952</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600952</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه خوارزمی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Edris</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ranji</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ادریس</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رنجی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>edris.ranji@gmail.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600953</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600953</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
