<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Persian Language and Literature</title>
<title_fa>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبیات فارسی</title_fa>
<short_title>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبيات فارسی</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2476-6925</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2476-6941</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/jpll</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>11</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1394</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2015</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>23</volume>
<number>78</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>حکمت روشنایی: ذات و صفات خداوند در نظرگاه حکیم سنایی</title_fa>
	<title>The Wisdom of Light God’s Essence and Attributes in Hakim Sanāyi’s View</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p&gt;حکیم سنایی غزنوی (ف532) یکی از اندیشمندان دوران&#8204;ساز و ازجمله تأثیرگذارترین سرایندگان شعر تعلیمی عرفانی است که همواره شاعران و عارفان این دیار به ذهن و زبان او اقتدا کرده&#8204;اند.&lt;br&gt;
در این نوشته کوشیده&#8204;ایم تا با تتبع نسبتاً جامع در دیوان و حدیقه، آرای سنایی را درباب تشبیه و تنزیه، قدم و حدوث، توقیفی&#8204;بودن یا نبودن اسما و صفات خداوند و غرضمندی حضرت حق در آفرینش هستی تبیین کنیم و با مواضع فِرق مشهور کلامی بسنجیم. ازاین&#8204;رو، ابتدا دیدگاه پیشوایان اشاعره، معتزله، ماتریدیه، کرامیه و شیعه امامیه درباب مسائل مزبور نقل و سپس آرای حکیم غزنه در این موارد طبقه&#8204;بندی و تحلیل شده است.&lt;br&gt;
تحقیق نشان می&#8204;دهد که سنایی در اثبات مدعیات خود در آثارش از متون اسلامی و معارف عقلی زمانه خود بهره گرفته، درباب خداشناسی رویکردی تنزیهی و حتی سلبی داشته و مواضع اوـ برخلاف دیدگاه رایج&#8204;ـ با آرای اشاعره، کرامیه و اهل حدیث به&#8204;کلی متفاوت بوده و با باورهای معتزله، شیعه و ماتریدیه همسویی بسیار دارد.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Hakim Sanāyi Qaznavi (d. 532 AH) who is one of the most influential thinkers and poets of didactic Sufi poetry has always been followed by other poets and mystics of Iran. This paper aims at making a comprehensive study of his &lt;em&gt;Hadiqah&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Divān&lt;/em&gt; and also intends to explain his opinions about the questions of transcendence or immanence, eternality and contingency, and whether divine Names and attributes are fixed or not and God's intention of creating the universe. The researchers have attempted to compare these opinions with those of other famous theological sects. Therefore, at first the views of the leaders of the Ash'arites, Mu'tazilites, Matoridites, Karrāmits, and 12-Imam Shiites were presented on these issues and then Sanāyi's opinion was analyzed and classified accordingly. This study shows that Sanāyi has used Islamic texts and rational teachings of his era to prove his claims. He has adopted a transcendent and even a negative approach in theology and his positions, contrary to the current views, have been different from those of the Ash'arites, Karāmits, and adherents of hadith, and have been in harmony with those of the Mu'tazilites, Mātoridites, and Shiites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>سنایی غزنوی , اشاعره , شیعه , عرفان , کلام اسلامی , ذات و صفات خدا , </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Sanāyi Qaznavi, Ash'arites, Shi'ites, Sufism, Islamic Theology, God's Essence and Attributes</keyword>
	<start_page>47</start_page>
	<end_page>72</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-3-50&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Hossein </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Heidari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حسین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حیدری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>golestan1387@gmail.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600971</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600971</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشیار دانشگاه کاشان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Hossein </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ghorbanpoor</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حسین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>قربانپور آرانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>ghorbanpoorarani@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600972</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600972</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>استادیار دانشگاه کاشان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
