<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Persian Language and Literature</title>
<title_fa>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبیات فارسی</title_fa>
<short_title>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبيات فارسی</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2476-6925</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2476-6941</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/jpll</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>11</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1389</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2010</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>18</volume>
<number>69</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بازتاب وقایع روزگار بر سروده های دهخدا</title_fa>
	<title> The Reflection of the Events of the Time on Dehkhoda’s Versifications</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p&gt;دهخدا از برجسته&#8204;ترین چهره&amp;shy;های فرهنگ و ادب این مرز و بوم است که علاوه بر عرصه&amp;shy;های سیاست، روزنامه&#8204;نگاری، پژوهش و تألیف، در نویسندگی و شاعری نیز نقش مهمی ایفا کرده است. او متعلّق به روزگار پرفراز و نشیبی است که جامعه ایرانی رویدادهای مهمی چون نهضت مشروطیت، جنگ&#8204;های جهانی اوّل و دوم، استبداد رضاخانی و ملّی&#8204;شدن صنعت نفت را پس پشت نهاده است. وی به&#8204;عنوان پژوهشگری آگاه به مسائل سیاسی و نویسنده&amp;shy;ای دارای ذوق شاعری بر وقایع اثر گذاشته یا از آن&#8204;ها تأثیر پذیرفته است. بعضی از این وقایع در اشعار باقی&#8204;مانده او بازتابی درخور تأمّل یافته که دقت در آن&#8204;ها مبین اهمیت واقعه و نظر دهخدا درباره آن است؛ در این گفتار سعی می&amp;shy;شود ضمن توضیح مختصری درباره زندگانی، آثار، خدمات فرهنگی و قدرت شاعری دهخدا، بازتاب این وقایع بر سروده&#8204;هایش با روش تحلیلی ـ توصیفی نشان داده شود. بدیهی است نقد و ارزیابی عملکرد اشخاصی&#8204; که &#8204;به بهانه&amp;shy;ای از آن&#8204;ها نام برده می&amp;shy;شود هدف این مقاله نبوده و مجالی درخور می&amp;shy;طلبد. حاصل این پژوهش عرضه شناختی تازه از دهخدا در عرصه سیاست و نمایش اتفاقات مهمی است که ذهن او را به خود مشغول داشته و گذر زمان بر اهمیت آن&#8204;ها صحه گذاشته است.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The great scholar Dehkhoda is one of the most outstanding characters of culture and literature of Iran who besides his contributions to political fields played an important role in journalism, research, editing, writing, and versification. He belongs to the time of abundant ups and downs in which Iranian society had passed important events such as Constitutionalism movement, the first and second world wars, Rezakhan&amp;rsquo;s despotism and nationalization of oil industry. He is indeed a knowledgeable researcher on political issues and a writer whose political talent had influenced the events of his age or was influenced by them. Some of these events left hesitating reflections on his versifications and a closer investigation of them&amp;nbsp; may explain the importance of the events and Dehkhoda's ideas. In this article, beside brief explanation on Dehkhoda&amp;rsquo;s life, works, cultural services and poetical power, attempts were made to illustrate the reflection of these events on his versification using a descriptive&amp;ndash;analytic method. Obviously, the criticism of functional evaluation of those people named for different excuses is not the aim of this article and claims its own proper opportunity. Result of this research offer a&amp;nbsp; new understanding about Dehkhoda in the politics field and give clues to the significant events that engaged his mind, as confirmed through the forthcoming events.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>بازتاب وقایع , اشعار , آزادی‌خواهی , دهخدا , مشروطیت ,</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Reflection of events, Poems,  Dehkhoda, Constitutionalism, Liberalism</keyword>
	<start_page>113</start_page>
	<end_page>136</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-3-96&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Abbas </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mahyar</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>عباس</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>ماهیار</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>info@jamegol.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846002400</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002400</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>استاد دانشگاه آزاد واحد کرج</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Hamidreza </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Jadidi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حمیدرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>جدیدی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002401</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002401</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد محلات</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
