<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1397</YEAR>
<VOL>26</VOL>
<NO>84</NO>
<MOSALSAL>27</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>269</PAGE_NO>


<ARTICLES>

	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>طبقه‌بندی استعاره از دیدگاه جرجانی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Classification of Metaphors from Jurjani's Viewpoint</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>عبدالقاهر جرجانی با دو کتاب معروفش مهم&#173;ترین عالم بلاغت اسلامی است. او را بنیان&#8204;گذار علم بلاغت در جهان اسلام می&#8204;دانند. یکی از برجسته&#8204;ترین کارهای جرجانی طبقه&#8204;بندی کاملی است که از استعاره به&#8204;دست می&#8204;دهد. او استعاره را به دو نوع کلی مفید و غیرمفید تقسیم می&#8204;کند و پس&#8204;ازآن نیز طبقه&#8204;بندی&#8204;های فرعی و کاملی برای استعاره مفید یا بیانی ارائه می&#8204;کند. اغلب نویسندگان پیش از جرجانی نوع خاصی از استعاره را در بحث&#8204;های خود به&#8204;منزله نمونه و شاهد مثال در نظر می&#8204;گیرند، اما او رویکردی را در پیش گرفت که در آن انواع مختلفی از استعاره وجود دارد که نمی&#8204;توانند به یک نوع واحد تقلیل یابند. جرجانی در طبقه&#8204;بندی خود نکات بسیار بدیعی را نیز درباب استعاره بیان می&#8204;کند. این مقاله بر آن است تا با نگاهی نو به بررسی این طبقه&#8204;بندی بپردازد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Abdul Qadir Jurj&#226;n&#238;, with his two famous books, is the most important scholar of Islamic rhetoric. He is the founder of rhetoric in the Muslim world. One of Jurj&#226;n&#238;&#8217;s most prominent accomplishments is his comprehensive classification of metaphors. First of all, Jurj&#226;n&#238; distinguishes between non-expressive and expressive metaphors, and then presents subclasses for expressive, or &#8220;useful&#8221;, metaphor. Most writers before Jurj&#226;n&#238; used a particular kind of metaphor to present examples for clarifications in their discussions, but Jurj&#226;n&#238; distinguishes different kinds of metaphors whose mechanism he does not reduce into a single one. In his classification, Jurj&#226;n&#238; approaches metaphors innovatively. This article aims to study this classification from a fresh perspective.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>7</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>29</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مرتضی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>براتی</Family>
				<NameE>Morteza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Barati</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>شهید چمران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Mt.barati@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Jurjânî</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Metaphor</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Classification</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>جرجانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>استعاره</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>طبقه‌بندی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>جلوه‌های درد سترونی در مجموعه داستان به‌کی سلام کنم؟</TitleF>
		<TitleE>The Representation of “Infertility Pain” in a Collection of Short Stories, Be Ki Salaam Konam?</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>یکی از مهم&#8204;ترین جنبه&#8204;های بررسی و تحلیل متون ادبی توجه به &#8204;انعکاس اندیشه&#8204;ها، آرزوها، اندوه&#8204;ها و حسرت&#8204;های نویسنده درقالب سازوکارهای دفاعی است. در بررسی بازتاب ناخودآگاه نویسنده در آثارش معمولاً از روش&#8204;های نقد روان&#8204;کاوانه یا روان&#8204;شناختی استفاده می&#8206;شود و منتقد می&#8204;کوشد با استفاده از قاعده&#8204;های روان&#8204;کاوی یا روان&#8204;شناختی، تأثیر دغدغه&#8204;های ذهنی مؤلف را در بخش&#8204;های پنهان اثر آشکار کند یا گره&#8204;های &#8204;متن را بگشاید. در این &#8204;مقاله، نگارندگان کوشیده&#8204;اند بازتاب یکی از مهم&#8204;ترین اضطراب&#8204;های روانی سیمین دانشور، یعنی &#171;درد سترونی&#187;، را در مجموعه داستان کوتاه به کی سلام کنم؟ بررسی کنند، دردی که البته به&#8204;شیوه جلال آل&#8204;احمد در اثری مستقل منعکس نشده است، اما در جای&#8204;جای داستان&#8204;های دانشور به&#8204;گونه&#8204;های مختلف ظهور کرده و مجموعه به کی سلام کنم را به روایتی زنانه از سنگی بر گوریِ جلال بدل کرده است. موضوع اغلب داستان&#8204;های این مجموعه درد سترونی است که با استفاده از بن&#8204;مایه&#8204;هایی چون فرزند، فرزندخوانده و نوه درقالب بن&#8204;مایه&#8204;های آزاد یا وابسته اثر به&#8204;نمایش گذاشته می&#8204;شود. دانشور در گسترش ناخودآگاه مسئله ناباروری از نمادهایی مانند پیرزنان نیز استفاده می&#8204;کند. واکنش&#8204;های شخصیت&#8204;های داستان دربرابر سترونی را می&#8204;توان ذیل سازوکار&#8204;های دفاعی همچون فرافکنی، والایش و برون&#8204;افکنی قرار داد. البته، در جریان بحث، به&#8204;مناسبت، موضوع از جنبه&#8204;های دیگری چون نقد اسطوره&#8204;ای نیز بررسی خواهد شد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>One of the most important aspects of analyzing literary texts is the consideration of the reflection of the author's thoughts, wishes, griefs and regrets as defense mechanisms. In reviewing the reflection of an author's unconscious in his or her work, psychoanalytic or psychological criticism is often used, in which the critic tries to reveal the influence of the author's mental constraints on hidden layers of the work or to open textual ambiguities using psychoanalytical or psychological principles. The authors of this article have tried to investigate in a short story collection, Be Ki Salaam Konam?, one of Simin Daneshvar&#8217;s most important psychological anxieties, that is, &#34;infertility pain&#34;; a pain which though is not traced in Jalal al-Ahmad's independent works, it is present in Daneshvar's stories and appears in different ways. Be Ki Salaam Konam? has become a feminine narrative of Jalal&#8217;s Sangi Bar Goori. The subject of most of the stories of the former is &#34;infertility&#34;, which is presented using child, adopted child, and grandson in the form of free or affiliated motifs. Daneshvar uses unconscious symbols such as the old women to suggest infertility. The reactions of characters in the stories to infertility can be described through defense mechanisms such as displacement, sublimation and projection. Nonetheless, throughout the discussion, when necessary, the paper will benefit from approaches such as archetypal criticism as well.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>31</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>51</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>بیات</Family>
				<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Bayat</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه خوارزمی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>خوارزمی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>hoseinbayat@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سعید</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>عبادی جمیل</Family>
				<NameE>Saeid</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ebadijamil</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه شیراز</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>شیراز</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>saeidebadijamil@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Childlessness</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Infertility</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Psychoanalytical Criticism</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Death and Life Drives</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Myth of Serpents</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Simin Daneshvar.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بیفرزندی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سترونی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نقد روان‌کاوانه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سائق مرگ و زندگی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اسطوره مار</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سیمین دانشور.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر شعر بر کاهش افسردگی و افزایش خوش‌بینی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Analyzing the Effect of Poetry on Decreasing Depression and Increasing Optimism</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>شعر ازجمله هنرهای هفت&#173;گانه است و منتقدان همواره به جایگاه زیباشناختی آن توجه نشان داده&#173;اند. در حوزه شعر، درمانگری بزرگ&#8204;ترین دستاورد علمی ادبیات در عصر جدید است. شعردرمانی به&#8204;مثابه درمانی نوپا برای بیماران افسرده در امریکا آغاز شد و به نتایج مفیدی دست پیدا کرد. در پژوهشی که این مقاله دستاورد آن است، به&#8204;شیوه&#173;ای متفاوت، به شعردرمانی پرداخته شده است. جامعه آماری ٣٠ نفر از بزرگسالانی هستند که در هشت جلسه درمانی حضور یافتند. انتخاب اشعار با توجه به مضامین بحث&#173;برانگیز صورت گرفت. با انجام پیش&#173;آزمون و پس&#173;آزمون افسردگی بک مشخص شد که: ١. زنان و مردان افسرده دربرابر شعر رفتار اثربخشی از خود نشان می&#8204;دهند. ٢. اشعاری که مضامین چالش&#173;برانگیز دارند قدرت تنش&#173;زدایی از افراد افسرده دارند. ٣. مردان نسبت به زنان واکنش بهتری به درمان&#8204;ِ با شعر نشان می&#173;دهند. ٤. شعر در افزایش میزان خوش&#173;بینی زنان و مردان تأثیرگذار است. به&#8204;نظر می&#173;رسد پژوهش بیشتر درباره شیوه خوانش و هنر بیان&#8204;ِشعر فارسی و معرفی این گونه درمانی مهم در جهان به نهادینه&#8204;ساختن آن در مراکز درمانی&#8204;ـ&#8204;بهداشتی کشور کمک خواهد کرد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Poetry is one of the seven arts and critics have always attended to its aesthetic features. The greatest modern scientific achievement of literature has been the discovery of the therapeutic quality of poetry. Poetry therapy as a new treatment for patients suffering from depression began in the US where it produced positive results. In this article, the authors investigate poetry in a different way. Statistical Society is composed of 30 adult people who attended 8 sessions of poetry therapy. Also, poems are selected from the ones with controversial themes. According to depression pretests and post-tests, the following results were suggested:
1. Depressed men and women have an impressive behavior towards poetry.
2. Poems with controversial themes can decrease the tensions.
3 Men are more prone to be affected by poetry therapy than women.
4. Poetry is effective in increasing men and women's optimism.
Seemingly, further research about the style and the way of reading Persian poetry and introducing this proposed type of therapy to the world will help to institutionalize poetry therapy in health and medical centers in the country.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>53</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>71</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>شبنم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>حاتم پور</Family>
				<NameE>Shabnam</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Hatampour</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد واحد شوشتر</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد واحد شوشتر</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>shahatampour@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>خاطره</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>پورحسن</Family>
				<NameE>Khatereh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Pourhasan</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد واحد شوشتر</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد واحد شوشتر</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Khatere1408@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Poetry</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Theme</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Poetry Therapy</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Depression</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Optimism</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شعر</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مضمون</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شعردرمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>افسردگی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>خوش‌بینی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>طنزپردازان مشروطه‌خواه: معماران تاریخ ایران جدید</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Constitutionalist Satirists: the Makers of the Modern Iranian History</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>در برخی مقاطع تاریخی، همه طبقات و صنوف جامعه، با همه تفاوت&#8204;ها و اختلافات، به جریان واحدی تبدیل می&#8204;شوند تا به غایتی متعالی دست یابند. این تجربه تاریخی را ملت ایران چندبار آزموده است: هم در انقلاب مشروطه 1285 و هم در انقلاب اسلامی 1357. در انقلاب مشروطه همه طبقات و اصناف جامعه یک هدف و غایت را، که برچیدن طومار استبداد و پیاده&#8204;کردن حکومت قانون است، دنبال کردند و توفیق هم یافتند. در این انقلاب، ادبیات فارسی اعم شعر و نثر نیز به&#8204;خدمت انقلاب درآمد، ازهمین&#8204;رو فن طنز را رسانه اصلی خود قرار داد. ادبیات این دوره چنان با سیاست درآمیخت که ادبای بزرگ را می&#8204;توان معماران بزرگ تاریخ ایران به&#8204;شمار آورد. در این جستار کوشیده&#8204;ایم که همین دقیقه را واکاویم و اثبات کنیم.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>At some historical points, all classes and professions of a society, despite all the differences and disagreements, flow into one single stream to reach a higher goal. Iranians have had this historical experience many times throughout history: during the Constitutional Revolution (1905-1911), and also in the Islamic Revolution in 1979. In the Constitutional Revolution, all classes and professions of the society sought a higher goal that was the eradication of despotism and the establishment of the reign of law. In this Revolution, Persian literature, including poetry and prose, was at the service of the Revolution and satire became the revolutionaries&#8217; main media. Literature of this era became so thoroughly mixed with politics that we can consider the great literati of this period as the great makers of the history of Iran. In this article, we have tried to explore and prove their importance.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>73</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>96</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>میرهادی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>حسینی</Family>
				<NameE>Mirhadi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Husseini</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه خوارزمی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>خوارزمی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>hosseini@khu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Constitutional Revolution</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Political Satire</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Iran</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>History</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Literature.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>انقلاب مشروطه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>طنز سیاسی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ایران</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تاریخ</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ادبیات</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تحلیل اشعار سهراب سپهری ازمنظر هستی‌شناسی هایدگر</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Reading Sohrab Sepehri's Poetry in Light of Heidegger’s Ontology</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>هایدگر یکی از فیلسوفان برجسته قرن بیستم است که درباب هستی&#173;شناسی نظریات ارزنده&#8204;ای دارد. فکر مسلط هایدگر &#171;پرسش هستی&#187; است. او معتقد است انسان یگانه&#8204;موجودی است که هستی برای او مسئله &#8204;است و نیز فقط اوست که می&#173;تواند درباب هستی به تحقیق بپردازد. از بین انسان&#173;ها نیز شاعران اصیل را سزاوار&#173;ترین افراد می&#173;داند. سهراب سپهری یکی از شاعران معاصر است که دستگاه فکری منسجمی دارد. او به&#8204;ویژه در مجموعه&#173;های آخرش آگاهانه و با شیوه&#173;های مختلف برای کشف حقیقت اشیا و هستی داد سخن می&#173;دهد و لحظه&#173;ای از آن غافل نیست. هدف ما در این پژوهش، با روش تحلیلی&#8204;ـ توصیفی، تبیین و تحلیل نگاه فیلسوفانه سپهری درباب هستی&#8204; است. او مانند هایدگر برای شناخت و معرفی هستی از نگاه تکراری و ابزاری پرهیز می&#173;کند و پیش&#8204;فرض&#8204;ها را کنار می&#8204;گذارد. در مجموعه آخرش، اگرچه با وجود تلاش برای فهم حقیقت هستی، درنهایت، به عدم فهم کامل از هستی اعتراف می&#8204;کند، ناامیدی در اندیشه او دیده نمی&#8204;شود.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>As one of the most famous philosophers of the twentieth century, Heidegger has proposed significant ideas about ontology. The undercurrent of his philosophy is the question of being in the world or Dasein. He believes that human is the only creature for whom being in the world is a question and only human is capable of asking about Dasein. Heidegger thinks that authentic poets with their particular use of language are the rightful peoples that can perceive and reveal the truth of being. Sohrab Sepehri is a contemporary poet who has a systematic frame of mind. In his poems, especially in his late works, consciously, continuously, and varyingly he speaks about the true being of things. In this analytic-descriptive article, the authors study Sohrab Sepehri's philosophical perspective towards the ontological state of being. Similar to Heidegger, in order to understand being in the world, he refrains from any stereotypical and utilitarian outlook on it, and ignores the presuppositions. In his final Collection, Sepehri's earnest endeavors to understand the reality of existence are evident. Yet, although he eventually confesses that he has not completely understood the meaning of existence, he never despairs.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>97</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>113</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>حیدری</Family>
				<NameE>Ali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Heidary</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه لرستان</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>لرستان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>aheidary1348@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>کیانوش</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>دانیاری</Family>
				<NameE>Kianoush</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Danyari</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه لرستان</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>لرستان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>k.danyari@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Heidegger</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Ontology</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Sohrab Sepehri</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Dasein.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>موقعیت اجتماعی- اقتصادی مردان در «مویه» لکی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>The Socioeconomic Status of Men in Laki "Moya" (An Elegiac Dirge)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>مویه &#34;مور&#34; از نواهای کهن مناطق لک&#173;زبانِ استان&#173;های لرستان، همدان، ایلام و کرمانشاه است. این نوای دلتنگی، که با آوازی حزین و غم&#8204;ناک، و بدون ضرب&#8204;آهنگ، فقط درقالب یک بیت به&#8204;مناسبت مرگ عزیز ازدست&#8204;رفته خوانده می&#173;شود، پیشینه&#173;ای بس کهن دارد. هدف مقاله حاضر، که به&#8204;شیوه توصیفی&#8204;ـ&#8204;تحلیلی و با استناد به منابع کتابخانه&#173;ای انجام شده است، کشف رابطه میان تک&#173;بیتی&#173;های مور و جایگاه اجتماعی&#8204;ـ&#8204;اقتصادی مردان لک&#173;زبان است. دراین&#173;باره، اشاره شده است که در نوای مور معمولاً شجاعت و دلاوری&#173;، مردم&#173;داری و مهمان&#173;نوازی، وضعیت اقتصادی و اجتماعی، قدرت بدنی و زور بازو و... مردان توصیف می&#8204;شود. این توصیف&#173;ها، که مبین جایگاه حماسه، سوگ، اندوه و وصف در ابیات شعر لکی است، گاه درقالب تک&#173;بیتی به&#8204;وصف دلاورمردان و جنگاوران، خوانین و کدخدایان طوائف، یا کشاورزان و گله&#173;داران می&#173;پردازند و ویژگی&#8204;های مشهود ممدوح را بیان می&#173;کنند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The &#34;Mour&#34; is an elegiac dirge in Laki &#8211; an ancient language still spoken in regions as diverse as Lorestan, Hamadan, Ilam, and Kermanshah. Sung in an elegiac non-rhythmic tune and just in one distich in memory of a dead person, these wistful melodies have a rather long history. The purpose of this article, which is descriptive-analytical and library-based, is to explore the relationship between the distiches of Mour and the socioeconomic status of Laki-speaking men. In this regard, it has been pointed out that in Mour dirges, men&#8217;s bravery, magnanimity and hospitality, as well as their economic and social status, physical strength, etc. are often described. The frequency of these descriptions indicate the position of epic, elegy, and narrative in verses of Laki poetry that often in just one distich capture the most outstanding feature of warriors, thanes, tribal sheriffs, farmers and herdsmen.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>115</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>131</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمدحسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>خان محمدی</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad Hussein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Khanmohammadi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه ارومیه</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>ارومیه</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>h.khanmohammadi@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>اکرم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>دولتی سیاب</Family>
				<NameE>Akram</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Dowlati Siab</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه ارومیه</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>ارومیه</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>dowlati.a4631@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Mour</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Laki</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Epic</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Bravery</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Hospitality</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مور</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>لکی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>حماسه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شجاعت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مهمان‌نوازی.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>نقش جنسیت در ساخت و گزینش استعاره در اشعار شاملو و مشیری ازمنظر نظریه گفتمانی استعاره</TitleF>
		<TitleE>The Role of Gender in Production and Selection of Metaphors in Poems by Shamloo and Moshiri based on Discourse Theory of Metaphor</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>تاکنون پژوهش&#173;های نسبتاً خوبی در زمینه روابط بین جنسیت، استعاره و گفتمان درباب متون سیاسی، رسانه&#173;ای و ادبی انجام شده است. در پژوهش حاضر، سعی شده است روابط جنسیت و استعاره در شعر بررسی شود. پرسش&#173;های اساسی پژوهش عبارت&#8204;اند از: نقش جنسیت در ساخت و گزینش استعاره در اشعار شاملو و مشیری چگونه است؟ آیا می&#173;توان پذیرفت که استعاره ابزاری برای بازنمایی جنسیت&#173;گرایی در اشعار ذکرشده است؟ در این پژوهش، داده&#173;ها از مجموعه اشعار احمد شاملو و فریدون مشیری استخراج و با توجه به نظریه گفتمانی استعاره چارتریس&#8204;ـ&#8204;&#8204;بلک تجزیه و تحلیل شده&#173;اند. نتایج پژوهش نشان می&#8204;دهد که جنسیت&#173;گرایی در اشعار شاملو و مشیری وجود دارد، اما میزان جنسیت&#173;گرایی در اشعار شاملو به&#8204;مراتب بیشتر از اشعار مشیری است؛ چراکه حوزه معنایی جنگ در استعاره&#173;های مفهومی اشعار شاملو بیشتر از اشعار مشیری است. بنابراین، نتایج پژوهش حاکی از آن است که در ساخت و گزینش استعاره در اشعار جنسیت، نگرش و اندیشه شاعر، احساسات او و فضای اجتماعی حاکم بر روزگار شاعران مؤثرند و البته عامل جنسیت نقش مهمی در ساخت و گزینش استعاره ایفا می&#173;کند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Many noteworthy studies have been done to examine the discursive relationship between gender and metaphor in the context of politics, media and literature. In this research, however, I try to investigate the relationship between gender and metaphor specifically in poetical discourse. The main questions of this research are as follows: What is the role of gender in the production and selection of metaphors in the poems by Shamloo and Moshiri? And also can we claim that metaphor is an instrument for representation of sexism in given poems? Research data are extracted from poems by Shamloo and Moshiri and they are analyzed based on Charteris-Black&#8217;s discourse theory of metaphor. The results of research indicate that there are manifestations of sexism in these poems, but the degree of sexism in the poems of Shamloo is higher than Moshiri&#8217;s. The reason is that the semantic domain of war on conceptual metaphors in Shamloo&#8217;s poems is more than Moshiri&#8217;s. Therefore, the results of the research indicate that the production and selection of metaphors in poems are decided by gender, attitude and thought of poets, as well as their feelings and social atmosphere. Indeed, gender plays an important role in production and selection of metaphors in poems.&#160;&#160;&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>133</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>156</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>ابراهیم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رضاپور</Family>
				<NameE>Ebrahim</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rezapour</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه سمنان</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>سمنان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>abrahim_rezapour@semnan.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Gender</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Metaphor</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Discourse Theory of Metaphor</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Shamloo</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Moshiri</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>جنسیت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>استعاره</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نظریه گفتمانی استعاره</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شاملو</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مشیری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تحلیل مفاهیم و کارکرد ارتباطات غیرکلامی در شاهنامه</TitleF>
		<TitleE>An Analysis of the Function of Non-verbal Communications in Shahnameh</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>ارتباطات غیرکلامی را می&#173;توان جزء نشانه&#173;های تصویری به&#8204;شمار آورد که امروزه برای روان&#8204;شناسان و جامعه&#173;شناسان، به&#8204;دلیل اهمیت آنها در انتقال معنا و تنظیم روابط بینافردی، جایگاهی ویژه دارد. یکی از مهم&#173;ترین زیرشاخه&#173;های این مبحث &#171;زبان بدن&#187; نامیده می&#173;شود که درمیان همه جوامع بشری از دیرباز تاکنون وجود داشته است. این نشانه&#173;های غیرکلامی ـ&#8204;که برخی قدمتی چندهزارساله دارندـ در فرهنگ&#173;ها و سنن اجتماعی اقوام گوناگون، با وجوه مشترک و گاه اختلافی، کاربرد و کارکرد فرهنگی و بلاغی دارند. روشن است هرچه بستر ادبی چنین بازنگری و رویکردی کهن&#173;تر و البته جامع&#173;تر باشد، ارزش تحلیل&#173;های آن در بازشناسی فرهنگی و اجتماعی و حتی زیبایی&#173;شناسی متون بیشتر است. بی&#173;گمان، شاهنامه فردوسی &#8204;ـ&#8204;که نماینده فرهنگ و تفکر ایرانی در عصر پیشاتاریخی تا ادوار تاریخی مقارن با ظهور اسلام است&#8204;ـ می&#173;تواند بهترین ظرف بازنمایی کنش&#173;های ارتباطی برون&#8204;زبانی در تاریخ فرهنگی کهن ایران باشد. چنان&#173;که به&#8204;سبب ماهیت پیش&#173;نمونی شخصیت&#173;های شاهنامه، بسیاری از نشانه&#173;های غیرکلامی آنها را نیز می&#173;توان کهن&#173;الگوی بسیاری از کنش&#173;های رفتاری یا زبان بدن ایرانی در ساحت و هنگامه زندگی حماسی، یعنی شکل&#173;گیری هویت ملی و اجتماعی ایرانیان، محسوب کرد. در این جستار با واکاوی مفاهیم &#171;زبان بدن&#187; در کنش&#8204;های غیرزبانی شخصیت&#173;های برجسته شاهنامه تلاش شده است این مفاهیم پوشیده و پیچیده فرهنگی رمزگشایی شود. از نتایج تحقیق برمی&#173;آید که بازنمایی زبان بدن شخصیت&#173;های شاهنامه نه از روی اتفاق که کاملاً آگاهانه به&#8204;قصد جلب &#8204;توجه مخاطب و بازاندیشی او در الگوهای رفتار فردی و اجتماعی اقوام ایرانی و غیرایرانی به&#8204;قصد بازشناسی هویت فرهنگی ایرانیان، بیشتر از رهگذر کنایه&#173;سازی و نمادپردازی صورت گرفته است.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Non-verbal communications could be a part of visual signs that, because of their importance in interpersonal relationships and transition of meaning, are highly regarded by psychologists and sociologists. One of the major subdivisions of this topic is called &#34;Body Language&#34; that has existed in all human societies since ancient times. These non-verbal signs, some thousands of years old, have cultural and rhetorical functions, with common and sometimes conflicting aspects, in the cultures and social traditions of different tribes. The more ancient and comprehensive the literary context of a piece of research is, the more valuable that analysis in explaining the cultural, social, and even aesthetic aspects of texts will be. Shahnameh of Ferdowsi, as a representative of Iranian culture and thought in prehistoric age up until the Islamic era, can be the best representation of metalingual communicative performance in Iranian cultural history. Due to the prototypic nature of characters in Shahnameh, many of their non-verbal signs can also be considered the archetypal source of the behavioral interactions or body language of the Iranian people when in the context of epic their national and social identities as Iranians are formed. In this article, attempts has been made to decode these obscure and complex cultural concepts by exploring the &#34;body language&#34; in non-linguistic acts of main characters in Shahnameh. The results of this research demonstrate that the body language of characters in Shahnameh is not accidental but totally conscious. Indeed, the purpose has been to draw the attention of the readers to rethink the patterns of individual and social behavior of Iranian and non-Iranian ethnicities so to recognize the cultural identity mainly through irony and symbolism.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>157</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>184</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سیدعلی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>قاسم زاده</Family>
				<NameE>Seyed Ali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ghasemzadeh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه بین‌المللی امام خمینی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه بین المللی امام خمینی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>s.ali.ghasem@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمدشفیع</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>صفاری</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad Shafi’</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Saffari</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه بین‌المللی امام خمینی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه بین‌المللی امام خمینی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>safari_706@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>علی‌نقی</Family>
				<NameE>Hussein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Alinaghi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه بین‌المللی امام خمینی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه بین‌المللی امام خمینی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>hoseinalinghi@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Non-verbal Communication</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Body Language</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Cultural Ethology</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Shahnameh of Ferdowsi.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ارتباط غیرکلامی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>زبان بدن</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>رفتار‌شناسی فرهنگی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شاهنامه فردوسی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بحران بازنمایی در رمان آزاده‌خانم و نویسنده‌اش نوشته رضا براهنی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>The Crisis of Representation in Azadeh Khanoom and Her Author by Reza Baraheni

</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>بحران بازنمایی از اصطلاحات متعلق به نقد و نظریه ادبیات پسامدرن است. این عبارت به بحران&#173;های عصر حاضر ازقبیل بحران معنا، سرگشتگی انسان معاصر درمیان انبوهی از داده&#8204;های معتبر و نامعتبر، ازخودبیگانگی و... اشاره دارد. ادبیات به&#173;مثابه آینه تمام&#173;نمای زندگی انسان، بازگوکننده این بحران&#173;ها در دوره معاصر است. رمان آزاده&#173;خانم و نویسنده&#173;اش یا آشویتس خصوصی دکتر شریفی، نوشته رضا براهنی، از شناخته&#173;شده&#173;ترین رمان&#173;های سه&#8204;دهه اخیر ایران است. این رمان را می&#173;توان اثری درخور &#8204;توجه در شیوه داستان&#8204;نویسی پسامدرن ایران دانست. در مقاله حاضر، بحران بازنمایی در رمان آزاده&#173;خانم و نویسنده&#173;اش، با تکیه بر &#34;سوژه&#34;، به&#173;مثابه جایگزین فلسفی مفهوم &#34;انسان&#34;، تحلیل شده است. در این تحلیل، عوامل بحرانی&#173;شدن بازنمایی، پیامدهای آن بر سوژ&#173;ه انسانی و نوع تأثیرگذاری آن بر شخصیت&#173;ها در اثری داستانی بررسی و تبیین شده است؛ درنتیجه، بحران&#173;هایی چون بحران هویت، بحران شخصیت و... را می&#173;توان از عوارض ابتلای انسان امروز به بحران بازنمایی دانست.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The crisis of representation is a topic widely discussed in critique and theory of postmodern literature. This refers to the crises of the present era including the crisis of meaning, the perplexity of contemporary humankind amidst a mass of valid and invalid data, alienation, etc. Literature, as the epitome of human life, is a reflection of these crises in the contemporary era. Azadeh Khanoom and Her Author or&#8204; the private Auschwitz of Dr. Sharifi, written by Reza Baraheni, is among the most well-known novels of the last three decades in Iran. This novel is regarded as a noteworthy example of postmodern fiction. In the present article, the crisis of representation in Azadeh Khanoom and Her Author is analyzed based on &#8220;subject&#8221;, as the philosophical substitute for the concept of &#8220;man&#8221;. In this analysis, the crisis of representation, its consequences for human subject and its influence on Baraheni&#8217;s fictional characters are explored; consequently, crises such as identity crisis, personality crisis, etc. can be considered as complications of man&#8217;s current affliction of the crisis of representation.
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>185</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>204</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>فرزاد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>کریمی</Family>
				<NameE>Farzad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Karimi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه شیراز</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>شیراز</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>frzd4233@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>​Azadeh Khanoom and Her Author</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Postmodern Literature</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Crisis of Representation</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Reza Baraheni</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Subject.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>آزاده‌خانم و نویسنده‌اش</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ادبیات پسامدرن</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بحران بازنمایی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>رضا براهنی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سوژه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>حضور شعری یا تجربه متنبی از نزدیک</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Al-Mutanabbi’s Poetic Presence or Experience-near</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>تاکنون کمتر شاعری مانند متنبی توانسته است اندیشه و قلم دانشمندان و ادیبان و شاعران بسیاری را، از گذشته تاکنون، به خود مشغول کند و در روزگار حیاتش با چنان اقبالی روبه&#8204;رو شود. در این جستار برآنیم راز این&#8204;همه اقبال به شعر متنبی و تفضیل او بر دیگران و خاتم شاعران عرب&#8204;بودنش را دریابیم. از گذشته&#8204;های دور تاکنون، این مهم را از زوایا و منظرهای مختلفی بررسیده و کاویده&#8204;اند. در پژوهش حاضر، این دقیقه در شعر متنبی از رهگذر دو اصطلاح &#34;حضور&#34; و &#34;غیبت&#34; صوفیه، که همانند شاعران بر شهود تکیه دارند و مفاهیمی چون &#34;تجربه از نزدیک&#34; و &#34;تجربه از دور&#34; و با تکیه بر این بیت متنبی: &#171;فالخیل و اللیل و البیداء تعرفنی/ و السیف و الرمح و القرطاس و القلم&#187; کاویده شده است. متنبی با حضور همیشگی&#8204;اش در تجربه&#8204;های شعری خویش توانسته آنچه را از اعیان در پرده بوده است آشکارا ببیند تا حکم غیبی برای او به حکم عینی تبدیل شود. راز جاودانگی متنبی را در همین حضور همیشگی یا به&#8204;تعبیری در همین تجربه از نزدیک یا به&#8204;قولی در آشنایی و معرفت شاعر می&#8204;توان جست. همین مهم سبب شده است تا شعرش &#171;مرجع ضمیر زندگی&#187; شود.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Hardly could any poet, like Al-Mutanabbi, draw to himself the constant attention of scholars, literary man and poets. In this article, we try to find the secret of the admiration that Al-Mutanabbi&#8217;s poetry has won and see why he is one of the most preferred poets and considered the prophet of Arab poets. Scholars have studied this issue from various perspectives. In this article, however, I will examine this issue taking a number of points into account: first, two terms of &#8220;presence&#8221; and &#8220;absence&#8221; in Sufism, wherein like poetry the emphasis is on intuition; second, concepts such as &#8220;experience-near&#8221; and &#8220;experience-distant&#8221; and, finally by relying on this verse of Al-Mutanabbi: &#8220;the horse and night and dessert are known to me / also sword, paper and pen&#8221;. Al-Mutanabbi by his constant presence in his poetic experience has been able to see so openly what has been hidden from many scholars that this spiritual perception turns into an objective reality to him. We can seek the secret of Al-Mutanabbi&#8217;s immortality in the constant presence or, in other words, in his &#8220;experience-near&#8221; and in his deep wisdom which made his poetry to be considered &#8220;the true reference of life&#8221;.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>205</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>218</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حبیب الله</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>عباسی</Family>
				<NameE>Habib-Allah</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Abbasi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه خوارزمی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>خوارزمی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>habibabbasi45@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Al-Mutanabbi</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Arabic Poetry</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Poetic Presence</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Experience-near.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>متنبی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شعر عربی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>حضور شعری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تجربه از نزدیک</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی زمینه‌های جبرباوری و اختیارگرایی در مثل‌های فارسی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>A study of Determinism and Free-will in Persian Proverbs

</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>ضرب&#8204;المثل&#8204;ها، به&#8204;منزله نوعی ادب محاوره&#8204;ای، همواره از آبشخورهای دین، فرهنگ، آداب&#8204;ورسوم و باورهای فلسفی و کلامی جامعه مایه می&#8204;گیرند و باورهای عوام را نیز آینگی می&#8204;کنند. تکرار و بسامد ضرب&#8204;المثلی با اندیشه خاص باعث می&#8204;شود که آن نوع اندیشه به الگوی رفتاری تبدیل شود و کنش&#8204;ها و رفتارهای مردم جامعه را تحت تأثیر قرار دهد. در جامعه ایرانی، همواره دو جریان کلامی اختیارگرایی معتزله و جبرباوری اشاعره حاکم بوده است، اما ازآنجاکه همواره حکومت&#8204;ها جریان جبرباور اشاعره را به&#8204;شیوه&#8204;های مختلف تقویت کرده&#8204;اند، این باورها در ذهن و زبان عامه مردم و به&#8204;تبع آن امثال فارسی راه یافته&#8204;اند، تاجایی&#8204;که بیشتر امثال فارسی با ذهنیتی جبرگرا ساخته شده&#8204;اند. همین جبرگرایی در ایران باستان در اندیشه زروانی باعنوان &#34;بخت&#34; مطرح است که حجم گسترده&#8204;ای از امثال را شامل می&#8204;شود. باورهایی مثل اعتقاد به جبر محض، اعتقاد به قضا و قدر و اراده حتمی خداوند و عدم استقلال انسان در سرنوشت خود، کژفهمی مسائلی مثل توکل و تفویض، رضا و تسلیم دربرابر قضای حتمی و توفیق و خذلان، در طی اعصار عواقب ناگواری برای فرهنگ ایرانی به&#8204;همراه داشته است.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Proverbs as a part of colloquial literature are always nourished by religion, culture, traditions, and philosophical beliefs of a community, and thus they mirror the common beliefs of a people. The frequent repletion of a proverb pregnant with a specific thought makes that type of thought a behavioral pattern and affects the actions and behaviors of the people of a society. In the Iranian society, always two trends in theological rhetoric were dominant; i.e. the Mu'tazila's espousal of free-will and the Ash'ari's advocacy of determinism. However, because governments continually and in different ways have reinforced the Ash'ari&#8217;s determinism, these beliefs have penetrated into the mindset and language ​​of the people. This mentality is so widespread that most Persian proverbs reverberate with this deterministic overtone. A similar determinism in ancient Iran is traceable in the creed of Zorvani who knows this through the concept of &#34;bhakht&#34; which is reflected, for example, in belief in absolute determinism, belief in God's judgment, the will of God and the lack of independence to control one&#8217;s own destiny. It also led them to misconstrue issues such as trust in God, delegation of authority, and submission to the will of God: misunderstandings that have had damaging consequences for the Iranian culture throughout ages.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>219</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>241</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مصطفی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>موسوی</Family>
				<NameE>Mostafa</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Musavi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>mmusavi@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>عباس</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شاه‌علی رامشه</Family>
				<NameE>Abbas</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Shahali Ramesheh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه کاشان</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>کاشان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>a.shahali.r70@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Thought</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Determinism</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Free-will</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Proverbs</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اندیشه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>جبر</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اختیار</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ضرب‌المثل‌ها</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی مؤلفه‌های زبان عامیانه در داستان‌های جلال آل‌احمد</TitleF>
		<TitleE>A Study of Colloquial Language in Jalal Al-e-Ahmad’s Fictions</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>جلال آل&#8204;احمد را می&#8204;توان بزرگ&#8204;ترین نویسنده نثر جدید فارسی نامید که در نثر داستانی تأثیر فراوانی گذاشته و افراد زیادی از سبک او تقلید کرده&#8204;اند. از ویژگی&#8204;های نثر او به&#8204;کارگیری زبان عامیانه است که &#34;زبان کوچه&#34; نامیده می&#8204;شود. او از زبان مردم کوچه &#8204;و بازار، که سرشار از تعابیر و اصطلاحات و واژه&#8204;های عامیانه است، در آثار داستانی خود بهره گرفته است و این شاخصه سبکی آثار داستانی او قلمداد می&#8204;شود.
آنچه نثر آل&#8204;احمد را از نویسندگان دیگر متمایز می&#8204;کند، به&#8204;کاربردن دقیق و جدی و استادانه این زبان در تمام آثارش است. با عنایت به فراوانی کاربرد زبان عامیانه در آثار داستانی آل&#8204;احمد، مقاله حاضر به شناسایی مؤلفه&#8204;های زبان عامیانه در حوزه واژگان و ترکیبات و عبارات، در مجموعه آثار داستانی جلال آل&#8204;احمد پرداخته است که ازجمله این مؤلفه&#8204;ها کنایه، شبه&#8204;جمله، اتباع، نام&#8204;آوا، کلمات کوچه&#8204;بازاری، ضرب&#8204;المثل و... است. در مقاله حاضر، پس از شناسایی این مؤلفه&#8204;ها در آثار منتخب، نمونه&#8204;هایی از آنها شاهدمثال آورده شده و بسامد همه مؤلفه&#8204;های عامیانه در آثار داستانی منتخب، در جدول&#8204;های متعدد، ارائه و تحلیل شده است.
با بررسی دقیق آثار داستانی آل&#8204;احمد، این یافته حاصل شد که از میان مؤلفه&#8204;های زبان عامیانه، عبارات کنایی، واژه&#8204;های کوچه&#8204;بازاری و سپس اتباع و هم&#8204;گون&#8204;سازی پربسامد&#8204;ترین عناصر عامیانه در نثر آل&#8204;احمد است. او از شکسته&#8204;نویسی به&#8204;منزله عاملی مهم برای ایجاد&#160; لحن عامیانه در داستان&#8204;های خود استفاده کرده و از عناصر مهم شکسته&#8204;نویسی در داستان&#8204;های او، ابدال و حذف بیشترین بسامد را داراست. شایان ذکر است که کاربرد این مؤلفه&#8204;ها، باعث نزدیکی زبان آل&#8204;احمد به زبان مردم کوچه و درنهایت سبب اقبال بیش&#8204;ازحد خوانندگان مردمی به آثار او است.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>As the most prominent novelist in contemporary Persian prose, Jalal Ale-Ahmad has had great influence on Persian writers, insofar as many writers have followed his suit. Employment of colloquial language is the characteristic style of his fiction. What makes his different, however, is mainly the employment of colloquialism in a subtle, precise and accurate way. Due to the extensive use of colloquial language in his fictions, this article studies terminologies, phrases and figures&#160; such as metonymy, interjection, onomatopoeia, reduplication,&#160; and also argot and proverb. Having defined these components in his selected works, the authors of this article will put forth some examples and, in multiple tables, illustrate their frequencies. According to a precise examination of his novels, we concluded that among different types of speech, respectively, the metaphoric phrases, argot, assimilation and then reduplication have the highest frequency in Al-e-Ahmad&#8217;s prose. He writes in broken Persian to convey the sense of colloquial language in his novels. Substitution and reduction are the most frequent methods he uses when he writes in broken Persian. Interestingly, this frequent colloquial style in his writings has led to a widespread popularity of his novels among the people.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>243</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>269</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>عفت</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>نقابی</Family>
				<NameE>Effat</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Neghabi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه خوارزمی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>خوارزمی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>neghabi_2007@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>فاطمه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>تاج‌فیروزه</Family>
				<NameE>Fatemeh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Taj Firouzeh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه خوارزمی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>خوارزمی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>f.firozeh67@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Contemporary Literature</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Persian Prose</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Al-e-Ahmad Prose</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Colloquial Prose.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ادبیات معاصر</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نثر فارسی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نثر داستان‌های جلال آل‌احمد</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>زبان و نثر عامیانه.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>

</ARTICLES>

</JOURNAL>
</XML>
