<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" 

"journalpublishing3.dtd">

<article 
article-type="research-article"
dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en" 
xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
>

<front>

<journal-meta>

  <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher">1</journal-id>
  <issn>2476-6925</issn>

  <publisher>

	<publisher-name>Kharazmi University</publisher-name>
  </publisher>

</journal-meta>



<article-meta>

  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">978</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject></subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>An Analysis of “the Voice of Narrator” and “Focalization” in Houshang Golshiri’s Shazdeh Ihtejab</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Dezfoulian</surname>
		<given-names>Kazem </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Moloudi</surname>
		<given-names>Foad </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2010</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>18</volume>

  <issue>69</issue>

  <fpage>7</fpage>

  <lpage>28</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>01</day>
				  <month>11</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Shazdeh Ihtejab by Houshang Golshiri is one of the most valuable examples of Iran&#8217;s fictional literature in terms of its use of narrative techniques and devices. Golshiri in Shazdeh Ihtejab has benefitted from various narrative elements; however, it can be argued that the complexity of the narrative techniques of the work is to a great extent due to his use of two elements of &#8220;the voice of narrator&#8221; and &#8220;focalization.&#8221; Selecting the limited third person narrator which is restricted to the minds of two main characters of the work (Shazdeh Ihtejab and Fakhri) and offering the thoughts and sayings of these two characters in direct and indirect discourse has caused the voice of the narrator or narrators to be mixed with the perspective of the focalizer or focalizers and has rendered understanding the relation between narrator and focalizer and the difference between the two difficult. Based on this, in the present article, the two elements of &#8220;voice of the narrator&#8221; and &#8220;focalization&#8221; in the narrative text of Shazdeh Ihtejab are discussed in order to present the artistic use of the two elements in the narrative text of Shazdeh Ihtejab.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">979</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject></subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Analyzing the Nonverbal Communication in Beyhaqi’s Narration of Hanging of the Hasanak Minister</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Razi</surname>
		<given-names>Ahmad </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Afrakhte</surname>
		<given-names>Allahyar </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2010</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>18</volume>

  <issue>69</issue>

  <fpage>29</fpage>

  <lpage>58</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>01</day>
				  <month>11</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Communication is one of the main functions of language. Linguistic communication usually combines with other modes of interaction such as nonverbal communication. People&#8217;s nonverbal behaviors display their styles and personality characteristics. Therefore, the fictionists and historians tend to reflect the quality and quantity of the character&#8217;s nonverbal relationship in their narration. The present study examines the adventure of Hanging of the Hasanak Minister in Tarikh-e Beyhaqi in order to show how Beyhaqi succeeds to imagine, objectify and portray the events of Qaznavi's periods and how it could improve the dramatic capacity of historical text with accuracy in nonverbal communication using a descriptive-analytical method and an interdisciplinary approach. This study displays that Beyhaqi often uses nonverbal communication in order to complete the verbal communication; but in many cases, they are replaced by verbal behavior or control the verbal behaviors.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">980</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject></subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Functions of mubads in Shahnameh</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Shamian Saroukalaei</surname>
		<given-names>Akbar </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Delpazir</surname>
		<given-names>Zahra </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2010</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>18</volume>

  <issue>69</issue>

  <fpage>59</fpage>

  <lpage>89</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>01</day>
				  <month>11</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

In ancient Iran, mubeds were always among the most prominent authorities of the country and were highly influential in kings&#8217; courts. This role is well depicted in Iran&#8217;s most famous national epic, and it is of such an importance that by examining their roles and positions in Shahnameh, one can find how religion and government were closely related in ancient Iran. In Shahnameh, the mubads&#8217; responsibilities were not just limited to conducting religious ceremonies and rites. They enjoyed power and authority in country&#8217;s administration and were the most educated people of their age. They were responsible for the education and also narrated ancient stories. Observing the economic affairs and bearing the flag in battles were other responsibilities of the mubeds which are also well depicted in Shahnameh. It should be noted that &#8220;mubed&#8221; in Shahnameh is used as a generic term and it is not always used to mean a &#8220;clergy&#8221;. Rather, its meanings had expanded and the term was attributed to wise and erudite people. In this paper, the authors attempt to explain the functions and hierarchies of mubeds according to Ferdowsi&#8217;s Shahnameh.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">981</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject></subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Rhythmic Defamiliarization in Naser Khosrow's  Poetry</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Eidgah Torghabehei</surname>
		<given-names>Vahid </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2010</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>18</volume>

  <issue>69</issue>

  <fpage>91</fpage>

  <lpage>111</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>01</day>
				  <month>11</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

This article, first takes a formalist approach and attempts to achieve two goals: defining the term defamiliarization, its essence and function. Then, it illustrates one of the prosodic features of Naser khosrow&#8217;s poetry which could be considered as an appropriate example of rhythmic defamiliarization. For this purpose, seven meters from his Divān, of which rare meters are usually called unpleasant/ unfamiliar, will be discussed; and, according to their different structures, they will be categorized into&#160; two groups: one incorporating six meters, and the other containing only one. The meters of the first group which are mainly analyzed in this study have different length from their current forms. When a poet such as Naser Khosrow employs these infrequent meters in his poetry, it sounds odd to most of Persian readers who are accustomed to the ordinary rhythms. This can be called rhythmic/ prosodic defamiliarization.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">982</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject></subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title> The Reflection of the Events of the Time on Dehkhoda’s Versifications</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Mahyar</surname>
		<given-names>Abbas </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Jadidi</surname>
		<given-names>Hamidreza </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2010</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>18</volume>

  <issue>69</issue>

  <fpage>113</fpage>

  <lpage>136</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>01</day>
				  <month>11</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The great scholar Dehkhoda is one of the most outstanding characters of culture and literature of Iran who besides his contributions to political fields played an important role in journalism, research, editing, writing, and versification. He belongs to the time of abundant ups and downs in which Iranian society had passed important events such as Constitutionalism movement, the first and second world wars, Rezakhan&#8217;s despotism and nationalization of oil industry. He is indeed a knowledgeable researcher on political issues and a writer whose political talent had influenced the events of his age or was influenced by them. Some of these events left hesitating reflections on his versifications and a closer investigation of them&#160; may explain the importance of the events and Dehkhoda's ideas. In this article, beside brief explanation on Dehkhoda&#8217;s life, works, cultural services and poetical power, attempts were made to illustrate the reflection of these events on his versification using a descriptive&#8211;analytic method. Obviously, the criticism of functional evaluation of those people named for different excuses is not the aim of this article and claims its own proper opportunity. Result of this research offer a&#160; new understanding about Dehkhoda in the politics field and give clues to the significant events that engaged his mind, as confirmed through the forthcoming events.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">983</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject></subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title> A Critical Analysis of the Definitions of Sufism and Mysticism</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Mirbaghrifard</surname>
		<given-names>  Ali. A.  </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Rezaei</surname>
		<given-names>Mehdi </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2010</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>18</volume>

  <issue>69</issue>

  <fpage>137</fpage>

  <lpage>174</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>01</day>
				  <month>11</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Islamic mysticism and Sufism are among important mental and cultural issues which have influenced Islamic &#8211; Iranian culture and Persian language and literature profusely. So the various dimensions of this mental and practical school must be revisited. One way to approach the subject and the end of this school as well as the history and content and changes is to examine the definitions which the pioneers and leading Sufis have provided. In this article, we have a critical look at these definitions in order to know this mental- practical school better and to clarify its hidden dimensions of that. To this end, in addition to referring to the leaders and followers of Sufism, their mental and practical framework will be illustrated.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">984</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject></subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Psychological analysis of Hermann Hesse's"Siddhartha"story</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Hashemi </surname>
		<given-names>Seyyed Morteza </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Khosravi</surname>
		<given-names>Ashraf </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2010</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>18</volume>

  <issue>69</issue>

  <fpage>175</fpage>

  <lpage>202</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>01</day>
				  <month>11</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

One of the dynamic branches of contemporary literary criticism is psychological&#160;criticism which, in turn, has several subdivisions. One such subdivision is based on Carl Gustav Jung's viewpoint. Hermann Hesse's works can be well criticized and analyzed&#160;through Jung's psychological point of view because his ideas and thoughts are in many ways similar&#160;to those of Jung. They were in close contact and communicated with each other. Both of them were interested in symbols and icons, as well as commenting and analyzing them. Hesse was as introvert as Jung was; he paid&#160;attention to psychological facts and social aspects are meager&#160;in his works. Hesse and Jung liked East mysticism including Indian Gnosticism. India was a link which joined Jung and Hesse. Indians live in the world of symbols; influencing on symbols, being influenced by them, although they didn't like to comment on them. Symbols are&#160;favorite subjects for Jung and Hesse and their dominance in Hesse's works provide an appropriate field for a critical analysis from Jung's point of view. An investigation of symbols and archetypical&#160;criticism of literary works, especially&#160;those works&#160;arising from the soul, is a suitable method for&#160;exploring the hidden meaning&#160;in exterior and surface-structural layers. These analyses may reveal common facts in human soul as well. In this article, the researchers attempt to criticize the Hermann Hesse's &#34;Siddhartha&#34;story based on archetypical approach.Archetypes such as&#160;dream, journey, hero, water, river and passing it ,anima, tree and old wiseman are within important symbols which are assembled harmoniously in&#160; this&#160; story. They represent human effort in his individual and self-realization process. These symbols will be examined in details here in this article.
</body>

</article>

