<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <ArticleSet>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2476-6925</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2476-6941</EISSN>
			<Volume>22</Volume>
			<Issue>76</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2014</Year>
				<Month>5</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The Relation of Language and Gender in Shabhaye Tehran</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>7</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>26</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Yadollah</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Bahmani Motlagh</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>y_bahmani43m@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Behzad</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Marvi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>b.marvi907@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>One of the new questions that should be studied and discussed in novel is the relationship between language and gender. In this paper, which is an interdisciplinary research, the researchers relying on sociolinguistic studies, especially Lykaf&#8217;s theory, intend to study the relationship between language and gender in Shabhaye Tehran and discuss the influence of the gender of the author of the novel on its language and the achievement of the novelist in introducing a language appropriate to the gender of the characters.For this purpose, the language of the male and female characters in the novel has been studied on the basis ofcertain variables, such as the use of standard language, imperative sentences, interrupted speeches, collaborative and competitive dialogues, and finally decisiveness and subjugation. The findings show that the language of the characters is influenced by the author's gender. The elements of feminine language have been repeated with a higher frequency and the author in many ways succeeded in creating a language appropriate to the gender of the characters. The deviation of some variables from linguistic standards indicates the feministic tendencies of the author.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>GhazalehAlizadeh, novel, Shabhaye Tehran, linguistics, language, gender.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2050-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2050-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2476-6925</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2476-6941</EISSN>
			<Volume>22</Volume>
			<Issue>76</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2014</Year>
				<Month>5</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>A Psychological Analysis of Vocation and Demand and Their Role in the Initiation of the Hero</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>27</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>50</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Maryam</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Hoseini</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>drhoseini@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Nasrin</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Shakibi Momtaz</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>nasrinshakibi@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>One ofthe important stages in the journey of the heroes in myths, legends or folk and fairy tales, according to Joseph Campbell, is separation. The separation usually happens with a secret call, a vocation or a dream, which includes some archetypal symbols. The summon or requestof a Prophet, a master or a father, or falling in love with an image of a beautiful girl who sometimes happens to be a fairy, along with yearning for wealth or power are oftenthe reasons of this ritualistic journey of the hero in the stories.In this article, besides surveying the different &#8220;callings&#8221;in the stories their psychologicalcauses are discussed.According to Sigmund Freud and his student Bruno Bettelheim, some defects or desires make the hero to start the journey and on passing this stage he has the honor to reach the stage of initiation. Freud and Rank believe this development happens in the first period of the individual&#8217;s life, whereas the unity of the conscious and the unconscious for Jung belongs to the second stage of the hero&#8217;s life, which is also confirmed by Campbell.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Hero, vocation, initiation, Freud, Jung.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2051-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2051-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2476-6925</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2476-6941</EISSN>
			<Volume>22</Volume>
			<Issue>76</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2014</Year>
				<Month>5</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The Madness of Shibli asa Masque</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>51</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>69</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Habibollah</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Abbasi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>abbasiborgan@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Minoudokht</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Hashemi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>masood_043@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Abu BakrShibli (247-334 AH), the eminent and famous mystical Sufi of Bagdad, despite his great status in mysticism and mystical wayfaring is known for his insanity, which made him known as one of the madmen of the prominent centuries of Islamic mysticism. No doubt those who tried to emphasize his greatness could see through the veil of his abnormal and subversive insanity his hidden wisdom and mystical perception. A glance at the personality and character of this Sufi Master and an analysis of the causes of his madness will help us to understand his real but different character. The present article is an attempt to demonstrate howShibliuses insanity as a mask in order to attain true knowledge.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Sufism, Shibli, insanity, wisdom, masqu</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2052-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2052-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2476-6925</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2476-6941</EISSN>
			<Volume>22</Volume>
			<Issue>76</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2014</Year>
				<Month>5</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>A Study of the Ontological Metaphors in the Songs of Southern Khorasan</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>71</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>88</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Jalilollah</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Faroughi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>j_faroughi@birjand.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Nahid</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Hosseini</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>s.n.hosseini1@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>In this article the Ontological Metaphors in the Songs of Southern Khorasan are studied in two parts: human as the central domain and non-human as the central domain. The importance of this article is that most researches done on songs are anthropological researches to introduce the national and local culture and they mainly focus on the musical aspects of these songs. No research so far has been done on the linguistic aspector the aspect considered in this research on these songs. The necessity of this research is due to the fact that with the change of generations and improvement in technologythe songs will no longer be remembered and this part of folklore will fade away sooner or later. Therefore, it is necessary to record and introduce this oral culture to people. The dataused in this article are collected from books about the culture of Southern Khorasan and also from interviewing the people of this region. With a view atLakaff and Johnsen&#8217;s theory about metaphor,that is, metaphor is not a linguistic issue but a mental one, this study aims to show how these mental conceptualizations in the songs can be a reflection of the people&#8217;s experiences.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Song, Southern Khorasan, Ontological Metaphor</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2053-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2053-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2476-6925</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2476-6941</EISSN>
			<Volume>22</Volume>
			<Issue>76</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2014</Year>
				<Month>5</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The Painting of the Astronomical Principles in the Poetry of Anvari</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>89</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>107</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Raziyeh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Fouladi Sepehr</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>raziyesepehr@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Abbas</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Mahyar</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>shahinma@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The influence of heaven and its contents on Iranian poets and artists hasproduced beautiful descriptions of heaven, the sun, the moon, the stars and other constellations in Persian poems which illustrate the power of the Iranian poets in creatingbeautiful images,exotic art and elegance. The present article is an attempt to show the waycertain astronomical imagesare used in Anvari&#8217;spoetry and also the poet&#8217;s innovation in languageand diction is studied. Moreover,by showing the art of Anvari&#8217;s verbal painting and conceptual creativity, the researchersendeavor to explain some of his complicated verses.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Anvari, astronomy, astronomical principles.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2054-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2054-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2476-6925</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2476-6941</EISSN>
			<Volume>22</Volume>
			<Issue>76</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2014</Year>
				<Month>5</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Three Romantic Narratives from Two Territories. &#34;Zal &#38; Roodabeh&#34;, &#34;Bijan &#38; Manijeh&#34;, &#34;Romeo &#38; Juliet&#34; Based On Narratology Theories and Discourse Analysis</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>109</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>136</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Mohammadi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>mohammadiali2@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Nooshin</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Bahramipoor</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>novin5670@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Narratology, which is the one of the achievements of structuralism in literature, helps the critic to analyze various stories at two levels of story and discourse by studying the role of functions and actions .At the story level, the critic can discover similar narratives in terms of episodes, characters and settings by ignoring the historical, cultural and social differences. With this in mind, The Shahnameh Stories &#34;Zal and Rudabeh&#34;, &#34;Bijan and Manijeh&#34; and the &#34;Romeo and Juliet&#34; play by Shakespeare is worthy of comparison and evaluation. All three stories narrate the love of lovers from two feuding families who face many obstacles in their way to :union:. With this level of analysis, we can find out what actions and functions cause the fate of the heroes of these stories. At the discourse level of narrative, Ferdowsi and Shakespeare's status as the narrator can be specified and their orientation and worldview can be sought in text through analyzing the&#160; language in the context. Through discourse analysis and the narrative codes, the underlying beliefs, traditions and culture can be perceived in the aforementioned narratives.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Zal and Roodabeh, Bijan and Manijeh, Shakespeare's play Romeo and Juliet, narrative, discourse</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2055-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2055-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Kharazmi University</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Half-Yearly Persian Language and Literature</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2476-6925</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2476-6941</EISSN>
			<Volume>22</Volume>
			<Issue>76</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2014</Year>
				<Month>5</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Theological Insights &#34;Payndany&#34; (Intercession)  in Persian Poetry</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>137</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>161</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Iffat</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Neghabi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>neghabi_2007@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Payandani (intercession and mediation) is one of the main theological topics in the opening centuries of the Islamic era. Theologians have haddifferent views on this issue, which along with other theological issues, such as determinism and free will, destiny, justice, and the vision of Allah, was widely discussed by Muslim scholars, and fiercely debated by the Mutazilite, the Asharite and later the Shia. The aim of this paper is to discuss in briefthe formation of Payandani and compare the views of the major Islamic schoolson this topic. Moreover, the researcher attempts totrace this subject in Persianpoetry, especially in the poetry of the distinguished Sufi poets of the sixth and seventh centuries, such as Sanai, Attar, Rumi and Saadi.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Payandani (intercession), theology, Mutazilite, Asharite, Shia, Persian poetry</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2056-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/article-1-2056-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
 </ArticleSet>
 
  
  
  
  
 