<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Persian Language and Literature</title>
<title_fa>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبیات فارسی</title_fa>
<short_title>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبيات فارسی</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2476-6925</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2476-6941</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/jpll</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>11</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1395</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2016</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>24</volume>
<number>80</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>مؤلفه‌های نوشتار زنانه در رمان سرخی تو از من </title_fa>
	<title> Elements of Feminine Writing in Sepedeh Shamlu’s Novel Sorkhi-e-to az man (“Your Redness Is Mine”)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:1.0cm;&quot;&gt;نقد فمینیستی با دست&#8204;یابی به زبان و مشخصه&amp;shy;های اصلی، به کاربردِ فرهنگ و ایدئولوژی&amp;shy; خاص زنانه در آثار ادبی نظر دارد. این نوع نقد در آثار داستانی به دو شیوه انجام می&amp;shy;شود: نخست، جلوه&amp;shy;های زن که شخصیت و نقش زن را در داستان پررنگ می&#8204;کند. دوم، نقد زنان که در آن به زنان نویسنده توجه می&amp;shy;شود. رمان &lt;em&gt;سرخی تو از من&lt;/em&gt; اثر سپیده شاملو یکی از رمان&amp;shy;های زن&#8204;محوری است که در سال&amp;shy;های اخیر با دغدغه بررسی دنیای زنان جای خود را در میان رمان&amp;shy;های معاصر فارسی باز کرده است. با توجه به اهمیت این رمان در جریان نوشتار زنانه در ادبیات داستانی پس&#8204;از انقلاب، این جستار به شیوه توصیفی&#8204;ـ&#8204;تحلیلی مبتنی بر مؤلفه&amp;shy;های نقد فمینیستی تلاش کرده است به واکاوی عناصر نوشتار زنانه بپردازد و به این نتیجه دست یافته است که این رمان مدرنیستی به&#8204;شیوه ساختارشکنانه درپی ایجاد تردید در تقابل&amp;shy; دوگانه مرد/ زن است. ازاین&#8204;جهت، شخصیت&amp;shy;های زن داستان موقعیت و هویت زنانه خویش را محصول روابط اجتماعی تحمیلی مردسالار می&amp;shy;دانند که مردان و اقتدار زبان مردانه برایشان آفریده است. زبان نوشتاری متن به سبب انعکاس باورها، جهان&#8204;بینی و عواطف زنانه، برجسته&#8204;کردن&#8204; اندام جنسی، توجه به حس بیزاری و هراس در زنان، هرزه&#8204;نگاری، اعتراض به نگاه خیره مردانه، برگزیدن جمله&#8204;های کوتاه و... تلاشی برای رسیدن به سبک نوشتاری زنانه به شمار می&#8204;آید.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Feministic criticism concerns the function of specific feminine cultural and ideological constituents in literal works. In its approach to narrative this kind of criticism follows two methods. First, the attributes of women and their role and personality in course of the story, and second a critique of women presented which studies female authors. Sorkhi-e-to az man by Sepedeh Shamlu is one the feministic novels, which concerns the world of women in recent years. It has attracted the attention of many readers interested in Persian contemporary novel. Considering the importance of this novel in the process of feministic narrative writing of post-revolutionary Iran, this paper attempts to explore the elements of feministic narrative following an analytic-descriptive method. The findings of this paper show that this modern novel seeks to cast doubt on the differences of men and women through a deconstruction method. The female characters of the novel consider their identity and situation to be molded by imposed patriotic social relations, which are created by men and the dominance of masculine language. By considering the beliefs, worldviews, emotions, privet parts, women&amp;rsquo;s feelings of disgust and fear, lewdness, objection to masculine gaze, choosing short sentences, etc. in the text the researchers attempt to highlight the feminine style of writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>نوشتار زنانه, زیباشناسی فمینیستی, زبان جنسیتی, سرخی تو از من</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Feministic Writing, Feministic Aesthetics, Gender Language, Your Redness Is Mine, Sepedeh Shamlu</keyword>
	<start_page>181</start_page>
	<end_page>205</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-653-36&amp;slc_lang=other&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Seyyed Ali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Ghasemzadeh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سیدعلی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>قاسم زاده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>s.ali.ghasem@gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846002348</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002348</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Fatemeh </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ali Akbari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>فاطمه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>علی اکبری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>hanie.aliakbari@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846002349</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002349</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
