<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Persian Language and Literature</title>
<title_fa>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبیات فارسی</title_fa>
<short_title>دوفصلنامه زبان و ادبيات فارسی</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2476-6925</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2476-6941</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>10.29252/jpll</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>11</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>25</volume>
<number>82</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>خوانش بینامتنی حکایت‌های طاقدیس و مثنوی معنوی برمبنای نظریه ترامتنیت ژنت</title_fa>
	<title>Intertextual Reading of Mathnavi Taghdis and Mathnavi Maanavi Based on the Theory of Genette’s Transtextuality</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;از دانشمند برجسته شیعی، ملااحمد نراقی، با تخلص شعری &amp;laquo;صفایی&amp;raquo;، کتابی معروف به &lt;em&gt;طاقدیس&lt;/em&gt; در دست است که مشابهت&#8204;های زیادی در ظاهر و در بطن کلام با &lt;em&gt;مثنوی&lt;/em&gt; مولوی دارد. این کتاب تحت سیطره معنوی &lt;em&gt;مثنوی&lt;/em&gt; مولانا و نظیر سایه آن است که هم در شیوه سرایش، آغاز و فرجام سخن و هم غایت معنایی، تلاشی شگرف برای همانندسازی آن با &lt;em&gt;مثنوی&lt;/em&gt; مولوی صورت گرفته&#8204;است. در این مقاله، خوانش بینامتنی حکایات مثنوی &lt;em&gt;طاقدیس&lt;/em&gt; و &lt;em&gt;مثنوی معنوی&lt;/em&gt; برمبنای نظریه ترامتنیت ژنت از طریق سه مشخصه بینامتنیت صریح و اعلام&#8204;شده، غیرصریح و پنهان&#8204;شده و ضمنی، همراه با نمونه و تحلیل کاربردی نظریه پیش&#8204;گفته، ارائه می&#8204;شود. یافته&#8204;های این پژوهش چنین نتیجه داده&#8204;است که از بین 65 حکایت مثنوی &lt;em&gt;طاقدیس&lt;/em&gt; برطبق نظریه ترامتنیت ژنت هیچ نشانه روشنی برای ارتباط بینامتنی صریح و اعلام&#8204;شده با &lt;em&gt;مثنوی&lt;/em&gt; معنوی وجود ندارد، بلکه بیشترین ارتباط بینامتنی به بینامتنیت غیرصریح و پنهان مربوط می&#8204;شود. این نتیجه روشن می&#8204;سازد پیرنگ، بن&#8204;مایه و اشخاصِ دست&#8204;کم هجده حکایت مثنوی &lt;em&gt;طاقدیس&lt;/em&gt; تا حد بسیاری از &lt;em&gt;مثنوی معنوی &lt;/em&gt;اخذ شده&#8204;اند. دست آخر، اینکه در سرتاسر حکایات مثنوی &lt;em&gt;طاقدیس&lt;/em&gt; الگوها و نمادهای گوناگونی از نظر فضای داستان، لحن و بیان، شیوه روایت، نام اشخاص و... وجود دارد که یادآور قصه&#8204;ها و حکایات &lt;em&gt;مثنوی معنوی &lt;/em&gt;هستند و براساس طبقه&#8204;بندی ژنت ذیل بینامتنیت ضمنی قرار می&#8204;گیرند.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>One of great Shiite scholar, Mullah Ahmad Naraghi, alias Safaee has left a book called Taghdis which has indisputable similarities to Mathnavi Maanavi in form and meaning. This book is affected by Mathnavi Maanavi written by Rumi and considerable effort has been made to compare it to Mathnavi Maanaviin matter of composition, commencement and completion of speech and also semantic goal. In this paper, an intertextual reading of Mathnavi Taghdis and Mathnavi Maanavi based on Genette&amp;rsquo;s theory of Transtextuality and three explicit and declared and hidden and implicit specifications is presented. Findings of this research show that according to the theory of Genette there is no evidence for the explicit and declared intertextual relation with Mathnavi Maanavi among 65 narratives of Mathnavi Taghdisand the most significant intertextual relation is associated with hidden and undeclared transtextuality. The results further indicate that the plot, theme and characters of at least 18 narratives have been adapted from Mathnavi Taghdis and there are different signs in the narratives of Mathnavi Taghdis in terms of space of story, tone, narration manner, name of character, etc., which associate with the narratives of Mathnavi Maanavi and are included in Genette&amp;rsquo;s classification of the implicit transtextuality.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>نظریه ترامتنیت ژنت, خوانش بینامتنی, مثنوی معنوی, مثنوی طاقدیس</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Mathnavi Taghdis, Mathnavi Maanavi, Genette’s Transtextuality, Intertextual Reading.</keyword>
	<start_page>95</start_page>
	<end_page>112</end_page>
	<web_url>http://jpll.khu.ac.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-11-1288-1&amp;slc_lang=other&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Ramin</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Khosravi Eghbal</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>رامین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>خسروی اقبال</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>R.khosravi57@gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846004294</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004294</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mir Jallal-al-Din </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Kazzazi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>میرجلال‌الدین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کزازی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>M.J.kazzazi@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846004295</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004295</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
