<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2008</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigation the engineering geology of rocks and presentation a criterion to used for construction of rubble mound breakwaters in southern coast of Iran.</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی زمین شناسی مهندسی مصالح سنگی و ارائه معیار جهت کاربرد دراحداث موج شکنهای توده سنگی سواحل جنوبی ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>22</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68110</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ناصر</FirstName>
					<LastName>حافظی مقدس</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نیکودل</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی مهندسی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>تلخابلو</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی مهندسی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>ارومیه­ای</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی مهندسی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>شفیعی فر</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه مهندسی عمران دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2006</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Rock materials are as natural materials which used in variety of coastal protection structures, especially in rubble mound breakwaters. Engineering properties of rocks, such as durability and resistance to degradation factors of the marine environments, are the important properties which the construction material of marine structures should be have. Rock durability is a function of rock properties and condition of environment in which the rock will be used. Regarding the economical importance of constructed coastal ports and facilities in coast lines of south Iran, it is necessary to evaluate the engineering properties of rocky construction materials in such structures in durability and degradation point of view. In this study, by investigating and sampling the used rock material in 27 constructed rubble mound breakwaters along the 1000km south Iran&#039;s coastlines, from Amery Port in western part to Pasabandar Port in 85km east Chabahar, and regarding the observations that collected in field visual investigations and engineering tests of durability examination, the experimental relationship between physical, mechanical and durability parameter of studied rocks have been concluded and consequently criterion to select the suitable rock of three group of rocks Limestone, Igneous rock and Bioclastic sedimentary rock (Lomashell) have been presented individually. </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مصالح سنگی از جمله مصالح طبیعی هستند که در ساختمان انواع سازه­های حفاظتی سواحل بویژه موج شکنهای توده سنگی بکار برده می­شوند. ویژگی­های مهندسی سنگها از جمله دوام و مقاومت آن در برابر عوامل مخرب و مهاجم حاکم بر محیط­های دریایی از مهمترین ویژگی هایی است که مصالح مورد استفاده در ساخت سازه­های دریایی باید از آن برخوردار باشند. دوام تابعی از ویژگی­های سنگ و محیط یا شرایطی است که در آن قرار می­گیرد. ضرورت ارزیابی ویژگی­های مهندسی مصالح سنگی مصرفی در این سازه ها از دیدگاه دوام و زوال پذیری با توجه به اهمیت اقتصادی و بعضا&quot; نظامی بنادر و تسهیلات ساحلی احداث شده در نوار ساحلی جنوب ایران مشخص می­شود. در این مقاله ضمن بررسی مصالح سنگی مصرفی و اخذ بیش از 800 نمونه از این مصالح از حدود 27 موج شکن توده سنگی احداث شده در طول حدود 1000 کیلومتر از سواحل جنوب کشور از بندر عامری تا چابهار و توجه به نتایج حاصل از بررسیهای مشاهده ای و انجام آزمایش­های مهندسی سنجش دوام، روابط تجربی از برقراری ارتباط بین پارامترهای فیزیکی، مقاومتی و دوام دارای سنگها استخراج گردیده و در نهایت معیارهای انتخاب سنگ برای سه گروه سنگ­های آهکی، آذرین و سنگ­های زیستی تخریبی (لوماشل ها) بطور مجزا پیشنهاد شده است . </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ویژگی‌های مهندسی سنگها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">موج شکن توده سنگی – دوام داری- سواحل جنوب ایران</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68110_e5607193f0c34e6e4d449cd06cfc253a.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
