<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 3 و 4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Laboratory investigating of mixed soil-shred tire behavior for application
 in railway track subgrade</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی آزمایشگاهی رفتار خاک مخلوط با خرده‌لاستیک به منظور بکارگیری در بستر خطوط ریلی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>79</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>88</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68336</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرتضی</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسماعیلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران، دانشکده مهندسی راه‌آهن</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نوید</FirstName>
					<LastName>نخعی</LastName>
<Affiliation>2. کارشناسی ارشد دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران، دانشکده مهندسی راه‌آهن</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>One of the suggested applications for use of waste tire is mixing of this material with soils in shredded form for use in retaining walls backfill and embankments. In this regard, comprehensive studies have been accomplished in the field of road engineering but no research works could be found in the railway engineering. As one of the important parameters is railway embankment design is Ev2 (modulus of elasticity in the second loading cycle in PLT) so this research is devoted to investigating of physical and mechanical behavior of soil mixed with shred tire. For his purpose by using the GW-GC as a base material which can be used in railway embankment and subgrade, it is mixed with three different percent 5, 10 and 15 of shred tire with range of aggregation 0.475 to 2.5 centimeters. In continue a series of physical and mechanical tests are performed on base soil and soil mixed with shred tire including compaction, sand equivalent, CBR, direct shear test. In the last stage of the laboratory investigations four cyclic plate loading tests are performed in loading chamber box with dimensions of 2.5×2.5×1.2 m respect to base soil and it mix with 5, 10 and 15 percent shred tire. It should be notified that the soil in all four tests the soil are compacted based on guidelines of ASTM D6270-2006. The plate dimensions in PLT test are considered as 30×30 cm. The obtained results indicate that due to increase in shred tire percentage in the range of 5 to 15 percent, the maximum dry density decreases form 11.86 to 19.36 percent respect to the base soil. On the other hand the CBR value show 34.35 to 67.47 percent and Shear strength parameters such as cohesion the First, increased to 2.1 percent, but then decreased back to levels 27.1 percent and Angle of internal friction value has been reduced by 10.8 to 21.67 percent decrease in the mentioned range. &lt;br /&gt;Focusing on the obtained Ev2 values in PLT tests reveals a decrease of 27.54 to 54.29 percent in this matter. Comparing the achieved Ev2 results with those proposed by UIC R719-1996 code confirms the limitation of shred tire application to 10 percent for use in subgrade layer while its use in embankment is forbidden.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">از جمله کاربردهای پیشنهادی برای بکارگیری لاستیک فرسوده مخلوط کردن این مصالح به فرم خرده شده با مصالح خاکی و بکارگیری در پشت دیوارهای حائل و خاکریزها می‌باشد. در این خصوص مطالعات جامعی در حوزه مهندسی راه صورت گرفته ولیکن در حوزه مهندسی راه‌آهن تحقیق مشخصی انجام نشده است. با توجه به آنکه در بستر و خاکریز خطوط ریلی یکی از پارامترهای کلیدی، مدول ارتجاعی در دومین مرحله بارگذاری(Ev&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) است. لذا در تحقیق حاضر مخلوطی از خاک GW-GC با مقادیر0، 5، 10و 15درصد خرده‌لاستیک با محدوده دانه‌بندی 475/0 تا 5/2 سانتی‌متر تحت یکسری آزمایش‌های استاتیکی فیزیکی و مکانیکی شامل تراکم، هم‌ارز ماسه، ظرفیت باربری کالیفرنیا، برش مستقیم و بارگذاری  صفحه مرحله‌ای قرار گرفته و سپس در اتاقک بارگذاری به ابعاد 1.2×5/2×5/2 متر، ریخته و به تراکم حداکثر آزمایشگاهی مطابق استاندارد ASTM D6270-2006 رسانده شده است. در ادامه با استفاده از جک 30 تن، بارگذاری در سه گام و به صورت مرحله‌ای بر روی صفحه مربعی به ابعاد 30×30 سانتی‌متر صورت گرفته است. نتایج آزمایش بیانگر آن است که در مقایسه با خاک بدون خرده‌لاستیک کاهش وزن مخصوص به میزان 86/11 تا 36/19 درصد، ظرفیت باربری کالیفرنیا به میزان 35/34 تا 47/67 درصد، پارامترهای مقاومت برشی همچون چسبندگی در ابتدا به مقدار 1/2 درصد افزایش یافته ولی پس از آن مجدداً به میزان 1/27 درصد کاهش پیدا کرده و زاویه اصطکاک داخلی به میزان 8/10 تا 62/21 درصد کاهش داشته است و مقدار E&lt;sub&gt;v2&lt;/sub&gt; به میزان 54/27 تا 29/54 درصد کاهش را به دنبال داشته است. با مقایسه نتایج بدست آمده با مقادیر مجاز آیین‌نامه‌ی UIC R719-1996 مشخص گردید که حداکثر تا 10 درصد از خرده‌لاستیک را می‌توان بصورت مخلوط با مصالح بستر مورد استفاده قرار داد لیکن استفاده از آن بعنوان بخشی از بدنه خاکریز توصیه نمی‌شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بستر و خاکریز راه‌آهن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خرده‌لاستیک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">CBR</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">PLT</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Ev2</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آیین‌نامه UIC R719</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68336_b03a64876e99485912857a65d2c6a8c6.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
