<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1399</YEAR>
<VOL>13</VOL>
<NO>1</NO>
<MOSALSAL>1</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>144</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تخمین حفاری ویژه انفجار در تونلهای کوچک مقطع با استفاده از ماشین بردار پشتیبان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Estimation of Specific Drilling in Small Tunnel by Using SVM</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>روش سنتی چالزنی و انفجار با توجه به انعطاف پذیری زیاد آن، مناسب ترین انتخاب به منظور حفاری تونل‌های کوتاه و مقاطع متغیر می باشد. یکی از پارامترهای مهم در طراحی و اجرای الگوهای آتشکاری تونل‌، تعیین حفاری ویژه آن است؛ حفاری ویژه، به متراژ حفاری لازم برای حفر واحد حجم سنگ اطلاق می شود؛ ارائه ی مدل مناسب تخمین حفاری ویژه در تکمیل طراحی الگوی چالزنی و انفجار و در کنترل و مدیریت پروژه حایز اهمیت است. در تحقیق حاضر بر مبنای نتایج ثبت شده از 41 سری داده مربوط به حفر چهار رشته تونل در کشور هند، اقدام به مدل سازی تخمین حفاری ویژه صورت گرفته است؛ برای این منظور از رگرسیون چند متغیره خطی و الگوریتم ماشین بردار پشتیبان مبتنی بر تابع کرنل چندجمله ای ساده، به عنوان ابزارهای کاربردی استفاده شده است. در مدلسازی پیشنهادی، شاخص کیفیت توده سنگ، سرعت امواج طولی در سنگ، سطح مقطع تونل، ماکزیمم طول چال‌ انفجاری و شاخص جفت شدگی چال انفجاری، به عنوان پارامترهای مستقل (ورودی مدل) در نظر گرفته شده‌اند. نتایج مدلسازی عملکرد ماشین بردار پشتیبان، با حداقل خطا را تائید میکند؛ مقادیر ضریب تعیین R2 برای هردو سری داده آموزش و آزمون ماشین بردار پشتیبان، برابر 0/98 بدست آمده است؛ این ضریب برای رگرسیون خطی نیز برابر 0/91 حاصل شده است. علی رغم برتری نسبی ماشین بردار پشتیبان، نتایج روش رگرسیون نیز کارا بوده و رابطه‌ی‌ مبتنی بر آن نیز به عنوان یک گزینه ی دردسترس پیشنهاد می شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Drilling and Blasting method is the controlled use of explosives to break rocks for excavation. It is practiced most often in mining and civil engineering. Basically short tunnels are usually constructed by drilling and blasting method. The value of specific drilling in tunnel blasting processes considerably affects the efficiency of the blasting. Specific drilling affects costs of drilling and blasting, specific charge, fragmentation size, muck pile shape, over break profile shape. In this paper, we present an application of Support Vector Machine (SVM) to the calculation of the specific drilling for small size tunnel blasting. Certain small size tunnel blast tests in four case studies have been used to present the SVM-based model. Among available existing parameters in the literature, some of the most influencing parameters are selected. These models are based on seismic wave velocity (P-wave), Rock Quality Designation (RQD), coupling ratio of explosive charge, maximum depth of blast hole and tunnel area. Evaluation of the numerical measures of the goodness of the statistical fit clearly indicated that corresponding SVM model is more acceptable than multiple linear regression model for estimating specific drilling.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>13</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عارف</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>علیپور</Family>
						<NameE>Aref</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Alipour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه مهندسی معدن دانشگاه صنعتی ارومیه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه مهندسی معدن دانشگاه صنعتی ارومیه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>aref.alipour@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مجتبی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مختاریان اصل</Family>
						<NameE>Mojtaba</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mokhtarian-Asl</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی ارومیه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه صنعتی ارومیه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.mokhtarian@uut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مصطفی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>اسدی زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Mostafa</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Asadizadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه مهندسی معدن، دانشگاه صنعتی همدان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه مهندسی معدن، دانشگاه صنعتی همدان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.asadizadeh@hut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>چالزنی و انفجار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>حفاری ویژه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ماشین بردار پشتیبان و رگرسیون چندمتغیره خطی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Alipour, A. , A. Jafari, and S. M. F.  Hossaini, 2012, Application of ANNs and MVLRA for Estimation of Specific Charge in Small Tunnel, International Journal of Geomechanics, 12 (2):189-192. doi: doi:10.1061/(ASCE)GM.1943-5622.0000125.##Chakraborty, A. K., and J. L. Jethwa, 1994, Tunnel blasting techniques in difficult ground conditions,  Geotechnical &amp; Geological Engineering, 12 (4):219-239. doi: 10.1007/bf00427054.##Chakraborty, A. K., J. L. Jethwa, and B. B. Dhar, 1997, Predicting powder factor in mixed-face condition: development of a correlation based on investigations in a tunnel through basaltic flows,  Engineering Geology, 47 (1):31-41. doi: https://doi.org/10.1016/S0013-7952(96)00117-2.##Chakraborty, A. K., P. Pal Roy, J. L. Jethwa, and R. N. Gupta, 1998, Blast performance in small tunnels - a critical evaluation in underground metal mines, Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology, 13 (3):331-339. doi: https://doi.org/10.1016/S0886-7798(98)00059-5.##Chakraborty, A. K., A. K. Raina, M. Ramulu, P. B. Choudhury, A. Haldar, P. Sahoo, and C. Bandopadhyay, 2004, Development of rational models for tunnel blast prediction based on a parametric study, Geotechnical &amp; Geological Engineering 22 (4):477-496. doi: 10.1023/B:GEGE.0000047042.90200.a8.##Cortes, Corinna, and Vladimir Vapnik. 1995, Support-vector networks,  Machine learning, 20 (3):273-297.##Cristianini, Nello, and John Shawe-Taylor, 2000, An introduction to support vector machines and other kernel-based learning methods, Cambridge university press.##Dibike, Yonas B, Slavco Velickov, Dimitri Solomatine, and Michael B Abbott, 2001, Model induction with support vector machines: introduction and applications,  Journal of Computing in Civil Engineering, 15 (3):208-216.##Du Pont, EI, 1977,Blasters handbook,  Du Pont Tech Serv Section, Explosives Product Div., Wilmington.##Goh, Anthony T. C., and S. H. Goh, 2007, Support vector machines: Their use in geotechnical engineering as illustrated using seismic liquefaction data, Computers and Geotechnics, 34 (5):410-421. doi: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compgeo.2007.06.001.##Hagan, TN, 1992, Safe and cost-efficient drilling and blasting for tunnels, caverns, shafts and raises in India,  Proc. of a Workshop on Blasting Technology for Civil Engineering Projects.##Hall, Mark, Eibe Frank, Geoffrey Holmes, Bernhard Pfahringer, Peter Reutemann, and Ian H Witten, 2009, The WEKA data mining software: an update,  ACM SIGKDD explorations newsletter, 11 (1):10-18.##Jimeno, E Lopez, C Lopez Jimino, and Ayala Carcedo, 1995, Drilling and blasting of rocks, CRC Press.##Jong, Yong-Hun, and Chung-In Lee, 2004, Influence of geological conditions on the powder factor for tunnel blasting,  International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 41:533-538. doi: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijrmms.2004.03.095.##Kahriman, A., Ş G. Özkan, Ö L. Sül, and A. Demirci. 2001, Estimation of the powder factor in bench blasting from the Bond work index,  Mining Technology, 110 (2):114-118. doi: 10.1179/mnt.2001.110.2.114.##Khandelwal, M., P. K. Kankar, and S. P. Harsha. 2010, Evaluation and prediction of blast induced ground vibration using support vector machine, Mining Science and Technology (China), 20 (1):64-70. doi: https://doi.org/10.1016/S1674-5264(09)60162-9.##Langefors, Ulf, and Björn Kihlström, 1978, The modern technique of rock blasting, Wiley.##Latham, J. P., and Ping Lu, 1999, Development of an assessment system for the blastability of rock masses,  International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 36 (1):41-55. doi: https://doi.org/10.1016/S0148-9062(98)00175-2.##Lilly, Peter, 1986, An empirical method of assessing rock mass blastability,  The Aus.##Longjun, Dong, Li Xibing, Xu Ming, and Li Qiyue, 2011, Comparisons of Random Forest and Support Vector Machine for Predicting Blasting Vibration Characteristic Parameters,  Procedia Engineering, 26:1772-1781. doi: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.proeng.2011.11.2366.##Olofsson, Stig O., 1990, Applied explosives technology for construction and mining, Applex.##Person, P-A, Roger Holmberg, and Jaimin Lee, 1995, Rock blasting and explosives engineering, International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences and Geomechanics Abstracts.##Pesaran, Bahram, and M Hashem Pesaran, 2010, Time series econometrics using Microfit 5.0, A user&#039;s manual: Oxford University Press, Inc.##Pokrovskiı̆, Nikolaĭ Mikhaĭlovich, 1980, Driving Horizontal Workings and Tunnels: Underground Structures and Mines, Construction Practices, Mir Publishers.##Shi, Xiu-zhi, Jian Zhou, Bang-biao Wu, Dan Huang, and Wei Wei, 2012, Support vector machines approach to mean particle size of rock fragmentation due to bench blasting prediction,  Transactions of Nonferrous Metals Society of China, 22 (2):432-441. doi: https://doi.org/10.1016/S1003-6326(11)61195-3.##Smola, Alex J, and Bernhard Schölkopf, 2004, A tutorial on support vector regression,  Statistics and computing, 14 (3):199-222.##Üstün, B., W. J. Melssen, and L. M. C. Buydens, 2006, Facilitating the application of Support Vector Regression by using a universal Pearson VII function based kernel,  Chemometrics and Intelligent Laboratory Systems, 81 (1):29-40. doi: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemolab.2005.09.003.##Widzyk-Capehart, E., and P. Lilly, 2002, A Review of General Considerations for Assessing Rock Mass Blastability and Fragmentation,  Fragblast 6 (2):151-168. doi: 10.1076/frag.6.2.151.8667.##Yu, Hwanjo, and Sungchul Kim. 2012, SVM tutorial—classification, regression and ranking, In Handbook of Natural computing, 479-506. Springer.##Zou, Dingxiang, 2017, Mechanisms of Rock Breakage by Blasting, In Theory and Technology of Rock Excavation for Civil Engineering, 205-233. Springer.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارزیابی اثر شکل و موقعیت بارگذاری بر پایداری شیب مسلح شده با ژئوتکستایل با استفاده از مدل سازی سانتریفوژ</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Evaluation of the effect of shape and loading position on the stability of geotextile-reinforced slope using centrifuge modeling</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>خاک مسلح ژئوسنتتیکی به عنوان یکی از روش‌های سریع و اقتصادی پایدارسازی شیروانی ها و احداث دیوارهای حائل شناخته می‌شود. در این تحقیق با استفاده از مدلسازی سانتریفوژ، رفتار دیوارهای خاک مسلح شده با ژئوتکستایل با ارتفاع نسبتا بلند و شیب (5 قایم به 1 افقی) تحت اثر سربار خارجی مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفته است. بدین منظور 3 نمونه شیب خاک مسلح به ارتفاع 35 سانتی متر با مقیاس 1:30 و یک مدل بدون مسلح کننده ساخته و پس از رسیدن به شتاب g30 در دستگاه سانتریفوژ تحت بارگذاری قرار گرفت. نتایج بدست آمده نشان داد، ظرفیت باربری پی های قرار گرفته بر روی کوله های خاک مسلح ارتباط کاملا مستقیمی با شکل پی داشته و برای پی های با عرض یکسان هرچقدر شکل پی از نوع مربع به نوع نواری تغییر یابد (طول پی افزایش یابد) از میزان باربری نهایی آن کاسته خواهد شد. با بررسی المان های مسلح کننده خاک در لایه های مختلف، مشخص گردید که بیشترین میزان خرابی ژئوتکستایل مربوط به حالتی است که تحت بار نواری بوده و کمترین تخریب مربوط به بارگذاری با سطح مقطع مربعی می باشد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Geosynthetic reinforced soil is recognized as one of the fastest and most economical ways to slopes and retaining walls. In this research, using centrifugal modeling, the behavior of soil walls reinforced with relatively high height and slope geotextiles (1H : 5V) under the influence of surcharge was evaluated. For this purpose, 3 models of reinforced soil slope with a height of 35 cm with a scale of 1:30 and an unreinforced soil slope were made and loaded on the centrifuge during acceleration of 30 g. The results showed that the bearing capacity of the foundations on the reinforced soil slope was directly related to the shape of the foundations and for the same widths as the square shape changed to the strip type (increasing the length of the foundations) from the final load will be reduced. Through the investigation of soil reinforcing elements at different depths in terms of failure and elongation, it was revealed that regarding the elongation and failure of geotextiles and the depth of failure for footings with equal widths the maximum value is associated with strip footing and the minimum value is associated with square footing.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>15</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>28</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>بهزاد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>معین</Family>
						<NameE>Behzad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Moeen</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه قم، گروه مهندسی عمران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه قم، گروه مهندسی عمران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>b.moein@stu.qom.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رجبی</Family>
						<NameE>Ali M.</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rajabi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>زمین شناسی مهندسی دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>زمین شناسی مهندسی دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>amrajabi@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خداپرست</Family>
						<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khodaparast</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه مهندسی عمران، دانشگاه قم، قم، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه مهندسی عمران، دانشگاه قم، قم، ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>khodaparast@qom.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شیب خاک مسلح</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ژئوتکستایل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدلسازی سانتریفوژ</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هندسه بارگذاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>جلیل زاده، ز.، حاجی علیلوی بناب، م.، کاتبی، ه.، 2018. بررسی آزمایشگاهی دیوار گود پایدار شده با ترکیب میخ‌کوبی و مهارگذاری. نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران 11(2)، 33-44.##Aklil, P., Wu, W., 2013a. Centrifuge model tests on foundation on geosynthetic reinforced slope [D]. Proceedings of the 18th International Conference on Soil Mechanics and Geotechnical Engineering, Paris 2013##Aklil, P., Wu, W., 2013b. Centrifuge model tests on foundation on geosynthetic reinforced slope [D]. Vienna, Austria: University of Natural Resources and Life Sciences.##Arriaga, F., 2004. Responses of geosynthetic-reinforced structures under working stress and failure conditions, University of Colorado at Boulder.##Bathurst, R., Walters, D., Vlachopoulos, N., Burgess, P., Allen, T., 2000. Full scale testing of geosynthetic reinforced walls, Advances in transportation and geoenvironmental systems using geosynthetics, pp. 201-217.##Bolton, M., Pang, P., 1982. Collapse limit states of reinforced earth retaining walls. Geotechnique 32(4), 349-367.##Bolton, M.D., Choudhury, S.P., Pang, P., 1978. Reinforced earth walls: a centrifugal model study, Proceedings of Symposium on Earth Reinforcement. ASCE: American Society of Civil Engineers, pp. 252-281.##Christopher, B.R., Elias, V., 1997. Mechanically Stabilized Earth Walls and Reinforced Soil Slopes Design and Construction Guidelines, United States. Federal Highway Administration.##Elgamal, A.-W., 1991. Design, construction and operation of 100 g-ton centrifuge at RPI. Centrifuge 91, 27-34.##Fannin, R., Hermann, S., 1990. Performance data for a sloped reinforced soil wall. Canadian Geotechnical Journal 27(5), 676-686.##Goodings, D., Santamarina, J., 1989. Reinforced earth and adjacent soils: centrifuge modeling study. Journal of geotechnical engineering 115(7), 1021-1025.##Guler, E., Cicek, E., Demirkan, M.M., Hamderi, M., 2012. Numerical analysis of reinforced soil walls with granular and cohesive backfills under cyclic loads. Bulletin of Earthquake Engineering 10(3), 793-811.##Güler, E., Goodings, D.J., 1992. Centrifuge models of clay-lime reinforced soil walls, Grouting, Soil Improvement and Geosynthetics. ASCE, pp. 1249-1260.##Guler, E., Ocbe, C., 2003. Centrifuge and full scale models of geotextile reinforced walls and several case studies of segmental retaining walls in Turkey. Emirates J Eng Res 8(1), 15-23.##Haza, E., Gotteland, P., Gourc, J.-P., 2000. Design method for local load on a geosynthetic reinforced soil structure. Geotechnical &amp; Geological Engineering 18(4), 243-267.##JONES, J., 2002. Guide to Reinforced Fill Structure And Slope Design.##Khoshnevivis Ansari, A., 2015. Three dimensional stability of reinforced soil bridge abutments by upper bound limit analysis method, University of Tehran.##Madabhushi, G., 2014. Centrifuge modelling for civil engineers. CRC Press.##Matichard, M., Blivet, J., Garnier, J., Delmas, P., 1988. Etude en grandes deformationes d&#039;ouvrages de soutenement renforces par geotextile, International Conference on Geotechnical Centrifuge Modelling, Jean Francois Corte, ed. Paris pp. 273-281.##Matsuo, O., Yokoyama, K., Saito, Y., 1998. Shaking table tests and analyses of geosynthetic-reinforced soil retaining walls. Geosynthetics International 5(1-2), 97-126.##Mitchell, J., Jaber, M., Shen, C., Hua, Z., 1988. Behavior of reinforced soil walls in centrifuge model tests, In: Proceedings of Centrifuge &#039;88, Paris, France, pp. 259-271.##Moein, B., Bazargan, J., Derakhshani, A., 2015. Evaluate the behavior of geosynthetic reinforced soil walls in centrifuge modeling and large-scale model under surcharge, 10TH INTERNATIONAL CONGRESS ON CIVIL ENGINEERING. University of Tabriz - Faculty of Civil Engineering.##Porbaha, A., Goodings, D., 1994. Geotextile reinforced cohesive slopes on weak foundations, Proceedings of Centrifuge, pp. 623-628.##Rojhani, M., Moradi, M., Galandarzadeh, A., Takada, S., 2012. Centrifuge modeling of buried continuous pipelines subjected to reverse faulting. Canadian Geotechnical Journal 49(6), 659-670.##Sommers, A., Viswanadham, B., 2009. Centrifuge model tests on the behavior of strip footing on geotextile-reinforced slopes. Geotextiles and Geomembranes 27(6), 497-505.##Taylor, R.e., 2003. Geotechnical centrifuge technology. CRC Press.##Thamm, B., Krieger, B., Krieger, J., 1991. Full scale test on a geotextile reinforced retaining structure: Proc 4th International Conference on Geotextiles, Geomembranes and Related Products, The Hague, 28 May–1 June 1990 V1 P3–8. Publ Rotterdam: AA Balkema, 1990, International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences &amp; Geomechanics Abstracts. Pergamon, pp. A384.##TSR101, 2013. General technical specifications of the road 101, Geosynthetics in road construction. Plan and Budget organization, president of the Islamic Republic of Iran, Tehran, IRAN.##Wichter, L., Risseeuw, P., Gay, G., 1986. Large scale test on bearing behaviour of a woven reinforced earth, Proceeding of the 3rd International Conference on Geotextiles, Vienna, Austria, pp. 1073-1078.##Won, M.-S., Kim, Y.-S., 2007. Internal deformation behavior of geosynthetic-reinforced soil walls. Geotextiles and Geomembranes 25(1), 10-22.##Won, M., Kim, Y., Lee, K., 2008. A study on the deformation behavior of laboratory geosynthetics reinforced soil walls, Geosynthetics in Civil and Environmental Engineering. Springer, pp. 291-294.##Wong, K., Broms, B., Chandrasekaran, B., 1994. Failure modes at model tests of a geotextile reinforced wall. Geotextiles and Geomembranes 13(6-7), 475-493.##Wood, D.M., 2003. Geotechnical modelling, 1. CRC Press.##Yoo, C., Kim, S.-B., 2008. Performance of a two-tier geosynthetic reinforced segmental retaining wall under a surcharge load: full-scale load test and 3D finite element analysis. Geotextiles and Geomembranes 26(6), 460-472.##Zohdi Tavassoli, H., 2010. Three dimensional Analysis of reinforced soil slopes with upper bound limit analysis method using laminar blocks, University of Tehran.##Zornberg, J.G., 1994. Performance of geotextile-reinforced soil structures, University of California, Berkeley.##Zornberg, J.G., Arriaga, F., 2003. Strain distribution within geosynthetic-reinforced slopes. Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering 129(1), 32-45.##Zornberg, J.G., Sitar, N., Mitchell, J.K., 1998. Performance of geosynthetic reinforced slopes at failure. Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering 124(8), 670-683.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارزیابی پتانسیل واکنش زایی سنگدانه های مختلف بر پایه مطالعات پتروگرافی و مقایسه آن با آزمون های شیمیایی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The evaluation of reaction potential of different aggregates based on petrographic studies and comparison with chemical tests.</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>چکیده: دوام بتن متأثر از عوامل مختلفی مانند اجزا تشکیل‌دهنده آن، عمل‌آوری، محیط قرارگیری و مدت سرویس‌دهی می‌باشد. واکنش زایی قلیایی ایجادشده درون بتن و فشار انبساطی و ترک‌دار شدن ناشی از واکنش مخرب تشکیل ژل سیلیسی-قلیایی می‌تواند به کوتاه‌تر شدن عمر بتن منجر شود. واکنش زایی قلیایی یک واکنش تدریجی می‌باشد که می‌تواند بین محلول منفذی قلیایی بتن و انواع مختلفی از سنگ‌دانه‌ها روی دهد. شناخت رفتار سنگ‌دانه به‌عنوان اصلی‌ترین تشکیل‌دهنده بتن در شناخت مکانیسم واکنش زایی قلیایی، کاهش پتانسیل واکنش زایی و حتی جلوگیری از آن ضروری می‌باشد. همه سنگ‌دانه‌ها در برابر واکنش‌زایی‌ قلیایی آسیب‌پذیر نمی‌باشند بنابراین شناسایی سنگ‌دانه‌های آسیب‌پذیر و انتخاب سنگ‌دانه‌های با واکنش زایی کمتر در ساخت بتن می‌تواند درنهایت منجر به کم شدن و جلوگیری از خسارت های ناشی از واکنش زایی قلیایی شود. هدف این تحقیق ارزیابی آسیب‌پذیری چهار سنگ‌دانه مورداستفاده در بتن شامل: گرانیت ، ریوداسیت، آهک و دولومیت می‌باشد. این مطالعه تحت شرایط تسریع شده بر اساس استاندارد ASTM C1260 و شرایط دمای اتاق انجام شد. آنالیز نمونه‌ها با استفاده از میکروسکوپ الکترونی همراه با پراش کننده انرژی (SEM/EDX)، میکروسکوپ نوری، آنالیزهای XRD و XRF انجام شد. نتایج این تحقیق نشان داد که سنگ‌دانه‌های ریوداسیتی و آهکی دارای پتانسیل واکنش زایی می‌باشند درحالی‌که سنگ‌دانه‌های دولومیتی و گرانیتی موردمطالعه فاقد واکنش زایی بوده‌اند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Abstract: The durability of concrete is affected by various factors including its ingredients, workmanship, environment, working life, and so on. The alkali reaction within the concrete can shorten its lifespan due to the expansive pressure build up and cracking caused by the deleterious action of alkali reaction by-products. The alkali reaction is a gradual reaction that can happen between the alkaline pore solution of the concrete and various types of aggregates. Understanding the behavior of the aggregate, as the main reactive component, is thus essential in understanding of the reaction mechanism, reducing the alkali reaction potential or even preventing it. Not all aggregates are susceptible to alkali reaction. Therefore, detecting susceptible aggregates and selecting the ones with low levels of reactive materials, can eventually help to minimize and mitigate alkali reaction problems. The aim of this research was to assess the susceptibility of four commonly used aggregates in constructing projects: Granite, Rhyodacite, Limestone and Dolomite. The study was performed under accelerated conditions in accordance with the ASTM test method C1260 and ambient condition (room temperature).specimens were analyzed using Scanning Electron Microscopy (SEM),X-ray Diffraction (XRD) and Light Microscopy. Limestone and Rhyodacite aggregates, were found to be susceptible to expansion reaction.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>29</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>45</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>پژمان</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کاظمی</Family>
						<NameE>Pezhman</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Kazemi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، گروه زمین شناسی مهندسی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، گروه زمین شناسی مهندسی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>p.kazemi@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نیکودل</Family>
						<NameE>mohammadreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>nikudel</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس تهران دانشکده علوم پایه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس تهران دانشکده علوم پایه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>nikudelm@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ماشااله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خامه چیان</Family>
						<NameE>Mashaelah</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>khamechian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، دانشکده علوم، گروهزمین شناسی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، دانشکده علوم، گروهزمین</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>khamechm@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سایمون</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مارتین کلارک</Family>
						<NameE>Simon</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Martin Clark</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه مکواری- دانشکده علوم زمین</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه مکواری- دانشکده علوم زمین</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>simon.clark@mq.edu.au</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>شیما</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>طاهری</Family>
						<NameE>Shima</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Taheri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه مکواری سیدنی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه مکواری سیدنی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>shima.taheri@mq.edu.au</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>پریتوش</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>گیری</Family>
						<NameE>paritosh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>giri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه مکواری، استرالیا</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه مکواری، استرالیا</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>paritosh.giri@mq.edu.au</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>واکنش زایی قلیایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سنگ‌دانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بتن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آزمون‌های تسریع شده</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مطالعات پتروگرافی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Alonso, E., Martınez, L., 2003. The role of environmental sulfur on degradation of ignimbrites of the Cathedral in Morelia, Mexico. Build. Environ. 38, 861–867.##Broekmans, M.A.T.M., 2004. Structural properties of quartz and their potential role for ASR. Mater. Charact. 53, 129–140.##Chatterji, S., Thaulow, N., Jensen, A.D., 1989. Studies of alkali-silica reaction. Part 5. Verification of a newly proposed reaction mechanism. Cem. Concr. Res. 19, 177–183.##Dähn, R., Arakcheeva, A., Schaub, P., Pattison, P., Chapuis, G., Grolimund, D., Wieland, E., Leemann, A., 2016. Application of micro X-ray diffraction to investigate the reaction products formed by the alkali–silica reaction in concrete structures. Cem. Concr. Res. 79, 49–56.##French, W.J., 1991. Concrete petrography: a review. Q. J. Eng. Geol. Hydrogeol. 24, 17–48.##Hobbs, D.W., 1988. Alkali-silica reaction in concrete. Thomas Telford Publishing.##Jen, G., Hay, R., Ostertag, C.P., 2019. Multi-scale evaluation of hybrid fiber restraint of alkali-silica reaction expansion in concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 211, 1117–1126.##Katayama, T., 1992. A critical review of carbonate rock reactions—Is their reactivity useful or harmful. In: Proceeding of the 9th International Alkali–Aggregate Reactions Conference, London, Concrete Society, Slough, Publ. CS-104. pp. 508–518.##Katayama, T., 2004. How to identify carbonate rock reactions in concrete. Mater. Charact. 53, 85–104.##Kurtis, K.E., Monteiro, P.J.M., Brown, J.T., Meyer-Ilse, W., 1998. Imaging of ASR gel by soft X-ray microscopy. Cem. Concr. Res. 28, 411–421.##Lindgård, J., Nixon, P.J., Borchers, I., Schouenborg, B., Wigum, B.J., Haugen, M., Åkesson, U., 2010. The EU “PARTNER” Project—European standard tests to prevent alkali reactions in aggregates: final results and recommendations. Cem. Concr. Res. 40, 611–635.##López-Arce, P., García-Guinea, J., 2005. Weathering traces in ancient bricks from historic buildings. Build. Environ. 40, 929–941.##Lukschová, Š., Přikryl, R., Pertold, Z., 2009. Evaluation of the alkali–silica reactivity potential of sands. Mag. Concr. Res. 61, 645–654.##Malvar, L.J., Cline, G.D., Burke, D.F., Rollings, R., Sherman, T.W., Greene, J.L., 2002. Alkali-silica reaction mitigation: state of the art and recommendations. Mater. J. 99, 480–489.##Min, D., Mingshu, T., 1993. Mechanism of dedolomitization and expansion of dolomitic rocks. Cem. Concr. Res. 23, 1397–1408.##Murlidhar, B.R., Mohamad, E.T., Armaghani, D.J., 2016. Potential alkali silica reactivity of various rock types in an aggregate granite quarry. Measurement 81, 221–231.##Peterson, K., Gress, D., Van Dam, T., Sutter, L., 2006. Crystallized alkali-silica gel in concrete from the late 1890s. Cem. Concr. Res. 36, 1523–1532.##Rajabipour, F., Giannini, E., Dunant, C., Ideker, J.H., Thomas, M.D.A., 2015. Alkali–silica reaction: current understanding of the reaction mechanisms and the knowledge gaps. Cem. Concr. Res. 76, 130–146.##Ramos, V., Fernandes, I., Silva, A.S., Soares, D., Fournier, B., Leal, S., Noronha, F., 2016. Assessment of the potential reactivity of granitic rocks—Petrography and expansion tests. Cem. Concr. Res. 86, 63–77.##RILEM, T.C., 2003. 191-ARP:’Alkali-reactivity and prevention-Assessment, specification and diagnosis of alkali-reactivity’, RILEM Recommended Test Method AAR-1: Detection of potential alkali-reactivity of aggregates-Petrographic method. Mater. Struct. 36, 480–496.##Rivard, P., Fournier, B., Ballivy, G., 2002. The damage rating index method for ASR affected concrete—a critical review of petrographic features of deterioration and evaluation criteria. Cem. Concr. Aggregates 24, 1–11.##Scrivener, K., Snellings, R., Lothenbach, B., 2018. A practical guide to microstructural analysis of cementitious materials. Crc Press.##Shafaatian, S., 2012. Innovative methods to mitigate alkali-silica reaction in concrete materials containing recycled glass aggregates.##Shayan, A., Morris, H., 2001. A comparison of RTA T363 and ASTM C1260 accelerated mortar bar test methods for detecting reactive aggregates. Cem. Concr. Res. 31, 655–663.##Shi, Z., Shi, C., Zhang, J., Wan, S., Zhang, Z., Ou, Z., 2018. Alkali-silica reaction in waterglass-activated slag mortars incorporating fly ash and metakaolin. Cem. Concr. Res. 108, 10–19.##St John, D.A., Poole, A.B., Sims, I., 1998. Concrete petrography: a handbook of investigative techniques.##Standard, A., 2007. Standard Test Method for Potential Alkali Reactivity of Aggregates (Mortar-Bar Method).##Stanton, T.E., 1940. Influence of cement and aggregate on concrete expansion. Eng. News-Record.##Thomas, M., Fournier, B., Folliard, K., Ideker, J., Shehata, M., 2006. Test methods for evaluating preventive measures for controlling expansion due to alkali–silica reaction in concrete. Cem. Concr. Res. 36, 1842–1856.##Turkington, A. V, Martin, E., Viles, H.A., Smith, B.J., 2003. Surface change and decay of sandstone samples exposed to a polluted urban atmosphere over a six-year period: Belfast, Northern Ireland. Build. Environ. 38, 1205–1216.##Wigum, B.J., French, W.J., Howarth, R.J., Hills, C., 1997. Accelerated tests for assessing the potential exhibited by concrete aggregates for alkali-aggregate reaction. Cem. Concr. Compos. 19, 451–476.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارزیابی تاثیر درصد ماسه‌های شکسته استاندارد بر روی ویژگی‌های بتن خودمتراکم</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Assessment of Crushed Sand Effects on the Properties of Self-Compacting Concrete</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>شکستگی سنگدانه‌ها، با توجه به تأثیرات آن در تنش تسلیم، لزجت خمیری و اصطکاک بین اجزای بتن، نقش مهمی در عملکرد بتن به ویژه بتن‌های خودمتراکم دارد، لذا در این تحقیق تاثیر درصد ماسه استاندارد شکسته بر روی خواص بتن خودمتراکم مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. برای این منظور طرح اختلاط‌های مختلفی برای دستیابی به طرح مخلوطی که الزامات حداقلی بتن خودمتراکم را برآورده کند، مورد آزمایش قرار گرفته و در نهایت از پنج طرح با جایگزین کردن مقادیر مختلف ماسه شکسته به جای ماسه طبیعی استفاده شده و آزمایش‌های رئولوژی (جریان اسلامپ، قیف V، حلقه‌ی J و جعبهL)، مشخصات مکانیکی (مقاومت فشاری، مقاومت کششی و مقاومت خمشی) و دوام (چرخه یخبندان و جذب مویینه) انجام شده است.  بر مبنای نتایج بدست آمده، با جایگزینی مقادیر ۲۵، ۵۰ و ۷۵ درصد از ماسه استاندارد طبیعی با ماسه استاندارد شکسته، مقادیر قطر پخش‌شدگی در آزمون جریان اسلامپ که بیانگر تنش تسلیم بتن تازه و معیاری برای ارزیابی قابلیت پرکنندگی بتن خودمتراکم می‌باشد به ترتیب برابر ۷/۰، ۲ و ۱۰ درصد کاهش یافته است. با توجه به نتایج بدست آمده مقاومت فشاری ۹۰ روزه نمونه‌های ساخته شده با ۲۵، ۵۰، ۷۵ درصد ماسه شکسته، به ترتیب برابر ۴، ۱/۷ و ۷/۶ درصد افزایش یافته است. همچنین، جذب موئینه با جایگزینی ماسه شکسته افزایش یافته است که نشان دهنده‌ تغییر و اصلاح دوام و پایایی نمونه‌های بتن خودمتراکم دارای ماسه شکسته می‌باشد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The crushed shape of aggregates, regarding its effect on the yield stress, plastic viscosity and the friction between concrete components play an important role in the performance of ordinary and also self-compacting concrete. In this research, the effect of standard crushed sand on the properties of SCC concrete has been studied. To do so, different mixture designs were tested to achieve a suitable mixture design that meets the minimum rheology and resistance requirements of self-consolidating concrete and as a result, five mixture designs with replacing different values of standard crushed sand with natural sand have been fabricated. Rheology Tests (slump flow, V-funnel, J-ring and L-box), Mechanical Resistance Tests (Compressive, tensile and flexural strength) and Durability Tests (capillary water absorption and freeze–thaw cycling resistance) tests have been assessed. It has been observed that by replacing a proportion of natural standard sand with crushed standard sand, filling ability and possibility of self-consolidating concrete have improved. Regarding the obtained results, the mechanical properties of SCC concrete in the specimens with crushed standard sand increased. Also, capillary water absorption has improved in these specimens which shows durability increase in specimens with crushed standard sand.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>103</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>118</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>جمید رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>امینی</Family>
						<NameE>Hamidreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Amini</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عمران سازه، دانشگاه زنجان، زنجان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عمران سازه، دانشگاه زنجان، زنجان، ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hr.amini@hotmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>بهزاد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سعیدی رضوی</Family>
						<NameE>Behzad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Saeedi Razavi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه پژوهشی ساختمانی و معدنی، پژوهشگاه استاندارد، سازمان ملی استاندارد. کرج. ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه پژوهشی ساختمانی و معدنی، پژوهشگاه استاندارد،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>bsaidi@standard.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>جمال</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>احمدی</Family>
						<NameE>Jamal</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ahmadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشگاه زنجان، زنجان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشگاه زنجان، زنجان، ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>j_ahmadi@znu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بابایی</Family>
						<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Babaei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشگاه زنجان، زنجان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشگاه زنجان، زنجان، ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mbabaei@znu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بتن‌خودمتراکم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ماسه استاندارد شکسته</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رئولوژی بتن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مقاومت مکانیکی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دوام بتن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>نویل، آدام.، (۱۳۷۸). «خواص بتن»، ترجمه هرمز فامیلی، بازنگری چهارم، تهران، ایران، ابوریحان بیرونی.##تدین، م.، مهاجری، پ.، شعبانیان، م.ر.، (۱۳۹۱). «بررسی تاثیر شکل سنگدانه بر مقاومت فشاری بتن»، چهارمین کنفرانس بین­المللی ملی سالیانه بتن ایران، تهران.##حق­طلب، م.، تدین، م.، دریایی، د.، (۱۳۹۰). «تاثیر درصد شکستگی سنگدانه­ها بر روی عیار سیمان مصرفی طبق روش ملی نسبت مخلوط بتن»، سومین کنفرانس بین­المللی ملی سالیانه بتن ایران، تهران،.##کریمی­نیا.، نوری، پ.، (۱۳۸۹). «بررسی اثرات استفاده از درصد­های مختلف ماسه شکسته بر جذب آب بتن­های آماده»، اولین کنفرانس بین المللی بتن های ناتراوا مخازن ذخیره آب شرب، گیلان، ایران،.##شریفی، ج.، نیکودل،  م .ر.، یزدانی، م.، (۱۳۹۲). « تأثیر خصوصیات زمین شناسی مهندسی سنگدانه ها بر مقاومت بتن»، مجله انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران، جلد ششم، شماره ۱ و ۲، صفحه ۶۷ تا ۸۲.##اسماعیلی­، ج.، کسائی، ج.، علی­زاده، غ.، (۱۳۸۹). «بررسی اثر مصالح سنگی ریزدانه شکسته و گردگوشه همجنس بر نفوذپذیری و مقاومت فشاری بتن»، اولین کنفرانس بین­المللی بتن­های ناتراوا مخازن ذخیره آب شرب، گیلان، ایران.##استاندارد ملی ایران با شماره: INSO 302، (۱۳۹۴). با عنوان: سنگدانه های بتن -ویژگی ها - و اصلاحیه مربوطه. ۴۵ص.##استاندارد ملی ایران با شماره: INSO 4980، (۱۳۹6). با عنوان: تعیین چگالی، چگالی نسبی(وزن مخصوص) و جذب آب سنگدانه‌ریز.##استاندارد ملی ایران شماره INSO 4982، (۱۳۹6). با عنوان: تعیین چگالی، چگالی نسبی(وزن مخصوص) و جذب آب سنگدانه درشت.##استاندارد ملی ایران با شماره: INSO 3203-10، (۱۳۹2). با عنوان: آزمون بتن تازه –قسمت۱۰بتن خود متراکم آزمون قیف جعبه L شکل -. ۱۱ص.##استاندارد ملی ایران با شماره: INSO 3203-9، (۱۳۹2). با عنوان: آزمون بتن تازه –قسمت۹-بتن خود متراکم آزمون قیف Vشکل-۱۳۹۲. ۹ص.##استاندارد ملی ایران با شماره: INSO 11270، (۱۳۹3). با عنوان: بتن- اندازه­گیری جریان اسلامپ بتن خود تراکم- روش آزمون- ۱۶ص.##استاندارد ملی ایران با شماره: INSO 11271، (۱۳۹3). با عنوان: بتن- اندازه­گیری قابلیت عبور بتن خود تراکم با استفاده از حلقه J- روش آزمون- ۱۴ص.##استاندارد ملی ایران با شماره: INSO 1608-3 ، (۱۳۹3). با عنوان: بتن سخت شده-قسمت۳- تعیین مقاومت فشاری آزمون ها -روش آزمون - ۲۵ص.##استاندارد ملی ایران با شماره: INSO 6047 ، (۱۳۹4). با عنوان: بتن- تعیین مقاومت کششی دو نیم کردن آزمونه های استوانه ای بتن -روش آزمون-. 15ص.##استاندارد ملی ایران با شماره: INSO 17731 ، (۱۳۹2).با عنوان: مقاومت خمشی بتن با استفاده از تیر ساده با بارگذاری نقطه­ای در مرکز-روش آزمون -۱۲ص.##استاندارد ملی ایران با شماره: ISIRI 12728 ، (۱۳89).با عنوان: جداول بتنی پیش ساخته - ویژگیها و روشهای آزمون و اصلاحیه مرتبط -۸۹ص.##سلیمانی، ا.، ، (۱۳۹5). «تعیین تاثیر درصد شکستگی سنگ­دانه­های استاندارد بر روی دوام بتن»، پایان نامه­ی کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه زنجان، صفحه ۱۰۵ تا ۱۱۱.##P. Kumar Mehta Paulo J. M. Monteiro, October 20, 2001. “Concrete Microstructure, Properties and Materials”, Third Edition, McGraw-Hill.##Poon CS, Shui  ZH, Lam  L, Fok H, and Kou SC, (2004). “ Influence of moisture states of natural and recycled aggregates on the slump and compressive strength of concrete”, Department of Civil and Structural Engineering, PP. 31-36.##Cordeiro CGC, Alvarenga LMSC, and Rocha CAA, (2016). “Rheological and mechanical properties of concrete containing crushed granite fine aggregate”, Construction and Building Materials, No 111: pp. 766–773,.##Sata V, Jaturapitakkul C, and Kiattikomol K, (2007). “Influence of pozzolan from various by-product materials on mechanical properties of high-strength concrete”, Construction and Building Materials, No 21. pp. 1589-1598.##Manguriu GN, Karugu CK, Oyawa WO, Abuodha SO, and Mulu PU. “Partial replacement of natural river sand with crushed sand in concrete production”, Global Engineers &amp; Technologists Review, Volume 3. No 4: pp. 7-14, (2013).##Vijayaraghavan N, and Wayal AS. “Effects of manufactured sand on compressive strength and workability of concrete”. International Journal of Structural and Civil Engineering Research, Volume 2. No 2: pp. 228-232, (2013).##Ilangovana R, Mahendrana N, and Nagamanib K. “Strength and Durability properties of Concrete Containing Qurry Rock Dust as Fine Aggregate”, Journal of Engineering and Applied Sciences, pp. 20-26, (2008).## BS EN 12390-3, 2009. Testing hardened concrete. Compressive strength of test specimens, 22P.##ASTMC496, 2004, Standard Test Method for Splitting Tensile Strength of Cylindrical Concrete Specimens, 5P.##ASTMC293, 2007 Standard Test Method for Flexural Strength of Concrete (Using Simple Beam with Center-Point Loading), 3P.##RILEM, CPC 11.2, “Absorption of water by concrete by capillarity”, RILEM Recommendations for the Testing and Use of Constructions Materials, E &amp; FN SPON, Pages: 34 – 35, 1994.##The European Guidelines for Self-Compacting Concrete, Specification, Production and Use, May 2005.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>استفاده از نخاله ساختمانی برای پایدارسازی دیواره گود عمیق</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Stabilization of a deep excavation using demolition and construction waste materials</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در این تحقیق یک گود که با استفاده از نخاله پایدارسازی شده، مورد مطالعه قرار گرفته است. گود مذکور در جنوب غرب تهران و در غرب رودخانه کن واقع شده است. جنس مصالح تشکیل دهنده دیواره گود شن و ماسه با مقادیر سیلت و رس بوده که از نظر زمین شناسی در گروه آبرفتهای C تهران طبقه‌بندی می‌شود. در تحقیق حاضر با استفاده از آنالیز برگشتی و با توجه به ابعاد گود، پارامترهای مهندسی مصالح دیواره گود، تعیین شد. به منظور تعیین پارامترهای مهندسی نخاله‌های ساختمانی یک خاکریز آزمایشی از نخاله‌های مذکور به طول، عرض و ارتفاع به ترتیب 500 ، 8 و 0.5 متر اجرا و با استفاده از غلطک ویبره، متراکم شد. سپس با انجام آزمایشهای دانسیته در محل، بارگذاری صفحه و کاوشگر دینامیکی بر روی خاکریز، پارامترهای مهندسی نخاله‌های ساختمانی تعیین گردید. با انجام مدل‌سازی با استفاده از نرم‌افزار Geo- Slope تحلیل پایداری گود و خاکریز در شرایط مختلف انجام شد. نتایج نشان می‌دهد که خاکریز مذکور قادر است پایداری دیواره گود را با توجه به مقادیر مجاز ضریب اطمینان تامین کند. با توجه به مشاهدات و برداشت‌های میدانی از آنجا که تنوع و تغییرات در نخاله‌های ساختمانی زیاد است به منظور کنترل کیفیت و حصول اطمینان از مناسب بودن مصالح و روش اجرا، دستورالعمل اجرایی برای استفاده از این مصالح جهت خاکریزی پیشنهاد گردید. نتایج این تحقیق نشان می‌دهد برخلاف رویه معمول، نخاله‌های ساختمانی، یه طور قابل توجهی می‌توانند در کاربردهای مهندسی قابل استفاده باشند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The increasing amount of demolition and construction waste (D&amp;CW) materials has created many problems in large cities. Recycling waste materials helps to protect the environment. D&amp;CW can be used in many projects, especially in road construction, retaining walls, landscaping and pavements. In this research, a project in which, D&amp;CW used as fill materials to stabilize a deep excavation is investigated. The project site is located at the southwest of Tehran and the west of the Kan River. Site soil is basically composed of the C alluvium of Tehran. Strength parameters of soil were determined using recursive stability analysis. By performing an experimental embankment of D&amp;CW (500 m length, 8 m width and 0.5 m height) and compacting it, in-situ density, plate load and dynamic probing tests were implemented and parameters of D&amp;CW were obtained. Then stability analysis of excavation was performed under different conditions using Geo-Slope and the results showed that the D&amp;CW embankment is capable to provide factor of safety. Finally, in order to control the quality of execution, according to the field observations, the guidelines were suggested to use D&amp;CW. The results of this study show that D&amp;CW can be significantly usable in engineering applications.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>47</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>59</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>زهرا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سبزی</Family>
						<NameE>Zahra</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sabzi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه مهندسی عمران، واحد کرج، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه مهندسی عمران، واحد کرج، دانشگاه آزاد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>zahra.sabzi@kiau.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>اکبر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>چشمی</Family>
						<NameE>Akbar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Cheshomi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>تهران - دانشگاه تهران - پردیس علوم دانشکده زمین شناسی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>تهران - دانشگاه تهران - پردیس علوم دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>a.cheshomi@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید رمضان</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رمضان نژاد</Family>
						<NameE>Seyed Ramezan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ramezannejad</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس مهندسین مشاور</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس مهندسین مشاور</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ramezan40@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پایدار‌سازی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>گود عمیق</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خاکریزی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نخاله‌های ساختمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>Geo-Slope</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>بلوری بزاز، جعفر ، زنجانی محمدمهدی ،بررسی مقاومت مصالح حاصل از بازیافت نخاله­های ساختمانی جهت استفاده در لایه های روسازی، پژوهشنامه حمل و نقل، سال هفتم، شماره دوم، تابستان 1389، ص 119 تا 203.##چشمی، اکبر؛ فاخر، علی و خامه چیان ماشاءالله، ۱۳۸7، زمین شناسی آبرفت های تهران و ارزیابی طبقه بندی ریبن جهت مطالعات زمین شناسی مهندسی مجله علوم دانشگاه تهران دوره  34 , شماره  2 (بخش زمین شناسی); از صفحه 1 تا صفحه 15.##عالی محمدی علی، مهدوی عادلی مهدی ، 2016، بررسی روش های بازیافت پسماندهای ساختمانی از نخاله ها، در ساخت و ساز مجدد در شهرستان مسجدسلیمان، اولین کنفرانس ملی رویکردهای نو در مهندسی عمران،معماری و شهرسازی، خرم آباد، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد خرم آباد.##کامران زاد فرناز ، معماریان حسین ، زارع، مهدی 1393، تخمین ضخامت آبرفت در جنوب غرب تهران به وسیله سرعت امواج برشی، شانزدهمین کنفرانس ژئوفیزیک ایران.##ACI Committee Report &quot;Removal and reuse of hardened concrete&quot; (2002) reported by ACI Committee 555, ACI Materials Journal.##Akash, R., Kumar, N. J. and Sudhir, M. (2007) &quot;Use of aggregates from recycled construction and demolition waste in concrete&quot;, Resources Conservation and Recycling&quot;, 50, 71-81, Elsevier Ltd.##Arulrajah, A., Jegatheesan, P., Disfani, M., Bo, M. (2013). Geotechnical and Geo-environmental Properties of Recycled Construction and Demolition Materials in Pavement Subbase Applications. Journal of Materials in Civil Engineering. 25. 1077 - 1088. 10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0000652.##Bastos, L. A. D. C.  Silva, G. C. Mendes, J. C., Peixoto, R. A. F. (2016) “Using iron ore tailings from tailing dams as road material,” Journal of Materials in Civil Engineering, vol. 28, no. 10, p. 04016102.##Chi S. P., Chan, D. (2006) “Feasible use of recycled concrete aggregates and crushed clay brick as unbound road sub-base,” Construction and Building Materials, vol. 20, no. 8, pp. 578– 585.##Cristelo, N. Vieira, C.S. Lopes, M. (2016) “Geotechnical and geoenvironmental assessment of recycled construction and demolition waste in road embankment”, Procedia Eng. 143 pp51–58.##D’Amato Avanzi, G., Galanti, Y., Giannecchini, R., Lo Presti, D., Puccinelli, A. (2013) Estimation of soil properties of shalloe ladslie source areas by dynamic penetration tests: first outcomes from Northern Tuscany (Italy). Bull. Eng. Geol. Environ. 72:609-624.##Ekanayake L. L., Ofori, G. (2004) “Building waste assessment score: design-based tool,” Building and Environment, vol. 39, no. 7, pp. 851–861.##Fakher, A., Cheshomi, A., and Khamechian M. (2007). &quot;The addition of geotechnical properties to a geological classification of coarse grain alluvium in a pediment zone&quot;. Quarterly Journal of Engineering Geology and Hydrogeology. V. 40, pp. 163-174.##Fakhri M. and Farshad, S. K. (2016) “The effect of waste rubber particles and silica fume on the mechanical properties of roller compacted concrete pavement,” Journal of Cleaner Production, vol. 129, pp. 521–530.##Favaretto, P., Hidalgo, G., Sampaio, C., Silva, R. &amp; Lermen, R. (2017). “Characterization and Use of Construction and Demolition Waste from South of Brazil in the Production of Foamed Concrete Blocks”. Applied Sciences, 7, 1090, http://www.mdpi.com/2076-3417/7/10/1090##G´omez-Meijide B., P´erez, I. (2014) “Effects of the use of construction and demolition waste aggregates in cold asphalt mixtures,” Construction and Building Materials, vol. 51, no. 51, pp. 267–277.##G´omez-Meijide, B. P´erez, I., A. R. Pasand´ın, (2016) “Recycled construction and demolition waste in cold asphalt mixtures: evolutionary properties,” Journal of Cleaner Production, vol. 112, pp. 588–598.##Jamshidi, A.  Kurumisawa, K. Nawa, T.  and Igarashi, T. (2016) “Performance of pavements incorporating waste glass: the current state of the art,” Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, vol. 64, pp. 211–236.##Kumutha R., Vijai K., (2010) “Strength of Concrete Incorporating Aggregates Recycled from Demolition Waste”, ARPN Journal of Engineering and Applied Sciences, VOL. 5, NO. 5 pp 64-71.##Lai, J. X. Liu, H. Q. Qiu, J. L., Chen, J. (2016a) “Settlement analysis of saturated tailings dam treated by CFG pile composite foundation,” Advances in Materials Science and Engineering, vol. 2016, Article ID 7383762, 10 pages.##Lai, J. X. Mao, S. Qiu J. L., (2016b) “Investigation progresses and applications of fractional derivative model in geotechnical engineering,” Mathematical Problems in Engineering, vol. 2016, Article ID 9183296, 15 pages.##Lai, J. X. Qiu, J. L.  Fan H. B. (2016c) “Fiber bragg grating sensors-based in-situ monitoring and safety assessment of loess tunnel,” Journal of Sensors, vol. 2016, Article ID 8658290, 10 pages.##Lai, J. X. Fan, H. B. Chen, J. X. Qiu, J., Wang, K. (2015) “Blasting vibration monitoring of undercrossing railway tunnel using wireless sensor network,” International Journal of Distributed Sensor Networks, vol. 2015, Article ID 703980, 7 pages.##Maghool, F. Arulrajah, A. Horpibulsuk, S., Du, Y. J. (2016) “Laboratory evaluation of ladle furnace slag in unbound pavement-base/subbase applications,” Journal of Materials in Civil Engineering, vol. 29, no. 2, p. 04016197.##Melbouci, B. (2009), “Compaction and shearing behaviour study of recycled aggregates,” Construction and Building Materials, vol. 23, no. 8, pp. 2723–2730.##Omotayo, Oluwafemi O., Akingbonmire, Samuel L. and Ikumapayi Catherine M., (2017) “Sustainable Application of Construction and Demolition Waste”: A Review, Annual Conference of the School of Engineering &amp; Engineering Technology (SEET), The Federal University of Technology, Akure, Nigeria.##Park, T. (2003) “Application of construction and building debris as base and subbase materials in rigid pavement,” Journal of Transportation Engineering, vol. 129, no. 5, pp. 558–563.##Pasand´ın A. R., P´erez, I. (2014) “Mechanical properties of hotmix asphalt made with recycled concrete aggregates coated with bitumen emulsion,” Construction and Building Materials, vol. 55, pp. 350–358.##Poon, C. S., Kou, S. C., Lam, L. (2002) &quot;Use of recycled aggregates in molded concrete bricks and blocks&quot;, Construction and Building Materials, 16, pp. 281-289.##Robinson, G. R., Menzie, W. D and Hyun, H. (2000) &quot;Recycling of construction debris as aggregate in the Mid-Atlantic Region, USA&quot;, Resources, Conservation and Recycling, Vol. 42, pp 275-294.##Samanth. S. Prakhar A., (2016) “Study of Strength Properties of Concrete with Construction Debris as Aggregates”, International Journal of Engineering Research in Mechanical and Civil Engineering, (IJERMCE), Vol 1, Issue 5.##Singh H., Singh Y. (2019) Applications of Recycled and Waste Materials in Infrastructure Projects. In: Singh H., Garg P., Kaur I. (eds) Proceedings of the 1st International Conference on Sustainable Waste Management through Design. Lecture Notes in Civil Engineering, vol 21. Springer, Cham##Sobhan K., Krizek, R. J. (1999) “Fatigue behavior of 7berreinforced recycled aggregate base course,” Journal of Materials in Civil Engineering, vol. 11, no. 2, pp. 124–130.##Wang, H. N. You, Z. P.  Mills-Beale, J.  and Hao, P. (2012) “Laboratory evaluation on high temperature viscosity and low temperature stiffness of asphalt binder with high percent scrap tire rubber,” Construction and Building Materials, vol. 26, no. 1, pp. 583– 590.##Wang, H. N. Zhang, R. Chen, Y. You, Z., Fang, J. (2016) “Study on microstructure of rubberized recycled hot mix asphalt based X-ray CT technology,” Construction and Building Materials, vol. 121, pp. 177–184.##Xuan, D. X. Molenaar, A. A. A., Houben, L. J. M. (2015) “Evaluation of cement treatment of reclaimed construction and demolition waste as road bases,” Journal of Cleaner Production, vol. 100, pp. 77–83.##Youyun L., Zhou, H. Linjian S., Hou, H., Dang, L. (2017) “Investigation into the Application of Construction and Demolition Waste in Urban Roads,” Advances in Materials Science and Engineering, vol. 2017, Article ID 9510212, 12 pages, https://doi.org/10.1155/2017/9510212.##Zhu, J. Wu, S. Zhong, J. Wang, D. (2012) “Investigation of asphalt mixture containing demolition waste obtained from earthquake-damaged buildings,” Construction and Building Materials, vol. 29, no. 4, pp. 466–475##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تحلیل الگوی شکست ماسه سنگ‌ها (مطالعه موردی: ماسه سنگ‌های استان مرکزی)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Failure Modes Analysis of Sandstones (Case Study: Markazi Province Sandstones)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف از این پژوهش، تحلیل الگوهای شکست ماسه سنگ‌های دوران مزوزوئیک و سنوزوئیک استان مرکزی با توجه به تغییرات مقاومت فشاری آنها می‌باشد. برای این منظور، الگوهای شکست پنج تیپ مختلف از ماسه سنگ‌های با مقادیر مقاومت فشاری تک‌محوره (UCS) متفاوت حاصل از نتایج آزمایشگاهی و آنالیز عددی مورد بررسی قرار گرفتند. همچنین در این مطالعه اثر الگوهای شکست بر روی مقاومت فشاری تک‌محوره کمی‌سازی گردید. برای انجام این پژوهش نمونه‌های بلوکی از ماسه سنگ‌های سازند‌های مختلف واقع در بخش شمالی استان مرکزی جمع‌آوری و براساس ویژگی‌های بافتی و کانی‌شناسی به پنج تیپ (تیپ‌‌‌‌های 1 تا 5) تقسیم گردیده و تحت آزمایش UCS قرار گرفتند. بررسی الگوهای شکست این ماسه سنگ‌ها در محدوده‌های مختلف مقاومتی نشان داد که در مقادیر پایین مقاومت، الگوی شکست عمدتا از نوع برشی ساده (Simple shear) می‌باشد که با افزایش مقاومت فشاری به نوع کششی چندگانه (Multiple extenssion) تغییر می‌یابد. الگوی غالب شکست برای تیپ‌های 1، 2 و 4 از نوع برشی ساده و برای تیپ‌های 3 و 5 از نوع کششی چندگانه می‌باشد. بررسی الگوهای شکست در بازه‌های مقاومتی مختلف برای کل نمونه‌‌‌‌های ماسه‌سنگی نشان داد که تا مقادیر 140 مگاپاسکال، الگوی شکست غالب از نوع برشی ساده و برای مقادیر بیش از 140 مگاپاسکال، الگوی شکست از نوع کششی چندگانه می‌باشد. همچنین در این مطالعه، الگوهای شکست نمونه‌های آزمایشگاهی با استفاده از نرم‌افزار PFC2D به صورت عددی شبیه‌سازی شدند و ملاحظه گردید که نتایج بدست آمده از مدل‌سازی عددی، همخوانی قابل قبولی با نتایج آزمایشگاهی نشان می‌دهند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The aim of this study is analyzing the failure modes of sandstones related to Markazi Province using compressive strength changes. For this purpose, the fracture modes of five different types of sandstones with different compressive strength values have been studied experimentally and numerically. Also, The effect of failure modes on uniaxial compressive strength was quantified. block samples were collected from different sandstone formations located in northern part of Markazi province. These sandstones were divided into five types based on the textural and mineralogical characteristics. These samples were subjected to uniaxial compressive strength testing. Examination of the fracture modes showed that simple shear mode occurred at low values of strength and it changes to multiple extension mode with increasing the compressive strength. The dominant failure mode for types 1, 2 and 4 is simple shear and for types 3 and 5 is multiple extension. Investigation of failure modes in different strength ranges showed that the dominant failure modes up to 140 and over 140 MPa are simple shear and multiple extension, respectively. Therefore, strength of 140 MPa was considered as the transisson point. Also, in this study, the failure modes of the experimental samples were numerically simulated using PFC2D software. The results of numerical modeling showed a good agreement with the experimental results.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>61</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>86</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهران</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نوری</Family>
						<NameE>mehran</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>nouri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه زمین‌شناسی دانشگاه بوعلی سینا همدان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه زمین‌شناسی دانشگاه بوعلی سینا همدان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>noori_mehran90@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>غلامرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خانلری</Family>
						<NameE>Gholamreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khanlari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه زمین‌شناسی دانشگاه بوعلی سینا همدان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه زمین‌شناسی دانشگاه بوعلی سینا همدان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>khanlari_reza@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>وهاب</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سرفرازی</Family>
						<NameE>Vahab</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sarfarazi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه مهندسی معدن دانشگاه صنعتی همدان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه مهندسی معدن دانشگاه صنعتی همدان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>vahab.sarfarazi@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>بهروز</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رفیعی</Family>
						<NameE>Behrooz</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rafiei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه زمین‌شناسی دانشگاه بوعلی سینا همدان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه زمین‌شناسی دانشگاه بوعلی سینا همدان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>b_rafiei@basu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ماسه سنگ‌ها</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الگوی شکست</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مقاومت فشاری تک‌محوره</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نرم‌افزار PFC2D</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Akesson, U., Hansson, J., Stigh, J., 2004. Characterization of microcracks in the Bohus granite, western Sweden, caused by uniaxial cyclic loading. Eng Geol, 72:131–142.##Anon., 1979. Classification of rocks and soils for engineering geo logical mapping. Part 1—Rock and soil materials. Bulletin of the International Association of Engineering Geology, 19, 364–371.##Bahaaddini, M., Sharrock, G., Hebblewhite, B.K., 2013. Numerical investigation of the effect of joint geometrical parameters on the mechanical properties of a non-persistent jointed rock mass under uniaxial compression. Computers and Geotechnics, 49: 206-25.##Basu., A. 2006. Mechanical characterization of granitic rocks of Hong Kong by improved index testing procedures with reference to weathering induced microstructural changes. PhD thesis, The University of Hong Kong.##Basu, A., Celestino, T.B., Bortolucci, A.A., 2009. Evaluation of rock mechanical behaviours under uniaxial compression for different weathering grades. Rock Mech Rock Eng, 42:73–93.##Basu, A., Mishra, D.A., Roychowdhury, K., 2013. Rock failure modes under uniaxial compression, Brazilian, and point load tests. Bull Eng Geol Environ, 72:457–475.##Bobet, A., 1997. Fracture Coalescence in Rock Materials: Experimental Observations and Numerical Predictions, MIT, Massachusetts, Cambridge, 1997.##Deere, D.U., Miller, R.P., 1966. Engineering classification and index properties for intact rock. Tech. Rep. AFWL-TR- 65-116, Air Force Weapons Lab., Kirtland Air Force Base, 308 pp.##Diederichs, M., 2003. Manuel rocha medal recipient rock fracture and collapse under low confinement conditions. Rock Mech Rock Eng, 36(5):339–381.##Diederichs, M.S., 1999. Instability of hard rockmasses: the role of tensile damage and relaxation. Ph.D Thesis, University of Waterloo, Canada.##Dyskin, A.V., Sahouryeh, R.J.Jewell. 2003. Influence of Shape and Locations of Initial 3-D Cracks on Their Growth in Uniaxial Compression. Engineering Fracture Mechanics, 70:2115-2136.##Folk, E., 1980. Petrography of Sedimentary Rocks, Hemphill Publishing Company, 182p.##Hudyma, N., Avar, B.B., Karakouzian, M., 2004. Compressive strength and failure modes of lithophysae-rich Topopah Spring Tuff specimens and analog models containing cavities. Eng Geol, 73:179–190.##Ingersoll, R.V., Bullard, T.F., Ford, R.L., Grimm, J.P., Pickle, J.D., Sars, S.W., 1984. The effect of grain size on detrital modes: a test of the Gazzi–Dickinson point-counting method. Journal of Sedimentary Petrology 54 (1), 103–116.##ISRM., 1981. The complete ISRM Suggested methods for rock characterization, testing and monitoring, edited by Brown. Pergamon Press, Oxford, UK.##Itasca Consulting Group Inc., 2004/2005. PFC2D/3D (Particle Flow Code in 2/3 Dimensions) User’s Guides, Minneapolis, MN, USA.##Jaeger, J.C., Cook, N.G.W., 1979. Fundamentals of rock mechanics, 3rd edn. Chapman &amp; Hall, London.##Klein, E., Baud, P., Reuschle, T., Wong, T.F., 2001. Mechanical behavior and failure mode of Bensteim sandstone under triaxial compression. Phys Chem Earth (A) 26:21–25.##Maji, V.B., 2011. Understanding failure mode in uniaxial and triaxial compression for a hard brittle rock. In: Proceedings of the 12th ISRM international congress on rock mechanics. CRC Press/ Balkema, Leiden, pp 723–726.##Martin, C., Chandler, N., 1994. The progressive fracture of Lac du Bonnet granite. Int J Rock Mech Min Sci Geomech Abstr Pergamon, 31(6):643–659.##Imani, M., Nejati, H.M., Goshtasbi, K., 2017. Dynamic response and failure mechanism of Brazilian disk specimens at high strain rate. Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering. 100: 261–269.##Mogi, K., 2007. Experimental rock mechanics. Taylor &amp; Francis Group, London.##Park, C.H., Bobet, A., 2010. Crack Initiation, Propagation and Coalescence from Frictional Flaws in Uniaxial Compression. Engineering Fracture Mechanics, 77: 2727-2748.##Potyondy, D.O., 2012. A flat-jointed bonded-particle material for hard rock. In: Proceedings of the 46th US Rock mechanics/geomechanics symposium. American Rock Mechanics Association.##Potyondy, D.O., Cundall, P.A., 2004. A bonded-particle model for rock. Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci, 41(8):1329-64.##Sammis, C.G., Ashby, M.F., 1986. The failure of brittle porous solids under compressive stress state. Acta Metall, 30:511–526.##Santarelli, F.J., Brown, E.T., 1989. Failure of three sedimentary rocks in triaxial and hollow cylinder compression tests. Int J Rock Mech Min Sci Geomech Abstr, 26:401–413.##Schopfer, M.P., Abe, S., Childs, C., Walsh, J.J., 2009. The impact of porosity and crack density on the elasticity, strength and friction of cohesive granular materials: insights from DEM modelling. Int J Rock Mech Min Sci, 46(2):250–261.##Shunchuan, W.u.,  Xueliang, X.u., 2016. A Study of Three Intrinsic Problems of the Classic Discrete Element Method Using Flat-Joint Model.  Rock Mech Rock Eng, 49(5): 1813–1830.##Szwedzicki, T., 2007. A Hypothesis on Modes of Failure of Rock Samples Tested in Uniaxial Compression Rock Mech. Rock Engng, 40(1): 97–104.##Szwedzicki, T., Shamu, W., 1996. Detection of planes of weakness in rock samples using nondestructive testing method. In: Proc., ’96 International Symposium on Mining Science and Technology, China. AA Balkema, Rotterdam, pp 759–763.##Szwedzicki, T., Shamu, W., 1999. The effect of material discontinuities on strength of rock samples. In: Proc., Australasian Institute of Mining and Metallurgy, 304(1): 23–28.##Taoying, l., Ping, C., 1989. Failure Mechanisms Of Brittle Rocks under Uniaxial Compression. Journal of Theoretical and Applied Mechanics, Sofia, 47(3): 59-80.##Xueliang, X.,  Shunchuan, W., Yongtao, G., Miaofei, X., 2016. Effects of Micro-structure and Micro-parameters on Brazilian Tensile Strength Using Flat-Joint Model Rock Mech Rock Eng, 49:3575–3595.##Zhang, Q., Zhu, H., Zhang, L., Ding, X., 2012. Effect of micro-parameters on the Hoek–Brown strength parameter mi for intact rock using particle flow modeling. In: The 46th US rock mechanics geomechanics symposium, ARMA-12-672.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارزیابی تغییرات سرعت موج برشی و چگالی خشک سنگ شیست تحت تأثیر هوازدگی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Evaluating the variations of shear wave velocity and dry density of schist rock under the weathering effect</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>چرخه‌های انجماد-ذوب یک هوازدگی طبیعی جدی برای پروژه‌های مهندسی سنگ و سازه‌های ساخته شده بر روی سنگ‌ها در مناطق کوهستانی می‌باشد. لذا ارزیابی کاهش پارامترهای ژئومکانیکی سنگ در اثر چرخه‌های انجماد-ذوب در این مناطق بسیار حیاتی است. در این تحقیق سرعت موج برشی و چگالی خشک نمونه‌های سنگ شیست بکر و هوازده (چرخه‌های انجماد-ذوب 7، 15، 40 و 75) دیواره معدن انگوران اندازه‌گیری شده است. در هر چرخه هوازدگی 5 نمونه مورد آزمایش قرارگرفته و محاسبات بر مبنای میانگین آن‌ها صورت گرفته است. نتایج نشان می‌دهد که با افزایش تعداد چرخه‌های هوازدگی، مقدار سرعت موج برشی و چگالی خشک نمونه‌ها به صورت نمایی کاهش می‌یابد بطوریکه چرخه‌های اولیه انجماد-ذوب تأثیر کمتری بر روی خواص سنگ داشته است. با برازش نتایج، روابطی تجربی جهت محاسبه سرعت موج برشی و چگالی خشک سنگ شیست به ازای چرخه‌های مختلف انجماد-ذوب در این تحقیق استخراج و پیشنهاد شده است. همچنین، بافت نمونه‌ها در حالت بکر و پس از 75 چرخه انجماد-ذوب به‌وسیله میکروسکوپ الکترونیکی مورد مطالعه قرار گرفت. نتایج مطالعه میکروسکوپی نشان‌دهنده متراکم بودن بافت نمونه‌ها در حالت بکر می‌باشد. همچنین پس از اعمال 75 چرخه انجماد-ذوب، فاصله بین ناپیوستگی‌ها افزایش یافته و ترک‌های جدیدی در بدنه نمونه‌ها ایجاد شده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Freezing-melting cycles are a serious natural weathering for rock engineering projects and constructed structures on the rocks in mountainous regions. So evaluation of the rock geo mechanical parameters reduction due to freezing-thawing cycles is very crucial in these areas. In this study, shear wave velocity and dry density of intact and weathered schist samples (under freezing-thawing cycles of 7, 15, 25, 40 and 75) of the Angouran mine wall were measured. For each weathering cycle, 5 samples have been tested and calculations were made based on their average values. Results showed that by increasing the number of weathering cycles, the shear wave velocity and dry density values of samples are exponentially decreased while the initial cycles of freezing-thawing have the less effect on rock properties. By analyzing the obtained results, an experimental equation was extracted and proposed to calculate shear wave velocity and dry density in schist against the different cycles of freezing-thawing. Also, the texture of samples in intact status and after 75 cycles of freezing-thawing was studied by an electronic microscope. The results of microscopic study indicate that the texture of intact samples is denser than those of the weathered status. Also, after applying 75 cycles of freezing-thawing, the spacing between discontinuities has been increased and new cracks created in the samples body.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>87</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>102</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید زانیار</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سید موسوی</Family>
						<NameE>Seyed Zanyar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Seyed Mousavi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>بخش مهندسی معدن، دانشکده فنی و مهندسی، دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان، کرمان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>بخش مهندسی معدن، دانشکده فنی و مهندسی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>s.zanyar.mousavi@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>توکلی</Family>
						<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Tavakoli</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>بخش مهندسی معدن، دانشکده فنی و مهندسی، دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان، کرمان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>بخش مهندسی معدن، دانشکده فنی و مهندسی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>tavakoli@uk.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>پرویز</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>معارف‌وند</Family>
						<NameE>Parviz</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Moarefvand</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه مکانیک سنگ، دانشکده مهندسی معدن و متالورژی، دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه مکانیک سنگ، دانشکده مهندسی معدن و متالورژی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>parvizz@aut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رضائی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rezaei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه مهندسی معدن، دانشکده مهندسی، دانشگاه کردستان، سنندج، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه مهندسی معدن، دانشکده مهندسی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.rezaei@uok.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>&quot;معدن انگوران&quot;</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>&quot;سنگ شیست&quot;</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>&quot;چگالی خشک&quot;</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>&quot;سرعت موج برشی&quot;</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>&quot;فرآیند انجماد-ذوب&quot;</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>باباخانی، ا.، 1369. گزارش زمین شناسی معدن انگوران، شرکت توسعه معادن روی ایران.##فهیمی­فر، ا.، سروش، ح.، 1380. آزمایش­های مکانیک سنگ، مبانی نظری و استانداردها. جلد اول: آزمون­های آزمایشگاهی، آزمایشگاه فنی و مکانیک خاک، چاپ اول، تهران، 719 ص.##قبادی، م.، بابازاده، ر.، اسفندیاری، م.، 1392. پیش­بینی دوام طولانی مدت ماسه سنگ­های سازند قرمز بالایی در مقابل پدیده ذوب-انجماد و هوازدگی نمک با استفاده از مدل تابع تخریب، مجله انجمن زمین­شناسی مهندسی ایران، جلد هفتم، شماره 3 و 4، 70-57.##قبادی، م.، طالب بیدختی، ع.، نیکودل، م.، 1394، اثر فرآیند ذوب و انجماد بر روی شاخص دوام وارفتگی و مقاومت کششی بریزیلی توف­های سازند کرج، مجله انجمن زمین­شناسی مهندسی ایران، جلد هشتم، شماره 1 و 2، 50-35.##کوشا معدن، 1391. گزارش زمین شناسی معدن انگوران، شرکت مهندسین مشاور کوشا معدن.##Bayram, F., 2012. Predicting mechanical strength loss of natural stones after freeze–thaw in cold regions, Cold Regions Science and Technology, 83: 98-102.##Chen, J., Xu, Z., Yu, Y., Yao, Y., 2014. Experimental characterization of granite damage using nonlinear ultrasonic techniques, NDT &amp; E International, 67: 10-16.##Chen, T.C., Yeung, M.R., Mori, N., 2004. Effect of water saturation on deterioration of welded tuff due to freeze-thaw action, Cold Regions Science and Technology, 38(2-3): 127-136.##Darot, M., Reuschlé, T., 2000. Acoustic wave velocity and permeability evolution during pressure cycles on a thermally cracked granite, International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 37(7): 1019-1026.##Ding, Q.L., Song, S.B., 2016. Experimental investigation of the relationship between the P-wave velocity and the mechanical properties of damaged sandstone, Adv. Mater. Sci. Eng. 10 pages, http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2016/7654234.##Dreesen, R., Dusar, M., 2004. Historical building stones in the province of Limburg (NE Belgium): role of petrography in provenance and durability assessment, Materials Characterization, 53(2-4): 273-287.##Ghobadi, M.H., Babazadeh, R. 2015. Experimental studies on the effects of cyclic freezing–thawing, salt crystallization, and thermal shock on the physical and mechanical characteristics of selected sandstones, Rock Mechanics and Rock Engineering, 48(3): 1001-1016.##Hori, M., Morihiro, H., 1998. Micromechanical analysis on deterioration due to freezing and thawing in porous brittle materials, International Journal of Engineering Science, 36(4): 511-522.##Iñigo, A.C., García-Talegón, J., Vicente-Tavera, S., Martín-González, S., Casado-Marín, S., Vargas-Muñoz, M., Pérez-Rodríguez, J.L., 2013. Colour and ultrasound propagation speed changes by different ageing of freezing/thawing and cooling/heating in granitic materials, Cold Regions Science and Technology, 85: 71-78.##Iñigo, A.C., Vicente, M.A., Rives, V., 2000. Weathering and decay of granitic rocks: its relation to their pore network, Mechanics of Materials, 32(9): 555-560.## ISRM., 1981. Rock characterization testing and monitoring. In: Brown ET (ed) ISRM suggested methods, Pergamon Press, Oxford.##Jamshidi A, Nikudel M.R, Khamehchiyan M., 2016. Evaluation of the durability of Gerdoee travertine after freeze–thaw cycles in fresh water and sodium sulfate solution by decay function models, Engineering Geology, 202: 36–43##Jiang, N., Zhou, C., Luo, X., Lu, S., 2015. Damage characteristics of surrounding rock subjected to VCR mining blasting shock, Shock Vib. Article ID 373021, 8 pages, http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2015/373021.##Karaca, Z., Deliormanli, A.H., Elci, H., Pamukcu, C., 2010. Effect of freeze–thaw process on the abrasion loss value of stones, International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 7(47): 1207-1211.##Karakurt, C., Bayazıt, Y., 2015. Freeze-thaw resistance of normal and high strength concretes produced with fly ash and silica fume, Adv. Mater. Sci. Eng. Article ID 830984, 8 pages, http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2015/830984.##Lai, Y., Zhang, S., Yu, W., 2012. A new structure to control frost boiling and frost heave of embankments in cold regions, Cold Regions Science and Technology, 79: 53-66.##Lee, J. S., Yoon, H.K., 2014. Porosity estimation based on seismic wave velocity at shallow depths, Journal of Applied Geophysics, 105: 185-190.##Lee, J.S., Yoon, H.K., 2015. Theoretical relationship between elastic wave velocity and electrical resistivity, J Appl Geophys. Journal of Applied Geophysics, 116: 51-61.##Luo, X.D., Jiang, N., Fan, X.Y., Mei, N.F., Luo, H., 2015. Effects of freeze–thaw on the determination and application of parameters of slope rock mass in cold regions, Cold Regions Science and Technology, 110: 32–37.##Ma, J., Zhao, G., Dong, L., Chen, G., Zhang, C., 2015. A comparison of mine seismic discriminators based on features of source parameters to waveform characteristics, Shock Vib. Article ID 919143, 10 pages, http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2015/919143.##Malaga-Starzec, K., Åkesson, U., Lindqvist, J.E., Schouenborg, B., 2006. Microscopic and macroscopic characterization of the porosity of marble as a function of temperature and impregnation, Construction and Building Materials, 20(10): 939-947.##Molero, M., Aparicio, S., Al-Assadi, G., Casati, M.J., Hernández, M.G., Anaya, J.J., 2012. Evaluation of freeze–thaw damage in concrete by ultrasonic imaging, NDT &amp; E International, 52: 86-94.##Moreno de Jong van Coevorden, C., Cobos Sánchez, C., Rubio Bretones, A., Fernández Pantoja, M., García, S.G., Gómez Martín, R., 2012. Nondestructive evaluation of the preservation state of stone columns in the Hospital Real of Granada, Nondestructive Testing and Evaluation, 27(4): 335-351.##Ozcelik, Y., Careddu, N., Yilmazkaya, E., 2012. The effects of freeze–thaw cycles on the gloss values of polished stone surfaces, Cold Reg Sci Technol. Cold Regions Science and Technology, 82: 49-55.##Özgan, E., Serin, S., Ertürk, S., Vural, I., 2015. Effects of freezing and thawing cycles on the engineering properties of soils, Soil Mechanics and Foundation Engineering, 52(2): 95-99.##Ruedrich, J., Kirchner, D., Siegesmund, S., 2011. Physical weathering of building stones induced by freeze–thaw action: a laboratory long-term study, Environmental Earth Sciences, 63(7-8): 1573-1586.##Ruedrich, J., Siegesmund, S., 2007. Salt and ice crystallisation in porous sandstones, Environmental Geology, 52(2): 225-249.##Saad, A., Guédon, S., Martineau, F., 2010. Microstructural weathering of sedimentary rocks by freeze–thaw cycles: experimental study of state and transfer parameters, Comptes Rendus Geoscience, 342(3): 197-203.##Shen, S., Xia, C., Huang, J., Li, Y., 2015. Influence of seasonal melt layer depth on the stability of surrounding rock in permafrost regions based on the measurement, Natural Hazards, 75(3): 2545-2557.##Shojaei Baghini, M., Ismail, A., 2015. Freeze-thaw performance and moisture-induced damage resistance of base course stabilized with slow setting bitumen emulsion-Portland cement additives, Adv. Mater. Sci. Eng. Article ID 348691, 10 pages, http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2015/348691.##Siegesmund, S., Ullemeyer, K., Weiss, T., Tschegg, E.K., 2000. Physical weathering of marbles caused by anisotropic thermal expansion, International Journal of Earth Sciences, 89(1): 170-182.##Sousa, L.M., Del Río, L. M.S., Calleja, L., de Argandona, V.G.R., Rey, A.R., 2005. Influence of microfractures and porosity on the physico-mechanical properties and weathering of ornamental granites, Engineering Geology, 77(1-2): 153-168.##Takarli, M., Prince, W., Siddique, R., 2008. Damage in granite under heating/cooling cycles and water freeze–thaw condition, International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 45(7): 1164-1175.##Tan, X., Chen, W., Yang, J., Cao, J., 2011. Laboratory investigations on the mechanical properties degradation of granite under freeze–thaw cycles, Cold Regions Science and Technology, 68(3): 130-138.##Wang, P., Xu, J., Fang, X., Wang, P., Zheng, G., Wen, M., 2017. Ultrasonic time-frequency method to evaluate the deterioration properties of rock suffered from freeze-thaw weathering, Cold Regions Science and Technology, 143, 13-22.##Yavuz, A.B., Topal, T., 2007. Thermal and salt crystallization effects on marble deterioration: examples from Western Anatolia, Turkey, Engineering Geology, 90(1-2): 30-40.##Yavuz, H., Altindag, R., Sarac, S., Ugur, I., Sengun, N., 2006. Estimating the index properties of deteriorated carbonate rocks due to freeze–thaw and thermal shock weathering, International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 43(5): 767-775.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				