<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1390</YEAR>
<VOL>4</VOL>
<NO>0</NO>
<MOSALSAL>0</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>90</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>پیش‌بینی زمین‌لغزش‌های ناشی از زلزله با مدل‌های نیومارک و شبیه‌سازی مونت کارلو</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The prediction of earthquake-induced landslides using 
Newmark model and Monte Carlo simulation approach</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در این مطالعه در یک محدوده‌ی متأثر از زلزله منجیل(1369) که نقشه فهرست زمین­لغزش‌های ناشی از آن تهیه شده است، مطالعات تحلیل خطر زمین­­لغزش‌های ناشی از زلزله، به دو روش تعیینی و احتمالاتی انجام شده است. در روش تعیینی، با بهره­گیری از تحلیل جابه‌جایی نیومارک و در نظرگرفتن پارامترهای مؤثر در وقوع زمین­لغزش به صورت ثابت، نقشه خطر زمین­لغزش‌های ناشی از زلزله در محدوده مورد مطالعه تهیه و با نقشه فهرست مقایسه شده است. در مرحله بعد، به منظور وارد کردن تأثیر عدم قطعیت‌های ناشی از یک روش تعیینی، روشی احتمالاتی با استفاده از توابع توزیع و به کار بردن شبیه­­سازی مونت­کارلو معرفی شده است. در این روش عدم قطعیت‌های ناشی از پارامترهای ژئوتکنیکی و تأثیر اشباع­شدگی شیب، مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. سپس نقشه­ای احتمالاتی براساس پارامتر جابه‌جایی نیومارک به منظور بررسی توزیع مکانی خطر زمین‌لغزش‌های ناشی از زلزله، در منطقه مورد مطالعه تهیه شده و با نقشه حاصل از روش تعیینی مقایسه شده است. این عملیات بر پایه‌ی مجموعه­ای از کدهای نوشته شده در محیط نرم‌افزار MATLAB انجام شده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In this study, considering a limited rectangle affected by Manjil Earthquake, 1990 (Ms=7/7), whose inventory is available, the studies of earthquake-induced landslides risk analysis have been carried out by deterministic and probabilistic approaches. In deterministic approach, using Newmark displacement analysis and considering effective parameters in sliding permanently, a map showing of earthquake-induced landslides hazard in the study area has been prepared and compared with the inventory. In the next stage, to consider the effect of uncertainty caused by deterministic parameters, using probabilistic distribution functions and Monte Carlo simulation a probabilistic approach has been introduced. In this method, uncertainties originated by geotechnical parameters (friction angle and cohesion) and slope saturating effect have been assessed. In this case some codes in MATLAB environment have been written and used.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>17</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی‌محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رجبی</Family>
						<NameE>Ali Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rajabi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانش آموخته دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، استادیارگروه عمران، دانشگاه قم</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانش آموخته دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، استادیارگروه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ماشااله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خامه چیان</Family>
						<NameE>Masha allah</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khamehchian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه تربیت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>khamechm1@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حمیدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مهدوی‌فر</Family>
						<NameE>Hamidreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mahdavifar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار مرکز تحقیقات مهندسی ژئوتکنیک، پژوهشگاه بین‌المللی مهندسی زلزله و زلزله‌شناسی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار مرکز تحقیقات مهندسی ژئوتکنیک، پژوهشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زمین‌لغزش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زلزله</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نیومارک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مونت کارلو</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شبیه‌سازی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>کمک‌پناه، ع. و ن، حافظی مقدس، 1372. پهنه‌بندی خطر زمین‌لغزه در ایران، جلد ششم: شناسایی و به نقشه در آوردن زمین‌لغزه­های مهم تحریک شده در زمین‌لرزه خرداد 1369 منجیل. پژوهشگاه بین‌المللی زلزله‌شناسی و مهندسی زلزله.##مهدوی‌فر، م.ر، 1385. ارزیابی تحلیلی و طراحی سامانه مدیریت ریسک زمین لغزش‌های ناشی از زلزله در کشور. پایان‌نامه دکترا، پژوهشگاه زلزله‌شناسی و مهندسی زلزله.##Arias, A., 1970. A measure of earthquake intensity. In: Hansen R.J. (Ed.), Seismic Design for Nuclear Power Plants. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press, pp. 438–483.  ##Capolongo, D., Refice, A., Mankelow, J., 2002.Evaluating earthquake-triggered landslide hazard at the basin scale through GIS in the upper Selle River Valley. Surveys in Geophysics, 23: 595–625.##Chowdhury, R.N., 1984. Recent developments in landslide studies: probabilistic methods, state-of-the-art-report-session VII (a). Proceedings of the 4th International symposium on Landslides, Toronto, Canada, September 16-21. 1: 209-228.##Jibson, R.W., Harp, E.L., Michael, J.A., 2000. A method for producing digital probabilistic seismic landslide hazard maps. Engineering Geology, 58: 271–289.##Jibson, R.W., 2007. Regression models for estimating coseismic landslide displacement. Engineering Geology, 91: 912-918.##Keefer, D.K., 1984. Landslides caused by earthquakes. Geol. Soc. Am. Bull., 95:406–421.##Keefer, D.K., Wilson, R.C., 1989. Predicting earthquake-induced landslides, with emphasis on arid and semi-arid environments, in:  Sadler, P.M., Morton, D.M. (Eds.), Landslides in a Semi-Arid Environment, Inland Geological Society, 2: 118–149.##Newmark, N.M., 1965. Effects of earthquakes on dams and embankments. Geotechnique,15: 139–159.##Plafker, G., Galloway, J.P., 1989. Lessons learned from the Loma Prieta, California earthquake of October 17, and extracted specific data sets from them. US Geol. Surv. Circ. 1045 1989.##Van Western, C.J., 2000. The modeling of landslide hazards using GIS, Survey in Geophysics, Kulwer Academic Publishers, 21:241-225.##Vose, D., 1996. Quantitative Risk Analysis: A Guide to Monte Carlo Simulation Modeling. Wiley, Chichester, England, 328p.## Wilson, R.C., Keefer, D.K., 1985. Predicting the areal limits of earthquake-induced landsliding. In: Ziony JI, ed. evaluating earthquake hazards in the Los Angeles region-an earth science perspective, US Geological Survey, Prof. Paper 1360, pp. 316–345.##Xie, M.W., Esaki, T., Zhou, G.Y., Mitani, Y., 2003. Three-dimensional stability evaluation of landslides and s sliding process simulation using a new geographic information systems component, Environmental Geology, 43: 503-512.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>نقش مطالعات ژئومورفولوژی کارست در شناخت منشاء غارها</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Importance of karst geomorphology study in recognition genesis of caves</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در این پژوهش شرایط زمین‌شناختی و نحوه گسترش پدیده‌های ژئوموفولوژیکی کارست سطحی و زیر سطحی در محل غارهای علی‌صدر و کتله‌خور بررسی و با انجام مطالعات سنگ‌شناختی و تعیین خصوصیات فیزیکی، عوامل مؤثر در نحوه تشکیل غارهای مذکور با هم مقایسه شده است. منطقه غار علی‌صدر از نظر زمین‌ساختی در محدوده پرتحرک‌ترین پهنه ساختاری ایران یعنی زون سنندج - سیرجان است و منطقه غار کتله‌خور از نظر زمین‌ساختی در بخش شمال‌غرب ایران مرکزی جای گرفته است. غار علی‌صدر درون توده سنگ‌های آهکی متعلق به دوره ژوراسیک شکل گرفته و غار کتله‌خور درون توده سنگ‌های آهکی معادل سازند قم تشکیل شده‌ است.  بر اساس بازدیدهای صحرایی، پدیده‌های ژئومورفولوژی سطحی کارست در منطقه غار علی‌صدر به چند چشمه و غار کوچک محدود می‌شود، ولی در زیر سطح آن کارست کاملاً گسترش یافته است. در منطقه غار کتله‌خور پدیده‌های ژئومورفولوژیک کارست هم در سطح و هم و در زیر سطح کاملاً گسترش یافته است. در محدوده غار علی‌صدر وجود چشمه‌های با آبدهی کم از عدم توسعه آبخوان کارستی حکایت می‌کند، که این پدیده با کمبود آثار کارستی سطحی هم‌خوانی دارد. چشمه‌های موجود در محدوده غار کتله‌خور نسبت به چشمه‌های جاری در اطراف غار علی‌صدر آبدهی بیشتری دارند. این موضوع می‌تواند به توسعه آبخوان­های کارستی دلالت داشته باشد. با توجه به مطالعه‌ی مقاطع نازک سنگ، سنگ­های آهکی محدوده غار علی‌صدر به طور عمده از کلسیت متبلور تشکیل شده و می‌توان آنها را مرمر ضعیف نامگذاری نمود. ولی سنگ­های آهکی  محدوده غار کتله‌خور بایومیکرایت وکستون (Biomicrite wackestone) هستند. نتایج آزمایش‌هایXRF  و XRD نشان می‌دهد که نمونه‌های سنگ مربوط به هر دو غار از لحاظ ترکیب شیمیایی و کانی‌شناختی شباهت زیادی به هم دارند. با توجه به نتایج آزمایش­های تعیین خصوصیات فیزیکی، درصد جذب آب و تخلخل نمونه‌های سنگ منطقه غار کتله‌خور نسبت به نمونه­های سنگ منطقه غار علی‌صدر بیشتر است. بر اساس نتایج این پژوهش غار علی‌صدر درونزاد(Hypogenic)   بوده و حاصل صعود و فعالیت آب‌های هیدروترمال ژرف می‌باشد در حالی که غار کتله‌خور برونزاد(Epigenic)  بوده و حاصل فعالیت آب های نفوذی است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In this study effective factors in generation of Alisadr and Katalekhor caves have been compared with considering of geology condition, surface and subsurface karstic features, petrographical studies and determination of physical properties of rocks in the sites. From geotectonic point of view Alisadr cave is located in the sanandaj – sirjan zone and the katalekhor cave is located in the central Iran zone. Alisadr and Katalekhor caves are generated in Jurassic limestone and Qom formation (Oligo- miocene) limestone, respectively. According to site investigation results, in the Alisadr cave subsurface karst is developed but surface karstic features were rare and limited to afew small springs. In Katalekhor cave area both surface and subsurface karst developed. Spring with small discharge potential in Alisadr area indicated that karstic aquifers are not developed which is in accordance with scarcity of surface karstic features. Spring in the Katalekhor area have high discharge potential in respect to the Alisadr area springs that can be illustrate as a development of karstic aquifers in this regions. According to thin section studies results, Alisadr limestone mainly composed of crystallized calcite and Katalekhor limestone is a biocalcite Wackestone limestone samples tests results indicated that the Katalekhor limestone samples have porosity and water absorption percent higher than the Alisadr limestone. According to this research results, the Alisadr cave is hipogenetic that resulted from hydrothermal solutions activation, while Katalekhor cave is epigenic and generated as a result of penetration water activation.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>19</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>30</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قبادی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Hosein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Gobadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>1- دانشیار گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، همدان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>1- دانشیار گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه بوعلی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>amirghobadi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>یزدان</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محبی حسن­ آبادی</Family>
						<NameE>Yazdan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mohebi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیات علمی دانشگاه پیام نور اسدآباد، همدان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیات علمی دانشگاه پیام نور اسدآباد، همدان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>یاسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عبدی­ لر</Family>
						<NameE>Yasin</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Abdilor</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری زمین‌شناسی مهندسی  دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، همدان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری زمین‌شناسی مهندسی  دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>غار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>علی‌صدر</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کتله‌خور</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کارست</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>محلول‌های هیدروترمال</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ژئومورفولوژی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>قبادی، م.، صالحی، ط.، 1389. نقش ساختارهای تکتونیکی در جهت‌یابی جریان آب چشمه‌های دشت کبودرآهنگ، شمال غرب همدان، بیست‌وهفتمین گردهمایی علوم زمین و دوازدهمین همایش انجمن زمین‌شناختی ایران، ص 1 تا 6 .##اکبرزاده خویی، ح.، 1379. تهیه نقشه توپوگرافی و بررسی ویژگی‌های زمین‌شناسی غار علیصدر همدان، نوزدهمین گردهمایی علوم زمین، سازمان زمین‌شناسی کشور، تهران.##امیری، م.، امیری، ع. م.، 1389.سازوکار تشکیل کارست درونی در دشت‌های شمالی استان همدان، نخستین کنفرانس ملی پژوهش­های کاربردی منابع آب ایران، کرمانشاه،  ص 171 تا 180 .##محمودی سیوند، س.، باقری‌نژاد، ر.، 1389. ریخت‌شناسی و نقشه‌برداری غار کارستی ­کتله‌خور زنجان، نخستین کنفرانس ملی پژوهش­های کاربردی منابع آب ایران، کرمانشاه،  ص 279 تا 285 .##سازمان زمین‌شناختی کشور. نقشه زمین‌شناختی کبودرآهنگ، مقیاس 250000/1##سازمان زمین‌شناختی کشور. نقشه زمین‌شناختی گرماب، مقیاس 100000/1##کریمی، ح.، رئیسی،ع.، زارع، م.، 1379. بررسی هیدروژئولوژیکی و مکانیسم تشکیل غار سریزجان فیروزآباد، چهارمین همایش انجمن زمین‌شناختی ایران، ص 375 تا 378 .##رهنمایی، م.، افراسیابیان، ا.، 1379. زمین‌شناختی و هیدروژئولوژی کارست در غار علی‌صدر همدان، چهارمین همایش انجمن زمین‌شناختی ایران، ص 22 تا 25 .##شیروانی، ر.، کشاورز، ت.، کشفی، م.، یوسفی، ب.، 1383. منشاء و سازوکار تشکیل غار منچ ، سد کارون 4، هشتمین همایش انجمن زمین‌شناختی ایران.##فریمانی،ع.، لشگری‌پور، غ.، 1379. غار پوسه نمونه‌ای از غارهای کارستی کاذب، نوزدهمین گردهمایی علوم زمین.##Ford. D.C.,  Williams,  S., 1989. Karst geomorphology and hydrology, 350p.##Palmer, A.N., 1991.Origin and morphology limestone caves, Geological Society of America Bulletin, 103(1): 1-21.##Kambesis, P., 2006. The importance of cave exploration to scientific research. Journal of Cave and Karst Studies, 69(1): 46–58.##Nozzoli, F., Bevilacqua, S., Cavallari, L., 2008. The genesis of cave rings explained using empirical and experimental data. Journal of Cave and Karst Studies, 71(2): 130–135.##Laumanns, M., Kaufmann, G., Müller, T., (2001). Alisadr con.speleological projects were to survey Ghar Alisadr and to produce an accurate map of the cave passages according to international standards. Ghar Alisadr (Iran, Hamadan Province), Final Report, 74 p.##Palmer, A.N., 2008. Cave exploration as a guide to geologic research in the Appalachians. Journal of Cave and Karst Studies, 19(3): 180–192.##ASTM (1999). Annual Book of ASTM Standards, Vol. 04. 08 &amp; 04, 09, ASTM, USA.## Folk, R. L., 1959. Practical petrographic classification of limestones, American Association of Petroleum Geologists, 43: 1-38.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارزیابی آزمایش تحکیم منفرد جهت برآورد رمبندگی خاک‌های لسی استان گلستان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Evaluation of single oedometer test to measure the collapsibility of soils in Golestan province</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در این پژوهش خواص فیزیکی- مکانیکی خاک‌های لسی نقاط شمالی، میانی و جنوبی استان گلستان مطالعه شده و ضریب رمبندگی لس‌ها تعیین شده است. در ارزیابی میزان رمبندگی خاک‌های لسی استان گلستان، ضریب رمبندگی تعیین شده به روش آزمایش تحکیم منفرد برای نمونه‌های با درصد سیمان کلسیتی بیش از 17 درصد،  کمتر از مقدار ضریب رمبندگی حقیقی است. علت کاهش ضریب رمبندگی، انحلال سریع سیمان کلسیتی خاک‌های لسی و اشباع شدن آب درون ظرف تحکیم از یون کلسیم می‌باشد. اشباع شدن آب درون ظرف تحکیم، مانع تخریب کامل پیوندهای ناشی از سیمان‌شدگی بین ذرات خاک می‌گردد. بنابراین در این تحقیق پیشنهاد شده است، آب درون ظرف تحکیم هر شش ساعت یک بار باید تعویض گردد تا آب تازه جایگزین شده بتواند به طور کامل پیوندهای بین ذرات خاک را از بین ببرد. در این تحقیق، به منظور پرهیز از خطرات ناشی از برآورد غیر واقعی پتانسیل رمبندگی در محل سازه‌های هیدرولیکی، پیشنهاد شده است که برای تعیین  ضریب رمبندگی خاک‌های لسی استان گلستان که حاوی درصد سیمان کلسیتی زیادی هستند، از آزمایش تحکیم منفرد اصلاح شد، استفاده شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>  From an engineering geological point of view, collapsible soils are of the problematic soils. Due to this distribution of loess soils through the Golestan province, physical and mechanical properties of loess soils from north, center and south of Golestan province were studied and collapsible coefficient has been determined. Results show that measured collapsible coefficient by standard single oedometer test method for soil samples with more than17% calcite, are lower than real collapsible coefficient. The decrease of collapsibility coefficient is due to the speed of cement solution and saturation of water within the mold of consolidation container by calcium ions. It should be noted that, rapid saturation of water within the mold of consolidation container, prevents of destruction of cement bounds between the soil particles. Therefore, based on the results of this research, it has suggested to changes the water of mold every 6 hour and the testing time to be continue for 7 days. In this condition, the fresh water can breaks the bounding between the soil grains and leads to fully destroy of soil structure.  Based on the results of this research for loess soils of Golestan province, in order to avoid of hazards of non-real estimation of collapsibility coefficient in hydraulic Structures, a modified single oedometer test has been suggested</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>31</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>40</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مجتبی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حیدری</Family>
						<NameE>Mojtaba</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Heidari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>1- استادیار زمین شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، دانشکده علوم</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>1- استادیار زمین شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه بوعلی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>heidari_enggeol@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>غلامرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خانلری</Family>
						<NameE>Gholamreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khanlari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار زمین شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، دانشکده علوم</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار زمین شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه بوعلی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>khanlari-reza@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سهیل</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>گنجه­ فر</Family>
						<NameE>Soheil</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Gangehfar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>3- استادیار مهندسی برق کنترل، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، دانشکده مهندسی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>3- استادیار مهندسی برق کنترل، دانشگاه بوعلی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>طاهره</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صالحی</Family>
						<NameE>Tahere</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Salehi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد زمین شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، دانشکده علوم،</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد زمین شناسی مهندسی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رمبندگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خاک‌های لسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اصلاح شده</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آزمایش تحکیم منفرد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سیمان کلسیتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>پاشایی، ع. 1376. بررسی ویژگی‌های فیزیکی و شیمیایی و چگونگی خاستگاه رسوب‌های لسی در منطقه گرگان و دشت، فصل‌نامه علمی­ پژوهشی علوم زمین، شماره 24-23، ص 78-67.##پاشایی، ع. 1385. ترکیب کانی‌هاى رسى در مواد لسى وتغییرات آن نسبت به شرایط محیط در استان گلستان، فصل نامه علمی- پژوهشی علوم زمین، شماره60.##جعفری اردکانی، ع .، بیات، ر .، پیروان، ح.،  شریعت جعفری، م. 1388. بررسی وضعیت فرساش و رسوب در نهشته‌های لسی استان گلستان. ششمین کنفرانس زمین‌شناسی مهندسی و محیط زیست ایران، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، ص 1173-1161.##خواجه. م.، غیومیان، ج.، فیض‌نیا، س. 1383. بررسی تغییرات جانبی اندازه ذرات و کانی‌شناسی به منظور تعیین جهت بادهای غالب در تشکیل رسوبات لس استان گلستان. نشریه بیابان، جلد 9، شماره 2، ص 306-293.##عندلیبی، م. ج. 1373. مشخصات، منشاء و طبقه‌بندی لس­های کواترنر پسین در حوضه خزر ایران. رساله کارشناسی ارشد زمین‌شناسی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد تهران شمال، 150 ص.##ASTM D1556, 2000. Standard test method for density and unit weight of soil in place by the sand-con method. Annual Books of ASTM Standards.##ASTM D2216, 2000. Standard test method for laboratory determination of water (moisture) content of soil and rock by mass. Annual Books of ASTM Standards.##ASTM D4318, 2000. Standard test method for liquid limit, plastic limit and plasticity index of soil. Annual Books of ASTM Standards.##ASTM D854, 2000. Standard test methods for specific gravity of soils. Annual Books of ASTM Standards.##Cahney, R.C., 1982. Geotechnical Properties, Behaviour and Performance of Calcareous Soils, ASTM STP777, 3-15.##Clevenger, W.A., 1958. Experiences with loess as a Foundation material. Transactions American Society for Civil Engineers, 123:151-80.##Day, R.W., 2001. Soil Testing Manual. 1st Ed., McGraw- Hill, New York, ISBN: 0-07-136363-7.##Denisov, N.Y., 1963. About the nature of high sensitivity of Quick clays. Osnov. Fudam. Mekh. Grunt, 5: 5-8.##Feda, J., 1966. Structural stability of subsidence loess soils from Praha-Dejvice. Engineering Geology, 1(3): 201-219.##Gibbs, H.J., Bara, J.P., 1962. Predicting surface subsidence from basic soil tests. ASTM Spec. Tech. Pub., 322: 231-246.##Handy, R.L., 1973. Collapsible loess in Iowa. Soil Science American Proceeding, 37: 281-284.##Jennings, J., Knight, K., 1956. Recent experience with the consolidation test as a means of identifying conditions of heaving or collapse of foundation on partially saturated soils. Trans., Sought African Inst. Of Civil Engineering. Aug, pp. 255-256.##Karakouzian, M., A. Pitchford, M. Leonard and B. Johnson, 1996. Measurements of soluble salt content of soils from arid and semi-arid regions. Geotechnical Testing Journal, 19: 364-372.##Knight, K., 1963. The origin and occurrence of collapsing soils. Proceedings of 3rd Regional African Conference on Soil Mechanics and Foundation Engineering(1): 127-130.##Lutenger, A. J., &amp; Halberg, G.R., 1988. Stability of loess. Engineering geology, 25(2-4):  247-261.##Miao, T., 2001. Present status of collapse deformation mechanism of loess. In: Iuo yusheng, wang Guolie, (Eds.), Engineering and Research on Collapsible Loess, China Architecture press, Beijing, pp: 73-82.##Okhravi, R., Amini, A., 2001. Characteristics and provenance of the loess deposits of the Gharatikan watershed in Northeast Iran, Global and Planetary Change, v. 28: 11-22.##Reznik, Y.M., 2005. A Method of Calculations of Soil Structural Pressure Values. Engineering Geology, 78(1-2): 95–104.##Yuan, Z.X., Wang, L.M., 2009. Collapsibility and seismic settlement of loess. Engineering Geology. 105(1-2): 119-123.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارزیابی خصوصیات مهندسی مصالح فیلتر مانع فرسایش در سد خاکی کبودوال استان گلستان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Evaluation the engineering properties of non-erosion filter materials at Kaboodval emabankment dam, Gollestan Province</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>انتخاب مصالح فیلتر مناسب در یک سد خاکی، در محافظت از هسته و پوسته در مقابل فرسایش نقش مؤثری دارد و این مصالح یک زون انتقالی میان آن‌ها و لایه زهکش به وجود می‌آورد. لایه زهکش نیز به نوبه خود وظیفه تخلیه آب از بدنه و شالوده سد و همچنین کاهش فشار آب بین منفذی در ساختگاه سد را دارد. از آنجا که استفاده از زهکش در ساختمان سدهای خاکی از ضروریات طراحی است، به کارگیری لایه فیلتر در ایجاد زون انتقالی نیز ضرورت پیدا می‌کند. در این مقاله خصوصیات مصالح فیلتر مورد استفاده درساختمان سد کبودوال مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. سد کبودوال نوعی سد خاکی همگن با ارتفاع 8/35 متر در جنوب شهرستان علی‌آباد کتول از استان گلستان است. منطقه عموماً دربرگیرنده خاک‌های ریزدانه حاصل از هوازدگی سنگ‌های شیستی می‌باشد. در این بررسی باتوجه به خصوصیات دانه‌بندی، شاخص‌های خمیری و میزان گسترش خاک‌ها، انتخاب منابع قرضه به عنوان فیلتر مانع فرسایش صورت پذیرفت. از آنجا که دانه‌بندی مصالح فیلتر مورد استفاده در محدوده D5 تا D50 مصالح بدنه است و از مرز بحرانی D15 فراتر می‌رود، بنابراین در این تحقیق علاوه بر ارزیابی توان واگرایی مصالح مورد استفاده، خصوصیات فرسایش‌پذیری آن‌ها نیز مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. در این راستا خصوصیات دانه‌بندی و شاخص‌های دانه‌بندی 25 نمونه مطالعه شد. از میان آن‌ها 5 نمونه که از نظر دانه‌بندی ریزتر بودند جهت آزمایش‌های واگرایی و آزمایش فرسایش‌پذیریNEF  انتخاب شدند. از نظر واگرایی نمونه‌ها در رده غیرواگرا طبقه‌بندی شدند و از نظر فرسایش‌پذیری، نمونه K11 با D85=0.017mm  مناسب‌ترین نمونه خاک برای تعیین D15 بحرانی فیلتر انتخاب شد. بر اساس مقایسه نتایج به دست آمده از مجموع آزمایش‌های NEF انجام شده بر روی نمونه خاک‌های منتخب، D15 بحرانی فیلتر برای خاک‌های غیر فرسایشی بین 35/0 تا 50/0 به دست آمد که برای اطمینان بیشتر مبنای طراحی D15  برابر با 45/0 میلی‌متر در نظر گرفته شد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Selection suitable filter material for an embankment dam plays a great role in preventing the core and the shoulder materials from erosion. Drain materials functions as to dewater and to decrease the possible increment of pore water pressure through the dam structure and its location. Since the use of drains is part of dam structure, therefore the application of filter material as a transitional zone is necessary. In this paper the properties of filter material used in Kaboodval dam was investigated. Kaboodval dam is a homogeneous earthfill dam with 35.8 meters height which is located to the south of Ali-abad Katool town of Gollestan Province. The region is mainly consisted of fine grain soil deposits which are produced from the weathering of schistose bedrocks. According to the soil gradation, plastic index and the distribution of the deposits, selection of the suitable materials as non-erosion filter was made. Since the grading of the filter materials has to be within the range of D5 to D50, and to exceeds the critical boundary of D15 limit, therefore the capability of the filter materials regarding the dispersion and erosion was evaluated in this paper. In this regards, the properties of 25 samples were studied. Five of the samples of finer gradation were selected to undergo the dispersive and NEF (non-erosion filter) test. The test results showed that the samples were non dispersive, and according the erosionabilty, sample K11 with D85=0.017mm is most suitable sample for critical filter of D15 gradation. The test results also showed that the D15 of non-erosionable filter were in the range of 0.35 to 0.50 mm. For the case of safety, it is suggested that filter materials of D15 equal to 0.45 mm can be used in this project as non-erosion material.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>41</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>52</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی‌حسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شریفی</Family>
						<NameE>Ali Hasan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sharifi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد زمین‌شناسی مهندسی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد زمین‌شناسی مهندسی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ارومیه ای</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Oromiehei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه تربیت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>uromeiea@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید محمود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فاطمی عقدا</Family>
						<NameE>Seyed Mahmood</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Fatemi Aqda</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه تربیت معلم، تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه تربیت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فیلتر مانع فرسایش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مصالح زهکش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سد کبودوال</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>منابع قرضه ریزدانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سد خاکی همگن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>شرکت راه سازی و عمران ایران. 1385. گزارش مشخصات فنی و اسناد سد کبودوال، جلد دوم، 200 ص.##دانشکده عمران. 1386. گزارش آزمایشات فیلتر مانع فرسایش، پردیس دانشکده‌های فنی، دانشگاه تهران، 91 ص.##مهندسین مشاور پژوهاب. 1382. گزارش نقشه 205، آلبوم نقشه‌های پروژه سد مخزنی کبودوال.##حائری، سید محسن و حسینی، سید عباس. 1379. تعیین معیارهای طراحی فیلتر سدهای خاکی و سنگریز برای هسته مرکزی متشکل از مصالح با دانه‌بندی مخلوط، چهارمین کنفرانس سدسازی ایران، ص 1162- 1154.##Arulandan, K., Perry, E.B., 1983. Erosion relation to filter design criteria in earth dams. Journal of Geotechnical and Environmental Engineering, 109( 5): 682-698.##Corps of Engineers, 1994. Earth and rock-fill dams, general design construction considerations, U.S. Department of the Army, EM-1110-2-2300, July.##Das, B.M., 1994. Principle of Geotechnical Engineering, 3rd edition, PWS Publication Company, Boston, 672 p.##Indraratna, B., Raut, A.K., 2006. Enhanced criterion base soil retention in embankment dam filters. Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering, 132(12): 1621-1627.##Indraratna, B., Vafai, F., Haque, A., 1996. Laboratory and analytical modeling of granular filters. Proceedings 8th Australia New Zealand Conference on Aeromechanics, vol. 1, pp. 80-85.##ICOLD, 1995. Embankment Dams Granular Filter and Drains, Review and Recommendations, International Commission on Large Dams, Bulletin No.100,##Locke, M., Indraratna, B., 2002. Filtration of broadly graded soils-the reduced PSD method. Geotechnique,  52(4): 285-287.##Sherard, J.L., Dunnigan, L.P., 1989. Critical filters for impervious soils. Journal of Geotechnical Engineering, ASCE, 115(7): 927-947.##Silviera, A., 1965. An analysis of the problem of washing through in protective filters. Proceeding 6th International Conference on Soil Mechanics and Foundation Engineering, Montreal, Canada, vol.2, 551-555.   ##Soroush, A., Shourijeh, P.T., 2009. A review of the no erosion filter test. Geotechnical Testing Journal, ASTM, 32(3): 12 pages.##Yasrobi, S., Azad, A., 2004. Assessment of granular filter functioning in embankment dams. Proceedings of EuroSoil 2004 conference, Freiburg, Germany, 8pages. ##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>انتخاب طرح بهینه برای دهانه خروجی تونل‌های انحراف آب سد مشمپای زنجان با استفاده از تحلیل سلسله مراتبی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Locating the portal of Moshampa dam diversion tunnels
 using AHP approac</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>از مسائل مهم و تأثیرگذار در ساخت سازه­های زیرزمینی، انتخاب موقعیت دهانه خروجی تونل است. انتخاب نامناسب موقعیت دهانه خروجی تونل بر اقتصاد و زمان اجرای پروژه تأثیر چشمگیری خواهد داشت. از آنجا که تعیین موقعیت خروجی تونل باید براساس معیارهای مختلف فنی مانند فاکتورهای ایمنی استاتیک و دینامیک، سختی و موقعیت حوضچه آرامش و معیارهای اقتصادی مانند زمان، هزینه نگهداری و هزینه لاینینگ و خاک‌برداری باشد، یکی از مسائل مهم تصمیم‌گیری چند معیاره است که در حل آن می­توان از روش­های مختلفی مانند نزدیکی به نقطه ایده‌آل و تحلیل سلسله مراتبی استفاده کرد. در این مقاله ابتدا معیارهای انتخاب موقعیت خروجی تونل بیان و درجه اهمیت‌شان نسبت به هم بررسی می‌شود. سپس با استفاده از روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی(AHP)، روند مناسبی برای انتخاب بهینه موقعیت خروجی تونل ارائه می­گردد. در پایان، با استفاده از روش پیشنهادی، موقعیت بهینه خروجی تونل انحراف آب سد مشمپا از بین گزینه­های مطرح شده انتخاب می­شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Location of tunnel portal is always one of the vital concerns of geotechnical engineers and inappropriate selection of its position on financial conditions and the time the project will have significant impact. Locating the tunnels portal depends on different technical parameters (such as ecstatic and dynamic safety factor, hardness and position of relaxation pool) and financial factors (time, Maintenance, lining and soil stripping costs). In many situations, there are some proposed sites with different parameters, and it is necessary that the optimum tunnel portal location be selected with the help of multi-criteria decision making methods.In this paper, we have first studied the tunnel portal site selection criteria and their effects on the selection of the location of the tunnel portal. Then, using the Analytic Hierarchy Process (AHP) method, the decision making problem was hierarchically structured at three levels. To check the practicality of the method, the appropriate site for diversion tunnel portal was selected at Moshampa dam, Zanjan province, Iran.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>53</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>62</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سعید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سلطانی محمدی</Family>
						<NameE>Saeed</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Soltani Mohammadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه مهندسی معدن، دانشکده مهندسی، دانشگاه کاشان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه مهندسی معدن، دانشکده مهندسی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>امینی</Family>
						<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Amini</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه مهندسی معدن، دانشکده مهندسی، دانشگاه کاشان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه مهندسی معدن، دانشکده مهندسی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شفیعی علویجه</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Shafiee Alavijeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد استخراج معدن، دانشکده مهندسی، دانشگاه کاشان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد استخراج معدن، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فریدن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بهرامی سامانی</Family>
						<NameE>Fereidoon</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Bhrami Samani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>شرکت مهندسین مشاور تماوان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>شرکت مهندسین مشاور تماوان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مشمپا</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زنجان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تونل‌ انحراف آب</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تحلیل سلسله مراتبی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>امینی، م. 1389. تحلیل پایداری، پایدارسازی و ابزاربندی شیروانی مشرف به خروجی تونل­های انحراف آب سد مشمپای زنجان.##عطایی، م. 1389. تصمیم‌گیری چند معیاره. دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود.##قدسی‌پور، ح. 1382، مباحثی در تصمیم‌گیری چند معیاره برنامه‌ریزی چند هدفه، مرکز نشر دانشگاه صنعتی امیر کبیر.##Expert Choice. 2000. Quick start guide and tutorials: User’s manual, PA: Expert Choice Inc., Pittsburgh.##Hosseinali, F., Alesheikh, A.A., 2008. Weighting spatial information in GIS for copper mining exploration, American Journal of Applied Sciences, 5(9): 1187-1198.##Lee, A.H.I., Chen, W.C., Chang, C.J., 2008.  A fuzzy AHP and BSC approach for evaluating performance of IT department in the manufacturing industry in Taiwan,  Expert Systems with Applications, 34(1):96-107.##Mahmoodzadeh, S., Shahrabi, J., Pariazar M., and Zaeri, M. S., 2007.  Project selection by using fuzzyAHP and TOPSIS technique, International Journal of Human and Social Sciences, 2(7): 393-402.##Nakamura, F., Ohtsu, H., 2006. Development of a tunnel management system for existing railroad tunnel, In Tunneling and Underground Space Technology,  21(3, 4): 312 – 313.##Oraee, K,. Hosseini, N,. Gholinejad, M., 2009. A new approach for determination of tunnel supporting system using analytical hierarchy process (AHP), Proceeding of Coal Operators Conference, pp. 78-89.##Oraee, K,. Bakhtavar E., 2010. Selection of tunnel support system by using multi criteria decision-making tools, The 29th International Conference on Ground Control in Mining, Virginia, U.S.A, pp. 1-9.##Padma, T., Balasubramanie, P., 2009. Knowledge based decision support system to assist work-related risk analysis in musculoskeletal disorder, In Knowledge-Based Systems,  2291): 72 – 78.##Panou, K.D., Sofianos, A.I., 2002. Fuzzy multicriteria evaluation system for the assessment of  Tunnels visa – vis Surface roads: theoretical aspects – part I, In Tunneling and Underground Space Technology, 17(2): 195 – 207.##Saaty, T.L., 1980. The Analytic Hierarchy Process: Planning, Priority Setting, Resource Allocation, 1st Ed., McGraw-Hill, New York.##Saaty TL., 1990. How to mark a decision: the analytic hierarchy process, European Journal of Operational Research,  48: 9–26.##Saaty, T.L., 2000. Fundamentals of Decision Making and Priority Theory, 2nd Ed., PA: RWS Pub., Pittsburgh.##Taheri, A,. Mansoori Borujeni, H. A., 2006. Tunnelling machine selection for tunnel excavation in rock, using the AHP method: case study: line 1 of the Esfahan metro project, International Conference &amp; Exhibition on Tunnelling and Trenchless Technology.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی ویژگی‌های هیدرولیکی آبخوان واقع در مسیر قطعه شرقی- غربی خط هفت تونل مترو تهران در زمان انجام حفاری مکانیزه با نگرشی بر میزان آب ورودی به تونل</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Study of hydraulic characteristics of aquifer in the path of East-West section of the tunnel line-7 of Tehran subway during mechanized excavation from the aspect of groundwater inflow into tunnel</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>تأثیر وجود آب­های زیرزمینی بر روی حفاری تونل از جهت تأثیر بار هیدرولیکی آب زیرزمینی بر روی شرایط حفر تونل و در نتیجه میزان آب ورودی به تونل، مسئله بسیار مهم در حفاری مکانیزه در محیط­های شهری است. نفوذ آب به تونل می­تواند منجر به وارد شدن خساراتی به تجهیزات ساخت تونل، پرسنل و روند اجرای کار شود. لذا جهت طراحی سیستم ایمنی تونل و پیش‌بینی تمهیدات ایمنی قبل از شروع عملیات حفاری، بررسی وضعیت هیدروژئولوژی مسیر تونل ضروری است. آگاهی از میزان نشت آب به تونل می­تواند در انتخاب روش حفاری مناسب و همچنین شرایط طراحی و نوع پمپ مورد نیاز، برای خروج آب از تونل مؤثر باشد.  در این مقاله با استفاده از روش مدل­سازی عددی تفاضل محدود (با استفاده از نرم‌افزار GMS7.0 و کد MODFLOW) و روش­های تحلیلی میزان دبی آب زیرزمینی به قطعه شرقی - غربی خط هفت تونل متروی تهران تخمین زده شده است. داده­های مورد استفاده شامل تراز آب زیرزمینی در سال آبی 88-87، میزان پمپاژ چاه­ها، آب برگشتی چاه­های فاضلاب، بارش و تغییرات میزان هدایت هیدرولیکی در طول مسیر تونل می­باشد. میانگین مقدار دبی بدست آمده برای کل 12 کیلومتر قطعه شرقی- غربی خط هفت متروی تهران در روش تحلیلی 345 لیتر بر ثانیه و در روش مدل­سازی عددی 295 لیتر بر ثانیه است. در پایان، نتایج مدل­سازی تفاضل محدود و روش­های تحلیلی برای زون­های مختلف مسیر تونل با هم مقایسه شده است. این مقایسه نشان می­دهد که میزان نفوذ به دست آمده از روابط تحلیلی به نتایج مدل نزدیک است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Remarkable set of features havecaused of widespread applications of artificial ligthweight aggregates. According to their application in various industries, the mechanical properties of these aggregates are important. Due to the absence of bedrock, determination mechanical properties of artificial ligthweight aggregate have special complexity.Ligth expanded clay aggregate (LECA) is the only industrialized ligthweigth aggregates that use in structural concrete in our country at now, which are produced with different density. In this research, to determination the diameter effect on the specific gravity, water absorption, resistance to abrasion, impact and pressure, various tests have been done on four size of structural Leca. Since there is not a standard procedure to determine the elastic modulus of ligthweigth aggregate, the combination of experimental methods and theory of composite material is used to estimate this parameter. With the combination of ligthweigth aggregate and cement-sand mortar (matrix), cylindrical composite specimens with 30% and 40% volume fractions of aggregates were cast and their elastic parameters of them are determined. Then with differential method and using elastic parameters of composite specimens and matrix, elastic modulus of ligthweigth aggregates is calculated. Test results indicate a significant effect of the grain diameter on mechanical propertiesof aggregates which produced with the same condition.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>63</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>74</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حمیدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ناصری</Family>
						<NameE>Hamidreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nassery</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>1. عضو هیئت علمی دانشکده علوم زمین دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>1. عضو هیئت علمی دانشکده علوم زمین دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>h-nassery@sbu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سهراب</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>زارع</Family>
						<NameE>Sohrab</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Zare</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد هیدروژئولوژی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد هیدروژئولوژی، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>جعفر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حسن‌پور</Family>
						<NameE>Jafar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hasanpour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری زمین شناسی مهندسی، مدیر پروژه­های زیرزمینی، مهندسی مشاور ساحل</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری زمین شناسی مهندسی، مدیر پروژه­های</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مسعود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مرسلی</Family>
						<NameE>Masood</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Morssali</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری هیدروژئولوژی، دانشکده علوم، دانشگاه تربیت معلم، کرج</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری هیدروژئولوژی، دانشکده علوم،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدل‌سازی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تفاضل محدود</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کد MODFLOW</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>روش‌های تحلیلی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تونل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نشت آب زیرزمینی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>آقانباتی، س. ع. 1385. زمین­شناسی ایران، سازمان زمین­شناسی و اکتشافات معدنی کشور.##ناصری، ح. ر. اسدیان، ف.، 1381. شبیه سازی هیدرولیک قنات. مجله علوم زمین، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، شماره‌های 8 و 9.##شرکت مهندسین مشاور ساحل. 1388. مطالعات زمین‌شناسی مهندسی و ژئوتکنیک، مسیر مترو خط هفت تهران.##Bonomi, T., Bellini, R., 2003. The tunnel impact on the groundwater level in an urban area: A modeling approach. J. of Material and Geoenvironment, 50(1): 45-48.##Brigham Young University, 2010. GMS7.0 Tutorials. Environmental Modeling Research Laboratory.##Dunning, C.P., Feinstein, D.T., Hunt, R.J., Krohelski, J.T., 2004. Simulation of ground-water flow, surface-water flow, and a deep sewer tunnel system in the Menomonee valley, Milwaukee, Wisconsin”, Scientific Investigations Report, U.S. Department of the Interior, U.S. Geological Survey, No. 5031.##Eltani, M, 1999. Circular tunnel in a semi-infinite aquifer, Tunneling and Underground Space Technology, 18: 49-55.##Yang, F.R.,  Lee, C.H.,  Kung, W.J., Yeh, H.F., 2009. The impact of tunneling construction on the hydrogeological environment of Tseng-Wen Reservoir Transbasin Diversion Project” in Taiwan, Engineering Geology, 101: 39-58.##Freeze, R.A., Cherry, J. A., 1979. Ground Water. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice Hall.##Goodman, R.E., Moye, D.G., Van schalkwyk, A., Javandel, I., 1965. Ground water inflows during tunnel driving, Engineering Geology, 1(1): 39-56.##Guglielmetti,V., Grasso, P., Mahtab, A.,  Xu, S., 2008. Mechanized Tunneling in Urban Areas. Taylor &amp; Francis Publication.##Kim, S., Hyun, Y., and Lee, K., 2005. Time series modeling for evaluation of groundwater discharge rates into an urban subway system, Geoscience Journal, 9(1): 15-22.##Lei, S., 1999. An analytical solution for steady flow into a tunnel. Ground Water, 37: pp. 23-26.##Loney, B., 2001. Simulation Of De Watering During Construction Of A Bedrock Tunnel, Nepean, Ontario”, A Thesis of M.Sc. in Earth Sciences, University of Ottawa, Canada.##Rooney, O. T., 2002. Hydrogeological, Three Dimensional, Numerical Flow Modelling Of The Dublin Port Tunnel And Region. A Thesis of M.Sc. in Geosciences, Department of Geosciences, The Pennsylvania State University.##Zaidel, J., Markham, B., Bleiker, D., 2009,Simulating seepage into mine shafts and tunnels with MODFLOW. Ground Water, 48: 390-400##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>روشی پیشنهادی برای تعیین وضعیت لایه‌بندی با استفاده از روش‌های زمین‌آمار و تحلیل گروهی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A method of stratification profiling by using of geostatistic and cluster analysis technique based on dynamic probing test data</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>شناسایی لایه‌های زیر سطحی و تعیین نیم‌رخ لایه‌ها در روش‌های معمول مطالعات ژئوتکنیک بر اساس مقطع حاصل از گمانه‌های حفر شده با درون‌یابی و قضاوت فردی انجام می‌شود. در بعضی موارد چنان‌چه فاصله بین گمانه‌ها زیاد باشد با استفاده از انجام آزمایش‌های در محل نظیر آزمایش‌های نفوذسنجی دینامیکی در بین گمانه‌ها سعی می‌شود تعیین لایه‌بندی با دقت بیشتری انجام پذیرد. در این مقاله با فرض در اختیار داشتن اطلاعات مربوط به حفر چند گمانه و انجام آزمایش‌های نفوذسنجی دینامیکی در بین گمانه‌ها، روش جدیدی مبتنی بر استفاده از دو فن زمین‌آمار و تحلیل گروهی ارائه می‌شود که با استفاده از آن می‌توان دو دسته اطلاعات حاصل از گمانه‌ها و نفوذسنجی را ترکیب کرد و وضعیت لایه‌بندی و تغییر مقاومت لایه‌ها را در عمق تعیین نمود. در روش مذکور با ارائه تعریفی جدید برای برخی از مفاهیم زمین‌آمار، یک سطح نسبت به یک نقطه مبنا تعیین می‌شود که در آن سطح، وضعیت لایه‌ها و تغییر مقاومت ثابت است. سپس با استفاده از اعمال روش تحلیل گروهی بر نتایج آزمایش‌های نفوذسنجی دینامیکی در محدوده مذکور، نیم‌رخ مربوط به لایه‌ها تعیین می‌شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>  The investigation and estimation of surface subsidence and ground settlement is an important aspect in the design of shallow tunnels in urban areas. Proper exploration could lead to correct measures and avoiding any damage to structures over and underground. In this study, four sections of the east-western part of Tehran’s Metro Line 7 with the most potential for surface subsidence were chosen and studied. This part of the metro project is positioned in the young alluvial deposits of Tehran and consists mainly of fine grained soil. Ground settlement requires three dimensional design. Hence, FLAC 3D was used to investigate the surface subsidence of the ground along the tunnel route in sections mentioned above. One of the most important advantages of three dimensional design is the possibility of stepwise excavation, and to explore the effect of each excavation step on the surrounding ground. Hence, the stepwise excavation was carried out and continued in 1.5 m advancing stages, until the advancement stopped affecting the ground settlement at the point over the tunnel portal considered in the model. Even though, analytical and empirical methods are unable to evaluate the effect of ground water and the effect of overburden due to the presence of structures and traffic at the surface, because of not installing the monitoring system, analytical methods suggested by Sagaseta, Loganathan and Poulos, Verruijt and Booker, and Bobbet, and also Peck’s empirical method were used to investigate the ground settlement in this project. After using the various methods to study the four chosen sections of the metro line, and analyzing the settlement curves in these sections, it was concluded that the ground settlements is permissible (except the second section).</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>75</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>90</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خداپرست</Family>
						<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khodaparast</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار و عضو هیئت علمی دانشکده فنی و مهندسی دانشگاه قم</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار و عضو هیئت علمی دانشکده فنی و مهندسی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>khodaparast@qom.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>لایه‌بندی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زمین‌آمار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تحلیل گروهی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نفوذسنجی دینامیکی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>تاج الدین، ر. 1376. مدل‌سازی آماری توزیع سه بعدی مشخصه‌های ژئوتکنیکی خاک. پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد مهندسی خاک و پی، فرزانه، اورنگ (راهنما)، گروه مهندسی عمران دانشکده فنی دانشگاه تهران، 209 ص.##حسنی پاک، ع. ا. 1377. زمین‌آمار. نشر دانشگاه تهران، 314 ص.##خداپرست، م. و فاخر، ع. 1389. کاربرد کاوشگر دینامیکی در مطالعه خاک‌های ریزدانه و بررسی تکرارپذیری نتایج. چهارمین همایش بین‌المللی مهنـدسی ژئوتکنیک و مکانیک خاک ایران، تهران.##خداپرست، م. و فاخر، ع. 1384. توسعه تکنیک‌های شناسایی ژئوتکنیکی خاک‌ها با  کاوشگرهای دینامیکی در پروژه‌های آبی. گزارش تحقیقی، مرکز تحقیقات آب وزارت نیرو.##داس، ب. م. ،1372. اصول مهندسی ژئوتکنیک، مکانیک خاک. صالح زاده، حسین (مترجم)، جلد دوم، نشر دانشگاه علم و صنعت، 380 ص.##رندو، ج. م. ، 1371. اصول زمین‌آماری. خدایاری، علی‌اصغر (مترجم)، نشر جهاد دانشگاهی دانشگاه تهران، 212 ص.##شکرانی، ح. 1379. ساخت، بکارگیری و کالیبره نمودن ابزار مکینتاش برای شناسایی زمین. پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد مهندسی خاک و پی، فاخر، علی(راهنما)، گروه مهندسی عمران دانشکده فنی دانشگاه تهران، 77 ص.##مدنی، ح. 1373. مبانی زمین‌آمار. نشر دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر، 660 ص.##Alam, M.J., Azad, A.K., Rahman, Z., 2008. Prediction of Liquefaction Potential of Dredge Fill Sand by DCP and Dynamic Probing. Proc.  Seismic Engineering Conference, Reggio Calabria, Italy, pp 413-418.##Baecher, G.B., Christian, J.T., 2003. Reliability and Statistic in Geotechnical Engineering. Wiley and Sons, Inc., 605 p.##Butcher, A.P., Mcelmeel, K., Powel, J.J. M., 1996. Dynamic probing and its use in clay soils. Advance in Site Investigation Practice, Thomas Telford, London, pp. 383-395.##Card, G.B., Roche, D.P., Herbert, S.M., 1990. Application of continuous dynamic probing in ground investigation: Field Testing in Engineering Geology. Geological Society Engineering Geology Special Publication No 6: pp. 129-135.##Chiasson, P., Lafleur, J., Soulié, M., Law, K.T., 1995. Characterizing spatial variability of a clay by geostatistics. Canadian Geotechnical Journal, Vol. 32: pp. 1-10.##DIN 4094, 1974. Dynamic and Static penetrometers: Dimensions of apparatus and method of operation. Deutsches Institut fur Normung e. V. Berlin.##Eitner, V., Katzenbach, R., Stolben F., 2004. International and European Standards on                characterization. Proc. 2nd Int. Conf. Geotechnical and Geophysical Site Characterization, Porto, pp. 307-313.##Facciorusso J., Uzielli M., 2004. Stratigraphic profiling by cluster analysis and fuzzy soil classification from mechanical cone penetration tests. Proc. 2nd Int. Conf. Geotechnical and Geophysical Site Characterization, Porto, pp. 905-912.##Fakher, A., Khodaparast, M. Jones, C.J.F.P., 2006. The use of Mackintosh Probe for site investigation in soft soils. Q.J.E.G. London, No. 39: pp. 189-196.##Sabtan, A.A., Shehata, W.M., 1995. Mackintosh Probe as an exploration tool. Bulletin of the International Association of Engineering Geology, Paris, No. 50: pp. 89-94.##Fakher, A., Khodaparast, M., Pahlvan, B., 2001. Coastal soft clay improvements using preloading - A case study. Proceeding of 3rd International Conference Soft Soil Engineering, Hong Kong,     pp. 465-469.##Gaba, A.R., Pickles A.C., Oliveira R., 2004. Casa da música do Porto: Site characterization. Proc. 2nd Int. Conf. Geotechnical and Geophysical Site Characterization, Porto, pp. 1089-1096.##Huntley, S.L., 1990. Use of dynamic penetrometer as a ground investigation and design tool in Hertfordshire. Field Testing in Engineering Geology: Geological Society Engineering Geology Special Publication, No. 6: pp. 145-159.##Low, I.J., Zaccheo¸ P.F., 1990. Subsurface explorations and sampling. Foundation Engineering Handbook, Fang, Y.H. (eds), Chapman &amp; Hall Publishers, pp. 12-14.##Miyamoto, S., 1990. Fuzzy sets in information retrieval and cluster analysis. Kluwer Academic Publishers, 251 p.##Neter, J., Wasserman, W., Kutner, M.H., 1990. Applied linear statistical models: Regression analysis of variance and experimental designs. Richard D. Irwin, Inc., 1012 p.##Phoon, K.K., Kulhawy, F.H., 1995. Characterizing of geotechnical variability. Canadian Geotechnical Journal, Vol. 36: pp. 612-624.##Phoon, K.K., Kulhawy, F.H., Grigoriu, M.D., 1995. Reliability based foundation design for transmission line structures. Electric Power Research Institute, Palo Alto, Report TR-105000.##Spry, M.J., Kulhawy, F.H., Grigoriu, M.D., 1988. Reliability based foundation design for transmission line structures: geotechnical site characterization strategy. Electric Power Research Institute, Palo Alto, Calif., Report EL-5507##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				