<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigation and comparison of common TBM performance prognosis models using the actual data from the second lot of Zagros</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی ومقایسه مدل‌های رایج در پیش بینی عملکرد ماشین با استفاده از داده‌های واقعی در قطعه دوم تونل انتقال آب زاگرس</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>17</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">79169</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی اصغر</FirstName>
					<LastName>قائدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>. کارشناسی ارشد زمین‌شناسی‌مهندسی، دانشکد علوم پایه، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جعفر</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسن‌پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیات علمی گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکد علوم پایه، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اکبر</FirstName>
					<LastName>چشمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیات علمی گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکد علوم پایه، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0024-6161</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Different methods have been introduced for estimating the performance of tunneling boring machines (TBMs) for each area; therefore, their use in other projects may lead to errors in different geological conditions. Therefore, it is necessary for each project to use models that have similar geological conditions with the project. In this paper, using the actual machine data in the Zagros Water conveyance Tunneling Project, the machine&#039;s performance has been predicted by conventional models. Then, the results obtained from the common models including the empirical models of NTNU, Palmestrom (1995) and the theoretical model of CSM compared with the results obtained from Hassnpour et al. (2009, 2011) model, which has been developed based on data from projects with similar geological conditions, and the differences between them are quantitatively explained. The results of this study indicate that the empirical model of Hassanpour et al., due to the compatibility of the database with internal projects, shows the results closer to reality than the other models. Then, empirical models of NTNU and RMi provide more reliable results than CSM model due to consideration of different geological parameters, especially rock masses.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">روش‌های مختلفی برای تخمین عملکرد ماشین‌های حفر تونل (TBM) برای هر منطقه معرفی‌شده‌اند؛ بنابراین ممکن است که استفاده آن‌ها در دیگر پروژه‌ها با شرایط زمین‌شناسی متفاوت، موجب خطاهایی شود. لذا ضروری است برای هر پروژه از مدل‌هایی استفاده شود که شرایط زمین‌شناسی مشابه­ای را با پروژه دارند. در این مقاله ابتدا با استفاده از داده‌های واقعی عملکرد ماشین در پروژه تونل سازی انتقال آب زاگرس، عملکرد ماشین به‌وسیلهٔ مدل‌های رایج، پیش‌بینی‌شده است. سپس نتایج به‌دست‌آمده از مدل‌های رایج ازجمله مدل‌های تجربی NTNU، Palmestrom (1995)  و مدل تئوریک CSM را با نتایج به‌دست‌آمده از مدل Hassnpour et al. (2009, 2011) که بر اساس داده‌های پروژه‌هایی با شرایط زمین‌شناسی مشابه توسعه داده‌ شده است، مقایسه و اختلاف میان آن‌ها به‌صورت کمی تبیین گردیده است. نتایج این مطالعه نشان می‌دهد که مدل تجربی حسن‌پور و همکاران به دلیل همخوانی بانک اطلاعاتی با پروژه‌های داخلی، نتایج نزدیک‌تر به واقعیت را نسبت به دیگر مدل‌ها نشان می‌دهند. همچنین مدل‌های تجربی NTNU و RMi به دلیل در نظر گرفتن پارامترهای زمین‌شناسی مختلف به‌ویژه پارامترهای درزه‌داری توده سنگ، نتایج قابل‌قبول‌تری را نسبت به مدل CSM ارائه می‌دهند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تونل انتقال آب زاگرس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ماشین حفر تونل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل‌های تجربی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل تئوریک</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_79169_27895be3dd953025341e7fcc5ccf43d5.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
