<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 3 و 4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2009</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>New method for selecting the location of additional drillings based on indicator kriging; case study Semilan dam</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>پیشنهاد روشی برای تعیین محل حفاری‌های جدید، بر اساس کریجینگ شاخص؛ (مطالعه موردی سد سمیلان)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>45</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>58</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68154</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امین حسین‌</FirstName>
					<LastName>مرشدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مهندسی اکتشاف معدن، دانشکده فنی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>معماریان</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد مهندسی زمین، دانشکده فنی دانشگاه</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2009</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Defining indicator is used for classification of data, based on a threshold and converting qualitative to quantitative data. One of the applications of the indicatoring in estimation is indicator kriging. In the present study, two geotechnical parameters (Lugeon and RQD) from 27 boreholes, along with various structures of the Semilan dam were studied. Based on indicator functions, Lugeon parameter divided to four, RQD to three and various structures of the dam site to four indexes. Then, indicator variogram of each parameter was calculated and their variogram characteristics were extracted. The geotechnical parameters were estimated, by 3D kriging. Based on the average of kriging error (Lugeon and RQD) were also divided into four indexes. The function to locate additional drillings is based on maximizing parameters such as Lugeon, average of error estimation and index of dam structures; and minimizing RQD. The function to locate additional drillings is found by dividing the result of multiplying Lugeon, estimation error, and index of dam structures, by RQD. In this paper, based on the function of additional drilling locations, two extra boreholes were suggested for the studied dam site. It should be noted that new boreholes in early stage of drillings can more effectively reduces error estimation, compare to those drilled in the later stages. Hence, although adding two boreholes to 27 existing boreholes of Semilan dam cannot considerably decrease the error estimation, but effectively decrease the uncertainty around them.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به‌‌منظور طبقه‌بندی داده­ها در ساختگاه سد سمیلان، شاخص‌گذاری بر اساس حد آستانه و تبدیل داده­های کیفی به‌کمی، مورد استفاده قرار گرفت. یکی از مبانی کاربردی شاخص‌گذاری در تخمین، کریجینگ شاخص است. در بررسی حاضر، پارامتر­های ژئوتکنیکی (لوژون و شاخص کیفی سنگ)، به‌همراه سازه‌­های مختلف سد، مطالعه شد. بر‌اساس توابع شاخص‌گذاری، پارامتر لوژون به‌چهار شاخص، پارامتر شاخص کیفی سنگ به‌سه شاخص و سازه‌های مختلف سد به‌چهار شاخص تقسیم شد. سپس واریوگرام شاخص برای هر یک از پارامتر­های مذکور محاسبه و خصوصیات واریوگرام استخراج شد. با استفاده از کریجینگ، پارامتر­های مذکور به‌صورت سه‌بعدی تخمین زده شد. بر‌اساس میانگین خطای تخمین کریجینگ نیز پارامتر­های لوژون و شاخص کیفی سنگ به‌چهار شاخص تقسیم شد. تابع تعیین محل حفاری­های اضافه براساس بیشینه سازی شاخص­های لوژون، میانگین خطای تخمین و سازه‌­های مختلف سد و کمینه سازی شاخص کیفی سنگ صورت گرفت و به‌صورت حاصل‌ضرب مقدار کریجینگ شاخص لوژون در مقدار شاخص سازه‌های مختلف سد در شاخص خطای تخمین، تقسیم بر مقدار کریجینگ شاخص خصوصیت کیفی سنگ، تعریف شد. در مطالعه حاضر، بر اساس تابع تعیین محل حفاری­های اضافه، دو گمانه جدید برای تکمیل حفاری­های این سد پیشنهاد شد. نکته قابل توجه این است که تأثیر گمانه­ها بر کاهش خطای تخمین در مراحل اولیه به‌مراتب بیش‌تر از مراحل بعد است و افزایش دو گمانه در برابر بیست و هفت گمانه‌ موجود نمی­تواند خطای تخمین را به‌طور قابل ملاحظه‌ای کاهش دهد ولی عدم قطعیت را در آن مناطق کاهش می­دهد. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شاخص گذاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کریجینگ شاخص</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">لوژون</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">RQD</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تابع تعیین محل حفاری‌های اضافه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سد سمیلان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68154_2d01545731490671cb7fac53907aafd1.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
