<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 و 2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Sustainability Analysis and Design of water tunnel Maintenance system
on Mashoorh Dam</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل پایداری و طراحی سیستم نگهدارنده تونل آب بر سد معشوره</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>97</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>111</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">75685</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهزاد</FirstName>
					<LastName>سبزواری ده کبود</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد زمین شناسی مهندسی دانشگاه یزد</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0422-4699</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امین</FirstName>
					<LastName>فلاح</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد زمین شناسی مهندسی دانشگاه یزد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>مشرفی فر</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار و عضو هیئت علمی گروه زمین شناسی، دانشگاه یزد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عنایت الله</FirstName>
					<LastName>امامی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار و عضو هیئت علمی گروه زمین شناسی، دانشگاه یزد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The water tunnel at Mashooreh Dam has been constructed to supply the required water for the hydropower plant at the dam. Mangeni and Khorram-Ababd anticlines are among the most primary geological structures through which the tunnel has been built. In this research, three methods were used to propose a support system for the tunnel: empirical, analytical, and numerical methods. In the empirical method, RMR and Q techniques were employed. RocSupport Software was utilized to analyze stability of the tunnel analytically. In the numerical analysis, Phase&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Software (based on finite-element method (FEM)) was used. Results of the numerical analysis indicated total, horizontal, and vertical displacements of 11.4, 6.3, and 11.4 cm, respectively, when no support was installed. However, upon installing the proposed support, total, horizontal, and vertical displacements decreased by 4.7, 2.8, and 7.4 cm, respectively. Following the installation of the support system, safety factor enhanced to 2.21, indicating stability of the tunnel. The results of the three experimental, analytical and numerical methods of the similar maintenance system are presented.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">تونل آب­بر سد معشوره با هدف تامین آب مورد نیاز برای نیروگاه برق آبی سد مذکور احداث شده است. تاقدیس منگنی کوه و خرم آباد از  اصلی­ترین ساختارهای تشکیل دهنده  مسیر تونل هستند. در این مقاله با استفاده از سه روش تجربی، تحلیلی و عددی سیستم نگهداری پیشنهادی ارائه شده است. در روش تجربی از دو روش RMR و Q استفاده شده است. با استفاده از نرم افزار RocSupport شرایط پایداری تونل به روش تحلیلی انجام شد. در تحلیل به روش عددی از نرم افزار phase&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; که بر پایه اجزای محدود است استفادهشده است. نتایج تحلیل عددی نشان می دهد که جابجای های کل، افقی و عمودی بدون نصب سیستم نگهداری به ترتیب 4/11، 3/6 و 4/11 سانتیمتر است که با نصب سیستم نگهداری میزان جابجای کل، افقی و عمودی به ترتیب 7/4، 8/2 و 7/4 سانتیمتر کاهش پیدا کرده است. ضریب اطمینان بعد از نصب سیستم نگهداری به 21/2 می رسد که پایداری تونل را نشان می دهد. نتایج حاصل از سه روش تجربی، تحلیلی و عددی سیستم نگهدارنده مشابه را ارائه می دهند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل پایداری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">طراحی سیستم نگهداری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش عددی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش تحلیلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش تجربی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_75685_856b21c9f998bf73ca4f6b3d0d36e7ae.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
