<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 3 و 4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The effect of mineralogical and textural characteristics on engineering geological properties of Alvand granitoids and hornblendgabroo (southwest Hamedan)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اثر بافت و ویژگی های کانی شناسی بر روی خصوصیات زمین شناسی مهندسی گرانیتوئیدها و هورنبلندگابروهای الوند</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>41</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>52</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68208</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>قبادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه زمین شناسی د انشگاه بوعلی سینا همدان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>علیجانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، همدان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2009</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>27</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Granitoid and Hornblend gabroo rocks of Alvand area show a variety of engineering geological properties that may affect quarrying operation, tunneling, mining, slope stability and use of rock as construction materials. The physical and mechanical properties are functions of the mineralogical and textural characteristics of rock. The purpose of this study is to apply correlation analysis to investigate the relationship between petrographical and engineering geological properties of rocks. For this research, 90 rock samples (Granitoids and hornblend gabroo) from Alvand mountains (southwest Hamedan) were subjected to petrographic studies. The same samples were then tested to determine solid specific gravity, dry and saturated unit weight, water absorption and total porosity. Schmidt hardness, point load strength index, uniaxial compressive strength, modulus of elasticity and Linear Crack Density Index (LCDI). The relationships between these properties and the petrographic characteristics are described by simple regression analyses. The study revealed that the influence of the textural characteristics on the engineering geological properties appears to be more impotant than the mineralogy. It also determined that the type of contacts, grain (mineral) shape and size significantly influence the engineering geological properties of these rocks.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">گرانیتوئیدها و هورنبلندگابروهای منطقه الوند همدان دارای خصوصیات زمین شناسی مهندسی متنوعی هستند. این تنوع روی عملیات معدنکاری، تونل­بری، پایداری شیب و استفاده از آنها به­عنوان سنگ­های ساختمانی تاثیر می­گذارد. تفاوت در خصوصیات زمین شناسی مهندسی این سنگ­ها متأثر از بافت و ویژگی­های کانی­شناختی است. هدف ازاین پژوهش بررسی روابط بین خصوصیات پتروگرافی با ویژگی­های زمین­شناسی مهندسی سنگ­ها است. بدین منظور 90 نمونه از گرانیتوئیدها (مونزوگرانیت و سینوگرانیت) و هورنبلندگابروهای توده باتولیتی الوند تهیه گردیده و به منظور تعیین ویژگی­هایی مانند درصد جذب آب، تخلخل، وزن واحد حجم (خشک، مرطوب، اشباع) شاخص خطی ریزترک­ها، مقاومت فشاری      تک­محوری، شاخص مقاومت بار نقطه­ای، مدول الاستیسیته و سختی اشمیت مورد آزمایش قرار گرفتند. روابط بین این خصوصیات و ویژگی­های پتروگرافی بررسی گردید. از برقراری ارتباط  بین این ویژگی­ها مشخص شد که در تعیین خصوصیات زمین­شناسی مهندسی سنگ، اهمیت ویژگی­های بافتی بیشتر از خصوصیات کانی شناسی می­باشد. بدین معنا که خصوصیات دانه­ها مانند شکل و اندازه، نوع تماس با یکدیگر، درجه قفل شدگی ذرات و شاخص ریزترک­ها تأثیر مهمی روی خصوصیات زمین­شناسی مهندسی سنگ­ دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گرانیتوئیدها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هورنبلند گابرو</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الوند</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خصوصیات زمین شناسی مهندسی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68208_36e948c0a0ba8960a8f6d8483c288c99.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
