<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2008</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Determinining contributions of lithological types of Pouldasht basin to sediment yield using sediment source fingerprinting techniques</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>استفاده از روش منشأیابی در تعیین سهم واحدهای سنگ‌شناسی حوضه پلدشت در تولید رسوب</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>63</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>74</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68134</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شاهرخ</FirstName>
					<LastName>حکیم خانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکده منابع طبیعی، دانشگاه ارومیه  Hakimkhani@yahoo.com</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>احمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، دانشکده منابع طبیعی، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جعفر</FirstName>
					<LastName>غیومیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار پژوهشی، مرکز تحقیقات حفاظت خاک و آبخیزداری</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2006</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>08</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Because of the many problems associated with traditional procedures for identifying sediment sources, fingerprinting method, based on physical, chemical and organic properties of sediment and source materials, are increasingly being used as a valuable and effective alternative approach to assembling such information. In this method, a suitable composite (set) of diagnostic properties and a multivariate mixing model are employed to estimate the relative contributions of sediment sources to sediments yield. In this study, using a suitable composite of geochemical elements capable of discriminating subareas underlain by individual lithological types of the study basin and a multivariate mixing model, the contributions of lithological types to sediments yield were determined. The study basin is the main subbasin of Pouldasht water spreading station basin, located in Makoo township, West Azarbaijan province. The lithological subereas were categorized in five groups as sediment sources. Over 106 representative source material samples and 6 sediment samples were collected from lithological groups and sediments deposited in the river bed respectively. Then, the samples were analyzed to determine the concentrations of 18 geochemical elements. 12 out of the 18 geochemical elements were selected as a suitable composite fingerprint using discriminant function analysis. Mean contributions from the lithological subereas of Marl, Conglomerate, Limestone and dolomite,  Shale and Slate, and Quaternary sediments were estimated to be 53.9, 29.75, 8.85, 7.5 and 0 percent respectively. Mean absolute error and model efficiency of the method were estimated to be 17.5% and 0.99 respectively. The fingerprinting approach to source ascription is seen as providing valuable information regarding sediment sources in the study basin.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به دلیل‌ وجود مشکلات زیاد در کاربرد روشهای‌ سنتی‌، روش انگشت­نگاری، ردیابی یا بعبارتی منشأیابی به‌ عنوان‌ روشی جایگزین‌ و مناسب مورد توجه ‌محققین‌ مختلف‌ قرار گرفته‌ است. در این روش‌، خصوصیات فیزیکی‌، ژئوشیمیایی‌ و آلی‌ رسوب و منابع رسوب برای‌ تعیین‌ منابع‌ اصلی‌ رسوب و اهمیت نسبی‌ آنها مورد استفاده قرار می­گیرند. در روش یاد شده با استفاده از ترکیبی مناسب از خصوصیات جدا کننده منابع‌ رسوب، سهم منابع رسوب در تولید رسوب تعیین می­شود. در این تحقیق، سعی شده است با بهره­گیری از ترکیبی مناسب از عناصر ژئوشیمیایی که قادر به جداسازی واحدهای سنگ­شناسی در یکی از زیر حوضه­های حوضه ایستگاه پخش سیلاب پلدشت واقع در شهرستان ماکو از استان آذربایجان غربی است سهم واحدهای یاد شده تعیین شود. بعد از برداشت 106 نمونه معرف از واحدهای سنگ­ شناسی و 6 نمونه رسوب از انتهای حوضه نسبت به تجزیه 18 عنصر ژئوشیمیایی اقدام شد. با بهره­گیری از روش تحلیل تشخیص، حدود 12 عنصر از 18 عنصر به عنوان ترکیب مناسب انتخاب شدند. در آخر با استفاده از ترکیب یاد شده و مدل­های چند متغیره ترکیبی سهم واحدهای مارن، کنگلومرا، آهک و دولومیت، شیل و اسلیت و رسوبات کواترنری به ترتیب برابر با 9/53، 75/29، 85/8،  5/7 و 0 درصد بدست آمد. میانگین خطای نسبی تقریبا برابر با 5/17 درصد و متوسط ضریب کارایی مدل حدود 99/0 است. روش منشأیابی رسوب به عنوان روشی با ارزش برای کسب اطلاعات از منابع رسوب تشخیص داده شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عناصر ژئوشیمیایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">منابع رسوب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">واحدهای سنگ شناسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پلدشت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل تشخیص</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">منشأیابی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68134_e2ea3c87f4f0e70e645250958c828037.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
