<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Experimental Study of the Microbial Induced Carbonate Precipitation (MICP) Effect on the Permeability of Carbonated Sands</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مطالعه‌ی آزمایشگاهی تاثیر رسوب زیستی کربنات کلسیم (MICP) بر میزان نفوذپذیری ماسه‌های کربناته</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>43</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>55</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">89188</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>حیدری نقدعلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه یاسوج-دانشکده فنی و مهندسی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>منصور</FirstName>
					<LastName>پرویزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه یاسوج-دانشکده فنی و مهندسی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مسعود</FirstName>
					<LastName>رابطی مقدم</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه یاسوج-دانشکده فنی و مهندسی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نقی ها</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه یاسوج؛ دانشکده کشاورزی؛ گروه علوم دامی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>11</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Microbial induced carbonate precipitation (MCIP) is an environmentally and suitable method for soil remediation. In this method, urea is hydrolyzed by the urease enzyme, that is splashed from Sporosrcina Pasteurii bacteria. The calcium carbonate is formed in the presence of calcium ion. Calcium carbonate connects the soil particle like a bridge and improve its engineering characteristics. In the present research, the effect of MICP on the permeability of carbonated sand was investigated. The effect of factors such as concentration of the cementation solution, curing time and relative density on soil permeability have been studied. To consider the effect of different factors on the MICP performance, number of samples have been treated with MICP method and then constant head permeability test were conducted on the treated samples. the results show that as the concentration of cement solution was increased, the permeability of the samples was decreased. Loose Samples resulted in more decrease in permeability with respect to the dense samples. Also, bacterial activity was increased with time and after 14 days the variation in permeability was reduced. The highest rate of permeability reduction was around 60% for the sample prepared in loose state and cured with one molar concentration of cementation solution for 28 days</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">رسوب زیستی کربنات کلسیم (MICP) روشی سازگار با محیط زیست و مناسب برای بهسازی خاک است. در این روش، اوره توسط آنزیم اوره آز ترشح شده از باکتری، هیدورلیز شده و کربنات کلسیم در حضور یون کلسیم تشکیل می شود. کربنات-کلسیم مانند پلی ذرات خاک را به یکدیگر متصل می کند و باعث بهبود مشخصه های خاک می شود. در مقاله حاضر تاثیر MICPبر میزان نفوذپذیری ماسه های کربناته در آزمایشگاه مطالعه شده است. عواملی نظیر غلظت محلول سیمانی، میزان تراکم خاک و مدت زمان تیمار بر میزان نفوذپذیری خاک مورد مطالعه قرار گرفته است. نتایج نشان داد غلظت بالاتر محلول سیمانی باعث کاهش بیشتر در نفوذپذیری نمونه‌ها می شود. نمونه های با تراکم کمتر، کاهش نفوذپذیری بیشتری را نشان دادند. هم چنین با گذشت زمان از 14 روز به 28 روز، فعالیت باکتریایی بسیار اندک بوده است. بیشترین میزان کاهش نفوذپذیری در نمونه ی سست، با غلظت محلول سیمانی 1 مولار و با مدت زمان عمل آوری 28 روز، برابر با 60 درصد بوده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">MICP</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">باکتری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کریستال کربنات‌کلسیم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بیوسمنتاسیون</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آزمایش نفوذپذیری با بار ثابت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_89188_62b4e187d56fe2538697c764ba0c7390.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
