<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 3 و 4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Comparison coefficient of consolidation from CPTu and one- dimensional consolidation Tests</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مقایسه ضریب تحکیم حاصل از آزمایش CPTu و آزمایش تحکیم یک بعدی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>81</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>94</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68368</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اکبر</FirstName>
					<LastName>چشمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکده زمین‌شناسی، پردیس علوم، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0024-6161</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>عزالدین</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، دانشکده زمین‌شناسی، پردیس علوم، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کاظم</FirstName>
					<LastName>مرادی هرسینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، مهندسین مشاور سازه‌پردازی ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Coefficient of consolidation (C&lt;sub&gt;V&lt;/sub&gt;) is one of the important parameters used in geotechnical design. This parameter is usually achieved from one dimensional consolidation test in laboratory. Cone penetration Test (CPT) is an in situ test, in this test can be measure pore water pressure with time this test has previously been introducing dissipation test. Teh (1987), Houlsby and Teh (1988), Teh and Houlsby (1991) and Jones and Rust (1995) have been proposed different methods to determine C&lt;sub&gt;V&lt;/sub&gt; from CPTu results. In this paper, have been used 43 dissipation tests and 35 one dimension laboratory consolidation tests that were conducted in three areas in southern Iran and are compared C&lt;sub&gt;V&lt;/sub&gt; are obtained from CPTu test by from 4 methods listed above with each other’s and one dimensional laboratory consolidation test. The results show that C&lt;sub&gt;V&lt;/sub&gt; obtained from laboratory test is higher than the value obtained by from Teh &amp; Houlsby (1991) method and lower than the value obtained from others methods. The similarity of results obtained from laboratory test in terms of amount and trend are closer to results obtained from Teh &amp; Houlsby (1991) method. The empirical relationships between laboratory and in situ C&lt;sub&gt;V&lt;/sub&gt; are proposed. For all equations, coefficient of correlation is higher than 0.7.  The highest value is belong to Houlsby &amp; Teh (1988) method and the least value is belong to the Jones &amp; Rust (1995) method. &lt;br /&gt;Once the empirical equation is proposed for each site indecently, coefficient of correlation in all methods is high but while the empirical equation is proposed for all sites together coefficient of correlation is decrease. Thus these empirical equations are influenced by the characteristics of each area so for each area must be independently evaluated and empirical equation are proposed.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">ضریب تحکیم یکی از پارامترهای مهمی است که در طراحی‌های ژئوتکنیکی استفاده می­شود. این ضریب معمولا از آزمایش تحکیم یک بعدی آزمایشگاهی بدست می­آید. آزمایش نفوذ مخروط آزمایشی برجاست که در آن امکان اندازه­گیری تغییرات فشار آب منفذی با زمان و تعیین ضریب تحکیم وجود دارد. این آزمایش قبلا بعنوان آزمایش محو فشار آب­منفذی (Dissipation) معرفی شده است. ته (Teh, 1987)، هولسبی و ته (Houlsby &amp; Teh, 1988)، ته و هولسبی (Teh &amp; Houlsby, 1991) و جونز و راست (Jones &amp; Rust, 1995) روش‌های مختلفی برای تعیین ضریب تحکیم از نتایج آزمایش نفوذ مخروط پیشنهاد نموده­اند. در این مقاله با استفاده از 43 آزمایش محو فشار منفذی و 35 آزمایش تحکیم آزمایشگاهی در سه ناحیه در جنوب ایران، ضمن مقایسه ضریب بدست آمده از 4 روش فوق، ضریب بدست آمده از این روش‌ها با ضریب حاصل از آزمایش آزمایشگاهی تحکیم مقایسه شده است. نتایج نشان می­دهد ضریب بدست آمده از آزمایش آزمایشگاهی از مقادیر بدست آمده از روش ته و هولسبی بیشتر و از سایر روش‌ها کمتر است. نتایج آزمایشگاهی از نظر مقدار و روند به نتایج بدست آمده از روش ته و هولسبی نزدیکتر هستند. رابطه تجربی بین ضریب تحکیم آزمایشگاهی و برجا با ضریب تعیین بیشتر از 0.7 پیشنهاد شده است. بیشترین ضریب تعیین مربوط به روش هولسبی و ته و کمترین مربوط به روش جونز و راست است. زمانی‌که یک رابطه تجربی برای همه سایت­های مطالعه شده پیشنهاد گردیده ضریب تعیین نسبت به زمانیکه روابط تجربی برای هر سایت بصورت مستقل تعیین گردیده، کاهش یافته است بنابراین روابط می­توان گفت روابط تجربی متاثر از ویژگی­های هر منطقه می­باشند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">: آزمایش نفوذ مخروط</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آزمایش محو فشار منفذی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ضریب تحکیم</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68368_c0fc0d25cb685f1af1e47daf596424df.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
