<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 3 و 4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Improvement of clayey soils using lime in the south west of Hamedan</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بهسازی خاک‌های رسی جنوب غرب همدان با استفاده از آهک</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>16</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68315</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>قبادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>1. عضو هیات علمی گروه زمین‌شناسی دانشگاه بوعلی سینا،  همدان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>یاسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>عبدی‌لر</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجویان دکتری زمین‌شناسی مهندسی دانشگاه بوعلی سینا</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>بابازاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجویان دکتری زمین‌شناسی مهندسی دانشگاه بوعلی سینا</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>25</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This paper deal with to investigation of the results of mineralogical and geotechnical studies on lime–stabilized soft clay soils in the southwest of Hamedan. In this order, the hydrated lime was added in the order of 1%, 3%, 5% and 7% by weight and laboratory experiments including mineralogical studies, grain size distribution, plasticity limits, compaction and uniaxial compressive strength were conducted on samples after 7, 15, 30 and 45 days of curing time. The test results indicate that increasing the lime percentage, the soil gradually loses it&#039;s plasticity characteristics and finally, it is non-plastic. In addition to, increasing the added lime and curing time, the compressive strength and elasticity modulus of the lime - treated soils increases. Based on the test results was determined that by addition of 7% lime and after 30 days curing time, the studied soft clay soil is stabilized as satisfactory. Therefore, the optimum lime content and proper curing time for lime-treated soils is 7% and 30 days, respectively. Also, In order to investigation of relationship between lime-treated geotechnical properties with lime percentage and curing time, the multivariate regression analysis has been carried out that the results demonstrate high regression coefficients for the proposed relationships.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این مقاله به بررسی نتایج مطالعات کانی‌شناختی و ژئوتکنیکی خاک‌های رسی نرم بهسازی شده با آهک در جنوب غرب همدان می پردازد. بدین منظور آهک شکفته با درصدهای وزنی 1، 3، 5 و 7  به خاک اضافه شده است و آزمایش­های آزمایشگاهی شامل مطالعات کانی‌شناسی، توزیع اندازه ذرات، حدود خمیری، تراکم و مقاومت فشاری تک‌محوری بعد از 7، 15، 30 و 45 روز دوره عمل‌آوری، بر روی نمونه‌های مورد نظر انجام شده است. نتایج آزمایش‌ها نشان داد که با افزایش درصد آهک، خاک مورد نظر به­تدریج خواص خمیری خود را از دست می‌دهد و در نهایت غیرخمیری می‌شود. همچنین با افزایش درصد آهک و افزایش زمان عمل‌آوری، مقاومت فشاری و مدول الاستیسیته نمونه‌های مخلوط شده با آهک افزایش می‌یابد. بر اساس نتایج حاصل شده خاک رس نرم مورد مطالعه با افزایش 7% آهک و بعد از گذشت یک دوره عمل‌آوری 30 روزه به صورت مطلوبی بهسازی می‌شود. علاوه بر این به منظور بررسی ارتباط بین ویژگی‌های ژئوتکنیکی خاک مخلوط شده با درصد آهک و زمان عمل‌آوری، آنالیز رگرسیون غیرخطی انجام شده و روابط خوبی با ضریب رگرسیون بالا ارائه شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آهک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بهسازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خاک رس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شاخص خمیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مقاومت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">همدان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68315_1a6d8ab41582cf606124c3adbb4b68ed.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
