<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1388</YEAR>
<VOL>2</VOL>
<NO>0</NO>
<MOSALSAL>0</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>98</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مطالعه خصوصیات زمین شناسی مهندسی سنگ آهک سازند آسماری در شمال شرق مسجد سلیمان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Study of engineering geological properties of Asmari limestone in the north-east Masjed-Suliman</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>شناخت خصوصیات زمین‌شناسی مهندسی سازندهای سنگی ایران به عنوان یک ضرروت مطرح است. در این پژوهش بر اساس مطالعات سنگ‌شناسی وبا انجام آزمایش‌های مکانیک سنگ بر روی 20 نمونه از سنگ آهک‌های سازند آسماری در شمال شرق مسجد سلیمان ویژگی‌های زمین‌شناسی مهندسی آنها تعیین و ارتباط خصوصیات سنگ‌شناسی با خصوصیات فیزیکی و مکانیکی بررسی شده است. بر اساس مطالعات پتروگرافی و مطابق با رده‌بندی دانهام عمده سنگ‌های کربناته سازند آسماری از نوع بایوکلاست پکستون packstone) (Bioclast و بایوکلاست وکستون (Bioclast wackestone) هستند. سنگ آهک‌های سازند آسماری تخلخل خیلی کم تا متوسط  دارند و نفوذپذیری آنها خیلی کم تا کم می‌‌باشد. حداقل و حداکثر عدد سختی برای این سنگ‌ها به ترتیب 18 و 39 می‌باشد. با توجه به رده‌بندی مهندسی سنگ بکر و بر اساس دو عامل مقاومت تراکمی تک محوری و نسبت مدولی سنگ آهک‌های سازند آسماری در رده CL قرار می‌گیرند.  </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The main purpose of this research is to assess the engineering geological properties of Asmari limestone in the north-east of Khuzestan province. For this purpose, 20 samples of limestone were selected from the north-east of Karun 1 dam site, and the relationships between petrographic characteristics, physical and mechanical properties were investigated. Index properties such as total porosity, dry unit weight, schmit hammer value, strength under uniaxial  compression and Brazilian tension were determined. Microscopic studies on the limestone reveal that they are mostly bioclast packstone and bioclast wackestone according to Dunham classification. From the statictical analysis of the data, regression equations were established among rock material parameters, while conversion factors relating index properties and strength were also determined. The petrographic characteristics of the studied rocks such as mineral composition and microstructure were analyzed in thin sections and their intrinsic influence on the measured strength parameters was also investigated</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>18</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قبادی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Hosein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Gobadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه زمین شناسی د انشگاه بوعلی سینا همدان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه زمین شناسی د انشگاه بوعلی سینا</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>amirghobadi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محسنی</Family>
						<NameE>Hasan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mohseni</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>  عضو هیات علمی گروه زمین‌شناسی دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، همدان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>  عضو هیات علمی گروه زمین‌شناسی دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رسولی فرح</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rasooli Farah</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>3-      دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، زمین‌شناسی مهندسی دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، همدان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>3-      دانشجوی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سنگ آهک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سازند آسماری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خصوصیات پتروگرافیکی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ویژگی‌های فیزیکی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ویژگی‌های مکانیکی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مسجد سلیمان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>آقانباتی، سیدعلی. (1383) زمین شناسی ایران، انتشارات سازمان زمین شناسی و اکتشافات معدنی کشور.##قبادی، محمدحسین. (1383) مطالعه انحلال‌پذیری سنگ‌های کربناته دراستان خوزستان، طرح تحقیفات ملی، گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز.##قبادی، محمدحسین. (1378) نوع کارست و مسئله آب‌بندی سد میرزای شیرازی (کوار)، سومین همایش انجمن زمین‌شناسی ایران, دانشگاه شیراز، صفحات468-465.##قبادی، محمدحسین و محمد رجب پور. (1378) انحلال‌پذیری و گسترش ناپیوستگی‌ها در توده‌های سنگ‌های آهکی محل سد شهید عباسپور (کارون 1). هجدهمین گردهمایی علوم زمین، سازمان زمین‌شناسی کشور، صفحات 1004-999.##فهیمی‌فر، احمد و حامد سروش. (1380) آزمایش‌های مکانیک سنگ (مبانی نظری و استانداردها) انتشارات آزمایشگاه مکانیک خاک وزارت راه و ترابری و دانشگاه امیرکبیر واحد تفرش.##Adams, T. D. and Bougeois, F. (1967) Asmari Biostratigraphy, Iranian Oil Operating   Companies, Geological and Exploration Division, Rep. # 1074. 59 p.##Alavi, M. (1994) Tectonic of the Zagros orogenic belt of Iran: new data and   interpretations, Tectonophysics, Vol. 229, 211-238.##Bell, F.G., (1998a). A survey of the physical properties of some carbonate rocks. Bulletin of International Association Engineering Geology, Vol. 24,105-110.##Bell,F. G., (1983). Fundamentals of engineering geology. Buterwrths. UK.##Bell, F.J. (2000). Engineering Properties of Soils and Rocks. Blackwell Sciences.##Bordenave, M. L., and Burwood, R. (1990) Source rock distribution and maturation in the Zagros orogenic belt; provenance of the Asmari and Bangestan Reservoir oil Accumulations, Org.   Geochem. Vol. 16, No. 1-3, 369-378.##Brown, E.T., (1981). Rock characterization testing &amp; monitoring ISRM suggested methods. Pergamon Press.##Burnett,A.D. and Epps,R.J. (1979). The engineering geological description of the carbonate suite rocks and soils. Ground Engineering, Vol. 2,41-48.##Dearman, W.R., (1981). Engineering properties of carbonate rocks. Bulletin International Association Engineering Geology, Vol. 24,3-17.##Dickson, J. A. D. (1980) Staining thin section: Alizarin Red S and Potassium  Ferricyanide stain, in: Okhravi, R. (1982) Carbonate microfacies and Depositional environment of the Joachim Dolomite (MiddlOrdovician)  Southeast Missouri and Southern Illinois, U.S.A., Unpub. Ph.DThesis, university of Illinois (Urbana   Champaign), 141 p.##Dunham, R. G., (1962). Classification of carbonate rocks according to deposition texture, in: Classification of Carbonate Rocks (ed. By W. E. Ham) A A P G Mem. #1, 108- 121.##Frankline, J.A. and Broch, E. (1972). The point Load Strength Test. Inter. J. Rock Mechanics Mining Sciences,Vol.9. pp.669-697.##James,A.N., and Kirkpatrick, I.M., (1980). Design of foundations of dams containing soluble rocks and soils. Quarterly Journal of Engineering Geology, Vol. 13,189-198.##Ghobadi, M.H. (1997). The influence of aperture of joints on solubility of carbonaceous rocks, International Symposium Engineering Geology and Environment, Balkema, pp.127-131.##Ghobadi, M.H., Khunlari,G., and Jalali,H. (2005). Seepage problems in the right abutment of the Shahid Abasspour dam, southern Iran. Journal of Engineering Geology, Vol.82, pp.119-126.##Ghobadi, M.H.  (2005). Assessment of solubility of Asmari limestone in Karun 1 damsite, Iran. ICOLD, 73th Annual Meeting of ICOLD, Tehran, Iran.##McQuillan, H. (1967). Fracture density in  Asmari formation and relationship to bedding thickness and structural setting. Technical report.##Milanovic, P.T.,  (2000). Geological Engineering in karst. Zebra Publishing Ltd.##Merrit. A.H., (1988). Foundation treatment in karstic limestone: El Cajon Hydroelectric Project, Honduras, Bulletin International Association Engineering Geology, Vol. 28,390-392##Moshanski, V.A., and Parabouchev,I.A., (1981). The nature of strength and deformability of weak carbonaceous rocks. Proceedings of the International symposium on weak rocks. Vol.1.326-333.##Tucker, M. E. and Wright. P.V. (1990) Carbonate Sedimentology, Blackwell Scientific  Pub. Oxford, 482 p.##Warren, J, (2000) Dolomite: Occurences, evolution and economically important associations, Earth-Science Reviews, 52, 1-81.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تحلیل و رده‌بندی پتانسیل ناپایداری شیب‌های سنگی مشرف به جاده گردنه خوش‌ییلاق با استفاده از رویکرد سیستمی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The analysis and classification of rock slopes instability potential along  the Khosh-Yeylagh mountainous road using systems approach</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>موضوع تحلیل پایداری شیب‌ها با روش‌های تحلیلی و عددی به علت پیچیدگی رفتار توده سنگ و تعداد عوامل مؤثر بر آن، همواره کاری دشوار به حساب آمده است. روش‌های تجربی نیز علیرغم استفاده فراگیر، به دلیل در نظر گرفتن فاکتورهای مشخص و مخصوص به خود، از دقت و کارایی لازم برای تمامی موقعیت‌ها برخوردار نیستند. رویکرد سیستم‌های مهندسی سنگ (RES) به عنوان یک روش سیستمی در تحلیل‌ها و رده‌بندی‌های پروژه‌های مهندسی سنگ مطرح می‌باشد. در این رویکرد، تأثیر متقابل پارامترهای مؤثر بر یکدیگر در مقیاسی برابر سنجیده شده و بدین ترتیب اثر هر پارامتر در میزان تولید ناپایداری مورد توجه قرار می‌گیرد. هدف از این مقاله استفاده از رویکرد سیستم‌های مهندسی سنگ در رده‌بندی شیب‌های سنگی مشرف به جاده گردنه خوش‌ییلاق واقع در محور ارتباطی شاهرود- آزادشهر می‌باشد. بدین منظور، پس از انجام بازدیدها از منطقه مورد مطالعه و بررسی شرایط محیطی، تعیین ایستگاه‌ها و سنجش وضعیت شیب‌های سنگی، مهم­ترین پارامترهای مؤثر در ایجاد ناپایداری در توده سنگ ها شناسایی شدند. سپس با پیروی از مراحل کلیدی اجرای روش مذکور نظیر تشکیل ماتریس اندرکنش، کدگذاری ماتریس، تشکیل منوهای رده‌بندی، تعریف اندیس ناپایداری به صورت فرمول ریاضی برای منطقه و پس از به دست آوردن داده‌های مربوط به خواص مکانیکی سنگ‌ها، درزه‌های سنگی و شرایط حاکم بر منطقه، اندیس‌های خاص هر شیب سنگی مورد محاسبه قرار گرفت. بدین ترتیب رده‌بندی جامعی از ایستگاه‌ها و در نتیجه شیب‌های منطقه ارائه گردید. در نهایت، با به­کارگیری یک روش تجربی و تحلیل پایداری شیب‌های مورد نظر، یک اعتبارسنجی اولیه برای کاربرد رویکرد سیستمی در منطقه مورد مطالعه انجام شد که مقایسه‌ها تطبیق نسبتاً خوبی را میان نتایج دو روش نشان داد. نتایج این تحقیق نشان می‌دهد که استفاده از رویکرد سیستمی در تحلیل پایداری شیب‌ها در مقیاس وسیع و در مسائل دارای پارامترهای مؤثر متعدد می‌تواند بسیار مفید واقع گردد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Rock slope stability analysis with the use of analytical and numerical approaches is usually a complicated engineering task because of complex behaviour of the rock mass and also of the various affecting parameters. On the other hand, even though the wide application of empirical methods, they don’t have an acceptable accuracy and efficiency in all situations due to the consideration of the specified influencing major factors. The Rock Engineering Systems (RES) is a systems approach which can be considered as a suitable method for rock engineering analyses and classifications particularly in areas with complex environment and multiple affecting parameters. In this method, the interactions between the system’s parameters are analyzed and then the effect of each parameter on the subject (system) is considered. The aim of this paper is to utilize the RES approach to classification of rock slopes in Khosh-Yeylagh mountainous road between Shahrood and Azadshahr cities in Iran. In this way, the study region and its conditions have been visited and some stations on the rock slopes have been selected. Then, the key steps of the mentioned approach such as selection of the most important parameters generating the instability, establishment of the interaction matrix and its coding, setting up the classification menus, defining the instability index in the form of a mathematical formula have been consecutively followed. Then, the experimental data of rock and rock joint physical characteristics were achieved and the indices for each slope were calculated. In this manner, the rock slopes in the stations were classified from the instability point of view. Finally, as a preliminary validation on the utilization of systems approach in the study region, the stability of investigated rock slopes were analyzed using an empirical method and the results were compared. The comparisons showed a rather good coincidence between the given classes of two methods. The results of this research showed that the utilization of the systems approach could be considered very useful in rock slope stability analysis specifically in large scale problems with various affecting parameters.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>19</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>32</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خالوکاکایی</Family>
						<NameE>Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khalukakei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار دانشکده مهندسی معدن، نفت و ژئوفیزیک، دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار دانشکده مهندسی معدن، نفت و ژئوفیزیک،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مسعود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>زارع نقدهی</Family>
						<NameE>Masoud</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Zare Naghadehi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>2-      دانشجوی دوره دکتری، دانشکده مهندسی معدن، نفت و ژئوفیزیک، دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>2-      دانشجوی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>masoud.zare@hotmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تحلیل پایداری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شیب‌های سنگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جاده گردنه خوش‌ییلاق</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رویکرد سیستمی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سیستم‌های مهندسی سنگ (RES)</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>اداره کل آمار و فناوری اطلاعات (1385) سالنامة آماری هواشناسی. ناشر سازمان هواشناسی کشور.##مؤسسه جغرافیایی ایران (1380) اطلس راه‌های ایران. مؤسسة جغرافیایی، کارتوگرافی و گیتاشناسی.##Ali K.M., Hasan K. (2002) Rock mass Characterization to indicate slope instability in Bandarban: a rock engineering systems approach. Environmental and Engineering Geoscience, Vol. 8, No. 2, pp. 105-119.##Budetta P., Santo A., Vivenzio F. (2008) Landslide hazard mapping along the coastline of the Cilento region (Italy) by means of a GIS-based parameter rating approach. Geomorphology, Vol. 94, pp. 340-352.##Castaldini D., Genevois R., Panizza M., Puccinelli A., Berti M., Simoni A. (1998) An integrated approach for analyzing earthquake-induced surface effects: a case study from the Northern Apennins, Italy. Journal of Geodynamics, Vol. 26, No. 2-4, pp. 413-441.##Ceryan N., Ceryan S. (2008) An application of the interaction matrices method for slope failure susceptibility zoning: Dogankent settlement area (Giresun, NE Turkey). Bulletin of Engineering Geology and the Environment, Vol. 67, No. 3, pp. 375-385.##Eberhardt E. (2003) Rock slope stability analysis- utilization of advanced numerical techniques. Earth and Ocean Sciences at UBC Report, University of British Columbia (UBC), Vancouver, Canada, 41 p.##Hill J.D., Warfield, J.N. (1972) Unified program planning. In: System Engineering: Methodology and Applications Edited by A.P. Sage, IEEE Press, New York, NY.##Hudson J.A. (1992) Rock Engineering Systems, Theory and Practice. Ellis Horwood Ltd., Chichester. 185 p.##Hudson, J.A., Harrison, J.P. (1992) A new approach to studying complete ‌rock engineering problems. Quarterly Journal of  Engineering Geology, Vol. 25, pp. 93-105.##ISRM (1981) Rock characterization, testing and monitoring- Suggested methods, Part 1: Site characterization, Brown, E.T. (ed.), Pergamon.##Mazzoccola D.F., Hudson J.A. (1996) A comprehensive method of rock mass characterization for indicating natural slope instability. Quarterly Journal of Engineering Geology,Vol. 29, pp.37-56.##Romana M. (1985) New adjustment ratings for application of Bieniawski classification to slopes. In: Proceedings of the International Symposium on the Role of Rock Mechanics ISRM. Zacatecas, pp. 49-53.##Romana M., Serón J.B., Montalar E. (2003) SMR Geomechanics classification: Application, experience and validation. In: Proceedings of the ISRM 2003–Technology roadmap for rock mechanics, South African Institute of Mining and Metallurgy, pp. 981-984.##Rozos D., Pyrgiotis L., Skias S., Tsagaratos P. (2008) An implementation of rock engineering system for ranking the instability potential of natural slopes in Greek territory- An application in Karditsa County. Landslides, Vol. 5, No. 3, pp. 261-270.##Smith G.J. (1994) The engineering geological assessment of shallow mine workings with particular reference to chalk. PhD Thesis, University of London.##Varnes D.J. (1978) Slope movement types and processes. In: Schuster RL, Krizek RJ (eds.) Landslides Analysis and Control. Transportation Research Board Special Report 176. National Academy of Sciences, Washington##Zhang L.Q., Yang Z.F., Liao Q.L., Chen J. (2004) An application of the rock engineering systems (RES) methodology in rockfall hazard assessment on the Chengdu-Lhasa highway, China. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, Vol. 41, No. 3, pp. 833-838.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مطالعه خصوصیات فیزیکی و رفتار مکانیکی خاکهای گچی متورم شونده و روش‌های بهسازی آنها</TitleF>
				<TitleE>An investigation on physical characteristics and mechanical behavior of swelling gypsum soils and their improvement methods</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>وجود خاک­های متورم شونده در سراسر دنیا خسارات جبران ناپذیری را به ساختمان­ها وارد می­نماید. خاک­های گچی در ناحیه جنوب غربی مشهد، به دلیل خاصیت تورم­زایی که دارند از دیرباز مشکلاتی مانند ایجاد ترک در نمای ساختمان‌ها، شکم دادن دیوارها و برآمدگی کف­سازی­ها را به وجود آورده­اند. خاک­های این منطقه عموماً ریزدانه بوده و از نوع ML یا CL محسوب می­شوند. این پژوهش کوششی برای تعیین مشخصات و بررسی خواص تورمی خاک­های گچی ML در این منطقه می­باشد. به این منظور 6 نمونه از میان نمونه­هایی که دانه بندی یکسان ولی درصد گچ طبیعی متفاوتی دارند انتخاب شده­اند. پس از تعیین خصوصیات اصلی ژئوتکنیکی (مقدار گچ، حدود اتربرگ، وزن مخصوص طبیعی و چگالی) این خاک­ها، اثر میزان گچ بر پتانسیل تورم و فشار تورم بررسی گردید. با توجه به تاثیر به سزای وزن مخصوص بر پتانسیل و فشار تورم، از هر یک ازخاک­های شش­گانه 10 نمونه با رطوبت اولیه یکسان و وزن مخصوص مختلف ساخته شده و تغییرات پتانسیل و فشار تورم آنها تعیین گردید. نتایج این تحقیق بیانگر اثر شدید مقدار گچ، میزان تراکم و مقدار رطوبت بر پتانسیل و فشار تورم است. از طرفی بهسازی این­گونه خاک­ها که در زمره خاک­های مسئله­دار هستند همیشه مورد توجه محققین بوده است. در ادامه این تحقیق نمونه­ای از خاک­های فوق با 57/10 درصد گچ و با پتانسیل تورم مشخص انتخاب گردید و به سه روش مختلف بهسازی شامل اختلاط با آهک، اختلاط دو زمانه با آهک و اختلاط با سیمان بهسازی شد. مقدار ماده افزودنی در این سه روش 1، 2، 3 و 4 درصد بود که پس از مخلوط و متراکم نمودن، به وزن مخصوص خشک 83/1 گرم بر سانتی­متر مکعب رسید. نتایج بهسازی روی این­گونه خاک­های متورم شونده نشان می­دهد که روش اختلاط با سیمان می­تواند فشار تورم نمونه­ها را به مقدار قابل ملاحظه­ای کاهش دهد و خصوصیات تورمی آنها را به طور قابل توجهی اصلاح نماید.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The existence of swelling soils causes irretrievable damages to buildings all over the world. Due to the swelling property of the gypsum soils, located in South West of Mashhad, many problems such as cracking in building, heaving of walls, and pavement and bulging of floors have been reported. The soil in this region is generally fine and based on Unified Classification is predominantly ML and CL. In the present research, 6 typical samples, among many gathered samples, with identical gradation but different amount of gypsum, were selected. After determination of main geotechnical properties of samples (including gypsum percent, Atterberg limits, natural unit weight and density), the effect of gypsum amount on the swelling potential and swelling pressure was investigated. Considering the influence of degree of compaction, on the swelling potential and swelling pressure, 10 samples for each of 6 typical soils, with identical moisture content but different unit weight were prepared and the variation of the swelling potential and swelling pressure were studied. The results of this research indicate the harsh effect of the gypsum amount, degree of compaction and moisture content on the swelling potential and swelling pressure. The improvement of such soils which are a type of problematic soils has been of many researchers interest. In the present research a sample with 10.57% gypsum and unit weight of 1.83 g/cm3 and with a determined swelling potential was improved using three different methods, including mixing with lime, double mixing with lime and mixing with cement. The amount of admixture for all three methods was 1, 2, 3 and 4 percent. The results of this research indicate that mixing with cement is able to reduce considerably the swelling potential and to improve the swelling specifications of this type of soil.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>33</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>46</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>جعفر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بلوری بزاز</Family>
						<NameE>Jafar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Bolouri Bazaz</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>   استادیار گروه عمران، دانشکده مهندسی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>   استادیار گروه عمران، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>bolouri@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حمید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رجایی</Family>
						<NameE>Hamid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rajaea</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>  کارشناس ارشد ژئوتکنیک، دانشگاه صنعتی شریف</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>  کارشناس ارشد ژئوتکنیک، دانشگاه صنعتی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hmd_rajaee@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خاک گچی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پتانسیل تورم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فشار تورم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تراکم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>وزن مخصوص</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بهسازی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آهک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اختلاط دو زمانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سیمان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>فاخر، ع. و عسگری، ف. (1372)، تورم و واگرایی خاکها از دید مهندسی ژئوتکنیک، انتشارات جهاد دانشگاهی دانشگاه تهران##Ameta N. K., Purohit D. G. M., and Wayal A. S., 2007, Characteristics, Problems and Remedies of Expansive Soils of Rajathan, India, Electronic Journal of Geotechnical Engineering, Vol.12,Bundle E, pp 1-8.##Azma, S., Abduljauwad, S. N. and Al-Amoudi, O. S. B., 2003, Volume Change Behavior of Arid Calcareous Soils, Journal of  Natural Hazards Review, Vol. 4, No. 2.##Bandyopadhyay S. S. (1981) Prediction of Swelling Potential for Natural Soil, ASCE, Journal of Geotechnical Engineering Division, Vol. 107, No. GTS7.##Chen R. H. (1975) Foundations on Expansive Soils, Elsevier Science Publishers.##Chen F. H. (1988) The Basic Physical Properties of Expansive Soils, Proceeding of the 3rd International Conference on Expansive Soils, Haifa, Israel.##Dongxu L., Zhongzi X., Zhimin L., Zhihua P. and Cheng L. (2002) The Activation and Hydration of Glassy Cementitious Materials, Cement and Concrete Research Journal, Elsevier Science Ltd. Vol.32 pp.1145-1152.##Einstein H. H. (1996) &quot;Tunneling in difficult ground&quot;, Swelling Behavior And Identification of Swelling Rocks, Rock Mechanics, Rock Engineering, Vol. 29, No. 3, pp. 113 –117.##Ferris G. A., Eades J. L., Graves R. E. and Mclellan G. H. (1995) Improved Characteristics in Sulfate Soils Treated with Barium Compounds Before Lime Stabilization, Transportation Research Record, 1259, pp. 45-51.##Hunter D. (1988) Lime Induced Heave in Sulfate, Bearing Clay Soils, Journal of Geotechnical Engineering, ASCE, Vol. 114, No. 2, pp. 150-167.##Mitchell J. K. (1986) Practical Problems from Surprising Soil Behavior, Journal of Geotechnical Engineering, ASCE, Vol. 112, No. 3, pp. 259-289.##Prakash B. S., Kota D. H., Hazlett D. and Perin L. (1996), Sulfate–Bearing Soils : Problems with Calcium–Based Stabilizers, Transportation Research Record 1546 TRR, pp. 62-69.##Shahid A. and Sahel N. A. (2000) Influence of Gypsification on Engineering Behavior of Expansive Clays, ASCE, Journal of Geotechnical and Geo-Environmental Engineering, Vol. 126, No. 6, pp. 538-542.##Wild S., Kinuthia J. M., Jones G. I., and Higgins D. D. (1998) Effects of Partial Substitution of Lime with Ground Granulated Blast Furnace Slag (GGBS) on the Strength Properties of Lime-Stabilized Sulphate-Bearing Clay Soils, Engineering Geology Journal, Elsevier Science Ltd. Vol. 51 pp. 37-53.##Wild S., Kinuthia J. M., Jones G. I., and Higgins D. D. (1999) Suppression of Swelling Associated with Ettringite Formation in Lime Stabilized Sulphate Bearing Clay Soils by Partial Substitution of Lime with Ground Granulated Blast Furnace Slag, Engineering Geology Journal, Elsevier Science Ltd. Vol. 51 pp. 257-277.##Yaujun D.; Shenglin L. and Shigenori H. (1999), Swelling-Shrinkage Properties and Soil Improvement of Compacted Expansive Soil, Journal of Engineering Geology No. 53, pp. 351-358.##Yucel G. and Hakan K. (2003) Environmental Effects on Expansive Soils, First International Conference on Environmental Research and Assessment, Bucharest, Romania.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>طراحی وساخت مدل فیزیکی شبیه سازی زمین‌لغزش با هدف ارزیابی توانایی روش-های ژئوالکتریک در آشکار سازی هندسه زمین‌لغزش‌ها</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Design and construction a physical model of a pseudo landslide in order to geoelectrical investigation in experimental scale for detecting the landslide geometry</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>مطالعه پیرامون رخداد و رفتار زمین­لغزش‌ها به منظور پایدارسازی و کاهش خطرات ناشی از آنها همیشه مورد توجه مهندسان بوده است. یکی از مسائل مهم در مطالعه زمین‌لغزش‌ها تعیین هندسه وعمق سطح گسیختگی است. امروزه روش‌های مختلفی برای بررسی هندسه زمین لغزش وجود دارد. روش‌های ژئوفیزیکی به­ویژه روش مقاومت ویژه الکتریکی یکی از بهترین و سریع‌ترین روش‌ها است. در این تحقیق هدف، فراهم کردن یک بستر مناسب برای انجام مطالعات ژئوالکتریک روی مدل‌های آزمایشگاهی و کوچک مقیاس به منظور یافتن بهترین روش‌ها برای مطالعه زمین‌لغزش به روش مقاومت ویژه الکتریکی است. برای رسیدن به این هدف یک مدل فیزیکی شبه زمین‌لغزش داخل یک تانک ژئوالکتریک طراحی و ساخته شد. مراحل آماده‌سازی و انجام تست‌های مختلف روی تانک ژئوالکتریک به منظور رسیدن به بهترین نتیجه طبق آخرین یافته‌ها، انجام گرفت. نتیجه نهایی مطالعه ژئوالکتریک، تهیه مقطع مقاومت ویژه‌ای است که بر مدل ساخته شده انطباق بسیار خوبی دارد و موید این واقعیت است است که می‌توان تحقیقات گسترده‌ای در مورد روش‌های مختلف مطالعه ژئوفیزیکی و زمین‌لغزش­ها انجام داد و بهترین روش را برای کار صحرایی انتخاب کرد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>A landslide is a geological phenomenon which includes a wide range of destruction and damage. Determination of landslide geometry is an important problem in study of landslides. Geophysics methods, especially geoelectric, are the best ways to study the landslide geometry. In this regard an experimental model was provided for geoelectrical investigation. One of the preparation steps of the model is to test the geoelectric tank.the final stage is to provide a resistivity pseudo section.in the result of the resistivity pseudo section have a good fitness to the boundary of pseudo landslide. Researcher can test a lot of different geoelectrical arrays and choose the best one for use in the field.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>47</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>58</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رمضانی</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ramezani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>   دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد ژئوفیزیک دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>   دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد ژئوفیزیک</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>میرستار</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مشین‌چی‌اصل</Family>
						<NameE>Mirsattar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Meshinchi_Asl</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم وتحقیقات</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شریعت جعفری</Family>
						<NameE>Mohsen</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Shariat Jafari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>    عضو هیئت علمی پژوهشکده حفاظت خاک وآبخیزداری</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>    عضو هیئت علمی پژوهشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mshariatj@hotmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عباسی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Abbasi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد ژئوفیزیک دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد ژئوفیزیک دانشگاه آزاد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>: تانک ژئوالکتریک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شبه مقطع مقاومت ویژه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شبه زمین‌لغزش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>اسلامی هرندی،  مجتبی. (1383)، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد: مطالعه نظری وتجربی روی لایه‌های شیب‌دار با روش مقاومت ویژه و مقایسه نتایج با لایه‌های افقی. گروه ژئوفیزیک دانشگاه رازی.##بیت اللهی، علی. (1382) بررسی زمین‌لغزش‌ها با روش‌های ژئوالکتریکی نشریه مرکز تحقیقات ساختمان و مسکن.##خاکی، محمود. (1386)، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد: مقایسه روش‌های گوس نیوتون وشبه نیوتون در تفسیر وارون داده‌های مقاومت ویژه دوبعدی با آرایش‌های مختلف. گروه ژئوفیزیک دانشگاه رازی.##شریعت جعفری، محسن، (1375) زمین‌لغزش (مبانی و اصول پایداری شیب‌های طبیعی) انتشارات سازه##نصرآزادانی، احمد. (1388) ارزیابی و تعیین سطح لغزش با استفاده از روش ژئوالکتریک (مطالعه موردی منطقه پیشکوه فریدونشهر) ششمین کنفرانس زمین‌شناسی مهندسی و محیط‌زیست ایران، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، مهر 1388##هلاکوئی،  عبدالاحد. (1386)، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد: مدل‌سازی معکوس ژئوالکتریکی دو بعدی برای تعیین هندسه زمین‌لغزش در کیلومتر 52+200 بزرگراه قزوین- رشت. گروه ژئوفیزیک دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود.##Apparao and A. Roy )1971(:Resistivity model experiments. Geoexploration, 9:195-205##Björn Heincke, (2006): Characterizing an unstable mountain slope using shallow 2D and  3D seismic tomography. Geophysics، vol. 71،  No. 6 november-december 2006;   P. B241–B256.##Colin G. Farquharson, (2006): Comparison of integral equation and physical scale modeling of the electromagnetic responses of models with large conductivity contrasts. Geophysics، vol. 71, No. 4 July-August 2006; P. G169–G177,  10 .##Daily,  W. D.,  Ramirez,  A. L., and Johnson, R., )1998(: Electrical impedance tomography of a      perchloroethylene release: Journal of Environmental and Engineering Geophysics, 2, 189–201.##G. W. Jia (2009): Performance of a large-scale slope model subjected to rising and lowering water levels Engineering Geology 106 (2009) 92–103##Karl J. Ellefsen, (2004): Numerical study of electromagnetic waves generated by a prototype dielectric logging tool. Geophysics, vol. 69, No. 1 (January - February 2004); P. 64–77.##W. L. Lai, (2006): Experimental determination of bulk dielectric properties and porosity of porous asphalt and soils using GPR and a cyclic moisture variation technique Geophysics, vol. 71, No. 4 July-August 2006; P. K93–K102.##Mu Luo and Brian J. Evansz, (2004): An amplitude-based multiazimuth approach to mapping fractures using P-wave 3D seismic data. Geophysics, vol. 69, No. 3 (May-June 2004); P. 690–698.##A. Perrone، (2004): High-resolution electrical imaging of the Varco d’Izzo earthflow (southern Italy) Journal of Applied Geophysics 56 (2004) 17– 29.##E. Piegari, (2009): Electrical resistivity tomography and statistical analysis in landslide modelling: A conceptual approach Journal of Applied Geophysics (2009)##D. J. Verschuur 1 and A. J. Berkhout, (2005): 2Removal of internal multiples with the common-focus-point (CFP) approach: Part 2-Application strategies and data examples. Geophysics, vol. 70,  No. 3 (May-June 2005); P. V61–V72.##Vincenzo Lapenna, (2005): 2D electrical resistivity imaging of some complex landslides in the Lucanian Apennine chain, southern Italy. Geophysics, vol. 70, No.3 (May-June 2005); P. B11–B18.##S. C. Yim, (2009): Exprimental and computational activities  at the  Oregon  state university NEES  tsunami  research facility Science of Tsunami Hazards,  Vol. 28,  No. 1,  page 2 (2009).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر شکل گسیختگی بر مقاومت تراکمی تک محوره‌ی نمونه‌های سنگی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Assessing effect of mode of failure
on uniaxial compressive strength of rock samples</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>تعیین مقاومت تراکمی تک محوره‌ی نمونه­های سنگی در‌ آزمایشگاه به عنوان یکی از پارامترهای بسیار مهم در مهندسی سنگ همواره با مشکلات زیادی همراه می­باشد. یکی از مهم­ترین مشکلات در این زمینه، پراکندگی نتایج آزمایش­های تراکمی تک محوره و نبود معیار خاصی برای انتخاب داده­های معرف مقاومت ماده‌ی سنگ می­باشد. بررسی شکل و نحوه‌ی شکست نمونه­ها در آزمایش تک محوره مؤید تأثیر به سزای ریزشکستگی­ها و ناپیوستگی­های میکروسکوپی در شکل شکست و نتایج آزمایش می­باشد. نتایج این تحقیق نشان می­دهد که حداکثر نسبت مقاومت تراکمی تک محوره به مقاومت کششی و در نتیجه حداکثر مقدار مقاومت تراکمی تک محوره در شکست نوع کششی ساده بوقوع می­پیوندد که این موضوع معرف عدم تأثیر یا تأثیر بسیارکم ریزشکستگی­ها در شکست نمونه در این حالت، برخلاف سایر اشکال گسیختگی می­باشد. در حد نهایی دیگر حداقل نسبت مقاومت تراکمی تک محوره به مقاومت کششی و نیز مقاومت تراکمی تک محوره متعلق به نمونه­هایی است که دارای شکست نوع برشی ساده بوده و در این حالت شکستگی نمونه به طور کامل متأثر از ریزشکستگی‌ها می‌باشد. بنابراین با توجه به نسبت مقاومت تراکمی تک محوره به مقاومت کششی و هم­چنین شکل شکست نمونه­ها به راحتی می­توان داده­های واقعی معرف مقاومت تراکمی تک محوره‌ی ماده‌ی سنگ را انتخاب نمود. در این تحقیق معیار مناسبی جهت انتخاب داده­های درست آزمایش تراکمی تک محوره ارائه گردیده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Determining the UCS of rock samples as one of the most important parameters of rock engineering is so difficult because of occurrence of so many problems. One of the most important problems  in this regard  is  the scattering  of  the  results of USC tests  and lack of  specific  criteria for  choosing  the data which represents  the strength of intact rock. Investigating the form and  the mechanism of  samples failure  through the  USC tests shows the significant  impact of  micro-fractures and microscopic discontinuities  on  the failure mode  and  also on test results.  According to the research results, that the maximum ratio of  UCS to tensile strength  and consequently  maximum  rate of USC occurs in  the simple extension failure which indicates no impact or  so weak impact  of micro-fractures on  the sample failure of this type unlike other types. In case of other extreme,  the minimum USC  ratio  to tensile  strength  and the USC belongs to  the samples  with  simple shearing failure and in this case  the failures is totally impacted by  micro-fractures. So regarding the ratio of USC to tensile strength and also considering the samples fracture mode, the real data representing the USC of intact rock could be chosen. The suitable criteria for choosing the correct data of the UCS tests is submitted in this research</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>59</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>72</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بشیر گنبدی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Bashir Gonbadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>bashir@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ارومیه ای</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Oromiehei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه اربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه اربیت مدرس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>uromeiea@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نیکودل</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nikudel</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار بخش زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار بخش زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه تربیت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>nikudelm@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>غلامرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>لشکری پور</Family>
						<NameE>Gholam Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Lashkaripour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>4-      استاد بخش زمین‌شناسی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>4-      استاد بخش</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>lashkarg@hamoon.usb.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مقاومت تراکمی تک محوره</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ماسه سنگ</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شکل شکست</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ریزشکستگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سازند شمشک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>ASTM (American society for testing and materials) (2000) Standard test method for elastic moduli of Undrained Intact Rock Core Specimens in Triaxial Compression without Pore Pressure Measurement, Designation D 5407-95.##Fairhurst, C. and Cook, N. G. W. (1966) The phenomenon of rock splitting parallel to the direction of maximum compression in the neighbourhood of a surface, in Proceedings 1st Congress ISRM, Vol 1, 687-690 (ISRM: Lisbon).##Farmer, I. W., Kemeny, J. M. (1992) Deficiencies in rock test data. In: Proc., Int Symp. Eurock ’92, London, 298–303.##Folk, R. L. (1980) Petrology of sedimentary rocks. Austin Texas, Hemphill’s bookstore, pp. 182.##Gramberg, J. (1989) A non-conventional view on rock mechanics. Balkema, Rotterdam.##Hoek, E. and Brown, E. T. (1980) Underground Excavations in Rock, (Institution of Mining and Metallurgy: London).##Horii, H. and Nemat-Naser, S. (1985) Compression-induced microcracks growth in brittle solids: axial splitting and shear failure, Journal of Geophysical Research, 90(B4): 3105 - 3125.##Hudson, J. A., Harrison, J. P.  (1997) Engineering rock mechanics. Pergamon, Oxford.##ISRM Suggested Method (1978) Suggested method for determining compressive strength of rock material, International Journal of Rock Mechanics. A Min Sci Geomech, Abst, 15(3):1978.##ISRM Suggested Method (1979) Suggested Method for Determining the Uniaxial Compressive Strength and Deformability of Rock Material, International Journal Rock Mechanics, A Min Sci Geomech Abst, 12(2):1979.##Jumikis, A. R. (1983) Rock Mechanics, (Trans Tech Publications:).## Paul, B. and Gangal, M. (1966) Initial and subsequent fracture curves for biaxial compression of brittle materials, in Proceedings 8th US Symposium on Rock Mechanics, 131-141.##Peng, S., Johnson, A. M. (1972) Crack growth and faulting in cylindrical specimen of chemsford granite. In: J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci. 9,37–86.##Reinhart, J. S. (1966) Fracture of rocks, Internatioal Journal of Fracture Mechanics, Vol 2.##Szwedzicki,T.(2007) A Hypothesis  on  Modes of  Failure of Rock Samples Tested in Uniaxial Compression. Int RockMech.RockEngng. 40(1),97–104.##Szwedzicki, T., Shamu, W. (1999) The effect of material discontinuities on strength of rock samples. In: Proc., Australasian Institute of Mining and Metallurgy. 304(1), 23–28.##Szwedzicki, T. and Donald, D. (1996) Assessment of mechanical parameters of rock using an indentation test, in Proceedings Annual Conference (The Australaian Institute of Mining and Metallurgy: Melbourne).##Vutukuri, V. S., Lama, R. D. and Saluja, S. S.(1974) Handbook on Mechanical Properties of Rock, Vol 1 (Trans Tech Publications).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی اثر ابعاد هندسی قطعه، بر روی چقرمگی شکست سنگ مرمر هرسین</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Effect of specimen dimensions on fracture toughness 
of Harsin marble rock</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>برای تعیین چقرمگی شکست یک ماده سنگی نیاز به یک قطعه استاندارد با ابعاد هندسی مشخص است. اگر ابعاد هندسی قطعه از مقادیر مشخصی کمتر باشد، چقرمگی شکست محاسبه شده از دقت لازم برخوردار نمی‌باشد. به منظور محاسبه صحیح چقرمگی شکست مواد سنگی معیارهای مختلفی برای تعیین حداقل ابعاد هندسی قطعه ارائه شده است. در این تحقیق، با انجام آزمایش روی قطعه نیم دیسک با ترک لبه‌ای که تحت خمش سه نقطه‌ای قرار دارد، معیارهای ارائه شده برای حداقل طول ترک و ضخامتمورد نیاز برای تعیین چقرمگی شکست، مورد بررسی قرار می‌گیرد. قطعات تهیه شده، از جنس سنگ مرمر هرسین است. نتایج آزمایش‌های شکست انجام شده بر روی این سنگ نشان می‌دهد که معیارهای ارائه شده جامعیت لازم را برای تخمین این دو پارامتر در ماده سنگی آزمایش شده نداشته و لذا در این مقاله با در نظر گرفتن ضرایب تصحیح برای روابط مربوط به محاسبه حداقل طول ترک و ضخامت قطعه، معیارهای مربوطه به نحوی اصلاح می‌شوند که بتوانند نتایج حاصل از آزمایش شکست انجام شده بر روی سنگ مرمر هرسین را پیش‌بینی نماید.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The determination of fracture toughness of a rock material requires a standard specimen with specific geometry dimensions. If the dimensions of specimen are lower than special values, the obtained fracture toughness may not be accurate. In order to attain the fracture toughness of rock materials correctly, several criteria have been proposed for the required minimum dimensions. In this study, some tests were conducted on the semi-circular specimen containing an edge crack and subjected to three-point-bend loading (SCB specimen) and the suggested criteria for the required minimum crack length and thickness were assessed. The specimens were made of Harsin marble rock. The results obtained from the fracture tests showed that these criteria are not comprehensive and are not consistent with the experimental results. Therefore, by using the necessary correction factors in equations related to the minimum crack length and thickness, these equations were revised such that they can estimate the experimentally observed results for the Harsin rock.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>73</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>82</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مجیدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>آیت اللهی</Family>
						<NameE>Majid Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ayatollahi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>1-      آزمایشگاه خستگی و شکست دانشکده مکانیک دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>1-      آزمایشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.ayat@iust.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حامد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ثقفی</Family>
						<NameE>Hamed</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Saghafi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>1-      آزمایشگاه خستگی و شکست دانشکده مکانیک دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>1-      آزمایشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمدعلیها</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mohammad Aliha</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>آزمایشگاه خستگی و شکست دانشکده مکانیک دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>آزمایشگاه خستگی و شکست دانشکده مکانیک دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>: مواد سنگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>چقرمگی شکست</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قطعه SCB</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>طول ترک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ضخامت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سنگ مرمر هرسین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>آیت­اللهی مجیدرضا، محمدرضا محمدعلیها، سعید خادمی، &quot; تعیین استحکام کششی مواد سنگی به کمک قطعات دایره­ای شکل&quot;، پانزدهمین کنفرانس سالانه(بین المللی) مهندسی مکانیک ISME2007، 1386.##فاروق حسینی محمد، &quot;درآمدی بر مکانیک سنگ&quot;، انتشارات نشر کتاب دانشگاهی، تهران، ایران، 1378، صفحه 16##Barton C. C.,”Variables in fracture energy and toughness of Rock”, Proc. 24rd Us Symp. on Rock Mech., The Univ. of California, Berkeley, California, R.E. Goodman &amp; F.E. Heuze (Eds.), 1983, pp. 449-462.##Chong K. P., Kuruppu M. D., Kuszmaul J. S.,” Fracture toughness determination of layered materials”, Engng Fract. Mech. 28, 1987, pp. 43-54.##Chong K. P. and Kuruppu M. D., ”New specimen for fracture toughness determination for rock and other Materials ”, International Journal of Fracture, 26, 1984, pp. 59-62.##Fowell R. J., Chen J. F.,” The third chevron-notch rock fracture specimen-the cracked chevron-notched Brazilian disk”, Proc. 31st U.S. Syrup. On Rock Mechanics, 1990, pp. 295-302.##Ingraffea A. R., Schmidt R. A.,” Experimental verification of a fracture mechanics model for tensile strength prediction of Indiana limestone. Proc. 19th U.S. Svmp. on Rock Mechanics, 1979, pp. 247-253.##Khan K., Al-Shayea N. A.,” Effect of specimen geometry and testing method on mixed I-II   fracture toughness of a limestone rock from Saudi Arabia ”. Rock Mech. and Rock Eng., 33, 2000, pp.179–206.##Lim I. L., JohnstonI. W., Choi S. K., Boland J. N., ”Fracture testing of a soft rock with semi-circular specimens under three-point bending. Part 1 – mode I ”, Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci. Geomech. Abstr., 31, 1994, pp.199-212.##Schmidt R. A.,” Fracture-toughness testing of limestone”, Exp. Mech. 16, 1976, pp. 161-167.##Schmidt R. A., Lutz T. J.,” KIC and JIC of Westerly granite-effects of thickness and in-plane dimensions”, ASTM STP 678, 1979, pp. 166-182.##Singh R. N. and Sun G. X.,” An investigation into factors affecting fracture toughness of coal measures sandstone”, J. Mines, Metals &amp; Fuels, 1990, pp. 111-118.##Soo-Ho Chang, Chung-In Lee, Seokwon Jeon.,” Measurement of rock fracture toughness under modes I and II and mixed-mode conditions by using disc-type specimens ”, Engineering Geology,66, 2002, pp.79–97.##Sun Z., Ouchterlony F.,” Fracture toughness of Stripa granite cores”, Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci. &amp; Geomech. Abstr., 23, 1986, pp. 399-409.##Sun G., Singh R.N.,” A numerical and experimental investigation for determining fracture toughness of Welsh limestone ”, Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci. Geomech. Abstr., 31, 1994, pp. 199-212.##Whittaker B. N., Singh R. N., Sun G. ”Rock Fracture Mechanics, Principles, Design and Applications”, Developments in Geotechnical Engineering, 71. Elsevier, Amsterdam, 1992.##Williams M. L.,” On the stress distribution at the base of a stationary crack”, Journal of Applied Mechanics, 24, 1957, pp. 109-114.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>اثر تورم خاک بستر بر کانال‌های انتقال آب دشت تبریز و ارائه‌ی راهکاراصلاحی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The effect of swelling on the lining of tabriz plain canals and a countermeasure method</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هر ساله تعداد بسیار زیادی از سازه‌های جدید بر روی خاک­های متورم شونده ساخته می‌شوند. بخش عمده‌ای از این سازه‌ها متحمل خسارت‌های کوچک از قبیل ترک می‌گردند و بخشی نیز به شدت آسیب می‌بینند که دیگر قابل تعمیر نیستند. رفتار‌های مختلف خاک بستر کانال­ها که سازه­های سبکی می­باشند از جمله تورم، واگرایی و نشست مشکلات گوناگونی را برای آنها ایجاد می­کنند. لایه­های بالای دشت تبریز عموماً متشکل از ریزدانه­ها و اکثراً از جنس رس می­باشند. مطالعات مکانیک خاک نشان می­دهد که تغییرات پتانسیل تورم در این منطقه نسبتاً گسترده می­باشد. به این معنی که در بعضی از قسمت­ها پتانسیل تورم کاملاً ناچیز و در بعضی از قسمت­ها در حد متوسط و بعضاً متوسط به بالا می­باشد. بعضی از قسمت­های کانال اصلی طرح آجی­چای دشت تبریز (آذربایجان شرقی) متحمل ترک­ها و بالا آمدگی­هایی شد که بعد از بررسی­ها و آزمایش­ها این مشکلات به بحث تورم خاک نسبت داده شد. در این مقاله به بررسی کامل این فرضیه پرداخته می­شود.   آزمایش­های انجام یافته مورد تحلیل قرار گرفته و پیشنهاداتی برای جلوگیری و تقلیل اثر این پدیده ارائه می­گردد. برای بررسی اثر اصلاحی این روش قسمتی از کانال پر از آب شده و تغییر شکل کانال در اثر تورم به شکل دقیقی مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفته و نتایج آن ارائه می­گردد</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Many structures are being constructed on expansive soil every year. A considerable part of these structures are damaged such as cracks and a part of them are destroyed. When the irrigation canals are located on problematic soils like expansive and dispersive soils, different damages may occur. Top layers of Tabriz plain are generally consisted of fine grain soils and clays. A comprehensive site investigation was undertaken and the results show that the swelling potential varies from low to medium-high. Some parts of the AjiChay main canal of Tabriz (East Azerbaijan) suffered cracks and small uplifts. After investigation it was shown that these damages could be caused by soil bed swelling. In this paper this hypothesis was investigated. Different tests were undertaken to understand the phenomena and a countermeasure method was undertaken to reduce damages.In order to evaluate the effectiveness of countermeasure method, a part of canal was selected and filled with water and the deformation of canal caused by swelling was studied.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>83</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>98</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مسعود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حاجی علیلوی بناب</Family>
						<NameE>Hajialilue Bonab</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Masoud</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>1-      دانشگاه تبریز، دانشکده مهندسی عمران، رایانامه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>1-      دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hajialilue@tabrizu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فریبا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بهروز سرند</Family>
						<NameE>Fariba</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Behrouz Sarand</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization> دانشگاه تبریز، دانشکده مهندسی عمران، رایانامه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University> دانشگاه تبریز، دانشکده مهندسی عمران،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>fsarand@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>چشم دوست</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Cheshmdoost</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>مهندسین مشاور یکم و توان آب</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>مهندسین مشاور یکم و توان آب</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تورم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کانال‌های انتقال آب</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فیلتر</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آب اندازی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دشت تبریز</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Altmeyer, W.T., (1955) “Discussion of Engineering properties of expansive clays” Proceeding American Society of Civil Engineering 81. separate No. 658. pp. 17-19##Chen, F.H., (1975) “Foundation on Expansive Soild”, Elsevier Scientific Publishing Company”, Amsterdam.##El-Sohby, M.A., Rabba, E.A., (1981) “Some Factors Affecting Swelling of Clayey Soils”, Geotechnical Engineering, Vol. 12, pp. 19-33##Hallett, P.D., Newson, T.A., (2005) “Describing soil crack formation using elastic – plastic fracture mechanics”, European Journal of Soil Science 56, pp.31–38.##Holts, W.G., Gibbs, H.J., (1956) “Engineering Properties of Expansive clays”, Transact. ASCE 121. pp. 641-677##Jones D.E., and Holts, W.G., (1973) “Expansive soil- the hidden disaster”, Civil Engineering. ASCE 43(8). pp. 49-51##Lambe, T.W., and Whitman, R.V., (1969) “Soil Mechanics”, John Wiley and Sons, Co Inc., New York##Parker, J.C., Amos, D.F., Zelazny, L.W., (1982) Water adsorption and swelling of clay minerals in soil systems”, Soil Science Society of America Journal 46, pp.450–456.##Raman, V., (1967) “Identifications of expansive soils from the plasticity index and the shrinkage index data”, The Indian Engineer 11 (1967) (1), pp. 17–22.##Schafer, W.M., Singer, M.J., (1976) “Influence of physical and mineralogical properties on swelling of soils in Yolo County, California”, Soil Science Society of America Journal 40, 557–562.##Seed, H.B., Woodward, R.J., Lundgren, R., (1962) “Prediction of swelling potential for compacted clays”, Journal of S.M.F. Division, ASCE, 88, SM3, 53–87.##Snethen, D.R., (1984) “Evaluation of Expedient Methods for Identification of Potentially Expansive Soils”, 5th International Conference on Expansive Soils, Adelaide, South Australia.##Towner, G.D., (1987) “The mechanisms of cracking of drying clay”, Journal of Agricultural. Engineering Research 36, 115–124.##Van Der Merwe, D.H., (1964) “The prediction of heave from the plasticity index and percentage clay fraction of soils”, Civil Engineer in South Africa 6, pp. 103–106##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				