<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 3 و 4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Evaluation of land subsidence related disasters in plains and residential areas of Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی پی‌آمدهای ناشی از پدیده فرونشست در اراضی و دشت‌های مسکونی ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>43</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>58</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68238</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>شریفی‌کیا</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه سنجش از راه دور، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Land subsidence caused by heavy exploitation of groundwater is an acquaintance morphological phenomena occurrence Iran. Recently the areas involved with this phenomena has been rapidly increased, covered most part of Iran’s areas from desert land in center to semi moisture areas in west and north-west. This is mainly due to saver frequency drought occurred during last decade. The wide distribution of land subsidence occurrence over residential areas has brought serious problems and damage which appeared this phenomenon in form of Geo-Hazard for the country. As the most part of the areas involved with land subsidence are located in a high seismic zone, the simultaneity of land subsidence with earthquake occurrence can inclemently increase individual damage from each and converting these events to the disaster. The present research deals with lands subsidence areas identification and mapping for disaster evaluation over the counter. In other to extract the land subsidence vulnerability and hazard over the Iran’s areas, the land subsidence outcome map was superimposing with settlement and infrastructure distribution map. In the next step, the vulnerable residential and  infrastructure areas where overlaid with seismic hazard map to estimate and predict probable disaster. Thus, to mapping land subsidence over the country, the 18 areas where reported as land subsidence prone areas has been extracted from previous studies, where in 15 more areas the phenomena was measured using Differential Interferometric Synthetic Aperture Radar- D-InSAR techniques. The result of superimposing land subsidence map with seismic zonation map of Iran showed most land subsidence areas are located in a high hazard seismic zone. The reach outcome also shown earthquake occurrence over the land subsidence prone area can be a trigger for land collapsing over residential area, which can make double disaster. Moreover, land subsidence hazard can cause flood hazard over the residential areas where are not involved with this hazard so far. This is because of changing the river bed morphology and land downfall due to subsidence phenomena.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">فرونشست ناشی از ازدیاد بهره برداری از منابع آب زیرزمینی نسبت به توان ترمیمی آن در برخی نواحی داخلی ایران، سابقه طولانی دارد. تشدید این شرایط ناشی از خشکسالی‌های مکرر در سال‌های اخیر، علاوه بر نواحی خشک ایران مرکزی، نواحی نیمه خشک یا نسبتاً مرطوب شمال‌غربی کشور را با این پدیده درگیر ساخته است. فراگیری فرونشست در اغلب نواحی مسکون و پرجمعیت کشور و در پی داشتن خسارات فراگیر، این پدیده را در فرم یک مخاطره زمینی برای کشور مطرح ساخته است. با توجه به فراهم بودن زیرساخت مخاطره آمیز لرزه‌ای برای اغلب نواحی کشور، همزادی و همزمانی رخداد زمین لرزه در اراضی که فرونشست در آن حادث شده، امکان تشدید خسارات و ایجاد تلفات وسیع برای زایش یک فاجعه را فراهم آورده است. این تحقیق با هدف بررسی وضعیت فراگیری پدیده فرونشست در ایران و هم‌نهادسازی آن با الگوی توزیعی سکونتگاه‌ها و زیرساخت‌ها، به تبیین روند تبدیل پدیده به مخاطره پرداخته، سپس با سنجش شرایط مخاطره آمیز ناشی از همزادی آن با سایر مخاطرات، قابلیت پذیری رویداد فاجعه احتمالی را در برخی بسترهای نا امن معرفی نموده است. بدین منظور و با استفاده از مطالعات مقدم اطلاعات مربوط به نرخ و دامنه فضایی فرونشست برای 18 دشت کشور استخراج و برای 15 دشت دیگر نیز این مساله به کمک تکنیک تداخل سنجی راداری تبیین گردید. یافته نهایی نشان داد که فرونشست علاوه بر تهدیدات و توان خسارت‌زایی و فاجعه آفرینی فراگیر آن در نواحی مسکون، قادر به زایش مخاطره سیل و فاجعه‌سازی در رویداد زمین لرزه‌های کم شدت و عموماً غیر مخرب است. این تحقیق روشن ساخت رویداد فرونشست در دشت‌های کم شیب کشور، قادر است از طریق تغییر در تراز ایستایی سطح آب زیرزمینی، مخاطره سیل را ایجاد و یا تشدید نماید. به نحوی که بسیاری از نواحی مسکون کشور با زایش دو مخاطره نوین (سیل و فرونشست) مواجه می‌باشند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرونشست</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زمین‌لرزه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مخاطره</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فاجعه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تداخل سنجی راداری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیل</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68238_eda48dc59881ef03a4d519ca1556b0c5.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
