<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 3 و 4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Correlation of microscopic mineralogical and textural properties versus physical and mechanical properties of gabbroic and diorite rocks in Natanz area</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارتباط خواص کانی‌شناسی و بافتی میکروسکوپی با خصوصیات فیزیکی و مکانیکی سنگ‌های گابرو و دیوریت نطنز</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>69</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>78</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68335</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مسعود</FirstName>
					<LastName>ترکان</LastName>
<Affiliation>1. دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مکانیک سنگ، دانشکده مهندسی معدن، دانشگاه صنعتی اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>ایران‌نژادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکده مهندسی معدن، دانشگاه صنعتی اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>باغبانان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکده مهندسی معدن، دانشگاه صنعتی اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Microscopic and geomechanical properties of construction igneous rocks include the degree of alteration, the presence of microfractures, peak strength, porosity, the proportion of detrimental minerals, etc. As reported in the literature, porosity in igneous rocks has a significant negative on the peak strength of rock samples. In this research, samples of gabbro and diorite rocks from a construction stone quarry in west of Natanz were selected and subject to microscopic and geomechanical investigations. As per thin section investigations, the degree of alteration, the presence of microfractures, and the minerals detrimental to the strength of construction stones were studied. Therefore, the geomechanical experiments including determination of density, porosity, durability index, the Brazilian and triaxial tests were conducted. The obtained data were compared to standard values and consequently a qualitative correlation between strength and microscopic properties was detected, accentuating the importance of microscopic studies in the investigations upon construction stones. The correlation thereupon may be applied in the different stages of exploration, exploitation, and processing of the construction stones and in order to avoid prodigious costs and destruction in the environment and domestic resources. </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">خصوصیات میکروسکوپی و ژئومکانیکی سنگ‌های ساختمانی آذرین شامل مواردی از جمله میزان دگرسانی، وجود ریزدرزه‌ها، مقاومت نهایی، تخلخل، میزان کانی‌های مضر و ... می‌باشد. براساس پژوهش‌های قبلی، تخلخل در سنگ‌های آذرین به شدت بر روی مقاومت نهایی نمونه‌ی سنگی تأثیرگذار بوده و آن را کاهش می‌دهد. در این تحقیق یک نمونه سنگ گابرویی و یک نمونه سنگ دیوریتی متعلق به یکی از معادن سنگ ساختمانی غرب نطنز انتخاب شدند و مورد بررسی‌های میکروسکوپی و ژئومکانیکی قرار گرفتند. با توجه به مطالعات مقاطع نازک سنگ میزان دگرسانی، وجود ریزدرزه‌ها و کانی‌های مضر مؤثر بر روی استحکام سنگ‌های ساختمانی برآورد گردید. سپس آزمایش‌های ژئومکانیکی مانند تعیین چگالی، تخلخل، شاخص دوام، آزمون کشش برزیلی و مقاومت سه محوره مطابق استانداردهای ISRM انجام شد. داده‌های حاصل با مقادیر استاندارد تطبیق داده شد و پس از آن رابطه‌ی کیفی بین مقاومت و خواص میکروسکوپی مشاهده شد که بیانگر اهمیت مطالعات میکروسکوپی سنگ‌های ساختمانی می‌باشد. از رابطه‌ی به دست آمده می‌توان در مراحل اکتشاف، استخراج و فرآوری سنگ‌های ساختمانی بهره جست و از صرف هزینه‌های گزاف، تخریب محیط‌زیست و منابع ملی که پیامد حذف این مطالعات می‌باشد، جلوگیری به عمل آورد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خصوصیات میکروسکوپی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ویژگی‌های ژئومکانیکی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دگرسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سنگ ساختمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گابرو</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دیوریت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68335_d36b92da1d7c484fc54d422a0b2be448.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
