<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Effect of Urban Wastewater on Chemical, Physical and Mechanical Properties of Soil
(Case Study: Central Area of Mashhad)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر پساب شهری بر پارامترهای شیمیایی، فیزیکی و مکانیکی خاک (مطالعه موردی: منطقه مرکزی شهر مشهد)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>33</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">86871</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نرجس</FirstName>
					<LastName>قهرمانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجو/ دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ناصر</FirstName>
					<LastName>حافظی مقدس</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه زمین شناسی مهندسی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>غفوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>غلامرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>لشکری پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه زمین شناسی مهندسی دانشگاه فردوسی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>13</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Chemical changes in the soil have a significant effect on its physical and mechanical properties and the rate of settlement. In this research, the effect of urban wastewater on chemical properties and soil engineering characteristics such as Atterberg limits, uniaxial compressive strength and consolidation parameters in central areas of Mashhad have been investigated. Based on the results, some chemical parameters such as Ca, Mg, Al and K decreased after the soil samples has been saturated by wastewater. Also, changing the chemical properties of the soil has changed its physical and mechanical parameters. For example, the consolidation parameters of the selected soil indicate that the (Cc) has increased over time with changes in the concentration of input wastewater. Also, the (Cs) has decreased over time and the rate of change in high concentrations is less. In addition, the results show that low concentrations of wastewater in short time have the greatest effect on reducing the uniaxial strength of soil. An examination of the electron microscope images shows that when the soil sample is saturated with wastewater, a layer of salt is accumulated around the soil particles, which expands the size and surface of the particles and also tends its structure towards the grain pattern. Therefore, simultaneously, the two factors of time and the change in concentration of wastewater affect the physical and mechanical parameters of the soil, and the effect of concentration on the time is more indicative.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">آلودگی با پساب شهری یکی از شایع‌ترین انواع آلودگی خاک در مناطق مسکونی و شهری است که اثر قابل توجهی بر پارامترهای فیزیکی و مقاومتی خاک دارد. در این پژوهش اثر پساب شهری بر خصوصیات شیمیایی و مهندسی نمونه‌ای خاک ریزدانه در مرکز شهر مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. برای این منظور خصوصیاتی نظیر حدود آتربرگ، مقاومت تک محوری و پارامترهای تحکیمی نمونه اولیه و نمونه‌هایی که بصورت مصنوعی با درصدهای مختلفی از پساب آغشته شده است، مقایسه گردیده است. نتایج این پژوهش نشان داد که مقاومت فشاری تک محوری و نشانه فشردگی (Cc) خاک مورد مطالعه با افزایش غلظت پساب ورودی و ایجاد تغییر در سیال میان منفذی افزایش پیدا کرده است در حالی که نشانه خمیری و نشانه تورم (Cs) خاک با افزایش غلظت آلاینده‌ها در خاک کاهش نشان می‌دهند. همچنین غلظت کم پساب در زمان کوتاه تاثیر بیشتری در تغییر خصوصیات خاک داشته است. بررسی تصاویر میکروسکوپ الکترونی نشان می‌دهد زمانی که نمونه خاک با پساب اشباع می‌گردد، لایه‌ای از نمک‌ها به دور ذرات خاک تجمع یافته و سبب افزایش اندازه و سطح دانه‌ها و تغییر در ساختار خاک به الگویی مشابه الگوی دانه‌ای می‌گردد. بنابراین دو عامل زمان و غلظت بر پارامترهای فیزیکی و مقاومتی خاک تاثیر گذار است و تاثیر غلظت نسبت به زمان، شاخص‌تر می‌باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نشت پساب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خواص فیزیکی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خواص مکانیکی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ترکیب شیمیایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">منطقه مرکزی شهر</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_86871_371c72bd877e3df19c371e8375cfa70c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
