<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 و 2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The assessment and analysis of the relationship between water pressure test and cement grout take at Seymareh dam grouting operation</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی و تحلیل ارتباط نتایج آزمون فشار آب و خورند دوغاب سیمانی در عملیات تزریق سد سیمره</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>69</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>84</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68375</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>بخشنده امنیه</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه معدن، پردیس دانشکده‌های فنی، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجید</FirstName>
					<LastName>مسعودی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای تخصصی معدن، گروه معدن، دانشکده مهندسی، دانشگاه کاشان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>One of the properties that evaluate in geotechnical reviews at rock mass, is  the amount of permeability, that determine from water pressure test (WPT) and lugeon number. From the results of these test, use in determining of the amount of groutability in tunnel and dam site. Logical and practical relationship between amount of water penetration in Sections and cement grout take, leads to find  prediction model of  take amount in sections and so, necessity and the amount of grouting defined and will Cause to optimization of grouting operation in terms of technical and economic. In this study, using the Seymareh dam site data, relationship between lugeon number and grout take analysed. Then the effect of rock mass quality and depth of the grouting section to this relationship were studied. The results showed that in surface and much deep sections, penetration of water and grout, with correlation coefficients 0/86 and 0/82 have more relationship than central and deep sections, with coefficients 0/62 and 0/58. also in terms of quality of rock mass (according to RQD coefficient), in sections with very good and poor quality, these two parameters with correlation coefficients, respectively, 0/82 and 0/75, are closer together than good and medium sections with the coefficients 0/54 and 0/58. In central sections with state average quality, because of existence karst cavities and filling of joints and happening of hydraulic fracture, this correlation reduce.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">یکی از ویژگی‌هایی که در بررسی­ ژئوتکنیکی توده‌سنگ‌ها ارزیابی می‌گردد، نفوذپذیری است که از آزمون فشار آب و عدد لوژن تعیین می‌گردد و از آن در تعیین تزریق‌پذیری ساختگاه سد و تونل و پیش‌بینی مقدار خورند استفاده می‌گردد. در این تحقیق، با استفاده از اطلاعات سد سیمره، ارتباط بین عدد لوژن و خورند تحلیل گردید و تاثیر وضعیت کیفی توده‌سنگ و عمق مقطع، بر این رابطه مطالعه گردید. نتایج نشان­ داد بر اساس مقادیر RQD، در گروه سنگ‌های با کیفیت بسیار خوب با ضریب همبستگی 82/0 بیشترین ارتباط بین لوژن و خورند وجود دارد و براساس عمق نیز، در مقاطع بسیار عمیق با ضریب 85/0، بالاترین همبستگی دیده می‌شود. علت همبستگی بالا در سنگ‌های با کیفیت مطلوب و در اعماق زیاد که تعداد درزه‌ها و میزان بازشدگی محدود است، مسیرهای مشخص نفوذ سیال است. در نتیجه نفوذپذیری با روندی یکنواخت برای آب و دوغاب همراه است. در سنگ‌های ضعیف با وجود احتمالی پرشدگی‌های رسی، شکستگی­ و بازشدگی‌های مختلفی دیده می‌شود که باعث نفوذ متفاوت آب نسبت به دوغاب می‌شود. لذا در سنگ‌های با کیفیت بسیارخوب یا در اعماق زیاد، آزمون فشار آب می‌تواند در پیش‌بینی میزان تزریق‌پذیری استفاده گردد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تزریق</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خورند</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">لوژن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">RQD</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عمق مقطع</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68375_36d6c05334a5b852025909c9958a67a6.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
