<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 و 2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Modeling of joint propagation in fractured rock slopes 
(Case study: Final Slope of Tectonic block IV-2 of Choghart mine)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مدلسازی رشد درزه در شیب سنگ های درزه دار (مطالعه موردی: دیواره بلوک تکتونیکی2-4 معدن چغارت)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>13</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">75543</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>پیرنیا</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانش آموخته مکانیک سنگ دانشکده معدن و متالوژی دانشگاه یزد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رقیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>عزیزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانش آموخته مکانیک سنگ دانشکده معدن و متالوژی دانشگاه یزد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>یار احمدی بافقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکده مهندسی معدن و متالوژی دانشگاه یزد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>فاتحی مرجی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکده مهندسی معدن و متالوژی دانشگاه یزد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>27</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In nature, rocks contain non persistent joints and in rock slope stability analyses it is assumed that discontinuity is persistent, while stress intensity is centralized attips of non-persistent joints and this stress intensity affects the size and orientation of  joint growth in rock and  also stability of structures created in it such as rock slope. Fracture mechanics is a science that discusses the probability of joints growth and also fracture propagation path. The development of this science provides the possibility of using actual non persistent joints modeling in rock slope stability as well as controlling mechanical behavior of discontinuities especially in crack tips. By creating rock slopes and changing the matrix of regional stress, intensity of stress occurs in joints tips. If this stress overcomes strength parameters of the joint, it will grow and joint propagation will result. One type of failure that occurs in rocky environments due to crack propagation is toppling whose analysis is one of the most difficult problems in aeromechanics. The aim of this study is to model joint propagation by using the principles of rock fracture mechanics, growth and publication ofnon -persistent and random joints in rock slope with potential of toppling failure. An acceptable numerical method for joint propagation modeling that is boundary element method as displacement discontinuity method (DDM) was selected. As a case study tectonic block IV-2 of Choghart open pit mine was selected and3D geometrical model by random disk method by 3DGMMathematica program was simulated and also 2D cross section was prepared. The amount and direction of joint propagation were calculated by applying boundary conditions, in-situ stresses and stiffness matrix. The mechanical model was created according to geomechanical characteristics reported in stability analysis of this wall. Length of linear elements in joints was considered 3m and propagation step applied was 0.2 over the joint length and the model was run typically in four stages of crack growth. Obtained geometrical model contains early and propagation joints can be used in softwares  that  geometrical model of joints is essential I analysis but the propagation of joint is not available. So the program code can be used as a complementary method for analysis method as key-groups method and distinct element method (UDEC) to analyze the jointed rock mass</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">سنگ‌ها در طبیعت دارای دسته درزه‌های‌ ناممتد هستند و در تحلیل پایداری سنگ­ها عموما درزه‌ها بصورت ممتد بررسی میگردند در حالیکه نوک درزه‌ها‌ی ناممتد محل تمرکز تنش می­باشد و این تمرکز تنش در اندازه و جهت رشد درزه­های موجود در سنگ و پایداری سازه‌های ایجاد شده در آن مثل شیب‌های سنگی موثراست. مکانیک شکست سنگ علمی است که امکان رشد ترک و تعیین جهت انتشار آن را مطالعه می‌کند. توسعه این علم امکان استفاده از مدل‌های درزه‌ای واقعی ناممتد در تحلیل پایداری شیب­های سنگی و کنترل رفتار مکانیکی ناپیوستگی­ها بخصوص پیرامون نوک ترک را فراهم می کند. با ایجاد شیب­های سنگی و تغییر ماتریس تنش منطقه‌ای، در نوک درزه‌ها تمرکز تنش بوجود می‌آید. درصورت غلبه این تنش بر پارامترهای مقاومتی درزه رشد می­کند و با انتشار درزه‌ها بلوک‌های سنگی تشکیل می‌گردند. این مطالعه برآنست با استفاده از اصول مکانیک شکست، رشد و توسعه درزه­ها­ی ناممتد و تصادفی در شیب سنگ‌های درزه‌دار را مدل‌سازی نماید. روش عددی قابل قبول مدل‌سازی مکانیسم شکست درزه‌ها، روش المان مرزی با عنوان روش ناپیوستگی جابجایی (DDM) انتخاب گردید.بعنوان مطالعه موردی مدل هندسی3 بعدی ناپیوستگی‌های دیواره بلوک تکتونیکی 2-4 معدن چغارت بروش دیسک‌های تصادفی توسط برنامه 3DGM یاراحمدی ـ گودرزی در محیط نرم‌افزاری متمتیکا ساخته و مقطع 2 بعدی مورد نظر تهیه‌گردید.با اعمال شرایط مرزی، تنش‌های برجا، ماتریس سختی، مقدار و جهت انتشار درزهها محاسبه گردید. پارامترهای مکانیکی توده مورد مطالعه بر اساس ویژگی‌های ژئومکانیکی گزارش شده در تحلیل‌های پایداری شیب این دیواره استفاده شد. مش‌بندی ناپیوستگی‌ها با ابعاد 3 متر و گام انتشار 2/0 طول درزه در نظر گرفته شد و مدل برای 4 مرحله رشد ترک اجرا گردید. مدل هندسی بوجود آمده شامل درزه های اولیه و رشد یافته قابل استفاده در نرم افزارهایی است که مدل‌های هندسی ناپیوستگی‌ها در آنها پایه اصلی تحلیل بوده ولی قابلیت انتشار ترک را ندارند. پس کد تهیه شده به عنوان مکمل روش‌های تحلیلی مثل گروه­های کلیدی و عددی مثل روش های المان مجزا (نرم افزار UDEC) در تحلیل توده‌سنگ‌های درزه‌دار ناممتد قابل استفاده می باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شیب سنگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش ناپیوستگی جابجایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انتشار درزه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_75543_59b53d180a136ba29f8fc1404ffd37a8.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
