<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 3 و 4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Probabilistic Earthquake Hazard Zonation in Kerman using Statistical Analysis and Artificial Neural Networks</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>پهنه بندی خطر زلزله استان کرمان با استفاده از تحلیل های آماری و شبکه های عصبی مصنوعی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>9</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">76903</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>سیوندی پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکده مهندسی عمران ونقشه برداری، دانشگاه تحصیلات تکمیلی صنعتی و فناوری پیشرفته کرمان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The science of earthquake prediction has not yet reached its desired level of development. It has not yet led to a successful prediction of an earthquake based on physical principles. Therefore, the prediction of the occurrence of an earthquake has always been an interest for researchers. Three parameters of earthquakesincluding:  time, location and magnitude, are the most important uncertainties in earthquake prediction. Uncertainties of earthquakes have the fundamental role in assessment of reliability of structures. In reality, the mechanism of earthquakes makes predicting them more difficult. Earthquake prediction will have a special validity if random variables consider. Therefore, nowadays statistical hypothesis methode are used to determine the probability  of an earthquake. There are many studies in prediction of earthquake parameters, but there is not any particular research in the probabilistic earthquake hazard zonation. Kerman province has experienced destructive earthquakes such as Bam, Golbaf and Zarand as the one of the most seismic regions of Iran. In this study, the probability of future earthquakes location with the magnitude greater than 4.5 Richter has been predicted in Kerman by using artificial neural networks and statistical analysis. The most probable event of earthquake  has been predicted 38.6% in south of Kerman.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">علم پیش بینی زلزله در جایگاه خود هنوز به تکامل مطلوب نرسیده است و تاکنون پیش بینی کاملا دقیقی بر اساس اصول فیزیکی صورت نگرفته است. لذا پیش بینی مشخصات رخداد یک زلزله همواره مورد توجه محققین بوده است. سه پارامتر اصلی یک زلزله شامل زمان، بزرگی و محل وقوع از جمله عدم قطعیت‌هایی هستند که از اهمیت ویژه ای برخوردار می باشند. در بررسی قابلیت اعتماد پذیری لرزه ای سازه ها وجود عدم قطعیت‌های زلزله نقش اساسی دارد. ماهیت تغییر پذیری زلزله سبب شده است که پیش بینی پارامتر های آن بسیار سخت باشد. در پیش بینی زلزله اگر پارامتر های تصادفی رخداد را لحاظ شود از اعتبار خاصی برخوردار خواهد شد. از این رو امروزه اکثر مطالعات بر پایه استفاده از روش های آماری برای پیش بینی احتمال رخداد زلزله می باشد. در مورد پیش بینی پارامتر های زلزله، مطالعات گسترده ای انجام شده است، ولی در زمینه پهنه بندی مکان رخداد زلزله احتمالی مطالعات کمی صورت گرفته است. استان کرمان به عنوان یکی ار لرزه خیز ترین مناطق کشور، زلزله های مخربی چون، بم، گلباف و زرند را تجربه کرده است. در این پژوهش با استفاده از شبکه های عصبی مصنوعی و تجزیه و تحلیل آماری، احتمال رخداد زلزله های بزرگتر از 5/4 ریشتر در مناطق مختلف استان کرمان بررسی شده است. با توجه به نتایج  بدست آمده، بیشترین احتمال وقوع زلزله در این استان، در منطقه جنوبی وبا احتمال 6/38 درصد پیش بینی شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شبکه های عصبی مصنوعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیش بینی زلزله</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نقشه پهنه بندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خطر زلزله</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مطالعات آماری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_76903_13f266a78976fe23506f02d6f814146c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
