<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Flood zoning of Chalus basin using hydrologic model of HEC-RAS and Geographic Information System</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>پهنه‌بندی سیلاب رودخانه چالوس با تلفیق مدل HEC-RAS و سیستم اطلاعات جغرافیایی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>45</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>60</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">84116</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>رجبی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>طاهر</FirstName>
					<LastName>رجایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه مهندسی عمران، هیدرولوژی، دانشگاه قم</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>فلاح تفتی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانش آموخته عمران هیدرولوژی دانشگاه قم</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In this study combination of GIS and HEC-RAS were used for flood zoning in the Chalus basin. For this purpose GIS data processing was done and the coordinate system was defined for the data and then the boundaries of the basin and sub-basin were determined with archydro. Using the extracted data TIN, DEM, mean slop and dip direction of rivers maps were produced and then using HEC-GEORAS, the data required for HEC-RAS software were prepared. Then the manning coefficient values, soil hydrologic groups and distribution maps of CN were extracted from land-use map and subsequently data transferred to the HEC-RAS and the values of manning in each of the cross sections were entered and boundary conditions were defined. Then HEC-RAS model was run in steady-state conditions. By overlaying different layers in GIS (such as the depth and velocity), dangerous areas during the flood were determined. Then the overlapping land-use map and velocity and depth layers, the land-use types at risk from flooding have been identified. Results presented that the floodplain area is equal to 8 and 24 percentage (Min. and Max). Most of the floodplain consists of rice land, building blocks, orchards, meadows and forests in the 2-year flood; therefore maximum damage happens for farmers and residences. By increasing the return period flood, the area of forest (that is placed within the floodplain) increases with higher ratio than building blocks, rice fields and pastures.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این مطالعه با استفاده از نرم افزار Arc GIS و تلفیق آن با مدل هیدرولوژیکیHEC-RAS، پهنه بندی سیلاب در حوضه آبریز چالوس انجام شده است. به این منظور با استفاده از نقشه توپوگرافی منطقه و تصاویر ماهواره ای، مسیر دقیق رودخانه‌ها تعیین و پردازش اولیه بر روی اطلاعات صورت گرفت. در مرحله بعد با استفاده از الحاقیهArchydroوHEC-GEO-RAS اطلاعات مورد نیاز برای نرم افزار HEC-RASآماده شد و ضریب مانینگ، نقشه توزیع شماره منحنی در زیرحوضه ها و درصد مساحت هر کاربری (در هر زیرحوضه) مشخص شد و پس از آماده سازی اطلاعات، مدل HEC-RASدر شرایط ماندگار اجرا گردید. سپس ضمن پوشانی لایه های مختلف (از جمله لایه های عمق و سرعت در دوره های مختلف بازگشت سیلاب)، مناطق خطر در هنگام بروز سیل تعیین و انواع کاربری هایی که در معرض خطر سیلاب قرار دارند، مشخص شد.&lt;br /&gt; نتایج نشان داد که در رودخانه چالوس در بیشترین و کمترین حالت به ترتیب 24 و 8 درصد از مساحت حوضه استعداد سیل خیزی دارند. شیب افزایش درصد مساحت مناطق سیل گرفته نسبت به مساحت کل حوضه با دوره‌های بازگشت مختلف حدود 2% می باشد. در سیلاب2 ساله، بیشترین محدوده سیلابی را به ترتیب کاربری های شالیزار، بلوکهای ساختمانی، باغات، مراتع و جنگل در بر گرفته و لذا بیشترین خسارات به کشاورزان و منازل مسکونی وارد خواهد شد. همچنین با افزایش دوره بازگشت سیلاب رودخانه چالوس، مقدار مساحتی از جنگل که در محدوده سیلابی قرار می گیرد نسبت به مساحت بلوک های ساختمانی، باغات، شالیزارها و مراتع با رشد بیشتری افزایش می یابد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حوضه آبریز</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">چالوس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کاربری اراضی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیستم اطلاعات جغرافیایی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_84116_6788bfa080185b28a13f7b6e3c2ea5bb.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
