<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 و 2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigation on the geochemistry of formations of Gotvand-olya dam reservoir and its influence on the quality of water in reservoir</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی ژئوشیمی سازندهای مخزن سد گتوند علیا و تأثیر آنها بر کیفیت آب سد</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>29</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>40</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68340</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهناز</FirstName>
					<LastName>دهرآزما</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ناصر</FirstName>
					<LastName>حافظی مقدس</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه زمین شناسی مهندسی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مائده</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسنوند</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رامین</FirstName>
					<LastName>کرمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>مربی دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Gotvand-Olya Dam is located near Gotvand City, 25 km north of Shooshtar city in Khozestan province. The present research aimed at investigation on the influence of outcrop formations in the reservoir on the water quality (concentration of anions and cations, TDS, EC, and concentration of heavy metal strontium) at three levels of 150, 200, and 250 m. The results showed that Gachsaran and Mishan formations release the highest concentrations of anions and cations to the water in all three levels respectively. Concentration of strontium was especially high in the Gachsaran formation which is justified by the significant correlation between strontium and basic and sulfate environments. According to the effect of solubility rate of the Gachsaran formation in the levels of 150 and 200 m on the water quality after filling the dam, EC of water was estimated to be 36632 and 28872 mS/cm respectively which is classified as very high saline water. The results have also shown that the salinity drops significantly at the level of 250 m and the water at this level is classified as high saline water. In the case of the effect of the Mishan formation, the classification of water in the three levels are the same as Gachsaran formation, only EC at the level of 200 m is more than the two other levels.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">سد گتوند علیا بر روی رودخانه کارون در 25 کیلومتری شمال شهر شوشتر در استان خوزستان واقع شده است. هدف از این تحقیق بررسی میزان تأثیرگذاری سازندهای رخنمون یافته در مخزن سد گتوند بر کیفیت آب سد در سه تراز 150، 200 و 250 متری بعد از آبگیری می‌باشد. نتایج نشان داد که سازندهای گچساران و میشان در هر سه تراز بالاترین مقادیر آنیون­ها و کاتیون­ها را در آب آزاد می‌کنند. با توجه به تأثیرگذاری سازند گچساران در تراز 150 و 200 متر پس از آبگیری سد، EC آب مخزن سد به ترتیب  36632 و 28872 میکروزیمنس بر سانتی‌متر و جزء آب‎های با شوری بسیار بالا برآورد گردید. همچنین نتایج نشان از کاهش EC به میزان قابل توجه درآب مخزن سد در تراز 250 متری دارد و آب مخزن سد در این تراز در رده آب­های با شوری بالا رده‌بندی می‌گردد. در مورد سازند میشان، رده‌بندی آب در سه تراز، مشابه سازند گچساران بوده با این تفاوت که EC در تراز 200 متری بیش از دو تراز دیگر است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کیفیت آب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فلزات سنگین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازند گچساران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازند میشان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سد گتوند</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68340_242406e51713677c9c1a4ba1aef79d07.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
