<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Evaluation of Groutability in the Pliocene Conglomerate by SPI Method for Sealing 

 (A Case Study)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی تزریق پذیری با هدف آب بندی به روش SPI در گنگلومرای پلیوسن (مطالعه موردی)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>19</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>35</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">76906</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید داود</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم پایه، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، همدان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عبدالرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نوریزدان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجویان دکتری زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، همدان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>26</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>               The Dorud - Khorramabad Railway, with a length of 114 km, is under construction in 5 separate phases. In terms of geology, a large part of the route passes along the High Zagros and the Chaghalvandi Thrust in the form of tunnels and other structures. Phase 5, which is 26 kilometers long, from the 72nd kilometer to the 98th kilometer, between the Biran-Shahr Plain and the Deh-Pir region in North Khorramabad City, has two tunnels with a length of more than 7,500 meters. Given the local climate and the ground water level (average depth of 10 meters) on this route, for the sealing of the tunnels, it is necessary to study the rock mass. For this purpose, it is necessary to understand the characteristics of Pliocene Conglomerate including the mechanical and the physical parameters of the tunnel. The present study tries to determine the permeability by means of the data of water pressure tests. The groutability in this rock unit, in turn, was determined based on the Secondary Permeability Index (SPI). The results show that the behavior of this rock mass is 19% in Class C, 67% in Class B, and 14% in Class A in terms of the SPI, and that 86% of the rock mass needs to improve by means of cement grouting operations. Totally, because of similar geological conditions in the railway route, all of the railway route needs to improve.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">راه آهن دورود- خرم آباد با طول 114 کیلومتر،در 5 فاز جداگانه در دست ساخت می باشد. از نظر زمین شناسی، بخش زیادی از طول  این مسیر، از زون زاگرس خرد شده و راندگی چغلوندی عبور می کند. فاز 5 از کیلومتر 72 تا 98، و با طول 26 کیلومتر، حدفاصل  بیران شهر، تا منطقه ده پیر در شمال شهر خرم آباد، دارای دو دستگاه تونل با طول بیش از 7500 متر می باشد. با توجه به اقلیم منطقه و بالا بودن سطح آب زیر زمینی در مسیر، مطالعات توده سنگی  با هدف آب بندی تونل ضروری است.  به این منظور، شناخت ویژگی گنگلومرای پلیوسن شامل ویژگی های مکانیکی و فیزیکی در مسیر تونل، از اهمیت خاصی برخوردار است. به این منظور ابتدا میزان نفوذپذیری توده سنگ با استفاده از آزمایش های فشار آب(Water pressure tests) تعیین شده است. سپس، میزان تزریق پذیری  این واحد سنگی بر اساس شاخص SPI مشخص شده است. بر اساس نتایج SPI، رفتار توده سنگ در 19 % موارد در کلاس C، در 67 % از موارد در کلاسB  و در  14% از موارد در کلاس A قرار می گیرد. همچنین 86 درصد از توده سنگ در محل های مورد مطالعه نیاز به بهسازی با استفاده از سیمان دارد. همچنین می توان گفت، به علت شرایط یکسان زمین شناسی در این منطقه، تونل های در دست ساخت در گنگلومرای میوسن نیاز به عملیات بهسازی دارند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شاخص نفوذپذیری ثانویه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">لوژان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">راه آهن دورود- خرم آباد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گنگلومرای پلیوسن</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_76906_0b4b487d12be1aff070b11ef9616cfd5.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
