<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigating the Performance and Optimization of New Management Methods (LID-BMP) to Improve Surface Runoff in Tehran-A Case Study of District 22</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی عملکرد و بهینه سازی جانمایی روش‌های نوین مدیریتی (LID-BMP) در بهبود کمیت رواناب سطحی شهر تهران-مطالعه موردی منطقه 22</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>21</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">101076</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سودابه</FirstName>
					<LastName>تقی زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>عمران- سازه های هیدرولیکی-قم</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>طاهر</FirstName>
					<LastName>رجایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه مهندسی عمران، هیدرولوژی، دانشگاه قم</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This research presents urban flood risk management through new management approaches including the implementation of penetration trenches, permanent containment reservoirs and permeable pavements in the surface water collection network. The multi-objective optimization model presented in this research is based on the multi-objective MOPSO algorithm that is combined with Surface Surface Simulation Modeling Software by SWMM software. The application of the proposed method has been described on a case study of the Surface Surface Network of Tehran 22nd District, which consists of four different scenarios; the first scenario examines the performance of new management methods for improving surface runoff quantity without using BMP, and second scenarios, Third, and fourth, BMPs including penetrating trenches, permanent containment tanks and permeable pavements, which were applied in six, four and two percent of the sub basins for the return period of two, five and ten years, were used respectively. Modeling results show that biological storage tanks are more capable of reducing peak courier than penetration trenches and permeable pavements. Also, with the increase of the return period, the impact of BMPs decreases, so that the biosecurity tanks are 10% more effective than penetration trenches and about 20% more than penetrating pavements in reducing peak cours. The goal of the optimization model is to reduce peak coursing, which results suggest that using the optimal combination of all three new approaches leads to a 51% to 54% reduction in peak versus the most effective BMP.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این تحقیق مدیریت خطرپذیری سیلاب شهری را با به‌کارگیری روش‌های نوین مدیریتی شامل اجرای ترانشه های نفوذ، مخازن نگهداشت دائمی زیستی و روسازی‌های نفوذپذیر در شبکه جمع‌آوری آب‌های سطحی ارائه می‌نماید. مدل بهینه‌سازی چندهدفه ارائه شده در این تحقیق با استفاده از الگوریتمMOPSO چندهدفه توسعه‌یافته که با مدل شبیه‌سازی شبکه جمع‌آوری آب‌های سطحی توسط نرم‌افزار SWMM ترکیب شده است. کاربرد روش پیشنهادی بر روی مطالعه موردی شبکه جمع‌آوری آب‌های سطحی منطقه 22 تهران تشریح شده است که شامل چهار سناریو مختلف می باشد؛ سناریو اول به بررسی عملکرد روش های نوین مدیریتی در بهبود کمیت رواناب سطحی بدون استفاده از BMP پرداخته شده است و سناریوهای دوم، سوم و چهارم به ترتیب از BMP های شامل ترانشه نفوذ، مخازن نگهداشت دائمی زیستی و روسازی نفوذپذیر، که در شش، چهار و دو درصد از زیر حوضه‌ها برای دوره بازگشت دو، پنج و 10ساله اعمال شده، استفاده‌ گردیده است. نتایج مدل‌سازی نشان می‌دهد که مخازن نگهداشت زیستی نسبت به ترانشه های نفوذ و روسازی‌های نفوذپذیر، توانایی بیشتری در کاهش دبی پیک دارد. همچنین با افزایشی دوره بازگشت از تاثیر BMPs کاسته می شود بطوری که مخازن نگهداشت زیستی 10% بیشتر از ترانشه‌های نفوذ و حدود20% بیشتر از روسازی‌های نفوذ پذیر در کاهش دبی پیک تاثیر گذار می باشند. هدف مدل بهینه‌سازی کاهش دبی پیک می‌باشد که نتایج نشان می‌دهد به‌کارگیری ترکیب بهینه هر سه رویکرد نوین، منجر به کاهش 51% تا 54% دبی پیک نسبت به موثربخش ترین BMP می‌شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت سیلاب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">LID-BMP</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شبکه جمع‌آوری آب‌های سطحی شهری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خطرپذیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">PSO</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_101076_fba12c62403211b57702bb8a45fbc9f8.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
