<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 3 و 4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Evaluation of indentation method in determining fracture toughness of rocks</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی روش دندانه‌گذاری در تعیین چقرمگی شکست سنگ</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>59</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>68</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68334</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>زارع نجف‌آبادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>1. آزمایشگاه تحقیقاتی خستگی و شکست، دانشکده مهندسی مکانیک، دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران، تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجیدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>آیت اللهی</LastName>
<Affiliation>آزمایشگاه تحقیقاتی خستگی و شکست، دانشکده مهندسی مکانیک، دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران، تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>11</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Fracture toughness is an important parameter in some applications related to rock masses like fracture of rock, hydraulic fracturing process, design and manufacturing of tunneling apparatus. Different methods have been proposed for determining fracture toughness of quasi-brittle materials including the indentation test. In this research, the properties of some rocks with different textures (grain size and shape) are examined in the indentation test. Then applicability of the indentation method in determining fracture toughness of rocks is evaluated. It is shown that rocks exhibit two different types of behavior in the indentation test. For forces less than a critical force, rocks behave in accordance with other brittle materials, while for loads more than the critical force, the rocks behave completely in contrast with other brittle materials. This difference makes the indentation method an unsuitable option for determining fracture toughness of rocks. The main reason for this difference could be the presence of inherent defects in rocks.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">چقرمگی شکست سنگ یکی از پارامترهای مکانیکی مهم در برخی از کاربردهای مربوط به توده­های سنگی مانند فرآیند شکست در سنگ، فرآیند شکست هیدرولیکی، طراحی و ساخت ماشین‌آلات حفاری می‌باشد. با این وجود برای اندازه‌گیری این پارامتر روش‌های آزمایشگاهی مختلفی وجود دارد. یکی از روش‌های آزمایشگاهی ارائه شده در این زمینه، روش دندانه‌گذاری می‌باشد. در این تحقیق، در ابتدا رفتارچند سنگ مختلف از نظر نوع و اندازه دانه‌بندی، در آزمایش دندانه‌گذاری بررسی شده و در ادامه عملی بودن این روش در تعیین چقرمگی شکست آن­ها ارزیابی می­شود. با توجه به نتایج بدست آمده می‌توان گفت که سنگ‌ها در آزمایش دندانه‌گذاری رفتار دوگانه‌ای را از خود نشان می‌دهد. برای نیروهای کمتر از بار بحرانی، رفتار سنگ مشابه با مواد ترد دیگر بوده ولی برای نیروهای بیشتر از بار بحرانی، رفتار سنگ­های آزمایش شده به طور کلی متفاوت با مواد ترد دیگر می‌باشد. این تفاوت در رفتار باعث می‌شود که نتوان از روش دندانه‌گذاری برای تعیین چقرمگی شکست آن­ها استفاده کرد. دلیل اصلی این تفاوت را می‌توان ناشی ازبرخی عیوب ساختاری ذاتی در سنگ‌ها دانست.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">چقرمگی شکست</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سنگ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">‌ روش دندانه‌گذاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ترک</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68334_f1b991f56e4468f798100bf38fb6d266.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
