<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 و 2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigation on the mechanism of Saein Strait Landslide (Nir-Sarab Road) in regard to the hydrological and geomorphological conditions</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی سازوکار وقوع زمین لغزش گردنه صائین (جاده نیر- سراب) با نگرشی بر هیدرولوژی و شرایط ریخت شناسی منطقه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>13</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>33</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68356</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرهاد</FirstName>
					<LastName>شهیدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد زمین­شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>غلامرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>شعاعی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی واوسری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد زمین­شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Saein Strait landslide took place along Nir-Sarab Road by the southern flank of Sabalan volcano on June 6, 2005, and damaged 350 m of the main road. The main factors which might affect the stability of this particular slope are the thickness and texture of the soil, extensive weathering, gentle slope to cause the accumulation of the material, and finally the regionally affected groundwater level fluctuations. A research was planned based on the field studies, laboratory tests and numerical modeling to identify the main factors affecting the stability of this slope. Landslide profile and engineering geological properties of materials were applied in the numerical models. The effect of rainfall in soil saturation process was simulated for 35 days prior to the failure. Modeling results shows that the infiltrated rainwater (during the 35 days) into the sliding mass cannot percolate more than 7 m and, thus, it must be followed by another triggering factor. The impact of fluctuation in the groundwater level on the stability of the slop was evaluated using limit equilibrium and finite element modeling methods. Previous studies showed that the local conditions of paleogeomorphologyand the existence of a depression might cause the accumulation of volcanic eruptions materials to create sliding mass today. This depression may drain the surface and the groundwater toward the sliding mass from upstream catchment. The materials are highly weathered and groundwater rise due to the exceptional precipitation (rain and snow) during 2004-2005 water year are the main factors bringing the slope to its yield point&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زمین­لغزش 16 خرداد سال 1384 در منطقه آتشفشانی گردنه صائین در حد فاصل جاده نیر-سراب، سبب تخریب 350 متر از جاده مذکور شده است. عوامل مختلفی در ایجاد این زمین­لغزش نقش داشته­اند که از جمله می­توان به عوامل زمین­شناسی(ضخامت و بافت خاک، سنگ­های سست و شیب دامنه) و آب­های زیرزمینی اشاره نمود. برای مشخص نمودن عوامل مهم و اصلی تاثیرگذار در وقوع لغزش، پژوهشی مبتنی بر برداشت‌های صحرائی، آزمون­های آزمایشگاهی، و مدلسازی عددی برنامه‌ریزی گردید. بدین ترتیب نیمرخ لغزش و خصوصیات زمین­شناسی مهندسی مواد در مدل قرار گرفتند. سپس تاثیر بارندگی بر اشباع شدگی خاک بررسی شد و با توجه به مقدار نفوذ آب باران مشخص شد که باید عامل محرک دیگری در این توده نقش داشته باشد. به این دلیل تاثیر تغییرات سطح آب زیرزمینی درون توده لغزش بر پایداری آن به دو روش مدلسازی تعادل حدی و عناصر محدود مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفت. بررسی­های صحرائی و چینه­شناسی نشان دادند که شرایط محلی زمین‌ریخت‌شناسی دیرین و وجود یک محدوده فروافتاده سبب زهکش شدن آب­ از منطقه بالادست به سمت توده لغزشی می­گردد. بدین ترتیب، افزایش سطح آب زیرزمینی در محدوده توده لغزیده به­ دلیل بارندگی استثنایی فصل زمستان و بهار سال آبی 84-83 می­تواند مسبب اصلی ایجاد زمین­لغزش باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زمین‌لغزش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زمین‌ریخت‌شناسی دیرین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شبیه‌سازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مواد آذرآواری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آب زیرزمینی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گردنه صائین</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68356_cfe135688cc8fa49fef39999ad97494b.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
