<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Numerical Modeling for Determining Effective factors on initiation fracture Pressure in Hydraulic fracture Operation</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مدلسازی عددی برای تعیین عوامل موثر بر فشار شروع شکست در عملیات شکست هیدرولیکی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>57</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>74</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">88504</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>آریا</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام خمینی (ره)</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام خمینی (ره)</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>According to increasing demand of the country for more production rates and output from oil reservoirs, it&#039;s necessary to re-activate the oil wells in Iran. Oil production in overtime Reduces, The reason of this event is decreased reservoir&#039;s Pressure and Closure the cracks and microscopic holes. Hydraulic fracture as a method for stimulating oil reservoirs related to various factors including the characteristics of the environment which the fracture grows. Mechanical properties of the layers recognized as the one of the most effective parameters on the progress of hydraulic fracture and its geometry. In this study, we try to indagate the various factors involved in hydraulic fracture and the effect of each of them on hydraulic fracture until reduce both operation costs and better and more efficient failure. In this research, numerical modeling was done by ABAQUS software in 10 different cases and then, the effect of the each input parameters on the hydraulic fracture pressure was investigated by performing sensitivity analysis. Actually these input parameters are well&#039;s data and including Young&#039;s modulus, minimum and maximum horizontal stress, vertical stress, tensile strength, poison’s ratio and pore pressure. Required information is obtained from excavated wells in carbonate rocks in Iran. The results show&#039;s minimum horizontal stress has the most effect on the hydraulic fracture pressure and parameters such as vertical stress and Young&#039;s modulus are not effective in determination of hydraulic fracture pressure.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">با توجه به نیاز روزافزون کشور به نرخ تولید بیشتر از چاه‌های نفتی و بازدهی بیشتر مخازن نفت، فعال‌سازی مجدد چاه‌های نفت در ایران امری ضروری به نظر می‌رسد. تولید نفت باگذشت زمان، به دلیل کاهش فشار مخزن و بسته شدن ترک‌ها و منافذ میکروسکوپی موجود در سنگ مخزن کاهش می‌یابد. شکست هیدرولیکی به‌عنوان روشی برای تحریک مخازن نفتی به عوامل مختلفی ازجمله خصوصیات محیطی که شکستگی در آن رشد می‌کند، بستگی دارد. خصوصیات مکانیکی لایه‌ها به‌عنوان یکی از مهمترین پارامترهای تأثیرگذار بر رونـد گسترش شکسـت هیدرولیکی و هندسه‌ی آن شناخته می‌شوند. در پژوهش حاضر، سعی بر این است که عوامل مختلف دخیل در شکست هیدرولیکی و تاثیر هر یک از آنها بر شکست هیدرولیکی بررسی شود تا محل مناسب برای انجام عملیات شکست هیدرولیکی انتخاب شود که باعث می شود هم هزینه های عملیاتی پایین بیاید و هم شکست بهتر و موثر تری داشته باشیم. در این تحقیق، توسط نرم‌افزار ABAQUS مدل‌سازی‌های عددی در 10 حالت مختلف انجام‌شده و سپس اثر هر یک از این پارامترهای ورودی، روی فشار شکست هیدرولیکی با انجام تحلیل حساسیت بررسی ‌شده است. این پارامترهای ورودی که درواقع داده‌های چاه می‌باشند شامل مدول الاستیسیته، تنش افقی حداقل و حداکثر، تنش قائم، مقاومت کششی، نسبت پواسون و فشار منفذی می‌باشند. اطلاعات موردنیاز از چاه‌های حفرشده در سنگ‌های کربناته ی ایران گرفته شده است. نتایج نشان می‌دهد که تنش افقی حداقل بیشترین تأثیر را بر روی فشار شکست دارد و پارامتر هایی مثل تنش قائم و مدول یانگ در تعیین فشار شکست بی تاثیر هستند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شکست هیدرولیکی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل حساسیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدلسازی عددی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نرم افزار ABAQUS</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_88504_800eabd1daca8596801963112d040534.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
