<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 3 و 4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Determination of Ballast Layers Shear Interlocking Stiffness by Laboratory Method</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تعیین سختی برشی قفل‌شدگی لایه‌های بالاست به روش آزمایشگاهی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>69</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>82</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">79348</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهنام</FirstName>
					<LastName>سعداله زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانش‌آموخته کارشناسی دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران، دانشکده مهندسی را‌ه‌آهن، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرتضی</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسماعیلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران، دانشکده مهندسی راه‌آهن، تهران،</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جبارعلی</FirstName>
					<LastName>ذاکری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران، دانشکده مهندسی راه‌آهن، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Ballast shear interlocking is phenomenon that occurs between adjacent ballast masses under sleepers due to axial loading. This phenomenon is caused when three factors: 1) large thickness of the ballast layer, 2) large stress distribution angle at ballast mass of under sleeper, 3) small sleeper spacing are available at ballasted track. Thus, despite these three factors together and based on the assumption of transfer load from sleeper into ballast mass in accordance with a stress distribution pyramid, caused an overlap between two adjacent pyramids that this intersection would mobilize shear stiffness and shear damping in addition to stiffness and damping ballast layer in the vertical direction. This stiffness and damping is called the shear coupling. Considering the fact that so far, few studies have investigated about these parameters, but the method for calculating them is not provided in the technical literature. Therefore, in this research by developing a laboratory method in order to determine the ballast shear stiffness parameter and shear strength, shear tests of ballast in the vertical direction in the locking zone under static overheads 200, 300 and 400 kg in the relative density is 70.95% done and the effect of relative densities of 40, 70 and 94.44 percent on the shearing of the ballast is investigated. For this purpose, a device for shear of ballast in Railway Superstructure Laboratory of the railway engineering school was designed and built. Finally, based on the results and the integrate them, in order to use the results a mathematical relationship for ballast shear stiffness parameter has been determined which includes the axial load and vehicle speed and high density relative of the ballast. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پدیده قفل­شدگی برشی بین لایه­های بالاست­ قرارگرفته در زیر تروارس­های مجارو هم، در اثر بارگذاری محوری و با وجود سه عامل ضخامت زیاد لایه بالاست، زاویه توزیع تنش بزرگ در توده بالاست و کم بودن فاصله بین تراورس­ها رخ می­دهد. تحت این شرایط و با فرض انتقال بار در داخل توده­های بالاست به صورت یک توزیع تنش هرمی، یک همپوشانی بین هرم­های مجاورهم ایجاد می­شود که موجب بسیج شدن یک سختی و میرایی مضاف بر سختی و میرایی لایه بالاست در راستای قائم می­شود. این دو پارامتر کوپل برشی نامیده می­شوند. تاکنون در تحقیقات اندکی به مطالعه این پارامترها پرداخته شده است از اینرو در این مقاله با هدف ارزیابی سختی برشی بالاست در ناحیه قفل­شدگی، با توسعه یک روش آزمایشگاهی، آزمایش­های برش بالاست تحت سربارهای استاتیکی ۲۰۰، ۳۰۰ و ۴۰۰ کیلوگرم و در تراکم نسبی ۷۰ درصد صورت پذیرفته است. همچنین اثر مقادیر تراکم نسبی ۴۰ ،۷۰ و ۹۵ درصد نیز بر میزان مقاومت برشی بررسی شده است. برای انجام آزمایش­ها یک دستگاه برش بالاست بزرگ مقیاس در آزمایشگاه روسازی راه­آهن دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران ساخته شده و مورد استفاده قرار گرفته است. بر اساس نتایج بدست­آمده، برای تعیین پارامتر سختی برشی قفل­شدگی لایه­های بالاست، یک مدل ریاضی چهار پارامتری که در برگیرنده بارمحوری، وزن مخصوص لایه بالاست، سرعت قطار و قطر چرخ قطار می­باشد توسعه داده شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قفل‌شدگی برشی بالاست</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توزیع تنش هرمی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آزمایش‌‌های برش بالاست</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پارامتر سختی برشی قفل‌شدگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل ریاضی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_79348_a06e8f9a55b1e32ee530db66e07d2e3a.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
