<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Zonation of Rock-Slope Failure Potential of Sungun Copper Mine Based on SMR and Analytic Hierarchy Process (AHP)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>پهنه‌بندی پتانسیل گسیختگی شیب‌های سنگی معدن مس سونگون بر اساس امتیاز توده‌ی سنگ (SMR) و تحلیل سلسله مراتبی (AHP)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>99</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>113</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">85011</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>قدرت</FirstName>
					<LastName>برزگری</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه علوم زمین، دانشکده علوم طبیعی، دانشگاه تبریز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>موسی</FirstName>
					<LastName>فتحی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه علوم زمین، دانشکده علوم طبیعی، دانشگاه تبریز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>26</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Sungun copper mine is located in the East Azerbaijan province, 45 km north of Varzaqan County.&lt;br /&gt; In this research, in order to zonation of potentially unstable areas, slope mass rating (SMR), kinematical analysis and analytic hierarchy process (AHP) methods by using of Dips 6.0, Expert Choice and ArcGIS softwares were accomplished. In the study by using Analytical Hierarchy Process method, the effective general criterias on the failure of rock slopes and extraction benches including structural geology, geomechanics, groundwater condition of joints, morphology and degree of alteration were selected and ranked by forming a pairwise comparison matrix. Then the sub-criterias and alternatives are wheighted by using of overall row wheight method on the basis of their importance. Finally, by integration of obtained data layers in the ArcGIS system, the studied mine area was zoned in low, medium and higth category in terms of failure potentially. According to the results, the western, southern, southeast and scattered parts of the north area of the studied mine specially in mining benchs are more likely to rock slope failurs, which is in good agreement with field observations. The results showed that there is a fairly good agreement between the results of the methods used in this research. But due to the fact that in the hierarchical analysis method, other criteria involved in the failure are considered, and the result is more reliable.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">معدن مس سونگون در استان آذربایجان شرقی در 45 کیلومتری شمال شهرستان ورزقان قرار دارد. در این تحقیق برای پهنه‌بندی مناطق با پتانسیل ناپایداری از روشهای امتیاز توده‌ی‌سنگ (SMR )، تحلیل سینماتیکی و فرآیند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی ( AHP) و با استفاده از نرم‌افزارهایDips 6.0 ، Expert Choice و ArcGIS استفاده شده است. برای بررسی به روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی، معیارهای اصلی دخیل در گسیختگی شیب‌های سنگی و پله‌های استخراج شامل زمین‌شناسی ساختاری، ژئومکانیکی، وضعیت آب زیرزمینی درزه‌ها، مورفولوژی و درجه دگرسانی انتخاب و با تشکیل ماتریس مقایسه زوجی امتیازدهی شدند و زیرمعیارها و گزینه‌های تعیین شده برای هرکدام از معیارهای اصلی بر پایه میزان اهمیت آنها و به روش مجموع سطری وزن‌دهی شدند. سپس با تلفیق لایه‌های اطلاعاتی مختلف در محیط ArcGIS، محدوده‌‌ی معدن از لحاظ خطر ناپایداری شیب‌های سنگی در سه دسته کم، متوسط و زیاد پهنه‌بندی گردید. با توجه به نتایج بدست آمده، مناطق غربی، جنوبی، جنوب‌شرقی و بصورت پراکنده قسمتی از شمال محدوده‌ی معدن بویژه در پله‌های استخراج پتانسیل وقوع گسیختگی بیشتر است که با شواهد میدانی مطابقت نسبی دارد. نتایج بدست آمده نشان داد که همخوانی نسبتاً خوبی بین نتایج روشهای مورد استفاده در این تحقیق وجود دارد. ولی بدلیل اینکه در روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی سایر معیارهای دخیل در گسیختگی در نظر گرفته می‌شود نتایج قابل اعتمادتری بدست می‌آید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گسیختگی شیب‌های سنگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">امتیاز توده‌ی سنگ (SMR)</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ArcGIS</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل سلسله مراتبی(AHP)</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معدن مس سونگون</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_85011_6ab676d388cb95817e9844295553974e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
