<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 و 2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Geotechnical investigation of 33 pole bridge structure in Isfahan using Ground- Penetrating Radar method</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بکارگیری روش رادار نفوذی به زمین جهت مطالعات ژئوتکنیکی بنای تاریخی سی و سه پل اصفهان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>85</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>102</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68376</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>احمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>1. استادیار مهندسی معدن، دانشگاه صنعتی اراک</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نادر</FirstName>
					<LastName>فتحیانپور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکده مهندسی معدن، دانشگاه صنعتی اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>17</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In present study, the Ground- Penetrating Radar (GPR) as a non-destructive method has been employed to investigate the foundation condition, type of materials and structural discontinuities of the well-known 33 pole bridge in Isfahan. To achieve this goal, the improved 2-D finite-difference algorithm is used to simulate the GPR responses of synthetic models resembling common geotechnical targets including layered earth (slab), horizontal cylinders and 2-D prisms. Through using a 500 MHz GPR system equipped with shielded antennas, 46 profiles comprising 36 transverse profiles in the east-west direction perpendicular to the main bridge axis, 7 longitudinal profiles in the north-south direction along the main bridge axis and 3 transverse profiles from the bases of the bridge were surveyed. Processing and interpretation of longitudinal and transverse radargrams revealed various in-homogeneities including reinforcing joists and rebars, blocks of stone and wooden timbers as well as ruptures and subsidences in several locations. Concrete slabs reinforced with joists and rebars, are mainly associated with recent repairs of the bridge while reinforced sections by stone blocks and wooden timbers are related to the ancient construction works which have suffered several fractures and subsidences.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در پژوهش حاضر از روش غیرمخرب رادار نفوذی به زمین (GPR) به­منظور شناسایی وضعیت مصالح بکاررفته و ناپیوستگی‌های ساختاری بنای تاریخی سی‌وسه‌پل اصفهان استفاده شده است. برای این منظور ابتدا با استفاده از یک الگوریتم تفاضل محدود دوبعدی بهبود یافته، پاسخ GPR مدل‌های مصنوعی متناظر با ساختارهای ژئوتکنیکی متداول همانند زمین لایه‌ای، استوانه افقی و منشور دوبعدی شبیه‌سازی شد. سپس با استفاده از یک سیستم GPR مجهز به آنتن‌های پوشش‌دار با فرکانس مرکزی 500 مگاهرتز، تعداد 46 پروفیل GPR شامل 36 پروفیل عرضی در راستای شرقی- غربی عمود بر امتداد پل، 7 پروفیل طولی در عرشه پل در راستای شمالی- جنوبی به ­موازات امتداد پل و 3 پروفیل عرضی از پایه‌های پل برداشت شد. پردازش و تفسیر نگاشت‌های راداری نشان می‌دهد که در مقاطع طولی و عرضی، اشیاء و مصالح مختلف عمدتاً شامل تیرآهن و میلگرد تقویتی، بلوک‌های سنگی، الوارهای چوبی و نیز ناپیوستگی و نشست، در جای‌جای پل قابل مشاهده است که اسلب‌های بتنی تقویت شده با تیرآهن و میلگرد، عمدتاً مربوط به مرمت‌های جدید پل بوده و بخش‌های تقویت شده با بلوک‌های سنگی و الوارهای چوبی، اکثراً قدیمی است که متحمل نشست و شکستگی‌های متعددی گردیده‌اند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رادار نفوذی به زمین(GPR)</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل‌سازی عددی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اهداف ژئوتکنیکی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سی‌وسه‌پل اصفهان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ناپیوستگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پروفیل GPR</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68376_c41ec7d07ae6b1f4d235224329498d85.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
