<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Study of engineering geological properties of Asmari limestone in the north-east Masjed-Suliman</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Hosein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Gobadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Prof. of engineering geology, Bouali University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hasan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohseni</namePart>
				<affiliation>Member of Scientific board of Bu-Ali Sina university Univ, Hamedan, Iran.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rasooli Farah</namePart>
				<affiliation>3. Msc Student of Engineering geology, Bu-Ali Sina university Univ, Hamedan, Iran.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The main purpose of this research is to assess the engineering geological properties of Asmari limestone in the north-east of Khuzestan province. For this purpose, 20 samples of limestone were selected from the north-east of Karun 1 dam site, and the relationships between petrographic characteristics, physical and mechanical properties were investigated. Index properties such as total porosity, dry unit weight, schmit hammer value, strength under uniaxial  compression and Brazilian tension were determined. Microscopic studies on the limestone reveal that they are mostly bioclast packstone and bioclast wackestone according to Dunham classification. From the statictical analysis of the data, regression equations were established among rock material parameters, while conversion factors relating index properties and strength were also determined. The petrographic characteristics of the studied rocks such as mineral composition and microstructure were analyzed in thin sections and their intrinsic influence on the measured strength parameters was also investigated</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Scientific Quarterly Journal of Iranian Association of Engineering Geology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association of Engineering Geology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2228-5245</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>شماره 1 و 2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2009</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>18</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68196_1d5261fe618f23a304b68e62b9e2aa64.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The analysis and classification of rock slopes instability potential along  the Khosh-Yeylagh mountainous road using systems approach</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khalukakei</namePart>
				<affiliation>Member of Scientific board of Shahrod Univ.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Masoud</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Zare Naghadehi</namePart>
				<affiliation>2-Ph.D Student of Shahrod</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Rock slope stability analysis with the use of analytical and numerical approaches is usually a complicated engineering task because of complex behaviour of the rock mass and also of the various affecting parameters. On the other hand, even though the wide application of empirical methods, they don’t have an acceptable accuracy and efficiency in all situations due to the consideration of the specified influencing major factors. The Rock Engineering Systems (RES) is a systems approach which can be considered as a suitable method for rock engineering analyses and classifications particularly in areas with complex environment and multiple affecting parameters. In this method, the interactions between the system’s parameters are analyzed and then the effect of each parameter on the subject (system) is considered. The aim of this paper is to utilize the RES approach to classification of rock slopes in Khosh-Yeylagh mountainous road between Shahrood and Azadshahr cities in Iran. In this way, the study region and its conditions have been visited and some stations on the rock slopes have been selected. Then, the key steps of the mentioned approach such as selection of the most important parameters generating the instability, establishment of the interaction matrix and its coding, setting up the classification menus, defining the instability index in the form of a mathematical formula have been consecutively followed. Then, the experimental data of rock and rock joint physical characteristics were achieved and the indices for each slope were calculated. In this manner, the rock slopes in the stations were classified from the instability point of view. Finally, as a preliminary validation on the utilization of systems approach in the study region, the stability of investigated rock slopes were analyzed using an empirical method and the results were compared. The comparisons showed a rather good coincidence between the given classes of two methods. The results of this research showed that the utilization of the systems approach could be considered very useful in rock slope stability analysis specifically in large scale problems with various affecting parameters.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Scientific Quarterly Journal of Iranian Association of Engineering Geology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association of Engineering Geology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2228-5245</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>شماره 1 و 2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2009</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>19</start>
					<end>32</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68198_8be358a038643f76dd57d1640e19f90d.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>An investigation on physical characteristics and mechanical behavior of swelling gypsum soils and their improvement methods</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Jafar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Bolouri Bazaz</namePart>
				<affiliation>Civil Engineering Department, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Mashhad, Iran.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hamid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rajaea</namePart>
				<affiliation>Graduate Student, Civil Engineering Department, Sharif</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The existence of swelling soils causes irretrievable damages to buildings all over the world. Due to the swelling property of the gypsum soils, located in South West of Mashhad, many problems such as cracking in building, heaving of walls, and pavement and bulging of floors have been reported. The soil in this region is generally fine and based on Unified Classification is predominantly ML and CL. In the present research, 6 typical samples, among many gathered samples, with identical gradation but different amount of gypsum, were selected. After determination of main geotechnical properties of samples (including gypsum percent, Atterberg limits, natural unit weight and density), the effect of gypsum amount on the swelling potential and swelling pressure was investigated. Considering the influence of degree of compaction, on the swelling potential and swelling pressure, 10 samples for each of 6 typical soils, with identical moisture content but different unit weight were prepared and the variation of the swelling potential and swelling pressure were studied. The results of this research indicate the harsh effect of the gypsum amount, degree of compaction and moisture content on the swelling potential and swelling pressure. The improvement of such soils which are a type of problematic soils has been of many researchers interest. In the present research a sample with 10.57% gypsum and unit weight of 1.83 g/cm3 and with a determined swelling potential was improved using three different methods, including mixing with lime, double mixing with lime and mixing with cement. The amount of admixture for all three methods was 1, 2, 3 and 4 percent. The results of this research indicate that mixing with cement is able to reduce considerably the swelling potential and to improve the swelling specifications of this type of soil.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Scientific Quarterly Journal of Iranian Association of Engineering Geology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association of Engineering Geology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2228-5245</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>شماره 1 و 2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2009</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>33</start>
					<end>46</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68199_ea4e0b2c3ee21c82bc4ac15392832549.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Design and construction a physical model of a pseudo landslide in order to geoelectrical investigation in experimental scale for detecting the landslide geometry</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ramezani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Msc. Student of  Islamic Azad Univ. Science and Research Branch</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mirsattar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Meshinchi_Asl</namePart>
				<affiliation>Member of Scientific board  of Islamic Azad Univ. Science and Research branch</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohsen</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shariat Jafari</namePart>
				<affiliation>[3]- Member of Scientific board of  Soil Conservation and Watershed Management Research Institute</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Abbasi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Msc. Student of  Islamic Azad Univ. Science and Research Branch</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>A landslide is a geological phenomenon which includes a wide range of destruction and damage. Determination of landslide geometry is an important problem in study of landslides. Geophysics methods, especially geoelectric, are the best ways to study the landslide geometry. In this regard an experimental model was provided for geoelectrical investigation. One of the preparation steps of the model is to test the geoelectric tank.the final stage is to provide a resistivity pseudo section.in the result of the resistivity pseudo section have a good fitness to the boundary of pseudo landslide. Researcher can test a lot of different geoelectrical arrays and choose the best one for use in the field.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Scientific Quarterly Journal of Iranian Association of Engineering Geology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association of Engineering Geology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2228-5245</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>شماره 1 و 2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2009</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>47</start>
					<end>58</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68200_a104ebfd907b97ccd02b9534aaad663e.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Assessing effect of mode of failure
on uniaxial compressive strength of rock samples</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Bashir Gonbadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D Student of Engineering geology, Tarbiat Modares Univ.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Oromiehei</namePart>
				<affiliation>P{rof. of Engineering geology Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nikudel</namePart>
				<affiliation>Member of Scientific board of Shahrod Univ of Tarbiat Modares Univ.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Gholam Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Lashkaripour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Member of Scientific board of Shahrod Univ of Ferdousi Univ.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Determining the UCS of rock samples as one of the most important parameters of rock engineering is so difficult because of occurrence of so many problems. One of the most important problems  in this regard  is  the scattering  of  the  results of USC tests  and lack of  specific  criteria for  choosing  the data which represents  the strength of intact rock. Investigating the form and  the mechanism of  samples failure  through the  USC tests shows the significant  impact of  micro-fractures and microscopic discontinuities  on  the failure mode  and  also on test results.  According to the research results, that the maximum ratio of  UCS to tensile strength  and consequently  maximum  rate of USC occurs in  the simple extension failure which indicates no impact or  so weak impact  of micro-fractures on  the sample failure of this type unlike other types. In case of other extreme,  the minimum USC  ratio  to tensile  strength  and the USC belongs to  the samples  with  simple shearing failure and in this case  the failures is totally impacted by  micro-fractures. So regarding the ratio of USC to tensile strength and also considering the samples fracture mode, the real data representing the USC of intact rock could be chosen. The suitable criteria for choosing the correct data of the UCS tests is submitted in this research</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Scientific Quarterly Journal of Iranian Association of Engineering Geology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association of Engineering Geology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2228-5245</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>شماره 1 و 2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2009</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>59</start>
					<end>72</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68201_adc429be36e04f1ac3ffc914fea3b4e9.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Effect of specimen dimensions on fracture toughness 
of Harsin marble rock</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Majid Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ayatollahi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Fatigue and Fracture Lab., Department of Mechanical Engineering, Iran University of Science and Technology, Narmak, 16846 Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hamed</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Saghafi</namePart>
				<affiliation>1- Fatigue and Fracture Lab., Department of Mechanical Engineering, Iran University of Science and Technology, Narmak, 16846 Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammad Aliha</namePart>
				<affiliation>Fatigue and Fracture Lab., Department of Mechanical Engineering, Iran University of Science and Technology, Narmak, 16846 Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The determination of fracture toughness of a rock material requires a standard specimen with specific geometry dimensions. If the dimensions of specimen are lower than special values, the obtained fracture toughness may not be accurate. In order to attain the fracture toughness of rock materials correctly, several criteria have been proposed for the required minimum dimensions. In this study, some tests were conducted on the semi-circular specimen containing an edge crack and subjected to three-point-bend loading (SCB specimen) and the suggested criteria for the required minimum crack length and thickness were assessed. The specimens were made of Harsin marble rock. The results obtained from the fracture tests showed that these criteria are not comprehensive and are not consistent with the experimental results. Therefore, by using the necessary correction factors in equations related to the minimum crack length and thickness, these equations were revised such that they can estimate the experimentally observed results for the Harsin rock.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Scientific Quarterly Journal of Iranian Association of Engineering Geology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association of Engineering Geology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2228-5245</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>شماره 1 و 2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2009</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>73</start>
					<end>82</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68202_e4a1a68575c9d5059acfb68e6e45a91c.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The effect of swelling on the lining of tabriz plain canals and a countermeasure method</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hajialilue Bonab</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Masoud</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tabriz, Faculty of Civil Engineering, hajialilue@tabrizu.ac.ir</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fariba</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Behrouz Sarand</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tabriz, Faculty of Civil Engineering, fsarand@gmail.com</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Cheshmdoost</namePart>
				<affiliation>Yekom Consultant Engineers, Tavanab consultant Engineers</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Many structures are being constructed on expansive soil every year. A considerable part of these structures are damaged such as cracks and a part of them are destroyed. When the irrigation canals are located on problematic soils like expansive and dispersive soils, different damages may occur. Top layers of Tabriz plain are generally consisted of fine grain soils and clays. A comprehensive site investigation was undertaken and the results show that the swelling potential varies from low to medium-high. Some parts of the AjiChay main canal of Tabriz (East Azerbaijan) suffered cracks and small uplifts. After investigation it was shown that these damages could be caused by soil bed swelling. In this paper this hypothesis was investigated. Different tests were undertaken to understand the phenomena and a countermeasure method was undertaken to reduce damages.In order to evaluate the effectiveness of countermeasure method, a part of canal was selected and filled with water and the deformation of canal caused by swelling was studied.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Scientific Quarterly Journal of Iranian Association of Engineering Geology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association of Engineering Geology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2228-5245</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>شماره 1 و 2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2009</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>83</start>
					<end>98</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68203_4bd81c78c1fa867e37cf6e7bb28a3c31.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>