<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigation of tensile strength and deformation characteristics of Varamin collapsible soils at undisturbed, reconstituted and treated states</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی مقاومت و تغییر شکل کششی خاک های رمبنده دشت ورامین در حالت های دست نخورده، بازسازی شده و بهسازی شده</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>61</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>80</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">84166</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرتضی</FirstName>
					<LastName>هاشمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>هیات علمی دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمودیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رسول</FirstName>
					<LastName>اجل لوئیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه زمین شناسی مهندسی دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9770-1695</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>26</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Tensile failures including tensile cracks on the upper part of instable slopes, earth fissures, tensile cracks in earth dams, and any kind of tensile failures resulted from tensile stresses within soil body are considered as important engineering geological features. Studying tensile strength and deformation characteristics of soils can have a great role in the prevention of adverse phenomena resulted from tensile failures in soils. The Varamin collapsible soils are subjected to tensile fractures and earth fissuring because of the tensile stresses raised from the land subsidence of the Varamin plain. Therefore, in this study, the strength and deformation characteristics of these soils were investigated at undisturbed, reconstituted and treated states. Results indicate that, when undisturbed collapsible soils are subjected to tensile stresses, they show a low tensile strength and behave brittle in tension. Reconstituted soils have a lower tensile strength in comparison with undisturbed soils and behave very soft and fail easily in tension. Treated soils have a higher tensile strength in comparison with undisturbed soils and behave more ductile in tension and tolerate more deformation before tensile failure. Results indicate that the treatment of the collapsible soils with stabilizer materials together with compaction is an efficient method for strengthening these soils against tensile stresses and for improving their performance in tension.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">گسیختگی‌های کششی مانند ترک‌های کششی بالای دامنه‌های خاکی ناپایدار، شکاف‌های سطح زمین، ترک‌های کششی بدنه سد‌های خاکی و هر نوع گسیختگی دیگری در توده‌های خاک که از تنش‌های کششی ناشی می‌شود، از پدیده‌های مهم زمین‌شناسی مهندسی به حساب می‌آیند. مطالعه و شناخت مقاومت و تغییر شکل کششی خاک‌ها، می‌تواند سهم قابل توجهی در شناخت و پیشگیری از پدیده‌های ناشی از گسیختگی‌های کششی در خاک داشته باشد. خاک‌های رمبنده حاشیه دشت ورامین از جمله خاک‌هایی هستند که در اثر تنش‌های کششی ناشی از نشست زمین در دشت ورامین، در معرض گسیختگی کششی و تشکیل شکاف‌های سطح زمین قرار دارند. بنابراین در تحقیق حاضر ویژگی‌های مقاومت و تغییر شکل کششی این خاک‌ها در حالت‌های دست‌نخورده، بازسازی شده و بهسازی شده مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. نتایج تحقیق نشان می‌دهد هنگامی‌ که خاک‌های رمبنده در حالت دست‌نخورده تحت تنش کششی مستقیم قرار می‌گیرند، مقاومت کمی از خود نشان داده و در کشش به صورت شکننده رفتار می‌کنند. خاک‌های بازسازی شده در مقایسه با خاک دست نخورده، مقاومت کششی بسیار کمتری دارند و در کشش بسیار نرم رفتار کرده و به راحتی گسیخته می‌شوند. خاک‌های بهسازی شده در مقایسه با خاک‌های دست نخورده، مقاومت کششی بیشتری دارند و تحت تنش‌های کششی شکل‌پذیرتر رفتار کرده و تغییر شکل کششی بیشتری را قبل از گسیختگی تحمل می-کنند. نتایج این تحقیق نشان می‌دهد بهسازی خاک‌های رمبنده با استفاده از مواد افزودنی تثبیت کننده و سپس تراکم خاک، روش مناسبی برای تقویت این خاک‌ها در مقابل تنش‌های کششی و بهبود عملکرد آن‌ها در کشش است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خاک رمبنده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مقاومت کششی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کرنش گسیختگی کششی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شکنندگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شکل پذیری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_84166_83b94a3b44597b0c70497e2e9b396e13.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
