<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigation S20 brittleness index of limestone and effective parameters on it at dry and saturated states</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی شاخص شکنندگی S20 سنگ آهک و بررسی عوامل موثر بر آن در حالت خشک و اشباع</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>21</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>36</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">93635</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سجاد</FirstName>
					<LastName>صفری فرخد</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>غلامرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>لشکری پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد/ گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ناصر</FirstName>
					<LastName>حافظی مقدس</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد/ گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Brittleness is an important problem in rock boring. So far, various methods have been introduced for determining rock brittleness but no method has yet been standard to measure it. In this paper, an empirical study was done to provide a reliable method for predicting the S20 brittleness index. The S20 brittleness test was done for 35 limestone blocks pick out from different parts of Iran in dry and saturated state. In addition, physical (dry density, porosity, electrical resistivity, Schmidt rebound hardness number and water absorption), mechanical (uniaxial comprehensive strength and point load index) and dynamical properties (P and S wave velocity) was measured. Finally, the classification of the samples was done based on the studying of petrography and mineralogy and statistical studies were done for each class. According to the results, predicting S20 based on the provided classification has a high degree of certainty. In addition, by studying the brittleness of the samples in dry and saturated state, it was determined that the presence of Montmorillonite clay mineral causes a decrease of brittleness and the presence of intergranular micro cracks and high porosity leads to an increase brittleness in the saturation state relative to dry state.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">شکنندگی یکی از مسائل مهم در حفاری سنگ است. تاکنون روش های مختلفی برای تعیین شکنندگی سنگ معرفی شده است اما روشی برای اندازه گیری آن به عنوان استاندارد مطرح نشده است. در این مقاله، یک مطالعه تجربی برای ارائه روشی قابل اعتماد برای پیش بینی شاخص شکنندگی S20 صورت گرفته است. آزمایش تعیین شاخص شکنندگی S20 برای 35 بلوک سنگ آهک برداشت شده از نقاط مختلف ایران، در حالت خشک و اشباع انجام شد. به علاوه، خصوصیات فیزیکی (چگالی خشک، تخلخل، مقاومت الکتریکی، عدد سختی بازگشتی اشمیت و درصد جذب آب)، مکانیکی (مقاومت فشاری تک محوری و شاخص بار نقطه ای) و دینامیکی (سرعت موج برشی و تراکمی) اندازه گیری شد. در نهایت، رده بندی نمونه ها بر اساس مطالعات سنگ شناسی و کانی شناسی انجام شد و مطالعات آماری برای هر رده صورت گرفت. بر اساس نتایج، پیش بینی شاخص شکنندگی S20 بر اساس رده بندی ارائه شده از اطمینان بالایی برخوردار است. به علاوه، با بررسی شکنندگی نمونه ها در حالت خشک و اشباع مشخص شد که وجود کانی رسی مونتموریلونیت باعث افت شکنندگی و وجود ریزترک های درون دانه ای و تخلخل بالا باعث افزایش مقدار شکنندگی در حالت اشباع نسبت به خشک می شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شاخص شکنندگی S20</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حفاری سنگ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مونتموریلونیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سنگ‌شناسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سنگ آهک</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_93635_99eea64bd81434ef9849cb238ea74f6d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
