<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 3 و 4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Determination of geological and geotechnical parameters of rock mass along penstock tunnels of Rudbar-Lorestan dam</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تعیین پارامترهای زمین‌شناسی و ژئوتکنیکی توده‌سنگ مسیر تونل‌های پنستاک سد رودبار لرستان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>49</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>66</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68319</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهنام</FirstName>
					<LastName>ابره</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی اصفهان، دانشکده مهندسی معدن</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>لهراسب</FirstName>
					<LastName>فرامرزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی اصفهان، دانشکده مهندسی معدن</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرتضی</FirstName>
					<LastName>قارونی نیک</LastName>
<Affiliation>2. داشگاه علم و صنعت، دانشکده مهندسی راه آهن</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>13</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Accurate determination of geotechnical and geological parameters of rock mass was performed using geotechnical exploration results including, the laboratory and in situ tests, empirical relations, geological surveys and field observations. The rock masses along penstock tunnels of Rudbar-Lorestan have a complex geology and consist of Dalan, Hormoz and Mila formations, mostly composed of shale, marl, marly limestone to limestone and dolomite. In this study, based on the measured data, the rock masses along penstock tunnels were classified by engineering classification systems of RMR, Q and GIS. And, a new relationship between RMR and Q for the studied area was presented. There were various empirical relations between RMR, Q and GIS, that were used for estimating geotechnical parameters. It must be noted that each of the empirical relations found may produce proper results for special regions. In this paper, the deformation modulus, cohesion and friction angle of Dalan formation were evaluated using the results of in situ dilatometer tests, laboratory tests, and findings of more than 25 geotechnical exploration boreholes in Dalan formation. Afterwards, by calibrating the empirical equations through the measured data, the geotechnical parameters of Mila and Hormuz formations were accurately estimated.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">تعیین دقیق پارامترهای ژئوتکنیکی توده‌سنگ با استفاده از نتایج اکتشافات ژئوتکنیکی شامل: آزمایش‌های آزمایشگاهی و برجا، روابط تجربی، بررسی‌های زمین‌شناختی مهندسی و مشاهدات صحرایی انجام می‌شود. توده‌سنگ مسیر تونل‌های پنستاک سد رودبار لرستان از سازندهای دالان، میلا و هرمز تشکیل شده است که به طور عمده از سنگ های آهک تا آهک مارنی، دولومیت، شیل و مارن تشکیل شده‌ و از ساختار زمین‌شناختی پیچیده‌ای برخورداراست. در این تحقیق طبقه‌بندی توده‌سنگ مسیر تونل‌ها‌ی پنستاک بر اساس داده‌های اندازه‌گیری شده، با استفاده از سیستم‌های طبقه‌بندی مهندسی RMR، Q و GIS انجام شده است. سپس با استفاده از این داده‌ها رابطه‌ی جدیدی بینRMR - Q برای منطقه مورد مطالعه ارائه شد. روابط تجربی مختلفی بر اساس RMR، Q و GIS برای تخمین پارامترهای ژئوتکنیکی وجود دارد که این روابط، هر کدام برای نواحی و سازندهای خاصی می تواند نتیجه بهتری بدهد. در این تحقیق با استفاده از تحلیل نتایج حاصل از آزمایش‌های دیلاتومتری، مطالعات آزمایشگاهی و مطالعه بیش از 25 حلقه چاه و چاهک، پارامترهای مدول تغییرشکل‌پذیری، چسبندگی و زاویه اصطکاک داخلی سنگ‌های سازند دالان ارزیابی شد. سپس با کالیبره کردن روابط تجربی با استفاده از داده‌های اندازه‌گیری شده‌ی سازند دالان، پارامترهای ژئوتکنیکی سازندهای میلا و هرمز با صحت و دقت بیشتری تخمین زده شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پارامترهای ژئوتکنیکی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">÷نستاک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توده سنگ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تونل‌</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سد رودبار لرستان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68319_db9bd0a71110e57d200bbccabe60a25f.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
