<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The effect of hydrodynamic and morphologic conditions of Bahmanshir river on engineering geological properties 
of tidal deposits of Bahmanshir series]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Malek, Ghanbar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Khamehchian, Mashaallah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Moradi Harsini, Kazem]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association of Engineering Geology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2011]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Engineering geological properties]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Bahmanshir river]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Deposits of bahmanshir tidal series]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Hydrodynamic and morphology]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[  Bahmanshir river is a two directional tidal river in southwest Khuzestan province (IRAN). This river originates from Karun river near Khoramshahr city (upstream) and traverses downstream about 80 km before falling into the Persian Gulf. Holocene deposits along Bahmanshir river commonly consist of two clayey layers that have been separated by silty sand beds. These complexes have been known as Bhamanshir series which have deposited in tidal environment. Hydrodynamic and sedimentary environments studies of  Bahmanshir river show that tidal currents flow upstream from Arvand River and downstream from Persian Gulf also in the middle part of river due to its meandered morphology, the intensity and energy of tidal currents reduces. The main aim of this research is, to investigate the effect of hydrodynamic and morphologic conditions of Bahmanshir river on engineering geological properties of tidal deposits of Bahmanshir series. The results of studies reveal that engineering geological properties of deposits are approximately the same for both upstream and downstream of the river but in the middle part due to its meandered  morphology and reduction in energy intensity of flow, percentage of clayey minerals are more than upstream and downstream. This difference in percent of clayey minerals has caused the variety of engineering geological properties middle part rather than other region.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68293_a0a0ec10769cc0fd2fcda16cae481bc6.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.jiraeg.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Scientific Quarterly Journal of Iranian Association of Engineering Geology]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Shear velocity and normal stress level effects on shear stiffness 
of rock joints]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mousavi, Mahdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Atapour, Hadi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association of Engineering Geology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2011]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Rock joints]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Shear stiffness]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Shear velocity]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Shear stiffness is an important parameter of rock joints. This parameter along with normal stiffness is the basic input data of numerical modeling of jointed rock masses. There are several factors that influenced shear stiffness.  In this paper, the effects of shearing velocity, normal stress levels and the material of shearing blocks on shear stiffness are investigated. Artificial joint with planar surfaces were prepared with plaster (soft rock-like joints) and concrete (hard rock-like joints) and shear tests were performed on these samples under various normal stress levels and shearing velocities in the range of 0.3-30 mm/min. Results indicated that with increasing of shear velocity shear stiffness decreased.  On the other hand, when normal stress levels increased, shear stiffness increased linearly. This relation was named «shear stiffness linear envelope». It is remarkable that these results are correct for both artificial joints of different materials.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68294_ec4309cad3f6a09b4481d468567d83fa.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.jiraeg.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Scientific Quarterly Journal of Iranian Association of Engineering Geology]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Evaluation of correlation between internal friction angle and grains shape using laboratory tests and image technique of grains]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Cheshomi, Akbar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Khanmohammadi, Nasim]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Nasiri, Esmail]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association of Engineering Geology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2011]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Angle of friction]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Shape grains variable]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sphericity]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Roundness]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[  Determination of geotechnical parameter in coarse grained alluvia is important subject in geotechnical study. The paper presented a method that can be used to determine the angle of friction with use from particle shape for coarse grained alluvia. In this paper from 9 location in Tehran alluvia prepared soil samples. The angle of friction was determined based on the results of a number of laboratory test (Classification, triaxial and direct shear tests). Then, images of the grains forming the samples were taken and compared with the chart presented by Krumbein and Sloss (1963). In this manner determined shape grains variable (Sphericity and Roundness). In order to 2520 grains were taken images with use by microscope and without microscope. A relationship between the angles of friction was determined with laboratory tests and shape grains variable is investigated and proposed. With increase of angularity and decrease roundness, angles of friction increases.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68295_aea996f1842f8d595bc09fea311d1afd.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.jiraeg.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Scientific Quarterly Journal of Iranian Association of Engineering Geology]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Evaluation of collapsibility of loess deposits of Gharnaveh catchment in north of Kalale, Golestan province]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hafezi Moghaddas, Naser]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Nikudel, Mohammadreza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Bahrami, Kazem]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association of Engineering Geology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2011]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Golestan province]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Loess]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Collapsibility]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Consolidation test]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Kalale]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In engineering geology, collapsible soils are classified in problematic soil group and could be make serious problems for construction projects, especially in arid and semiarid areas. It also causes intensification of soil erosion and loss of vegetation. One of the major of collapsible soil group is losses deposits which are covered main surface area of Kalale in Golestan Province. This area is undergoing severe erosion in recent years also has experienced several destructive floods. There are a significant number of sinkholes in loess deposits of this area. In this research, to investigate and identify the loess soils characteristics, intact samples were taken and atterberg limits, unit weight, particle-size distribution, specific gravity, and shear strength parameters were determined in laboratory. The collapse potential of these soils was obtained by consolidation test results and based on two criteria of Hindi and Clevenger. The results show that these soils are clay loess with low plasticity index and have a high to medium potential of collapsibility. Also it found that the increased in porosity leading to increasing of collapse, whereas increasing in the activity of clay minerals is leading to decreasing of collaps.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68296_e101a9509a45bf786391c7c82e1f1bc5.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.jiraeg.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Scientific Quarterly Journal of Iranian Association of Engineering Geology]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Evaluation of improvement of mechanical resistance of fine soils due to the intrusion of calcium ions by means of electro kinetic method]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Davoodi, Mohammad Hadi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Kadivar, Amin]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association of Engineering Geology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2011]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Mechanical resistance]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fine soil]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Chloride calcium]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Electro kinetics]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Soil Improvement]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Many fine grain soils suffer from low shearing resistance and need to be improved. In cases the treatment is done using additive materials such as calcium ion, the process is time consuming and any accelerating process is highly valuable. In this article the feasibility of using electro kinetics for intruding reinforcing calcium ions into fine soil, in order to improve its mechanical resistance, is studied. Soil sample were prepared under equal conditions and a calcium chloride solution of 0.66 normal were permeated through them under direct current electricity (DC). Then a series of mechanical and chemical tests were conducted on soil samples and input-output solutions, respectively. Resistance parameters of the soil were measured by means of direct shear test, before and after permeation of calcium chloride solution. The results reveal that this method has an extraordinary effect in increasing the level of calcium absorption in soil along with its mechanical resistance. The cohesion and the internal friction angle of treated soil increased to 220% and 92% respectively under a voltage of 30 volts. This increase in resistance parameters was gained by permeating just one soil porous volume (Vv) of solution. The weight of added calcium chloride to the soil was just as much as 0.9 % of the dry weight of the sample.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68297_0e9b4030151cba73d38da1a70febaec3.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.jiraeg.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Scientific Quarterly Journal of Iranian Association of Engineering Geology]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Experimental study of grouting performance in Tehran alluvium type C]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Esmaeili, Morteza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Gharouninik, Morteza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hoseinpour, Hamed]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association of Engineering Geology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2011]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Tehran alluvium type C]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Groutability]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cement grout]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grouting pressure]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fine content]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[One Method of stabilizing the earth to dig underground spaces is using injection to minimize soil permeability and increase resistance during construction. Due to increasing construction subway and underground spaces and need to pass through loose zones, it is essential to study injection effects on loose alluvial soils that make up the bed of urban areas. In the present study, an experimental study is done on the soils based on the aggregation of Tehran alluvium type C which includes making cylindrical soil samples with some density and operations by injecting the slurry with different water to cement ratio and the various pressure, and the rate of soil samples groutability according to difference of samples weight before and after injection is investigated , and base on the various parameters, a numerical criteria for the groutability of Tehran alluvium type C is presented. Then broke the injected samples after reaching the 28-day strength the increasing cargo capacity of soil samples using uniaxial load test, measured, and also decrease soil permeability using the permeability test was evaluated.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68298_fffe9a6a6c9727001279f661cd2f596f.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.jiraeg.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Scientific Quarterly Journal of Iranian Association of Engineering Geology]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Study of physical characteristics effects of marl deposit on various erosional features in Sorkhe basin]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Pourkerman, Majid]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Charkhabi, Amir Hossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Fayazi, Farajollah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Peyrowan, Hamidreza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hashemi, Aliasghar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association of Engineering Geology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2011]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Erosion]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Marl]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Erosion index]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sorkheh watershed]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[PASW]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[  One of the greatest problems in Sorkheh artificial recharging system of Semnan province is the high amount of sedimentation into the system. Erosion of marl deposits around Sorkheh artificial recharging system supplies the main part of total sediments. Recognition of sensitivity to erosion and identifying effective factors such as physical and chemical properties and atterberg limits in marl deposits is the main target of this study. With reducing of sediment sorting and increasing of density, resistance to erosion of marl deposits increase. Such as effective main variables in eredibility are medium sand, medium silt and clay contents. Medium sand and medium silt increase both sorting and erosion index and ultimately reducing of density. These sizes of particles in marl units in rill erosion show the highest frequency. In the other hand, with increasing of clay parts, occurred opposite of above phenomenon. The highest frequency of this variable has observed in the low to moderate and high intensity of surface erosion. The obtained results were analyzed with factor analysis by Principal axis Factoring method. With this method, the two decreasing and increasing erosion factors are separated from together and confirm previous results.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68299_7e75e0ff2c9b6af81b8c690c1b9f3d28.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.jiraeg.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Scientific Quarterly Journal of Iranian Association of Engineering Geology]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>