<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2008</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Tectono-sedimentary analysis of high-altitude Plio-Quaternary sediments, southern slope of Mishow-Dagh, northwest of Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل زمین ساخت- رسوبی رسوبات پلیو- کواترنری مرتفع دامنه جنوبی میشوداغ در شمال باختری ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>87</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>101</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68145</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>داوود</FirstName>
					<LastName>مختاری</LastName>
<Affiliation>1-      دانشیار، گروه پژوهشی جغرافیا دانشگاه تبریز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2006</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study investigates the role of tectonic activities in fluvial systems and produce of accommodation space for Plio-Quaternary sediments of Southern slope of Mishow-Dagh horst which is an important structural element within the horst-graben system of north of the Orumia Lake, northwest of Iran. The result of these activities and other environmental and geomorphologic processes has been to impose control mechanisms in quality of sedimentation in sedimentary environments of the study area. Investigations on Plio-Quaternary sediments via interpretation of geological, topographical and areal photos and especially field studies, indicate that several evolution stages are occurred in sedimentary systems in the study area. Based on all constraints, a five stage evolutionary model of deposits as moderately consolidated conglomerate, Qt1, Qt2, Qt3 and Qt4 are proposed and then, the role of tectonic activities assessed on each of them. The results of study showed that present topographic and geomorphologic landscape of study area hardly influenced by Quaternary tectonic activities and this factor was played the main role in produce of accommodation space and formation of transverse drainage network. The record of formation of transverse drainage network referred to after the Pasadanian orogeny and before the beginning of stage Qt1 sedimentation. Since there are not witnesses based on uplift movements in central part of Mishow-Dagh in recent geologic times and especially Quaternary, therefore, it should be look for the reason of the increase in sediment yield of fluvial systems and spread sedimentation in Quaternary, in other factors such as climatic changes. However, geomorphologic witnesses based on fluvial systems properties, indicate that the Orumia Lake bed subsided in Pleistocene and Holocene as the result of Sharafkhaneh fault activities, that probably synchronous to Quaternary climatic changes(?) caused falling of Orumia Lake water surface. In particular, this paper provides a case study that contributes to the understanding of landscape development within tectonically active zones.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این مقاله نقش فعالیتهای زمین­ساختی در سامانه رودخانه­ای و ایجاد فضای رسوبگذاری برای رسوبات پلیوکواترنری دامنه جنوبی رشته کوهستانی میشوداغ به عنوان بخش مهمی از سامانه فرابوم فروبوم شمال دریاچه ارومیه در شمال باختری ایران، مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. نتیجه عملکرد این فعالیت­ها به همراه سایر فرآیندهای محیطی و زمین ریخت­شناسی، تحمیل ساز و کارهای کنترلی متعدد بر چگونگی رسوبگذاری در محیط­های رسوبی منطقه بوده است. بررسی­های انجام شده بر روی رسوبات پلیو- کواترنری منطقه از طریق تفسیر نقشه­های زمین­شناسی و توپوگرافی، عکس­های هوایی و به ویژه بازدیدهای میدانی، حاکی از وجود چندین مرحله فرگشتی در سامانه­های رسوبگذاری بخش­های مختلف منطقه می­باشد. بر این اساس، پنج دوره فرگشتی برای رسوبات فوق با عناوین رسوبات کنگلومرای نیمه متراکم، Qt1، Qt2، Qt3و Qt4 طرح شده است و در هریک از آنها نقش فعالیت­های زمین­ساختی در ایجاد فضای رسوبگذاری مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. بر اساس نتایج این پژوهش، سیمای توپوگرافی و زمین­ریختی فعلی منطقه به شدت از فعالیت­های زمین­ساختی کواترنری متأثر شده است و بر طبق شواهد موجود فعالیت­های زمین­ساختی کواترنری مهمترین  نقش را در ایجاد فضای رسوبگذاری و شکل­گیری شبکة آبراهه­ای  ناموافق داشته­اند. سابقه تشکیل شبکه رودخانه­ای ناموافق با ساختار زمین­شناسی منطقه به دوره بعد از کوهزایی پاسادنین و قبل از شروع رسوبگذاری واحد Qt1 بر     می­گردد. با توجه به این که شواهدی مبنی بر حرکات بالاآمدگی در هسته اصلی کوهستان در دوره­های اخیر زمین­شناسی و به ویژه در کواترنری وجود ندارد، لذا  باید دلیل افزایش تدارک رسوبی رودخانه­ها و بجاگذاری رسوبات کواترنری گسترده منطقه را در عوامل دیگری غیر از    فعالیت­های زمین­ساختی مانند تغییرات اقلیمی جستجو نمود. با این حال شواهد ژئومورفولوژی مبتنی بر ویژگی­های سامانه­های رودخانه­ای منطقه، حاکی از پائین رفتن بستر دریاچه ارومیه در اثر عملکرد گسل شرفخانه در پلئیستوسن پایانی و هولوسن است که همزمان با اثر تغییرات اقلیمی، افت سطح آب دریاچه ارومیه را سبب شده است. در مجموع، این مقاله مطالعه­ای موردی را که می­تواند به درک چگونگی برگشت چشم انداز در نواحی فعال زمین ساختی بیانجامد، در اختیار می­گذارد. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل‌های زمین ساخت- رسوبی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رسوبات پلیو- کواترنری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رسوبات رودخانه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شبکه آبراهه‌ای ناموافق</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فضای رسوبگذاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دامنه جنوبی میشوداغ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شمال باختری ایران</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68145_0909656d3ffa6a3810dd65e40ae3539a.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
