<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Case Study on the effects of physical parameters in electrical resistivity of fine grain soil</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی موردی اثر پارامترهای فیزیکی بر تغییرات مقاومت الکتریکی خاکهای ریزدانه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>65</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>74</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">101377</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عبداله</FirstName>
					<LastName>سهرابی بیدار</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده زمین‌شناسی، پردیس علوم، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ابراهیم</FirstName>
					<LastName>اصغری کلجاهی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیات علمی گروه علوم زمین/ دانشگاه تبریز</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0408-6107</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهزاد</FirstName>
					<LastName>امینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانش‌آموخته دوره کارشناسی ارشد، دانشکده زمین‌شناسی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Soil electrical resistivity is an easy indicator of soil corrosion potential assessment. In order to investigate the soil corrosion in an industrial zone on the margin of the Meyghan salt lake (Kheyr-Abad industrial town), the electrical resistivity was measured by Miller box in laboratory considering different conditions in terms of moisture content. Soils in the region are generally fine-grained and typically are from clay type (CL/CH) according to USCS. In the minimum considered moisture content for the test, which correspond to the dry season, the soils of the study area have the moderate to the severe corrosive potential that increases to the Meyghan lake side. The corrosion potential pattern in superficial soils (0 to 5 m) follows northeastern to southwest waterway channels and is more homogeneous in the deeper parts (5 to 10 m). With increasing moisture content, the electrical resistivity is strongly reduced and in the moisture content of 25%, the corrosion potential of the soils of the study area increases to severe and very severe. Analysis of covariance and correlation coefficient of resistivity decreasing ratio due to increased moisture content with the basic physical properties of soil indicates that the fine grained material content (passing #200) has the most effect on the decreasing of resistivity. The plasticity index, liquid limit and dry density have minor effects in comparison to fine grained material content.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مقاومت الکتریکی شاخصی ساده برای ارزیابی پتانسیل خورندگی خاکها می‌باشد. جهت بررسی خورندگی خاک در منطقه صنعتی شهرک خیرآباد در حاشیه دریاچه میقان در استان اراک، مقاومت ویژه الکتریکی به صورت آزمایشگاهی و با استفاده از جعبه میلر و در شرایط مختلف از نظر رطوبت اندازه گیری شده است. خاکهای منطقه از نوع ریزدانه بوده و نوعاً رسی هستند. در رطوبت کمینه و متناظر با وضعیت فصل خشک، خاکهای منطقه دارای پتانسیل خورندگی متوسط تا شدید هستند که به سمت دریاچه میقان افزایش می‌یابد. الگوی وضعیت خورندگی در خاکهای سطحی (0 تا 5 متر) از آبراهه‌های شمال شرقی به جنوب غربی پیروی می‌کند و در اعماق بیشتر (5 تا 10 متر) همگنی نسبی بیشتری دیده می‌شود. با افزایش مقدار رطوبت، مقاومت الکتریکی به شدت کاهش یافته و به تبع آن در رطوبت 25 درصد، پتانسیل خورندگی خاکهای منطقه به رده شدید و بسیار شدید تغییر می‌یابد. تحلیل کوواریانس و ضریب همبستگی نسبت کاهش مقاومت الکتریکی در اثر افزایش رطوبت با مشخصات فیزیکی پایه خاک، حاکی از اثرگذاری عمده مواد ریزدانه عبوری از الک 200 بوده و اثر شاخص خمیری، حد روانی و دانسیته خشک در مقایسه با آن کمتر است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مقاومت الکتریکی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خورندگی خاک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشخصات فیزیکی خاک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جعبه میلر</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_101377_017baa725a4f4714f10566f94670d028.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
