<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 و 2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2009</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Effect of specimen dimensions on fracture toughness 
of Harsin marble rock</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی اثر ابعاد هندسی قطعه، بر روی چقرمگی شکست سنگ مرمر هرسین</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>73</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>82</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68202</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجیدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>آیت اللهی</LastName>
<Affiliation>1-      آزمایشگاه خستگی و شکست دانشکده مکانیک دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حامد</FirstName>
					<LastName>ثقفی</LastName>
<Affiliation>1-      آزمایشگاه خستگی و شکست دانشکده مکانیک دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدعلیها</LastName>
<Affiliation>آزمایشگاه خستگی و شکست دانشکده مکانیک دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2008</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The determination of fracture toughness of a rock material requires a standard specimen with specific geometry dimensions. If the dimensions of specimen are lower than special values, the obtained fracture toughness may not be accurate. In order to attain the fracture toughness of rock materials correctly, several criteria have been proposed for the required minimum dimensions. In this study, some tests were conducted on the semi-circular specimen containing an edge crack and subjected to three-point-bend loading (SCB specimen) and the suggested criteria for the required minimum crack length and thickness were assessed. The specimens were made of Harsin marble rock. The results obtained from the fracture tests showed that these criteria are not comprehensive and are not consistent with the experimental results. Therefore, by using the necessary correction factors in equations related to the minimum crack length and thickness, these equations were revised such that they can estimate the experimentally observed results for the Harsin rock.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">برای تعیین چقرمگی شکست یک ماده سنگی نیاز به یک قطعه استاندارد با ابعاد هندسی مشخص است. اگر ابعاد هندسی قطعه از مقادیر مشخصی کمتر باشد، چقرمگی شکست محاسبه شده از دقت لازم برخوردار نمی‌باشد. به منظور محاسبه صحیح چقرمگی شکست مواد سنگی معیارهای مختلفی برای تعیین حداقل ابعاد هندسی قطعه ارائه شده است. در این تحقیق، با انجام آزمایش روی قطعه نیم دیسک با ترک لبه‌ای که تحت خمش سه نقطه‌ای قرار دارد، معیارهای ارائه شده برای حداقل طول ترک و ضخامتمورد نیاز برای تعیین چقرمگی شکست، مورد بررسی قرار می‌گیرد. قطعات تهیه شده، از جنس سنگ مرمر هرسین است. نتایج آزمایش‌های شکست انجام شده بر روی این سنگ نشان می‌دهد که معیارهای ارائه شده جامعیت لازم را برای تخمین این دو پارامتر در ماده سنگی آزمایش شده نداشته و لذا در این مقاله با در نظر گرفتن ضرایب تصحیح برای روابط مربوط به محاسبه حداقل طول ترک و ضخامت قطعه، معیارهای مربوطه به نحوی اصلاح می‌شوند که بتوانند نتایج حاصل از آزمایش شکست انجام شده بر روی سنگ مرمر هرسین را پیش‌بینی نماید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">: مواد سنگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">چقرمگی شکست</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قطعه SCB</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">طول ترک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ضخامت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سنگ مرمر هرسین</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68202_e4a1a68575c9d5059acfb68e6e45a91c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
