<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 و 2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Prioritization of landslide effective factors and its hazard mapping using AHP model (A case study: Keshvari watershed)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اولویت‌بندی عوامل مؤثر بر زمین‌لغزش و تهیه نقشه خطر آن با استفاده از مدل فرآیند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی (مطالعه موردی: حوضه کشوری)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>12</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68322</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سلمان</FirstName>
					<LastName>سوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، زمین شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد،</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>غلامرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>لشکری پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه زمین شناسی مهندسی دانشگاه فردوسی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>غفوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>طاهر</FirstName>
					<LastName>فرهادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، زمین‌شناسی اقتصادی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم تحقیقات، تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Identify the effective variables on landslides occurrence in the basin and zoning its hazard is one of fundamental methods for management and avoiding the risk. Keshvari watershed with an area about 345  km&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; is located in the 20 kilometers far from the south east of Khorram Abad city in Lorestan province. According to the tectonic and old basins division of Iran, this basin is part of folded Zagros and based on geological formations, topography, siesmology and climate, this basin is prone to landslide occurrence. In order to check the stability of slopes in this basin, in the first step landslide prone areas were identified. By merging the effective factors including slope, aspect, altitude, geology, earthquake, rainfall, landuse and distance from the fault and drainages on landslide with the landslide distribution map, impact of each of these factors assessed in ArcGIS software and then these factors were prioritized using AHP model. According the results of using the AHP in landslide risk zonation, 5.9, 38.2, 38.1, 15.79 and 2.01 percent of the area are located in very low, low, medium, high and very high risk classes respectively.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">شناسایی عوامل مؤثر در وقوع زمین‌لغزش در یک حوضه و پهنه‌بندی خطر آن یکی از ابزارهای اساسی جهت مدیریت و اجتناب از خطر می‌باشد. حوضه آبریز کشوری با مساحت ٣45 کیلومتر‌مربع در٢٠ کیلومتری جنوب شرق خرم‌آباد جزء زاگرس چین‌خورده است و با توجه به نوع سازند‌های زمین‌شناسی، وضعیت توپوگرافی، لرزه‌خیزی و اقلیم، از پتانسیل لغزشی بالایی برخوردار می‌باشد. به منظور بررسی پایداری دامنه‌ها در این حوضه ابتدا لغزش‌های حوضه شناسایی و ثبت گردیدند. با قطع نقشه‌های عوامل مؤثر بر لغزش با نقشه پراکنش زمین‌لغزش‌ها، تأثیر هر یک از عوامل شیب، جهت شیب، ارتفاع، زمین‌شناسی، بارش، کاربری اراضی، فاصله از گسل و آبراهه به ناپایداری شیب‌ها در محیط نرم‌افزار ArcGIS با استفاده از روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی (AHP) برآورد گردید. بر اساس نتایج پهنه‌بندی خطر زمین‌لغزش با روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی به ترتیب 9/5، 2/38، 1/38، 79/15 و 01/2 درصد از مساحت منطقه در کلاس‌های خطر خیلی کم، کم، متوسط، زیاد و خیلی زیاد قرار گرفته است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زمین‌لغزش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پهنه‌بندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حوضه کشوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل سلسله مراتبی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68322_4987fd8953a275583b3572c7af262408.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
