<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 و 2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2009</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Study of engineering geological properties of Asmari limestone in the north-east Masjed-Suliman</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مطالعه خصوصیات زمین شناسی مهندسی سنگ آهک سازند آسماری در شمال شرق مسجد سلیمان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>18</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68196</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>قبادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه زمین شناسی د انشگاه بوعلی سینا همدان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>محسنی</LastName>
<Affiliation>  عضو هیات علمی گروه زمین‌شناسی دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، همدان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>رسولی فرح</LastName>
<Affiliation>3-      دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، زمین‌شناسی مهندسی دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، همدان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2008</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The main purpose of this research is to assess the engineering geological properties of Asmari limestone in the north-east of Khuzestan province. For this purpose, 20 samples of limestone were selected from the north-east of Karun 1 dam site, and the relationships between petrographic characteristics, physical and mechanical properties were investigated. Index properties such as total porosity, dry unit weight, schmit hammer value, strength under uniaxial  compression and Brazilian tension were determined. Microscopic studies on the limestone reveal that they are mostly bioclast packstone and bioclast wackestone according to Dunham classification. From the statictical analysis of the data, regression equations were established among rock material parameters, while conversion factors relating index properties and strength were also determined. The petrographic characteristics of the studied rocks such as mineral composition and microstructure were analyzed in thin sections and their intrinsic influence on the measured strength parameters was also investigated</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">شناخت خصوصیات زمین‌شناسی مهندسی سازندهای سنگی ایران به عنوان یک ضرروت مطرح است. در این پژوهش بر اساس مطالعات سنگ‌شناسی وبا انجام آزمایش‌های مکانیک سنگ بر روی 20 نمونه از سنگ آهک‌های سازند آسماری در شمال شرق مسجد سلیمان ویژگی‌های زمین‌شناسی مهندسی آنها تعیین و ارتباط خصوصیات سنگ‌شناسی با خصوصیات فیزیکی و مکانیکی بررسی شده است. بر اساس مطالعات پتروگرافی و مطابق با رده‌بندی دانهام عمده سنگ‌های کربناته سازند آسماری از نوع بایوکلاست پکستون packstone) (Bioclast و بایوکلاست وکستون (Bioclast wackestone) هستند. سنگ آهک‌های سازند آسماری تخلخل خیلی کم تا متوسط  دارند و نفوذپذیری آنها خیلی کم تا کم می‌‌باشد. حداقل و حداکثر عدد سختی برای این سنگ‌ها به ترتیب 18 و 39 می‌باشد. با توجه به رده‌بندی مهندسی سنگ بکر و بر اساس دو عامل مقاومت تراکمی تک محوری و نسبت مدولی سنگ آهک‌های سازند آسماری در رده CL قرار می‌گیرند.  </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سنگ آهک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازند آسماری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خصوصیات پتروگرافیکی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ویژگی‌های فیزیکی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ویژگی‌های مکانیکی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مسجد سلیمان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68196_1d5261fe618f23a304b68e62b9e2aa64.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
