<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 3 و 4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Study of wind erosion in Sistan plain and its effects on engineering properties of soils</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی فرسایش بادی در دشت سیستان و تأثیر آن بر خصوصیات مهندسی خاک‌ها</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>13</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>26</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68206</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمید رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>سلوکی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین­شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ماشااله</FirstName>
					<LastName>خامه چیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین­شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ناصر</FirstName>
					<LastName>حافظی مقدس</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود، شاهرود، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید کاظم</FirstName>
					<LastName>علوی پناه</LastName>
<Affiliation>مرکز تحقیقات بیابان ایران، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Due to its specific climatic conditions (dry climate) and severe winds (including the 120 day long winds), wind erosion is accounted as one of the most important factors responsible for earth surface changes which in turn leads to the alteration of soil engineering properties. To investigate the role of wind erosion on soil properties changes, samples were collected between the years 1385 to 1387 from four different locations including areas without vegetation in the Hamoon Lake, areas with vegetation in the Hamoon Lake, barren lands and agricultural lands without cultivation. The in situ dry unit weight volume and undrained shear strength of soil were determined by in situ tests; however, gradation, atterberg limits, and the soil maximum dry density were determined by standard laboratory tests. The results indicate a decrease in liquid limits and soil adhesiveness with time in both farming lands and clay lands without vegetation; furthermore, clay soil showed trend towards transforming into silt. Soils will become more susceptible to erodibility when their adhesiveness values decrease. In areas which the loose surface layers erode, the in situ dry unit weight volume of soil increases and reaches to 2gr/cm3 at its maximum.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در منطقه سیستان به­دلیل شرایط خاص آب و هوایی(اقلیم خشک)و نیز وزش بادهای شدید (از جمله بادهای یکصدوبیست روزه)، فرسایش بادی یکی از عوامل مهم ایجاد تغییر شکل در زمین است که باعث تغییر خصوصیات مهندسی خاک نیز می­گردد. جهت بررسی نقش فرسایش بادی در تغییر خصوصیات خاک­های منطقه، از چهار محدوده­ی مختلف شامل، نقاط فاقد پوشش در دریاچه هامون، نقاط واجد پوشش در دریاچه هامون، زمین­های بایر و زمین­های کشاورزی بدون کشت در دو سال 1385 و 1387 نمونه­گیری به­عمل آمده است. همچنین آزمون­های برجا برای تعیین دانسیته در محل و مقدار مقاومت زهکشی نشده‌ی خاک و آزمون­های آزمایشگاهی برای تعیین دانه­بندی، حدود اتربرگ و حداکثر دانسیته خشک انجام گرفته است. نتایج نشان می­دهد که حد روانی و مقدار چسبندگی خاک، در زمین­های رسی بدون پوشش گیاهی و زمین­های کشاورزی، باگذشت زمان کاهش می­یابد و خاک­های رسی به سمت سیلتی شدن پیش می­روند. با کاهش  چسبندگی، خاک­ها بیشتر از پیش مستعد فرسایش­پذیری می­شوند. دانسیته برجای خاک­ها در نقاطی که لایه­های سست سطحی فرسایش می­یابند افزایش می­یابد و حداکثر به 2 گرم بر سانتی­متر مکعب می­رسد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دشت سیستان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرسایش بادی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خصوصیات مهندسی خاک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیلتی شدن</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68206_2efc8c2b5162d37a1d78a7da7bd2a31e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
