<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1391</YEAR>
<VOL>5</VOL>
<NO>0</NO>
<MOSALSAL>0</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>100</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مطالعه خصوصیات زمین‌شناختی مهندسی گرانیت‌های بروجرد</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The study of the engineering geological properties of Boroujerd granites</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>فراوانی سنگ­های گرانیتی و استفاده زیاد از آنها به عنوان سنگ نما و مالون، شناخت ویژگی­های زمین‌شناختی مهندسی این سنگ­ها را ضروری ساخته است. شناخت تنوع سنگ‌شناختی و ویژگی‌های فیزیکی و مکانیکی این سنگ‌ها از این جهت که ساختگاه برخی سدها (سدهای شهریار و طرق و پی سازه‌های مسکونی و تجاری را در بعضی از مراکز جمعیتی کشور تشکیل می­دهند نیز قابل اهمیت می­باشد. در این پژوهش بر اساس بازدیدهای صحرایی در شمال و شمال‌خاوری بروجرد، رخنمون­های مناسب توده گرانیتی بروجرد شناسایی شد و نمونه‌برداری از آن ها انجام شد. با مطالعه مقاطع نازک از نمونه­های تهیه شده از 7 معدن، خصوصیات کانی‌شناختی، بافت و نام زمین‌شناختی گرانیت­­ها تعیین گردید. با توجه به نتایج حاصله توده گرانیتی بروجرد متشکل از گرانودیوریت، مونزوگرانیت، گرانیت سفید و تونالیت می‌باشد. مطالعات سنگ‌شناختی وجود شکستگی­های میکروسکوپی ناشی از تکتونیک فعال منطقه را تایید می­کند. در این پژوهش خصوصیات فیزیکی و مکانیکی 224 نمونه سنگ گرانیت با انجام آزمون‌های استاندارد تعیین شده است. مطابق با رده‌بندی آنون (Anon) وزن واحد حجم گرانیت­های بروجرد متوسط تا زیاد می‌باشد. میزان جذب آب در اکثر نمونه‌ها کمتر از 1 درصد است. حداکثر سختی آنها 53 و حداقل 39 می‌باشد. شاخص دوام این سنگ‌ها بعد از 15 سیکل حداقل 34/96 و حداکثر19/99 درصد بوده است. بیشترین و کمترین مقدار مقاومت کششی در حالت خشک 6/3 و 12 مگاپاسکال است. بیشترین مقدار مقاومت فشاری سنگ­ها 123 و کمترین مقدار 58 مگاپاسکال می­باشد. بر اساس مقاومت فشاری تک‌محوری و نسبت مدولی، گرانیت­های بروجرد طبق رده‌بندی مهندسی سنگ بکر در رده CL و BL قرار می­گیرند. روابط به دست آمده بین خصوصیات سنگ‌شناختی، فیزیکی و مکانیکی با ضریب همبستگی مناسب می­تواند برای انجام مطالعات زمین‌شناختی مهندسی پروژه‌های عمرانی و معدنی در ناحیه فوق مورد استفاده قرار بگیرد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The abundance of granitic rocks and their frequent use as ornamental stones and Malones has made the recognition of their engineering geological properties important. Recognizing the diverse lithological, physical and mechanical properties of these rocks is also of importance because they are used in the construction of dams, and foundations of residential and commercial structures in different regions of the country.  In this research, based on field studies in the north and north- east Boroujerd, appropriate Boroujerd granite mass crops were identified and sampled.  Through studying thin sections taken from 7 mines the textual, mineralogical and geological characteristics of granites were determined. According to the results, Boroujerd granite masses composed of granodiorite, monzogranite, white granite and tonalite. Also petrological studies show the microscopic fractures caused by the active tectonic zone. In this study, using standard tests, the physical and mechanical properties of 224 samples of granite were determined.  According to Anon&#039;s classification the density of Boroujerd granites are medium to high.  Water absorption in most samples is less than 1 percent.  Their maximum hardness is 53 and at least 39.  The highest and lowest tensile strength when dry is 3.6 and 12 MPa. Based on maximum uniaxial compressive strength and elasticity ratio, and according to the engineering classification of intact rocks Boroujerd granites are classified in the categories of CL and BL. The obtained relations between lithological, physical and mechanincal properties and proper correlation coefficient can be used in geological studies and civil engineering projects of the area.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>16</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قبادی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Hosein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Gobadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه زمین شناسی د انشگاه بوعلی سینا همدان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه زمین شناسی د انشگاه بوعلی سینا</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>amirghobadi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رسولی­ فرح</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammadreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rasoli farah</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد آزمایشگاه زمین‌شناسی مهندسی و ژئوتکنیک، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا،  همدان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد آزمایشگاه زمین‌شناسی مهندسی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بروجرد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خصوصیات مکانیکی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سنگ‌شناختی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>گرانیت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ویژگی‌های فیزیکی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>احمدی خلجی، ا.، 1386. پترولوژی و ژئوشیمی توده‌های گرانودیوریتی بروجرد(غرب ایران)، مجله علوم دانشگاه تهران، جلد 33، شماره1، صفحه 1-14.##سازمان زمین‌شناختی کشور، 70 13. نقشه زمین‌شناختی 1:100000 بروجرد.##رسولی فرح، م.، 1389. مطالعه خصوصیات زمین‌شناسی مهندسی گرانیت‌های شمال و شمال خاوری بروجرد. پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشکده علوم، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا.##Akesson, U., Lindqvist, J.E., Go¨ransson, M., Stigh, J. 2001. Relationship between texture and mechanical properties of granites, central Sweden, by use of image-analysing technique. Bulletin of Engineering Geology and the Environment, 60: 277–284.##American Society for Testing Materials, 1998. Annual Book of ASTM Standard, vol.09.08 and 04.04.##Angeli M., Hebert, R., Menendez, B., David, C., Bigas, J.P., 2010. Influence of temperature and salt concentration on the salt weathering of a sedimentary stone with sodium sulphate. Engineering Geology, 115(3-4): 193–199.##Anon, 1979. Classficatoin of rocks and soils for engineering geological mapping. part 1- Rocks and soils material. Bulltin of Engineering Geology and the Environment, 19: 71-364.##Ayday, C.G., Oktan, R.M. 1992. Correlations between L and N-type Schmidt hammer rebound values obtained during field-testing. In: Hudson J.A. (Ed.), International ISRM Symposium on Rock Characterization. Chester. pp. 47–50.##I˙rfan, T.Y., 1996. Mineralogy, fabric properties and classification of weathered granites in Hong Kong. Quaterly Journal of Engineering Geology and Hydrogeology, 29: 5–35.##ISRM, 1981b. Rock Characterization Testing and Monitoring, Suggested Method. Brown E.T. (Ed.), Oxford: Pergamon Press., London, 221p.##Katz, O., Reches, Z., Roegiers, J., 2000. Evaluation of mechanical rock properties using a Schmidt hammer. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 37: 723–728.##Merriam, R., Rieke, H.H., Kim, Y.C., 1970. Tensile strength related to mineralogy and texture of some granitic rocks. Engineering Geology, 4: 155–160.##Onodera, T.F., Asoka Kumara, H.M., 1980. Relation between texture and mechanical properties of crystalline rocks. Bulletin of Engineering Geology and the Environment, 22: 173–177.##Ra¨isa¨nen, M., 2004. Relationships between texture and mechanical properties of hybrid rocks from the Jaala–Iitti complex, southeastern Finland. Bulletin of Engineering Geology and the Environment, 74: 197–211.##Sachpazis, C.I., 1990. Correlating Schmidt hardness with compressive strength and Young&#039;s modulus of carbonate rocks. Bulletin of the International Association of Engineering Geology, 42: 75–83.##Sousa, L.M.O.,  2007. Granite fracture index to check suitability of granite outcrops for quarrying. Engineering Geology, 92: 146–159.##Zhang L, 2005. Engineering Properties of Rocks, Vol. 4., 1-290. Elsevier Publ., Amsterdam.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تحلیل پایداری شیروانی‌های سنگی مشرف به نیروگاه سد سردشت با در نظر گرفتن اثر کلیواژ توده سنگ</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Stability analysis of large rock slopes for Sardasht dam hydraulic power plant trenches considering rock cleavage</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>از آنجا که ساختگاه سد سردشت دربرگیرنده توده سنگ‌های دگرگون شده  اسلیتی است، سطوح مشخص کلیواژ از ویژگی­های بارز این سنگ بوده و موجب کاهش مقاومت توده سنگ می‌گردد. بنابراین ارزیابی پایداری سازه‌های جانبی سد شامل فضاهای زیرزمینی و شیروانی‌ها از اهمیت زیادی برخوردار است. جهت تحلیل پایداری شیروانی مشرف به نیروگاه سد سردشت از روش‌های تعادل حدی، نرم‌افزار SLIDE و روش عددی تفاضل محدود، نرم‌افزار دو بعدی FLACSLOPE  برای حالت‌های بدون در نظر گرفتن اثر کلیواژ، با در نظر گرفتن اثر کلیواژ و اثر زون‌های خرد شده استفاده شده است. نتایج نشان می‌دهد که برای حالت‌های با در نظر گرفتن اثر کلیواژ و اثر زون‌های خرد شده، شیب شیروانی از ضریب اطمینان قابل قبولی برخوردار نمی‌باشد. به منظور بررسی دقیق‌تر اثر کلیواژ بر پایداری شیروانی مشرف به نیروگاه سد سردشت، بررسی‌های آماری نیز صورت گرفت. با توجه به منحنی تابع توزیع تجمعی، ضریب اطمینان حدود 68٪ داده‌ها کمتر از 7/1 برآورد گردید که این امر نشان دهنده اثر زیاد کلیواژ بر کاهش مقاومت فشاری توده سنگ اسلیتی است. بنابراین شیب حدود 1:6 ارائه شده در نقشه حفاری مطالعات مرحله اول، در این توده سنگ ناپایدار است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The site for Sardasht dam and its hydraulic power plant contains metamorphic slate rock masses with distinguished cleavage surface characteristics leading to reduced rock mass strength. Hence, stability analysis of the surrounding structures, underground spaces and slopes, is of great importance. Stability analysis of the slope, adjacent to the dam, was carried out for the three conditions of without cleavage, considering cleavage and inclusion of fractures zones, based on limit equilibrium and finite difference methods using SLIDE and FLACSLOPE 2D codes, respectively. The results indicate that the slope slide was not found safe in the presence of cleavage and fractured zones. For assurance, further statistical analysis was also carried out on the slope stability.  The accumulative distribution function indicated that the confidence coefficient for 68% of the data was found to be less than 1.7, which confirms the extreme influence of cleavage on the slate rock mass strength. Therefore, the 1:6 slope presented in the drilling map preliminary report is unstable.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>17</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>26</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بخشنده امنیه</Family>
						<NameE>Hasan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Bakhshndeh Amieh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>1. استادیار گروه معئن، دانشکده مهندسی، دانشگاه کاشان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>1. استادیار گروه معئن، دانشکده مهندسی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>bakhshandeh@kashanu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سعید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>طایی سمیرمی</Family>
						<NameE>Saeed</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Taei Semiromi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد استخراج  مهندسی معدن، دانشگاه کاشان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد استخراج  مهندسی معدن،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مرتضی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رحیمی</Family>
						<NameE>Morteza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rahimi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکترای مکانیک سنگ، دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکترای مکانیک سنگ، دانشگاه صنعتی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تحلیل پایداری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>روش تعادل حدی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شیروانی‌های سنگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کلیواژ سنگ</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نرم افزار FLACSLOPE</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>حسنی پاک، ع.الف.، 1377. زمین آمار. انتشارات دانشگاه تهران، چاپ اول.##خدابنده لو، ف.، بهادر بیگی، د.، 1390. نرم افزار FLAC. انتشارات جهاد دانشگاهی واحد صنعتی امیرکبیر, چاپ سوم.##مهندسی مشاور سپاسد – فراب.،1390. گزارش زمین شناسی مهندسی مطالعات مرحله دوم, تهران.##مهندسی مشاور مشانیر، 1390. گزارش بررسی، بازنگری و صحه گذاری مطالعات مرحله اول طرح سد ونیروگاه سردشت. تهران، فصل یازدهم.##Al-Harthi, A.A., 1998. Effect of planar structures on the anisotropy of Ranyah sandstone, Saudi Arabia. Engineering Geology, 50: 49–57.##Bromhead, E.N., 2002. The stability of slopes. Blackie Academic and Professional., 2nd edition, London and New York, 441p.##Giani, G.P., 1992.  Rock slope stability analysis. A.A.Balkema., United States of America, pp.47-73.##Goshtasbi, K., Ahmadi, M., Seyedi, J., 2006.  Anisotropic strength behavior of  slates in the Sirjan-Sanandaj zone. The Journal of the South African Institute of Mining and Metallurgy, 106: 71-76.##Hoek, E., Bray, J.W., 1981. Rock slope  engineering. 3rd Edition, London, Institute of mining and Metallurgy.##Johansson, L., Axelsson, K., 1992. Calculation of the slope stability using classical calculation methods, a comparison between different calculation programmes, Published in Swedish, the Swedish commission on slope stability, Report 2:91.##Kliche, C.A., 1999. Rock slope stability. Society for Mining, Metallurgy and Exploration, Inc. United States of America, 134p.##Nasseri, M.H.B., Rao, K.S., Ramamurthy, T., 2003. Anisotropic strength and deformational behavior of Himalayan schists. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 40:  3–23.##Piteau, D.,  Martin, D., 1982. Mechanics of rock slope failure. Third International conference on Stability of Surface Mining, Vancouver ,British Columbia, Society of Mining Engineering, pp. 113-169.##Rocscience, Inc., 2003. 2D Limit Equilibrium Slope Stability for Soil and Rock Slope (SLIDE), A users manual, Version 5.##Sjoberg, J., 1999 .Analysis of  large scale rock slopes. Department of Civil and Mining Enginering, Sweden, pp.11-35.##Tien, Y.M., Kuo, M.Ch., Juang, Ch.H., 2006. An experimental investigation of the failure mechanism of simulated transversely isotropic rocks. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 43:  1163–1181.##Tien, Y. M.,  Kuo,  M. C., 2001. A failure criterion for transversely isotropic rock. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 38:  399–412.##Walsh, M.J., 2003. Engineering and design slope stability. US Army Corps of  Engineers, Washangton, DC, 205p.##Wyllie, D., 2005. Foundations on rock. E and FN Spon is an imprint of the Taylor and Francis Group.New York, 457p.##Wyllie, D., Mah, C., 2004. Rock slope engineering. Spon Press is an imprint of the Taylor and Francis Group. New York, 455p.##Xue-min, Z., Feng, Y., Jun-sheng, Y., 2010. Experimental study on anisotropic strength properties of sandstone. The Electronic Journal of Geotechnical Engineering, 15: 1325-1335.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>شناسایی وارزیابی خصوصیات مکانیکی خاک‌های رمبنده</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Identification and evaluation of mechanical behavior collapsible soil
(case study in north eastern of Iran(</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>خاک­های رمبنده در صورت اشباع شدن بدون آنکه تغییری در تنش­های اعمالی ایجاد کنند و یا تحت اثر ارتعاش قرار گیرند، نشست زیادی    می­کنند و ممکن است به پی­، جاده­، خطوط ریلی، سدها، خطوط لوله و یا دیگر سازه­ها خسارت وارد آورند. خاک­های رمبنده در بسیاری از مناطق جهان به صورت پراکنده، و در ایران بیشتر در مناطق مرکزی و شرقی مشاهده می­شوند. در تحقیق حاضر، خاک محدوده­ی شمال‌شرق شهر مشهد مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. با توجه به مقاومت پایین خاک این منطقه هنگام اشباع شدن، به نظر می­رسد که خاک محل پروژه مستعد رمبندگی باشد. علاوه بر این، با عنایت به احداث سازه­های ریلی و ساختمان در محل، ممکن است در اثر ارتعاش ناشی از عبور قطار و افزایش رطوبت، نشست زیادی به خاک تحمیل شود و همین امر مشکلاتی برای سازه­های ریلی و ساختمان­های موجود ایجاد کند. در همین راستا تعیین میزان رمبندگی خاک ضروری می­نمود. به این منظور، ابتدا مشخصات فیزیکی و مکانیکی خاک منطقه مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفت و سپس جهت تعیین میزان رمبندگی، معیارهای مختلت رمبندگی بررسی و با یکدیگر مقایسه شدند. نتایج آزمایش­های آزمایشگاهی انجام شده نشان داد که خاک به افزایش رطوبت حساس بوده است و در صورت اشباع شدن، پارامترهای مقاومتی آن کاهش می­یابد. برای بررسی دقیق­تر پتانسیل رمبندگی، تعدادی آزمایش‌ برجا انجام شد. نتایج این آزمایش‌ها نیز نشان می­دهد که خاک محل به افزایش رطوبت و رمبنده بودن حساس است و می­تواند برای خطوط ریلی و سازه‌های احداثی در محل مشکل ایجاد کند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Collapsible soils, when saturated, without any change in applied stress or any vibration, undergo large settlements. This will cause damages to the building foundations, roads, rail road, dams, pipelines which may lead to fracturing and collapsing. Collapsible soils are scattered all over the world. In Iran they can be found in central and eastern part of the country. In the present research, the North Eastern of Mashhad has been studied in order to identify the collapsibility potential of soil in this area. This was necessary since new buildings construction such as subway of underground transportation system is in process. These buildings are commonly affected by vibration forces transmitted from this system. Physical and mechanical parameters of the collapsible soil in this area have been evaluated and various collapsibility criteria are compared. The laboratory test results indicate the collapsibility of the soil potential. Also field tests were performed to evaluate the mechanical properties and collapsibility potential of soils. The results have confirmed the possible collapsibility of sub-soil in this area, which may lead to unavoidable damages to the buildings and rail way system.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>27</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>40</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>جعفر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بلوری بزاز</Family>
						<NameE>Jafar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Bolouri Bazzaz</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار دانشکده‌ی مهندسی، گروه عمران دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار دانشکده‌ی مهندسی، گروه عمران دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>bolouri@ferdowsi.um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدعلی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>معروف</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Marouf</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مکانیک خاک و پی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مکانیک خاک و پی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>: آزمایش‌های صحرایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پتانسیل رمبندگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خاک رمبنده</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>معیار رمبندگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>رفیعی، ب.، 1387 .تثبیت خاک‌های رمبنده با تزریق– مطالعه‌ی موردی راه­آهن سمنان- تهران. پایان‌نامه کارشناسی‌ارشد، دانشگاه بین‌المللی امام‌خمینی، قزوین.##گودرزی، ا. ر، اوحدی، و. ر.، 1386 .تأثیر توام انحلال نمک‌های کربناتی یا سولفاتی و قابلیت رمبندگی بر تشدید شکل‌گیری فروچاله‌ها. مجله دانشکده فنی، جلد34، شماره 3،##Benatti,  J.C.B., Miguel, M.G., Rodrigues, R.A., Vilar, O.M., 2011. Collapsibility study for tropical soil profile using oedometric tests with controlled suction. In: Alonso, E., Gens, A. (Eds.), Unsaturated Soils., Taylor &amp; Francis Group, London, PP.193-198.##Das, B.M., 1990. Principles of Foundation Engineering”, 2nd Edition, PWS-Kent PubT Co.##Day, R.W., 1996. Discussion: Down-Hole Collapse Test System. Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering, 122: 869 – 872.##Feda, J., 1988. Collapse of  loess upon wetting. Engineering Geology, 25: 263-269.##Francisca, F.M., 2007. Evaluating the Constrained Modulus and Collapsibility of Loess from Standard Penetration Test. International Journal of Geomechanics, 7(4): 307–310.##White, J.L., Greenman, C., 2008. Collapsible Soils in Colorado. Engineering Geology, Colorado Geological Survey Publication EG-14.##Huat, B.B.K., AL Aziz, A., Faisal, H.A., Azmi, N.A., 2008. Effect of Wetting on Collapsibility and Shear Strength of Tropical Residual Soils. Ele. Journal of Geotechnical Engineering (EJGE), 13(Bund. G): 1-14.##Jennings, J.E., Knight, K., 1975. A Guide to construction or with materials exhibiting additional settlement due to collapse of grain structure.  6th Regional Conference for Africa On Soil Menchanics and Foundation Engineering, Durban, South Africa, PP. 99-105.##Lim, Y.Y., Miller, G.A., 2004. Wetting-Induced Compression of Compacted Oklahoma Soils.  Journal of Geotechnical an d Geoenvironmental Engineering (ASCE), 130(10): 1014–1023.##Lin, Z.G., Wang, S.J., 1988. Collapsibility and deformation characteristics of deep-seated loess in China. Engineering Geology, 25: 271-282.##Lollo, J. A., Rodrigues, R.A., Elis, V. R., Prado, R., 2011. Use of electrical resistivity to identify collapsible soils in Brazil. Bulletin of Engineering Geology and the Environments, 70: 299–307.##Madhyannapu, R.S., Madhira, R.M., Anand, J.P. Ghosh, A., 2008. Compressibility and collapsibility characteristics of sedimented fly ash beds. Journal of Materials in Civil Engineering (ASCE), 20(6): 401-409.##Rafie, B.M.A., Ziaie Moayed, R., Esmaeli, M., 2008. Evaluation of soil collapsibility potential: A case study of Semnan railway station. Journal of Geotechnical Engineering (EJGE), 13(Bund. G): 1-6.##Reznik, Y.M., 2000. Engineering approach to interpretation of oedometer tests performed on collapsible soils. Engineering Geology, 57: 205–213.##Reznik, Y. M., 2007. Influence of physical properties on deformation characteristics of collapsible soils.Engineering Geology, Vol. 92, pp. 27-37.##Rodrigues, R.A., Elis, V.R., Prado, R., Lollo, J.A., 2006. Laboratory tests and applied geophysical investigations in collapsible soil horizon definition.The Geological Society of London. International Association for Engineering Geology and the Environment ( IAEG), Paper No. 115.## Rust, E., Ben, H.G., 2010. Collapsible soils an overview.  Civil Engineering: Magazine of the South African Institution of Civil Engineering, 18(2): 14-17.##Santagata, M.C., 2011. Identification and Behavior of Collapsible Soils. Joint Transportation Research Program, Technical Report Series, Indiana Department of Transportation, ReportNo.765.463.1521. SPR-3109.##Scheffe, K.F., 2005. Collapsible soils in the Rio Grande valley of central New Mexico.  Geological Society of America(GSA), 37(7): 327.##Soliman S.h., 2010.  Performance of Reinforced Collapsible Soils. PhD thesis, Civil Eng. Dept., Concordia University Montreal, Quebec, Canada.##Pawlak, S.L., 1998. Evaluation, Design and Mitigation, Collapsible Soil Sites in Western Colorado. Colorado Geological Survey, Geologic Hazards and Engineering Practices in Western Colorado, Glenwood Springs, Colorado.##Williams, T.,  Rollins, K.M., 1991. Collapsible Soil Hazard for the Cedar City, Utahu Area. Contract report T91-10, UTAHU geological survey.##Yuan, Z.X., Wang, L.M., 2009. Collapsibility and seismic settlement of loess. Engineering Geology,105:119–123.##Yuanqing, Z., Zhenghan, C.H.,2009. New method of studying collapsibility of loess.  Front.  Archit. Civ. Eng. China, 3(3): 305–311##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارزیابی سایندگی خاک‌ها در حفاری مکانیزه تونل‌های شهری با نگرشی ویژه به خط یک قطار شهری تبریز</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Evaluation of soil abrasiveness in mechanized tunneling with special attitude to the Tabriz metro line1</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>یکی از عوامل مهم در حفاری مکانیزه تونل‌ها‌ی خاکی، اثر سایندگی خاک‌ها و سنگ‌دانه‌ها بر روی ابزارهای برشی و سایر قسمت‌های کله‌حفار می‌باشد. روش‌های متعددی برای اندازه‌گیری درجه سایندگی سنگ‌ها وجود دارد ولی در مورد خاک روش‌های تعیین سایندگی محدودتر است. وجود این محدودیت در ارزیابی مناسب درجه سایندگی خاک‌ها، یکی از چالش‌های علم زمین‌شناسی مهندسی در صنعت حفاری و تونل‌سازی مکانیزه می‌باشد. لذا لازم است با انجام آزمایش‌های آزمایشگاهی و استفاده از اطلاعات موجود و عملی نسبت به بررسی این موضوع اقدام شود. در این مقاله با انجام آزمون‌های مختلف  LCPCبه بررسی تأثیر برخی از پارامترهای مهم و مؤثر در سایندگی خاک‌ها (دانه‌بندی، درصد کوارتز معادل و درصد رطوبت) پرداخته شده و سپس وضعیت خاک مسیر خط یک متروی تبریز از لحاظ سایندگی ارزیابی شده است. نتایج این تحقیقات نشان داده با افزایش اندازه­ی دانه‌های خاک، میزان سایندگی افزایش می‌یابد. تأثیر درصد رطوبت در همه نمونه‌های مورد آزمایش یکسان نبوده، در تعدادی باعث افزایش و در تعدادی باعث کاهش میزان سایندگی می‌شود. بررسی تأثیر درصد کوارتز معادل در میزان سایندگی خاک نشان داد که با افزایش این پارامتر، بسته به اندازه دانه‌های خاک، میزان سایندگی به صورت توانی افزایش می‌یاید. بررسی میزان سایندگی خاک مسیر خط یک متروی تبریز، نشان داد خاک مذکور در حالت خشک، خیلی ساینده و در حالت اشباع در حد متوسط سایندگی است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Soil abrasivity and TBM component wear issues is one of the most important factor in success of this type of projects. Despite of rocks there are very few test methods to describe the abrasive characteristic of soils. It can be mentioned that impossibility of reliable estimation of soil abrasivity on mechanical tunneling is one of the engineering geology science gaps in tunneling and drilling industry. In this paper the influence of some important parameter on soil abrasivity (soil particle size, equivalent quartz content and water content) are studied by use of LCPC standard and the abrasiveness of Tabriz metro line 1 soil are estimated. The results indicate by increasing of soil particle size the abrasivity trend to be increased. The influence of water content on abrasivity was not the same in all of the samples. The presence of water in some samples cause to increase and in the other sample cause to decrease of abrasivity. With increasing the equivalent quartz content (EQC), the abrasivity of soil depends on grain size has trend to increase with power relation. Evaluation of Tabriz metro line 1 soil samples shown it is very abrasive  and medium abrasive in dry  and saturated condition respectively.   </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>41</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>58</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>قدرت</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>برزگری</Family>
						<NameE>Ghodrat</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Barzegari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، گروه زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، دانشکده علوم پایه، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، گروه زمین‌شناسی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>gbarzegari@tabrizu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ارومیه ای</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Oromiehei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیارگروه زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، دانشکده علوم پایه، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیارگروه زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، دانشکده علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>uromeiea@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>حفاری مکانیزه تونل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زمین‌شناسی مهندسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>‌ سایش TBM</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سایندگی خاک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>درویش زاده، ع.، 1370. زمین‌شناسی  ایران، انتشارات امیرکبیر.##سازمان زمین‌شناسی و اکتشافات معدنی کشور، 1372. نقشه زمین‌شناسی تبریز 1:100000، تهران.##سازمان قطار شهری تبریز، 1383. گزارش­های ژئوتکنیکی مسیر تونل خط یک، تبریز.##سازمان قطار شهری تبریز، 1388. گزارش­های زمین‌شناسی فاز اجرا.##معماریان، ح.، 1385. زمین‌شناسی برای مهندسین، انتشارات دانشگاه تهران.##Alavi Gharahbagh, E., Rostami, J., Palomino, A.M., 2011. New soil abrasion testing method for soft ground tunneling applications. Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology, 26: 604–613.##Dahl, F., Bruland, A., Jakobsen, P.D., Nilsen, B., Grov, E., 2012. Classifications of properties influencing the drillability of rocks, based on the NTNU/SINTEF test method. Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology, 28: 150-158.##Indian Geological Survey, 2011. http://libguides.com.edu/content.php##Langmaack, L., Grothen, B., Jakobsen, P.D., 2010. Anti-wear and anti-dust solutions for hard rock TBMs, Proceedings of World Tunneling Conference, Vancouver, Canada.##Lien, R., 1961. An indirect test method for estimating the drillability of rocks. PhD thesis, NTH Department of Geology, 90p.##Nilsen B., Dahl, F., Holzhauser, J. and Raleigh, P., 2007. New test methodology for estimating the abrasiveness of soils for TBM tunneling. Rapid excavation and tunneling conference, pp. 104-116.##Nilsen, B., Dahl, F., Holzhäuser, J., Raleigh, P., 2006b. Abrasivity testing for rock and soils. Tunnels and Tunneling International, 47–49.##Nilsen, B., Dahl, F., Holzhäuser, J., Raleigh, P., 2006c. SAT: NTNU’s new soil abrasion test. Tunnels and Tunneling International, 5: 43–45.##Nilsen, B., Dahl, F., Holzhäuser, J., Raleigh, P., 2006a. Abrasivity of soils in TBM tunneling. Tunnels and Tunneling International, 36–38.##Rostami, J., Alavi Gharabagh, E., Palomino, A.M., Mosleh, M., 2012. Development of soil abrasivity testing for soft ground tunneling using shield machines. Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology, 28: 245–256.##Plinninger, R., Kasling, H., Thuro, K. and Spaun, G., 2003. Testing onditions and geomechanical properties influencing the CERCHAR abrasiveness index (CAI) value, International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 40: 259-263.##Plinninger, R.J., Käsling, H., Thuro, K. 2003. Wear Prediction in Hard rock Excavation Using the Cerchar Abrasiveness Index (CAI, EUROCK 2004 &amp; 53rd Geomechanics Colloquium. Schubert.##Thuro, K., Singer, J., Käsling, H., Bauer, M., 2006. Soil abrasiveness assessment using the LCPC testing device. Felsbau, 24: 37–45.##Thuro, K., Käsling, H., 2009. Classification of the abrasiveness of soil and rock / Klassifikation der Abrasivität von Boden und Fels. Geomechanics and Tunneling, 2 (2): 179–188.##Thuro, K., Käsling, H., 2003. Hard rock tunnel boring, cutting, drilling and blasting: rock parameters for excavatability, ISRM, Technology roadmap for rock mechanics, South African Institute of Mining and Metallurgy, pp. 1227-1233.##West, G., 1989. Rock Abrasiveness Testing for Tunnelling.  International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences and Geomechanics. Abstracts, 26(2): 151-160##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی پتانسیل لرزه‌خیزی مناطق مختلف ایران با استفاده از شبیه‌سازی مونت‌کارلو</TitleF>
				<TitleE>An investigation on the seismicity of Iran seismotectonic provinces using Monte Carlo simulation</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>روابط تجربی رخداد زلزله، مانند رابطه­ی خطی گوتنبرگ - ریشتر، با رویکرد کاملا قطعی ارائه شده‌اند و با وجود عدم قطعیت­ها و احتمالات مختلف در رخداد زلزله، از دقت کافی برخوردار نمی­باشند. عدم قطعیت موجود در تعیین تعداد زلزله­های با بزرگی مشخص ایجاب می­کند تا برای تعیین تعداد رخداد زلزله از رویکرد احتمالاتی استفاده شود. در این مطالعه با بهره­گیری از شبیه­سازی مونت­کارلو و همچنین با فرض توزیع نرمال برای تابع توزیع احتمال بزرگی زلزله، پتانسیل لرزه­خیزی در مناطق مختلف ایران به صورت احتمالی مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است.   تحلیل­های احتمالاتی انجام شده برای مناطق مختلف ایران، تعداد رخداد زلزله با توزیع بزرگی نرمال و درصد احتمال مختلف را مشخص می­کند. بر این اساس چنانچه ایران به بیست منطقه­ی ­لرزه­خیز تقسیم شود منطقه­ی 12 (واقع در جنوب‌غربی ایران) لرزه­خیزترین منطقه و منطقة 16 (واقع در شمال غربی ایران) کمترین تعداد رخداد زلزله را در بازة زمانی معین دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Empirical relationships between earthquake magnitude and frequency of occurrence, e.g. Gutenberg - Richter’s relationship, have been presented for a special region using limited historical data. These relationships usually involve many sources of uncertainty (frequency of occurrence, magnitude, etc.). Therefore, it is necessary to use probabilistic simulation for determination of earthquake occurrence frequency instead of the deterministic one. In the present, Monte Carlo simulation, as the most preferred approach for probabilistic simulation, is used to evaluate seismic potential of Iran provinces. On the basis of probabilistic analyses, the frequency of earthquake occurrence by assuming a normal distribution of magnitudes and different occurrence probability are determined for 20 seismotectonic provinces of Iran. Furthermore, it can be concluded that the province situated in southwest of Iran (i.e. region number 12) is the most seismically active region and province number 16 (situated in the northwest of Iran) is the least seismically active region of Iran.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>59</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>68</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عبدالهادی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قزوینیان</Family>
						<NameE>Abdolhadi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ghazvinian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار مهندسی مکانیک سنگ، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار مهندسی مکانیک سنگ، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حمیدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نجاتی</Family>
						<NameE>Hamidreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nejati</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>2. دانشجوی دکتری مهندسی مکانیک سنگ، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>2. دانشجوی دکتری مهندسی مکانیک سنگ، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>nejatihmd@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>وهاب</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سرفرازی</Family>
						<NameE>Vahab</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sarafrazi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار مهندسی مکانیک سنگ، دانشگاه صنعتی همدان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار مهندسی مکانیک سنگ، دانشگاه صنعتی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حیاتی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hayati</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مهندسی معدن، دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مهندسی معدن، دانشگاه صنعتی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ارزیابی خطر زلزله</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تحلیل احتمالاتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شبیه‌سازی مونت‌کارلو</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>لرزه‌خیزی ایران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>برگی، خ.ف.، 1379. اصول مهندسی زلزله. انتشارات دانشگاه تهران.##شکری قصبه، م.، بخشیانی ع. و مفید م.، 1386. تحلیل ریسک وقوع زلزله در پروژه‌های ساخت برای نقاط مختلف ایران با استفاده از رگرسیون‌های درجه دوم GLS و کمک از تست‌های آماری و مدل آماری پواسن. فصلنامه­ی علمی پژوهشی شریف، شمارة 40،ص.17-13.##Abercrombie, R.E., 1996. The magnitude-frequency distribution of earthquake records with deep seismometers at Cajon Pass, southern California. Tectonophysics, 261: 1-7.##Akinci, A., Perkins, D, Lombardi, A.M., Basili, R., 2010. Uncertainties in probability of occurrence of strong earthquakes for fault sources in the Central Apennines, Italy. Journal of Seismology, 14:95–117##Day, R.W., 2002. Geotechnical Earthquake Engineering Handbook. McGraw-Hill Companies,##Fischer, T., Alvarez, M., De la Llera, J.C., Riddell, R., 2002. An integrated model for earthquake risk assessment of buildings. Engineering Structures, 24: 979–998.##Gutenberg, B., Richter C.F., 1944. Frequency of earthquake in California. Bullettin of Seismolology Society of America, 72: 1867-1879.##Kaila, K.L., Narian, H, 1971. A new approach for the preparation of quantitative seismicity maps, Bullettin of Seismolology Society of America, 61(5): 1275-91##Kramer, S.L., 1996. Geotechnical Earthquake Engineering. Prentice Hall, Upper Saddle River.##Krinitzsky, E.L., 2002. How to Obtain Earthquake Ground Motions for Engineering Design. Engineering Geology, 65: 1-16.##Mirzaei, N., Gao, M., Chen, Y.T., 1998. Seismic source regionalization for seismic zoning of Iran: major seismotectonic provinces. Journal of Earthquake Prediction Research, 7: 465-495.##Nowroozi, A., 1976. Seismotectonic Provinces of Iran, Bullettin of Seismolology Society of America, 66, 1249-1276.##Reiter, L., 1990. Earthquake Hazard Analysis - Issues and Insights. Columbia University Press, New York,##Tavakoli, B., Ghafoori Ashtiany, M., 2002. Seismic hazard assessment of Iran. Available in: WWW.IIEES.com##Weatherill, G., Burton, P.W., 2010. An alternative approach to probabilistic seismic hazard analysis in the Aegean region using Monte Carlo simulation. Tectonophysics, 492: 253–278.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>انتخاب مناسب‌ترین روش حفاری تونل انتقال آب بهشت‌آباد</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The selection of the most suitable excavation method of Beheshtabad water conveyance tunnel</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>تونل انتقال آب بهشت‌آباد به فلات مرکزی ایران به طول 65 کیلومتر و قطر تمام شده 6 متر به­منظور انتقال آب از سرشاخه‌های کارون به بخش مرکزی ایران در دست مطالعه است. در این تحقیق 17 کیلومتر اول برای انتخاب مناسب‌ترین روش حفاری مورد مطالعه قرار گرفت. 17 کیلومتر اول با توجه به شرایط زمین‌شناسی و ژئومکانیکی به سه پهنه حفاری از متراژ 0 تا 5450، 5450 تا 7800، و 7800 تا 17000 تقسیم شد. انتخاب روش مناسب حفاری تصمیمی پیچیده بوده که به در نظر گرفتن فاکتورهای بسیاری نیاز دارد. در این مقاله ابتدا با استفاده از فرآیند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی، مدلی ساخته شد و بر اساس این مدل به بررسی سه روش حفاری و انفجار، حفاری با رودهدر و حفاری با TBM با در نظر گرفتن معیارهای شرایط زمین‌شناختی و ژئومکانیکی، شرایط اقتصادی، شرایط عملیاتی، شرایط زیست‌محیطی، هندسه تونل و عوامل مدیریتی پرداخته شد. بر اساس نتایج به دست آمده در هر سه پهنه، روش حفاری با TBM بیشترین امتیاز را کسب کرد. در نتیجه پیشنهاد می‌شود برای حفاری از یک دستگاه TBM استفاده شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Beheshtabad water conveyance tunnel, which is 65 kilometers in length and 6 m in final diameter, is studied to convey water from Karun river  to central part of Iran. In this study the first 17 km of the tunnel is examined to select the most efficient excavation method. This interval of the tunnel was divided into three zones based on geological and geomechanical conditions, these three zones are from 0 to 5450, 5450to7800 and 7800 to17000 meters. Selection of the optimal excavation method was a complicated decision to make since it required many factors to take into account. In this paper, a model was first constructed using Fuzzy Analytical Hierarchy Process (FAHP).  Three excavation methods of drill and blast, road header and TBM were investigated based on the foregoing model, in which geological, geomechanical, economical, operational and environmental conditions as well as geometry of the tunnel and management factors were considered. Results showed that TBM scored the most point in all three zones. It is therefore, recommended a TBM to be used</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>69</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>82</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نیک‌منش</Family>
						<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nikmanesh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>1. دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مهندسی معدن، دانشگاه بین­المللی امام خمینی،</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>1. دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مهندسی معدن، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حسینی</Family>
						<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hosseini</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>2. استادیار گروه مهندسی معدن، دانشگاه بین­المللی امام خمینی(ره)</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>2. استادیار گروه مهندسی معدن، دانشگاه بین­المل</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ma.hosseini@eng.ikiu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>صفر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فضلی</Family>
						<NameE>Safar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Fazli</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه بین­المللی امام خمینی(ره)</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه بین­المللی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تونل انتقال آب بهشت آباد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>روش حفاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فرآیند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>TBM</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>آذر، ع.، فرجی، ح.، 1386. علم مدیریت فازی، مرکز مطالعات مدیریت و بهره­‌وری ایران (وابسته به دانشگاه تربیت مدرس). چاپ اول.##حسینی، م.، 1385. مقدمه‌ای بر مکانیک سنگ. انتشارات ایده گستر، چاپ اول.##دلیریان، ا.، گشتاسبی، ک.، شمسی، غ.، همتی شعبانی، ع.، 1385. انتخاب روش حفاری بهینه از لحاظ فنی برای تونل انتقال آب قمرود. هفتمین کنفرانس تونل ایران.##شرکت مهندسین مشاور زایندآب، 1387. جلد بیست و نهم گزارش­های تونل بهشت آباد - گزارش زمین‌شناسی مهندسی.##شرکت مهندسین مشاور زایندآب، 1387. جلد سی‌ام گزارش­های تونل بهشت‌آباد - گزارش مکانیک سنگ.##شوندی، حسن، ۱۳۸۵. نظریه مجموعه‌های فازی و کاربرد آن در مهندسی صنایع و مدیریت. انتشارات گسترش علوم پایه، چاپ اول.##عطایی، م.، حسینی، س. ه.، 1388. بررسی تأثیرسایندگی برقابلیت حفاری سنگ‌ها. مجله علوم زمین، سال نوزدهم، شماره 74، صفحه 137 تا 142.##غیاثوند، ص.، 1385. ارزیابی پتانسیل لهیدگی درتوده سنگ‌های مسیرتونل انتقال آب گلاب، هفتمین کنفرانس تونل ایران.##مدنی، ح.، 1383. تونل‌سازی. جلد اول، انتشارات دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر.##میخک بیرانوند، ا.، قائدرحمتی، ر.، الماسی، س.، 1388. انتخاب TBM مناسب برای حفاری تونل متروی شیراز با استفاده از روش AHP. ششمین همایش زمین‌شناسی مهندسی و محیط زیست ایران، صفحات 384-377.##میخک بیرانوند، ا.، 1388. انتخاب قطر بهینه تونل انتقال آب کاکارضا بر اساس پارامترهای هزینه و زمان. هشتمین کنفرانس تونل ایران.##Adnani, S., Sereshki, F., Alinejad-Rokny, H., Kamali-Bandpey. H., 2011. Selection of temporary ventilation system for long tunnels by fuzzy multi attributes decision making technique (Fuzzy- Madm), case study: Karaj water conveyance tunnel (Part Et- K’) in Iran. American Journal of Scientific Research, (29): 83-91.##Barla, G., 2002. Tunnelling under Squeezing  Rock Conditions, Department of Structural and Geotechnical Engineering. Politecnico di Torino.##Chang, D.Y., 1996. Applications of the extent analysis method on fuzzy-AHP. European Journal of  Operational Research, 95(3): 649-655.##Percin, S., 2008. Use of fuzzy- AHP for evaluating the benefits of information-sharing decisions in a supply chain. Journal of Enterprise Information Management, 21(3): 263-284.##Robbins, R.J., 1997. Hard rock tunneling machines for squeezing rock conditions. Three machine concepts. Balkema Rotterdam, Tunnel for people, Vol. 2 , Proc. Of the 23rd general assembly of the ITA, pp. 633− 638.##Saaty, T.L., 1990. Decision Making for Leaders. RWS Publications, USA.##Saaty, T., Vargas, L., 1987. Uncertainty and rank order in the AHP. European Journal of Operational Research, 32(1): 107–117.##Shinha, R.S., 1989. Underground Structures Design and Instrumentation. U.S.Bureau.##Stewart, Rodney A., Mohamed, Sherif and Daet, Raul, 2002. Strategic implementation of IT / IS projects in construction: a case study, Automation in Construction11(6): 681-694.##Wittaker, N., and Russele, F.,ّ1990. Tunneling, Design, Stability and Construction. The Institution of Mining and Metallurgy.    ##Wood, A. M., 2000. Tunneling Management by Design. E &amp; FN Spon, pp.1− 288 .##Zare Naghadehi, M., Mikaeil, R., Ataei, M., 2009. The application of fuzzy analytic hierarchy process (FAHP) approach to selectionof optimum underground mining method for Jajarm Bauxite Mine, Iran. Expert Systems with Applications, 36(4): 8218–8226.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>شناسایی و طبقه‌بندی مناطق گردوغباری در خاورمیانه با استفاده از تلفیق ویژگی‌های انعکاسی و مادون قرمز حرارتی سنجنده‌ی MODIS</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Dust storm detection and classification in the Middle East using the combination of reflectance and thermal infrared properties of MODIS sensor</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>طوفان­های گردوغبار، سالانه حجم عظیمی از ذرات معلق را وارد جو زمین می­کنند. وجود این ذرات معلق در هوا باعث افزایش بیماری­های تنفسی، چشمی، قلبی- عروقی و ... می­شود. فراوانی و شدت وقوع این پدیده­ی زیست محیطی در مناطق خشک و نیمه خشک جهان از جمله خاورمیانه در سال­های اخیر در حال افزایش است. جهت بررسی و مطالعه­ی مناطق تحت پوشش غبار، استفاده از ابزارها و تکنیک­های مناسب همچون سنجش از دور ضروری به نظر می­رسد. در این تحقیق با استفاده از پردازش داده­های سنجنده­ی MODIS، اقدام به ردیابی و طبقه­بندی مناطق تحت پوشش غبار در خاورمیانه شده است. اختلاف در میزان گسیل­مندی ذرات گردوغبار در محدوده­ی امواج مادون قرمز حرارتی به شکل مؤثری نواحی گردوغباری را متمایز می­نماید. در این مطالعه، شاخص D که ویژگی­های انعکاسی و اختلاف دمای روشنایی بین طول موج­های 11 و 12 میکرومتر را تلفیق می­کند برای 28 تصویر ماهواره­ای مربوط به روزهای غباری سال­های 1387 و 1388 (2008 و 2009) منطقه خاورمیانه محاسبه شد. نتایج نشان داد که پارامتر D برای تفکیک مناطق گردوغباری از روی تصاویر MODIS بسیار مناسب است. در ادامه، رابطه­ی این پارامتر با داده­های هواشناسی، قابلیت دید استخراج شد. نتایج نشان داد که رابطه­ی بین داده­های قابلیت دید و پارامتر D در منطقه­ی خاورمیانه به صورت تابع نمایی با همبستگی 68/0 است. با استفاده از این رابطه، نقشه­های قابلیت دید از نقشه­های پارامتر D با درصد خطای مطلق 6/45% استخراج گردید. با توجه به پیچیدگی مسئله و وسعت منطقه و تنوع آب و هوایی موجود، مدل دارای هم­بستگی 68/0 و خطای 6/45% مناسب به نظر می­رسد. در نتیجه­ی شدت واقعه طوفان گردوغبار، میزان دید کاهش می­یابد و بر این پایه، نقشه­های قابلیت دید بسته به میزان قابلیت دید به نواحی مختلف گردوغباری طبقه‌بندی شدند. این روش طبقه­بندی از تلفیق روش­های مختلف طبقه­بندی گردوغبار بر حسب قابلیت دید برای منطقه­ی خاورمیانه توسعه داده شده است که در آن، گردوغبار به پنج گروه گرد وغبار معلق، گرد وغبار پخش شده، طوفان گردوغبار سبک،  طوفان گردوغبار متوسط، و طوفان گردوغبار ضعیف تا شدید طبقه­بندی می­شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Dust storm events carry a huge amount of aerosols to the atmosphere. These particles reduce air quality and can cause breathing, allergic, cordial problems. This environmental disaster increasingly outbreaks in arid and semiarid areas (e.g. Middle East) in recent years. Monitoring from space using remote sensing is one of the most effective and extensive techniques for dust storm detection. Terra MODerate resolution Imaging Spectroradiometer (MODIS) data have been utilized in this study for dust detection and classification in the Middle East. Dust particles emissivity differences in thermal infrared signals can discriminate the dusty from non-dusty pixels. D-parameter is calculated by combination of visible reflectance properties and Brightness Temperature Difference (BTD) between 11 and 12 µm channels. D-parameter is examined were using 28 satellite images (expanded in 2008 to 2009) and showed that it is very effective approach for dust area detection. Relation between D parameter and visibility (obtained from 41 synoptic stations) was investigated. The results showed that there is an exponential relation with R=0.68 between them. This relationship can retrieved the visibility from D parameter with Mean Percent Absolute Error=45.6%. According to the complicacy of problem and vast study region, R=0.68 and MPAE=45.6% seems very good. Hence we utilized this developed exponential relationship to retrieved visibility maps in Middle East from D-parameter maps. Then these generated visibility maps were classified to the different dust storm classes. This classification method was developed using the combination of different dust classification methods according to the visibility values. In this classification method, the dust storms were classified to 5 different classes (Sever Dust Storm، Medium Dust Storm، Light Dust Storm، Blowing Dust and Dust in Suspension).</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>83</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>92</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>خدیجه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کریمی</Family>
						<NameE>Khadijeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Karimi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانش‌آموخته کارشناسی ارشد زمین­شناسی زیست محیطی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانش‌آموخته کارشناسی ارشد زمین­شناسی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حمید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>طاهری شهرآیینی</Family>
						<NameE>Hamid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Taheri shahraiyni</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مهندسی عمران- آب، استادیار، دانشکده مهندسی عمران و معماری، دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مهندسی عمران- آب، استادیار، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ناصر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حافظی مقدس</Family>
						<NameE>Naser</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hafezi Moghadas</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری زمین­شناسی مهندسی، دانشیار، گروه زمین شناسی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری زمین­شناسی مهندسی، دانشیار، گروه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>nhafezi@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مجید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حبیبی نوخندان</Family>
						<NameE>Majid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Habibi Nokhandan</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری اقلیم­شناسی، دانشیار، پژوهشکده اقلیم­شناسی، مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری اقلیم­شناسی، دانشیار، پژوهشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تصاویر ماهواره‌ای MODIS</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خاورمیانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ردیابی گردوغبار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>طبقه‌بندی گردوغبار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قابلیت دید</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>ایرانمنش، ف. عرب خدری، م. اکرم، م.. 1384. بررسی مناطق برداشت ذرات گرد و غبار و ویژگی­های انتشار آنها در طوفان­های منطقه سیستان با استفاده از پردازش تصاویر ماهواره ای. پژوهش و سازندگی، شماره67، ص33-25.##Achudume, A.C., Oladipo, B.O., 2009. Effects of dust storm on health in the Nigerian environment. Biology and Medicine, 1(4): 21-27.##Ackerman, S.A., 1997. Remote sensing aerosols using satellite infrared observations. Journal of Geophysical Research, 102: 17069-17080.##Bartlett, K.S., 2004. Dust storm forecasting for AL Udeid AB, Qatar: an empirical analysis. Air Force Institute of Technology., Wright-Patterson AFB, OH, 6-11.##Chaboureau, J.P., Tulet, C., 2007. Diurnal cycle of dust and cirrus over West Africa as seen from Meteosat Second Generation satellite and a regional forecast model. Geophysical Research Letters, 34, L02882. dio:10.1029/2006GL027771.##Di, M., Lu, X., Sun, L., Wang, P., 2008. A Dust-Storm process dynamic monitoring with Multi-Temporal MODIS data. Remote Sensing and Spatial Information Science, XXXVII (part B7), 965-969.##Diem, J.E., Comrie, A.C., 2002. Predictive mapping of air pollution involving sparse spatial observations.  Environmental pollution, 119: 99-117.##Evans, J.P., Smith, R.B., 2001. Modeling the climate of Southwest Asia. Available In: http://www.yale.edv/ceo/ projects/ swap/pubs/evans.smith2001.pdf##Goudie, A., Middleton, N., 2006. Desert Dust in the Global System. Springer, Berlin.##Jamalizadeh, M.R., Moghaddamnia, A., Piri, J., Arbabi, V., Homayounifar, M., Shahryari, A., 2008. Dust storm prediction using ANNs technique (A case study: Zabol city). Engineering and Technology, 43: 512-520.##Lin, T.H., Hsu, N.C., Tsay, S.C., Huang, S.J., 2011. Asian dust weather categorization with satellite and surface observations. International Journal of Remote Sensing, 32: 153-170.##Liu, G., Park, S.U., 2007. The logarithm-Linear relationship of the occurrence frequency to the duration of sand-dust storms: Evidence from observational data in China. Journal of Arid Environment, 71:  243-249.##Noh, Y.M., Muller, D., Shin, D.H., Lee, H., Jung, J.S., Lee, K.H., Cribb, M., Li, z., Kim, Y.J., 2009. Optical and microphysical properties of severe haze smoke aerosol measured by integrated remote sensing techniques in Gwangju, Korea. Atmospheric Environment, 43: 879-888.##Roskovensky. J.K., Liou, K.N., 2003. Detection of thin cirrus from 1.38 μm/0.65 μm reflectance ratio combined with 8.6 - 11 μm brightness temperature difference. Geophysical Research Letters, 30(19): 1985, doi: 10.1029/2003GL018135.##Roskovensky, J.K., Liou, K.N., 2005. Differentiating airborne dust from cirrus clouds using MODIS data. Geophysical Research Letters, 32, L12809, doi: 10.1029/2005GL022798.##Shao, Y., Dong, C.H., 2006. A review on East Asian dust storm climate modeling and monitoring. Global and Planetary Change, 52: 1-22.##Tegen, I., 2003. Modeling the mineral dust aerosol cycle in the climate system. Quaternary Science Reviews, 22: 1821-1834.##Yang, X., Oenema, O., Hoongmoend, W.B., Perdok, U. D., Dianxiong, C., 2006. Dust storm erosion and its impact on soil carbon and nitrogen losses in northern China. CATENA, 66: 221-227##Yang, Y. Q., Hou, Q., Zhou, C.H., Liu, H.L., Wang, Y.Q., Niu, T., 2008. Sand/dust storm processes in Northeast Asia and associated large-scale circulations. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics, 8, 25-23.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تخمین مدول تغییرشکل‌پذیری سنگ آهک آسماری با استفاده از سیستم عصبی- ژنتیک</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Estimation of the deformation modulus of Asmari limestone in Zagros Mountains, Iran, using a neural network –genetic model</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>مدول تغییر شکل‌پذیری توده­سنگ (Em) به عنوان مهم‌ترین خصوصیت برای طراحی پروژه­های مهندسی سنگ مطرح است و بهترین نماینده برای رفتار مکانیکی پیش از شکست توده­سنگ است. به دلیل هزینه بالا و زمان­بر بودن و مشکلات اجرایی در انجام دقیق آزمایش­های برجا، روش­های غیرمستقیم مانند روابط تجربی و شبکه­های پس انتشار عصبی (BPN) جایگاه بهتری پیدا می­کنند. از این میان  BPN دارای کاربردی گسترده در تخمین خصوصیات توده سنگ از جمله Em است. محققین متعددی از روش سعی و خطا برای ایجاد یک BPN کارا  بهره گرفته­اند که نیاز به صرف زمان و مهارت کاربر دارد. اما در این مطالعه، از الگوریتم ژنتیک برای بهینه کردن پارامتری مؤثر BPN به منظور تخمین Em در رشته   کوه­های زاگرس ایران استفاده شد.  برای این منظور، یک بانک اطلاعاتی از پروژه­های مختلف رشته کوه­های زاگرس جمع‌آوری و Em سنگ آهک آسماری تخمین زده و در نهایت نتایج به دست آمده از روش عصبی - ژنتیک با روش عصبی سعی و خطا  مقایسه شد. که براساس نتایج به دست آمده روش عصبی- ژنتیک  دارای دقت و سرعت بالاتر در تخمین Em است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The deformation modulus of rock mass (Em) is the most representative parameter of the pre-failure mechanical behavior of the rock material and of the rock mass .Due to the high cost and measurement difficulties of in situ tests, the predictive models using regression based statistical methods, back propagation neural networks (BPN) and fuzzy systems are recently employed for the indirect estimation of the modulus .Among these methods, the BPN has been reported to be very useful in modeling the rock material behavior, such as Em, by many researchers .Despite its extensive applications, design and structural optimization of BPN are still done via a time-consuming reiterative trial-and-error approach . However, in this research, the genetic algorithm (GA) is utilized to find the optimal parameters of BPN, such as the optimal number of neurons in hidden layer, learning rates and momentum coefficients of hidden and output layers of network. Then, the result is compared with that of trial-and-error procedure . For the purpose, a data base including118 data sets was employed from six dam sites locations in Zagros Mountains of Iran. According to the results, the GA -ANN model has higher accuracy than the trial-and-error model in the estimation of Em </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>93</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>100</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>زینب</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>علی‌آبادیان</Family>
						<NameE>Zeinab</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Aliabadian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد گرایش مکانیک سنگ، دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد گرایش مکانیک سنگ، دانشگاه صنعتی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مصطفی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شریف‌زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Mostafa</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sharifzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشکده مهندسی معدن و متالوژی، دانشگاه امیرکبیر</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشکده مهندسی معدن و متالوژی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الگوریتم ژنتیک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رشته کوه زاگرس</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شبکه پس انتشار عصبی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدول تغییر شکل‌پذیری توده سنگ</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Alvarez Grima, M., Babuska, R., 1999. Fuzzy model for the prediction of unconfined compressive strength of rock samples. International Journal of Rock Mechanica and Mining Sciences, 36: 339–349.##Bieniawski, Z.T. , 1993. Determining rock mass deformability:  experience Fromcase histories. International Journal of Rock Mechanica and Mining Sciences, 15: 237–247.##Fu, L.,  1995. Neural Networks in Computer Intelligence New York:McGraw-Hill.##Gokceoglu, C., 2002. A fuzzy triangular chart to predict the uniaxial compressive strength of the Ankara agglomerates from their petrographic composition. Engineering Geology, 66: 39–51.##Grimstad, E., Barton, N. , 1993. Updating the Q-system for NMT. Proceedings of the International Symposium on Sprayed Concrete Modern Use of Wet Mix Sprayed Concrete for Underground Support, Oslo, Norwegian Concrete Association.##Hassoun, M.H., 1995. Fundamentals of Artificial Neural Networks. CambridgeMA: MIT Press.##Hecht-Nielsen, R., 1987. Kolmogorov’s mapping neural network existence theorem; Proceedings of the first IEEE international conference on neural networks, San Diego CA, USA, pp. 11–14.##Henseler, J., 1995, Backpropagation. In: Braspenning P.J., Thuijsman, F., Weijters, A.J.M.M. (Eds.), Artificial Neural Networks, an Introduction to ANN Theory and Practice. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, Berlin : Springer, pp. 37–66.##Hertz, J., Krogh, A., Palmer, R.G., 1991. Introduction to the Theory of Neural Computation. Reading MA: Addison-Wesley.##Hush, D.R., 1989, Classification with neural networks: a performance Analysis. Proceedings of the IEEE international conference on systems Engineering Dayton Ohia, USA, pp. 277–280.##Hoek, E., Brown E.T., 1997. Practical estimates of rock mass strength. International Journal of Rock Mechanica and Mining Sciences, 34: 1165–1186.##Majdi, A., Beiki, M., 2010. Evolving neural network using a genetic algorithm for predicting the Deformation modulus of rock masses. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences, 47(2): 246–253.##Meulenkamp, F., Alvarez Grima, M., 1999. Application of neural networks for the prediction of the unconfined compressive strength (UCS) from equotip hardness. International Journal of Rock Mechanica and Mining Sciences, 36:29–39.##Mitri, H.S., Edrissi, R., Henning, J., 1994. Finite element modeling of cable bolted stops in hard rock ground mines; Presented at the SME Annual Meeting.New Mexico:  Albuquerque, pp. 94–116.##Osman, M.S., Abo-Sinna, M.A., Mousa, A.A., 2005. Combined genetic algorithm-fuzzy logic controller (GA-FLC) in nonlinear programming. Journal of Applied Mathematics and Computing, 170(2): 821–840.##Palonen, M., Hasan, A., Siren, K., 2009. A genetic algorithm for optimization of building envelope and HVAC system parameters.  Eleventh International IBPSA Conference Glasgow, Scotland, pp. 27-30.##Paola,  J.D., 1994. Neural Network Classification of Multispectral Imagery., MSc thesis, The University of Arizona, USA.##Read S.A.L., Richard L.R., Perrin N.D., 1999. Applicability of the Hoek-Brown failure criterion to New Zealand gerywack rocks. In: Vouille G, berest, P. (Eds.): Proceeding of the  Nineth International Congeress on Rock Mechanics; Paris, 2: pp. 655-660.##Serafim, J.L., Pereira, J.P., 1983.  Considerations on the geomechanical classification of Bieniawski. Proceedings of the Symposium on Engineering Geology and Underground Openings; Lisboa,Portugal, pp. 1133–1144.##Sietsma, J., Dow, R.J.F., 1991. Creating artificial neural network that generalize. Neural Networks,  4: 67–69.##Sonmez, H., Gokceoglu, C., Nefeslioglu, H.A., Kayabasi, A., 2006. Estimation of rock modulus for intact rocks with an artificial neural network and for rock masses with a new empirical equation. International Journal of Rock Mechanica and Mining Sciences, 43: 224–235.##Staufer, P., Fisher, M.M. , 1997. Specral pattern recognition by a two-layer perceptron: effects of training set size. In: Kanellopoulos, I., Wilkinson, G.G., Roli F., Austin J. (Eds.): Neuro-Computation in Remote Sensing Data Analysis. London: Springer, pp. 105–116.##Tahmasebi, P., Hezarkhani, A., 2009. Application of adaptive neuro-fuzzy inference system for grade estimation, case study, Sarcheshmeh porphyry copper deposit, Kerman, Iran. Australian Journal of Basic and Applied Sciences, 4(3): 408-420.##Wang, C. , 1994. A Theory of Generalization in Learning Machines with Neural Application., PhD thesis, The University of Pennsylvania, US.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				