<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 و 2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Producing lightweight aggregate from shale and comparison of their characteristics with lightweight aggregates which is produced in Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تولید سبکدانه از شیل و مقایسه مشخصات آن با سبکدانه‌های تولیدی در ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>31</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>4</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">75545</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدکاظم</FirstName>
					<LastName>امیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری زمین­شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نیکودل</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار،‌ گروه زمین‌شناسی مهندسی دانشکده علوم پایه دانشگاه تربیت مدرس  nikudelm@yahoo.com</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>15</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Lightweight aggregates are being used to reduce weight for making light products such as light concrete, mortar and lined, thermal and acoustic insulation, mortar and lined, bitumen productsand agricultural soil. Shaly formation is abundant in different structural zones of Iran, on the other hand, clay resources needed for producing lightweight aggregates are valuable to environmentally and agriculturaly, and hence shales are good alternative materials for production of lightweight materials. In this paper, chemical analysis on shaley and marly formation in Fars province was carried out. Then, according to these studiesBeckat argillous and Noorabad shale were recognized suitable for production of lightweight materials. In next step some physical, chemical and mechanical properties of lightweight aggregate were determined and compared with lightweight aggregates which were produced in Iran. Results showed that manufactured expanded lightweight aggregates have lower specific gravity and higher water absorption, pressure and impact value than Lica and Liapor. From aspects of grain size analysis and pH, all three types of lightweight aggregates were similar. According to the results,produced expanded shale is lighter than other lightweight aggregates which are produced in Iran. But it has lower strength than Leca and Liapor, so it can be used as bacfill, construction of insulation and lightweight aggregate for discriminant and non-load-bearing walls</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">از سبکدانه­ها به منظور کاهش وزن، عایق­کاری حرارتی و صوتی، ساخت فرآورده­های سبک مانند انواع بتن­های ­سبک، ملاتها و اندودها، فرآورده­های قیری و خاک کشاورزی استفاده می‌شود. با توجه به فروان بودن سازندهای شیلی در زونهای مختلف ساختاری ایران و از طرف دیگر ارزشمند بودن منابع خاک رس مورد نیاز برای تولید سبکدانه‌ها از لحاظ زیست محیطی و کشاورزی، شیل‌ها جایگزین مناسبی برای تولید این مصالح­اند. در این مقاله آنالیزهای شیمیایی بر روی شیل‌ها  و مارن­های استان فارس انجام گرفت، سپس با توجه به مطالعات صورت گرفته شیل‌های آرژیلیتی بکت و نورآباد برای حرارت­دهی و تولید سبکدانه‌ها مناسب تشخیص داده شد. سپس برخی خصوصات، فیزیکی، شیمیایی و مکانیکی نمونه­های حرارت داده شده و ویژگی­های اولیه سبکدانه­های تولیدی مورد بررسی قرار گرفت و با سبکدانه­های تولیدی حال حاضر در ایران مقایسه شد. نتایج نشان داد که سبکدانه­های شیل منبسط­شده تولیدی وزن مخصوص کمتر، درصد جذب آب، ارزش فشاری و ضربه­ای بیشتری از لیکا و لیاپور دارند و از لحاظ دانه­بندی و pH  هر سه سبکدانه در یک محدوده قرار دارند. با توجه به نتایج بدست آمده، شیل منبسط­شده تولید شده سبکتر از نمونه­های تولیدی در ایران است اما مقاومت کمتری از آنها دارد و می­توان از آن به عنوان پرکننده، ساخت عایق­های حرارتی و ساختن بتن برای دیوارهای جداکننده و غیرباربر استفاده کرد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شیل منبسط شده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تئوری ریلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حرارت‌دهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">لیکا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">لیاپور</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خواص فیزیکی و مکانیکی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_75545_3a7bcb26f46d4084bd23cc940dd2127b.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
