<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 و 2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigation of engineering geological behavior of surface oil hydrocarbons contaminated soils in Tabriz oil refinery area</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی رفتار زمین‌شناسی مهندسی خاک‌های سطحی آلوده به هیدروکربن‌های نفتی در محدوده پالایشگاه تبریز</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>41</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>56</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68341</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید داود</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم پایه، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، همدان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>خلیل</FirstName>
					<LastName>محرم‌زاده سرای</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، همدان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>25</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Infiltration of oil materials into the soils has environmental impacts and changes engineering geological properties of soils. This paper has investigated the engineering geological behaviour of contaminated soils from the Tabriz Oil Refinery. The oil materials contaminations were alkenes hydrocarbon that had more than 14 carbon atoms (C&lt;sub&gt;14&lt;/sub&gt;) and is classified in the solid – phase. Based on the results of particle size analysis, there were two types of contaminated soils including silty sand (SM) and lean clay (CL). The results of Atterberg test on CL sample show that the plasticity index (PI) decreased for more contamination and all of SM samples were none plastic. In standard compaction tests, the samples with more contamination was reached to maximum dry unite weight in lower optimum water content. Also, the CBR test results show that with increase of contamination, the CBR was decreased and the reduction for CL sample was more than the SM sample. Based on obtained data from direct shear and consolidation tests, the shear strength parameters (cohesion and internal friction angle) were decreased and the consolidation settlement was increased, respectively.  </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">نفوذ مواد نفتی در خاک علاوه بر اثرات زیست‌محیطی می­تواند باعث تغییر خصوصیات زمین­شناسی مهندسی خاک‌ها شود. در این پژوهش رفتار زمین­شناسی مهندسی خاک­های سطحی آلوده محدوده پالایشگاه نفت تبریز بررسی شده است. مواد نفتی آلوده‌کننده نمونه­های خاک مورد مطالعه از نوع هیدروکربن­های آلکانی جامد با بیش از 14 زنجیره­ اتم کربن (C&lt;sub&gt;14&lt;/sub&gt;) می‌باشند. بر اساس نتایج حاصل از آزمایش های دانه­بندی، نمونه­ها در رده خاک‌های SM و CL قرار می‌گیرند. نتایج آزمایش حدود آتربرگ در نمونه‌های CL نشان می­دهد که شاخص خمیری (PI) در نمونه خاک دارای آلودگی بیشتر، کمترین مقدار بوده و با کاهش غلظت آلودگی، افزایش می یابد و تمامی نمونه‌های آلوده SM رفتار غیرخمیری داشته‌اند. در آزمایش‌های تراکم استاندارد، نمونه­های با آلودگی بیشتر با درصد رطوبت بهینه کمتری به وزن واحد حجم خشک حداکثر رسیده­اند. همچنین نتایج آزمایش‌های نسبت باربری کالیفرنیا بیانگر کاهش مقدار CBR با افزایش میزان آلودگی بوده که این کاهش در نمونه­های CL به مراتب بیشتر از نمونه­های SM می­باشد. بر اساس داده­های حاصل از آزمایش­های برش مستقیم و تحکیم، با افزایش میزان آلودگی خاک، به ترتیب پارامترهای مقاومت برشی (چسبندگی و زاویه اصطکاک داخلی) کاهش و نشست تحکیمی افزایش یافته است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کروماتوگرافی گازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تراکم استاندارد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نسبت باربری کالیفرنیا (CBR)</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مقاومت برشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نشست تحکیمی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68341_e0ff7027d1bcddb6f0819477867883eb.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
