<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Stabilization of a deep excavation using demolition and construction waste materials</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>استفاده از نخاله ساختمانی برای پایدارسازی دیواره گود عمیق</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>47</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>59</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">103454</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>سبزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه مهندسی عمران، واحد کرج، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4919-9797</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اکبر</FirstName>
					<LastName>چشمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>تهران - دانشگاه تهران - پردیس علوم دانشکده زمین شناسی</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0024-6161</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید رمضان</FirstName>
					<LastName>رمضان نژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس مهندسین مشاور</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The increasing amount of demolition and construction waste (D&amp;CW) materials has created many problems in large cities. Recycling waste materials helps to protect the environment. D&amp;CW can be used in many projects, especially in road construction, retaining walls, landscaping and pavements. In this research, a project in which, D&amp;CW used as fill materials to stabilize a deep excavation is investigated. The project site is located at the southwest of Tehran and the west of the Kan River. Site soil is basically composed of the C alluvium of Tehran. Strength parameters of soil were determined using recursive stability analysis. By performing an experimental embankment of D&amp;CW (500 m length, 8 m width and 0.5 m height) and compacting it, in-situ density, plate load and dynamic probing tests were implemented and parameters of D&amp;CW were obtained. Then stability analysis of excavation was performed under different conditions using Geo-Slope and the results showed that the D&amp;CW embankment is capable to provide factor of safety. Finally, in order to control the quality of execution, according to the field observations, the guidelines were suggested to use D&amp;CW. The results of this study show that D&amp;CW can be significantly usable in engineering applications.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این تحقیق یک گود که با استفاده از نخاله پایدارسازی شده، مورد مطالعه قرار گرفته است. گود مذکور در جنوب غرب تهران و در غرب رودخانه کن واقع شده است. جنس مصالح تشکیل دهنده دیواره گود شن و ماسه با مقادیر سیلت و رس بوده که از نظر زمین شناسی در گروه آبرفتهای C تهران طبقه‌بندی می‌شود. در تحقیق حاضر با استفاده از آنالیز برگشتی و با توجه به ابعاد گود، پارامترهای مهندسی مصالح دیواره گود، تعیین شد. به منظور تعیین پارامترهای مهندسی نخاله‌های ساختمانی یک خاکریز آزمایشی از نخاله‌های مذکور به طول، عرض و ارتفاع به ترتیب 500 ، 8 و 0.5 متر اجرا و با استفاده از غلطک ویبره، متراکم شد. سپس با انجام آزمایشهای دانسیته در محل، بارگذاری صفحه و کاوشگر دینامیکی بر روی خاکریز، پارامترهای مهندسی نخاله‌های ساختمانی تعیین گردید. با انجام مدل‌سازی با استفاده از نرم‌افزار Geo- Slope تحلیل پایداری گود و خاکریز در شرایط مختلف انجام شد. نتایج نشان می‌دهد که خاکریز مذکور قادر است پایداری دیواره گود را با توجه به مقادیر مجاز ضریب اطمینان تامین کند. با توجه به مشاهدات و برداشت‌های میدانی از آنجا که تنوع و تغییرات در نخاله‌های ساختمانی زیاد است به منظور کنترل کیفیت و حصول اطمینان از مناسب بودن مصالح و روش اجرا، دستورالعمل اجرایی برای استفاده از این مصالح جهت خاکریزی پیشنهاد گردید. نتایج این تحقیق نشان می‌دهد برخلاف رویه معمول، نخاله‌های ساختمانی، یه طور قابل توجهی می‌توانند در کاربردهای مهندسی قابل استفاده باشند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پایدار‌سازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گود عمیق</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خاکریزی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نخاله‌های ساختمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">Geo-Slope</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_103454_542e39d12bdf512c836338ce3b389a02.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
