<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigation of the ability of ultrasonic parameters to evaluate the physical and mechanical characteristics and durability of carbonate rocks</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی قابلیت پارامترهای مختلف امواج التراسونیک در ارزیابی ویژگی های فیزیکی و مکانیکی و دوام سنگ های کربناته</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>81</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>98</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">84279</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>میلاد</FirstName>
					<LastName>بشیری گودرزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرتضی</FirstName>
					<LastName>هاشمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>هیات علمی دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امین</FirstName>
					<LastName>جمشیدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه لرستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>12</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In this research by analyzing the signals of ultrasonic waves and obtaining the ultrasonic parameters in nine carbonate rocks from different parts of Iran, the ability of these parameters to assess the physical and mechanical properties and durability of rocks was investigated. For this purpose, firstly the petrographic, physical and mechanical properties of studied rocks were determined and then, in order to determine the durability of samples, long-term weathering tests of slake durability and wetting-drying up to 15 and 50 cycles were carried out, respectively. Moreover, a precise ultrasonic device capable to record wave signal was used and ultrasonic parameters of compressional wave velocity (VP), maximum amplitude (Amax), spatial attenuation (αs), and temporal attenuation (αs) were determined from recorded signals, before and after wetting-drying cycles. Results indicated that each of the ultrasonic parameters has different capabilities in rock characterization, such as VP can assess both physical and mechanical properties more accurate in comparison with other ultrasonic parameters. Results also indicated that Amax and αs detect the development of the microcracks resulted from wetting-drying cycles and the development of weathering within rocks more better than VP. On the other hand, αt is not sensitive to the weathering development in rock, while if this parameter is corrected and converted to αtc, it can detect the development of weathering within rocks.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این تحقیق با تحلیل سیگنال امواج التراسونیک و استخراج پارامترهای مختلف التراسونیک در نه سنگ کربناته متعلق به مناطق مختلف ایران، قابلیت این پارامترها در تعیین و ارزیابی ویژگی های فیزیکی و مکانیکی و دوام سنگ ها مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. برای این منظور در ابتدا ویژگی های پتروگرافی، فیزیکی و مکانیکی سنگ های مورد مطالعه تعیین شد و سپس برای تعیین دوام، این سنگ ها در معرض آزمایش دوام شکفتگی تا 15 چرخه و آزمایش دوام در مقابل چرخه های متوالی تر و خشک شدن تا 50 چرخه قرار گرفتند. همچنین با استفاده از یک دستگاه دقیق التراسونیک با قابلیت ثبت سیگنال موج، سنگ ها قبل و بعد از چرخه های تر و خشک شدن مورد آزمایش التراسونیک قرار گرفتند و پارامترهای مختلف التراسونیک شامل سرعت موج تراکمی (VP)، دامنه حداکثر موج (Amax)، میرایی فاصله ای موج (αs) و میرایی زمانی موج (αt) از سیگنال های ثبت شده، تعیین و استخراج گردید. بررسی رابطه بین پارامترهای التراسونیک و ویژگی های سنگ های مورد مطالعه نشان می دهد هر یک از پارامترهای التراسونیک قابلیت های متفاوتی دارند به نحوی که در تعیین ویژگی های فیزیکی و مکانیکی VPقابلیت بیشتری دارد. از طرف دیگر دو پارامتر Amax و αs قابلیت بیشتری در ارزیابی دوام سنگ‌ها دارند و توسعه ریزترک های ناشی از چرخه های تر و خشک شدن و پیشرفت هوازدگی در سنگ را بهتر از VP آشکار می کنند. با اصلاح αt به αtc این پارامتر نیز می تواند به خوبی پیشرفت هوازدگی در سنگ را آشکار کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سنگ های کربناته</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرعت موج</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دامنه موج</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">میرایی موج</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دوام</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_84279_e281c9d5e91efe88499df8c2fe49450f.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
