<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Modeling and optimizing the drilling and blasting pattern of the Boghde-Kandi quarry rubble mine of Saghez</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مدل‌سازی و بهینه‌سازی الگوی چالزنی و انفجار معدن سنگ لاشه بغده‌کندی سقز</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>41</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>53</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">87517</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضائی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مهندسی معدن، دانشکده مهندسی، دانشگاه کردستان، سنندج، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In most surface mines, the convention empirical methods are used to design the blasting pattern that leads to the undesirable results and increasing the production costs. In this research, the Delpat software package was utilized to simulate and optimize the blasting pattern of Boghde-Kandi quarry rubble mine. For this purpose, mine information was firstly collected and essential rock geomechanical parameters were measured. Then using the above-mentioned software, simulation of blasting pattern was conducted for hole diameters i.e., 76, 89, 102 and 115 mm. Comparison of the costs related to selection of each of the above hole diameters showed that overall costs were decreased by increasing in hole diameter. However, higher hole diameter required the greater volume of explosives which causes further ground vibration and flyrock. By utilizing the greater hole diameters, official buildings and; crushing and grading equipment sites will be located in the flyrock and ground vibration area and may be damaged. On the other hand, applying the hole diameter of 102 mm leads to the considerable cost decreasing (0.08 $/m3) compared to the 76 mm hole diameter that currently is used in mine. Therefore, hole diameter of 102 mm was proposed as an optimum one. According to this hole diameter, other parameters related to drilling and blasting pattern were calculated and proposed to perform in practice. Practical implementation of the blasting operation based on the suggested pattern leads to improve fragmentation and minimizing costs and side effects compared to the previous pattern.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این تحقیق از نرم‌افزار Delpat برای شبیه‌سازی و بهینه‌سازی الگوی چالزنی و انفجار در معدن سنگ لاشه بغده‌کندی سقز استفاده شده است. بدین منظور، ابتدا اطلاعات لازم گردآوری و پارامترهای ژئومکانیکی مورد نیاز برآورد گردید. سپس بر اساس نرم‌افزار فوق، شبیه‌سازی الگوی انفجار برای قطر چال‌های مختلف انجام شد. با مقایسه هزینه‌های الگوی چالزنی و انفجار بر اساس قطر چال‌های مختلف، مشخص گردید که با افزایش قطر چال، هزینه‌ها کاهش می‌یابد. با این حال، استفاده از قطر چال بالا باعث افزایش حجم مواد منفحره مصرفی و درنتیجه لرزش زمین و پرتاب سنگ و آسیب رساندن به تجهیزات و ساختمان‌های اطراف خواهد شد. بر اساس نتایج مدل‌سازی، استفاده از چال با قطر 102 میلی‌متر باعث کاهش هزینه کلی قابل توجه (0/08 دلار بر متر معکب) نسبت به چال با قطر 76 میلی‌متر مورد استفاده در معدن شده و لذا به-عنوان قطر چال بهینه برای معدن مذکور در نظر گرفته شد. دیگر پارامترهای الگوی چالزنی و انفجار هم بر اساس این قطر چال برآورد و برای استفاده عملی در معدن پیشنهاد شد. اجرای عملی انفجار بر اساس الگوی پیشنهادی باعث بهبود خردایش سنگ و کاهش هزینه‌ها و اثرات سوء ناشی از انفجار نسبت به الگوی قبلی گردید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">"معدن سنگ لاشه بغده‌کندی"</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">"الگوی چالزنی و انفجار"</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">"خردایش سنگ"</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">"نرم‌افزار Delpat"</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_87517_5749b1d93f4b319b323f1643d1cf5f0c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
