<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Improvement of desert areas and their application in road construction
(Case study: Khor - Arababad axis of South Khorasan)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بهسازی خاک های مناطق کویری و کاربرد آنها در راهسازی (مطالعه موردی : محور خور – عرب آباد خراسان جنوبی)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>16</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">88496</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجتبی</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی مهندسی،دانشکده علوم،دانشگاه فردوسی،مشهد ،ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>غفوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>غلامرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>لشکری پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه زمین شناسی مهندسی دانشگاه فردوسی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In order to study the physical and mechanical properties of available soils in the Khor-Arab Abad road, the seven sampling stations were selected along the way at the distance of 10Km from each other that located on the edge of the road. Then lime is usually the first option for soil stabilization in road construction projects as an economic reason. Considering the existence of Magnesium Oxide production factory in southern Khorasan province, this option has been studied also as a stabilizing agent in the present study.the existence of the Qaleh-Zari copper mine near Khor-Arab Abad road was a motivation to study the application of utilizing copper waste of processing factory for stabilizing soil .In order to specify the optimum amount of lime, the samples containing 2%, 5% and 10% of Lime were prepared. The optimum percentage was selected to be 5% according to previous studies and related recommendations was proposed 2% of lime adding to half of the samples as an accelerator for magnesite and copper waste respectively. Three additive combinations of 5% lime, 5% fine-grained magnesite with 5% lime, 5% copper waste have shown the best performance in order to increase CBR, uniformity of effect on all samples and non-inflation of 7 days treated samples. In terms of uniformity of performance on increasing CBR, the condition of fine- grained magnesite situation is better than copper waste and weaker than lime.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">برای مطالعه خصوصیات فیزیکی و مکانیکی خاک های موجود در محور خور-عرب آباد تعداد 7 ایستگاه نمونه برداری در طول مسیر به فاصله 10 کیلومتر از هم و در حاشیه جاده انتخاب گردید. به دلایل اقتصادی و دسترسی آسان معمولاً گزینه اول تثبیت خاک در پروژه های راه سازی آهک می باشد. با توجه به وجود کارخانه تولید اکسید منیزیم در استان خراسان جنوبی، این گزینه نیز به عنوان یک عامل تثبیت کننده در تحقیق حاضر مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. وجود معدن مس قلعه زری در نزدیکی محور خور-عرب آباد انگیزه ای شد تا پتانسیل کاربرد باطله های کارخانه فرآوری مس این معدن نیز برای تثبیت خاک مورد بررسی قرار گیرد. درصد بهینه برای دو ماده منیزیت و باطله مس طبق مطالعات و پیشنهادات قبلی 5% انتخاب شد و 2% آهک نیز به نیمی از نمونه های به عنوان کاتالیزور اضافه شد. با توجه به نتایج بدست آمده سه ترکیب افزودنی آهک 5 درصد، منیزیت ریزدانه 5 درصد به همراه 2 درصد آهک و باطله مس 5 درصد بهترین عملکرد را از لحاظ افزایش CBR، یکنواختی تاثیر برروی همه نمونه ها، و عدم تورم از خود نشان داده اند. از لحاظ یکنواختی عملکرد در افزایش CBR وضعیت منیزیت ریزدانه بهتر از باطله مس و ضعیف تر از آهک می باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">منیزیت ریز دانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">باطله مس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خور -عرب آباد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خاک های شور</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بهسازی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_88496_cf1320da769ff647b56a24a82625395e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
