<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 1 و 2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2009</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An investigation on physical characteristics and mechanical behavior of swelling gypsum soils and their improvement methods</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مطالعه خصوصیات فیزیکی و رفتار مکانیکی خاکهای گچی متورم شونده و روش‌های بهسازی آنها</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>33</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>46</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68199</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جعفر</FirstName>
					<LastName>بلوری بزاز</LastName>
<Affiliation>   استادیار گروه عمران، دانشکده مهندسی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5106-1845</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمید</FirstName>
					<LastName>رجایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>  کارشناس ارشد ژئوتکنیک، دانشگاه صنعتی شریف</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2008</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The existence of swelling soils causes irretrievable damages to buildings all over the world. Due to the swelling property of the gypsum soils, located in South West of Mashhad, many problems such as cracking in building, heaving of walls, and pavement and bulging of floors have been reported. The soil in this region is generally fine and based on Unified Classification is predominantly ML and CL. In the present research, 6 typical samples, among many gathered samples, with identical gradation but different amount of gypsum, were selected. After determination of main geotechnical properties of samples (including gypsum percent, Atterberg limits, natural unit weight and density), the effect of gypsum amount on the swelling potential and swelling pressure was investigated. Considering the influence of degree of compaction, on the swelling potential and swelling pressure, 10 samples for each of 6 typical soils, with identical moisture content but different unit weight were prepared and the variation of the swelling potential and swelling pressure were studied. The results of this research indicate the harsh effect of the gypsum amount, degree of compaction and moisture content on the swelling potential and swelling pressure. The improvement of such soils which are a type of problematic soils has been of many researchers interest. In the present research a sample with 10.57% gypsum and unit weight of 1.83 g/cm3 and with a determined swelling potential was improved using three different methods, including mixing with lime, double mixing with lime and mixing with cement. The amount of admixture for all three methods was 1, 2, 3 and 4 percent. The results of this research indicate that mixing with cement is able to reduce considerably the swelling potential and to improve the swelling specifications of this type of soil.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">وجود خاک­های متورم شونده در سراسر دنیا خسارات جبران ناپذیری را به ساختمان­ها وارد می­نماید. خاک­های گچی در ناحیه جنوب غربی مشهد، به دلیل خاصیت تورم­زایی که دارند از دیرباز مشکلاتی مانند ایجاد ترک در نمای ساختمان‌ها، شکم دادن دیوارها و برآمدگی کف­سازی­ها را به وجود آورده­اند. خاک­های این منطقه عموماً ریزدانه بوده و از نوع ML یا CL محسوب می­شوند. این پژوهش کوششی برای تعیین مشخصات و بررسی خواص تورمی خاک­های گچی ML در این منطقه می­باشد. به این منظور 6 نمونه از میان نمونه­هایی که دانه بندی یکسان ولی درصد گچ طبیعی متفاوتی دارند انتخاب شده­اند. پس از تعیین خصوصیات اصلی ژئوتکنیکی (مقدار گچ، حدود اتربرگ، وزن مخصوص طبیعی و چگالی) این خاک­ها، اثر میزان گچ بر پتانسیل تورم و فشار تورم بررسی گردید. با توجه به تاثیر به سزای وزن مخصوص بر پتانسیل و فشار تورم، از هر یک ازخاک­های شش­گانه 10 نمونه با رطوبت اولیه یکسان و وزن مخصوص مختلف ساخته شده و تغییرات پتانسیل و فشار تورم آنها تعیین گردید. نتایج این تحقیق بیانگر اثر شدید مقدار گچ، میزان تراکم و مقدار رطوبت بر پتانسیل و فشار تورم است. از طرفی بهسازی این­گونه خاک­ها که در زمره خاک­های مسئله­دار هستند همیشه مورد توجه محققین بوده است. در ادامه این تحقیق نمونه­ای از خاک­های فوق با 57/10 درصد گچ و با پتانسیل تورم مشخص انتخاب گردید و به سه روش مختلف بهسازی شامل اختلاط با آهک، اختلاط دو زمانه با آهک و اختلاط با سیمان بهسازی شد. مقدار ماده افزودنی در این سه روش 1، 2، 3 و 4 درصد بود که پس از مخلوط و متراکم نمودن، به وزن مخصوص خشک 83/1 گرم بر سانتی­متر مکعب رسید. نتایج بهسازی روی این­گونه خاک­های متورم شونده نشان می­دهد که روش اختلاط با سیمان می­تواند فشار تورم نمونه­ها را به مقدار قابل ملاحظه­ای کاهش دهد و خصوصیات تورمی آنها را به طور قابل توجهی اصلاح نماید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خاک گچی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پتانسیل تورم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فشار تورم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تراکم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">وزن مخصوص</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بهسازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آهک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اختلاط دو زمانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیمان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68199_ea4e0b2c3ee21c82bc4ac15392832549.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
