<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>شماره 3 و 4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A method of stratification profiling by using of geostatistic and cluster analysis technique based on dynamic probing test data</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>روشی پیشنهادی برای تعیین وضعیت لایه‌بندی با استفاده از روش‌های زمین‌آمار و تحلیل گروهی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>75</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>90</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68306</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>خداپرست</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار و عضو هیئت علمی دانشکده فنی و مهندسی دانشگاه قم</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4007-4093</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;The investigation and estimation of surface subsidence and ground settlement is an important aspect in the design of shallow tunnels in urban areas. Proper exploration could lead to correct measures and avoiding any damage to structures over and underground. &lt;br /&gt;In this study, four sections of the east-western part of Tehran’s Metro Line 7 with the most potential for surface subsidence were chosen and studied. This part of the metro project is positioned in the young alluvial deposits of Tehran and consists mainly of fine grained soil. Ground settlement requires three dimensional design. Hence, FLAC 3D was used to investigate the surface subsidence of the ground along the tunnel route in sections mentioned above. One of the most important advantages of three dimensional design is the possibility of stepwise excavation, and to explore the effect of each excavation step on the surrounding ground. Hence, the stepwise excavation was carried out and continued in 1.5 m advancing stages, until the advancement stopped affecting the ground settlement at the point over the tunnel portal considered in the model. &lt;br /&gt;Even though, analytical and empirical methods are unable to evaluate the effect of ground water and the effect of overburden due to the presence of structures and traffic at the surface, because of not installing the monitoring system, analytical methods suggested by Sagaseta, Loganathan and Poulos, Verruijt and Booker, and Bobbet, and also Peck’s empirical method were used to investigate the ground settlement in this project. &lt;br /&gt;After using the various methods to study the four chosen sections of the metro line, and analyzing the settlement curves in these sections, it was concluded that the ground settlements is permissible (except the second section)&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">شناسایی لایه‌های زیر سطحی و تعیین نیم‌رخ لایه‌ها در روش‌های معمول مطالعات ژئوتکنیک بر اساس مقطع حاصل از گمانه‌های حفر شده با درون‌یابی و قضاوت فردی انجام می‌شود. در بعضی موارد چنان‌چه فاصله بین گمانه‌ها زیاد باشد با استفاده از انجام آزمایش‌های در محل نظیر آزمایش‌های نفوذسنجی دینامیکی در بین گمانه‌ها سعی می‌شود تعیین لایه‌بندی با دقت بیشتری انجام پذیرد. در این مقاله با فرض در اختیار داشتن اطلاعات مربوط به حفر چند گمانه و انجام آزمایش‌های نفوذسنجی دینامیکی در بین گمانه‌ها، روش جدیدی مبتنی بر استفاده از دو فن زمین‌آمار و تحلیل گروهی ارائه می‌شود که با استفاده از آن می‌توان دو دسته اطلاعات حاصل از گمانه‌ها و نفوذسنجی را ترکیب کرد و وضعیت لایه‌بندی و تغییر مقاومت لایه‌ها را در عمق تعیین نمود. در روش مذکور با ارائه تعریفی جدید برای برخی از مفاهیم زمین‌آمار، یک سطح نسبت به یک نقطه مبنا تعیین می‌شود که در آن سطح، وضعیت لایه‌ها و تغییر مقاومت ثابت است. سپس با استفاده از اعمال روش تحلیل گروهی بر نتایج آزمایش‌های نفوذسنجی دینامیکی در محدوده مذکور، نیم‌رخ مربوط به لایه‌ها تعیین می‌شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">لایه‌بندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زمین‌آمار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل گروهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نفوذسنجی دینامیکی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_68306_bbb2fe215cc06bd52f16edc7ac9787b7.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
