<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>نشریه انجمن زمین شناسی مهندسی ایران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2228-5245</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Relationship of Geosciences and Mechanical Engineering in Increasing the Productivity of Tunnel Boring Machines</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارتباط علوم زمین‌شناسی و مهندسی مکانیک در افزایش بهره‌وری ماشین‌های حفار تمام مقطع</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>24</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">87474</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>وحید</FirstName>
					<LastName>جودکی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه سازه های زیرزمینی، شرکت مهندسین مشاور ساحل امید ایرانیان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جعفر</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسن‌پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، دانشکده زمین‌شناسی، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رسول</FirstName>
					<LastName>اجل لوئیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، دانشکده زمین‌شناسی، دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9770-1695</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In the academic and industrial environments of Iran, there is little understanding of the relationship between geological science and technical branches of mechanics and electronics. Such concepts are not explained in Iran&#039;s higher education curriculum, and almost no source of research has been published in Persian. The history of collaborative studies between mechanical engineers and geoscientists can be considered at the onset of the topics of the Terramechanics. In this research, by studying the excavation conditions in Bazideraz tunnel, the necessity of initiation of interdisciplinary studies of geology graduates with the mechanical engineers in higher education and industries of the country is discussed. In this paper, with the analysis of the operational parameters of the TBM and the study of geological conditions, discusses how to change the structure of the TBM. The results show that in this project, in order to adapt the structure of the machine to the geological conditions of the route, a series of structural reforms including the removal of 26 thrust jacks, the installation of 9 probe drilling holes in the shield, the removal of all passive articulation cylinders (16 jacks), a change in the arrangement of the disc cutters, and the construction of 7 gearbox converters to increase the rotary speed of the cutterhead, inevitable.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در محیط‎های دانشگاهی و صنعتی ایران، شناخت چندانی از ارتباط علم زمین‎شناسی با شاخه‎های فنی مکانیک و الکترونیک وجود ندارد. چنین مفاهیمی، در سرفصل‎های دروس آموزش عالی ایران تبیین نشده است و تقریباً هیچگونه منبع پژوهشی به زبان فارسی در این زمینه منتشر نشده است. پیشینة حوزه‎های مطالعاتی مشترک مابین مهندسین مکانیک با متخصصین علوم زمین را می‎توان در شروع مباحث ترامکانیک (Terramechanics) دانست. در این پژوهش با تشریح تجربیات حفاری مکانیزه در تونل بازی‎دراز، به ضرورت آغاز مطالعات بین‎رشته‎ای دانش‎آموختگان زمین‎شناسی با مهندسین مکانیک در آموزش عالی و صنایع کشور پرداخته می‎شود. در مقاله حاضر با تحلیل پارامترهای عملیاتی دستگاه حفار و بررسی شرایط زمین‎شناسی در پروژه تونل بازی‎دراز به چگونگی اعمال تغییرات در ساختار دستگاه تی‎بی‎ام پرداخته می‎شود. نتایج نشان می‎دهد در این پروژه جهت سازگار نمودن ویژگی‎های دستگاه با شرایط زمین‎شناسی مسیر، مجموعه‏ای از اصلاحات مکانیکی از جمله: حذف جک شمارة 26 تراست، تعبیه 9 عدد چال گمانه پیشرو در نیمکره پایین سپر دستگاه، حذف تمام جک‎های مفصلی پسیو دستگاه (به تعداد 16 جک)، تغییر آرایش ابزارهای برشی کله‌حفار و ساخت 7 عدد مبدل گیربکس برای افزایش سرعت چرخش کله‎حفار، اجتناب ناپذیر بوده است</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ترامکانیک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مکانیک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مبدل گیربکس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جک مفصلی پسیو</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.jiraeg.ir/article_87474_e12c9c69cb412307e2a32d3aba576fe2.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
