<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1398</YEAR>
<VOL>11</VOL>
<NO>2</NO>
<MOSALSAL>0</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>0</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>الگوی نقش و ساختار حکمروایی محلی در نظام مدیریتی ایران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A Pattern of Role and Structure of Local Governance in Iran&#039;s Management System</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: علی‌رغم تأکید قانون اساسی بر جایگاه ویژه شوراها در ارکان نظام جمهوری اسلامی ایران، به‌ویژه در حکمروایی محلی، در حال حاضر دو سطح ملی و محلی فاقد ارتباط و ساختاری منسجم بوده و در نقش کنشگران هر دو سطح ابهاماتی وجود دارد. بنابراین بررسی حکمروایی محلی در نظام مدیریتی کشور، ضروری است و به شکل‌دهی الگویی برای شناسایی نقش‌ها و ساختارهایی برای تحقق آن نیاز دارد. پژوهش حاضر، نوشتاری است که به تبیین نقش و ساختار حکمروایی محلی در ایران می‌پردازد.
روش: در این پژوهش از نظریه‌پردازی داده‌بنیاد ساخت‌گرا استفاده شده و برای پاسخ به پرسش‌های پژوهش 21 مصاحبه عمیق با صاحب‌نظران انجام گرفته است. برای تحلیل داده‌ها، طی چهار مرحله اولیه، متمرکز، محوری و نظری به کدگذاری اقدام شده است.
یافته‌ها: تحلیل داده‌ها در نهایت به احصای 19 مقوله فرعی، شش مقوله‌ اصلی و شکل‌گیری الگوی نظری انجامید.
نتیجه‌گیری: برای ایران می‌توان در سطح محلی و مرکزی نقش‌های اختصاصی و ارتباطی را در نظر گرفت که نقش‌آفرینانی شامل چهار گروه دولتی، عمومی، خصوصی و مردمی آنها را بر عهده می‌گیرند. همچنین برای حکمروایی محلی ایران در حالات موجود، ممکن و مطلوب، به‌ترتیب سه شکل ساختاری مجزا، هماهنگ و همراه ارائه شده که برای برعهده‌گرفتن نقش‌ها، اولویت‌های متفاوتی دارند. بنابراین شکل‌گیری الگوی مطلوب حکمروایی محلی در ایران به شناخت وضع موجود و همچنین عبور از وضع ممکن نیاز داشته و به‌تدریج حاصل خواهد شد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: The oil industry is the most important and strategic industry in Iran and plays a dominant role in the economy of the country. Human capital is the main element in the creation and development of productivity, therefore the development of human capital productivity in this industry can be a major step towards achieving economic growth and long-term goals of the country. In planning the development of human resource efficiency, managers and planners have to cope with the complexity of human resources (systems of multidimensional systems) and, psychological relations and socio-cultural issues (systemic attitudes). Considering the fact that, human resource utilization in the oil industry is a turbulent issue, this research aimed at modeling, simulating and strategizing the human resources system of the oil industry using the formulation of a turbulent order and the dynamics of the system. Methods: The research’s methodology is inspired by the critical system thinking of research in multiple operations and methodologies (a system of systematic methodologies). This is primarily done using the barriers to the development of Ackoff / Gharage Daghie, the principled embedding of the structure of the problem turmoil, and then into modeling using the dynamics of the system. Results: The findings of the model show that insufficient attention to the transparency of the structure of the oil industry in terms of power and the use of intellectual and human capital in dimensions of value and motivation of staff in cosmetic aspects have caused damage to the abundance of human resources in the industry. Conclusion: The application of hybrid policies in the three sub-systems of value, strength, and beauty were selected as the best way to improve the productivity of human resources in the petroleum industry. It was shown that plans for increasing intellectual and human capital, structural transparency in the oil industry, and the incentivizing systems of workers have significant effects on increasing the value of human resources and improving its productivity in the oil industry.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>179</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>202</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>غلامرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کاظمیان</Family>
						<NameE>GholamReza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Kazemian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی،تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>kazemian1398@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>وجه‎اله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قربانی‎زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Vajhollah</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ghorbanizadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ghorbanizadeh@atu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>واعظی</Family>
						<NameE>Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Vaezi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری،دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی،تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>vaezi@atu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مرضیه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شاه‎محمّدی</Family>
						<NameE>Marzieh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Shahmohammadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.shahmohammadi4@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>حکمروایی محلی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تمرکززدایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت بخش عمومی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ساختار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نقش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>استراس، آنسلم و کوربین، جولیت (1387). اصول روش تحقیق کیفی: نظریه مبنایی، رویه‌ها و شیوه‌ها. (بیوک محمدی، مترجم). تهران: انتشارات پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##برک‎پور، ناصر؛ اسدی، ایرج (1388). مدیریت و حکمروایی شهری. تهران: نشر دانشگاه هنر.##پرهیزگار، اکبر؛ کاظمیان، غلامرضا (1384). رویکرد حکمروایی شهری و ضرورت آن در مدیریت منطقه‎ کلانشهری تهران، فصل‌نامه پژوهش‎های اقتصادی، (16)، 29- 49.##جانستون، جی. (1382). فرهنگ جغرافیای انسانی (حکمروایی). (ناصر برک‎پور، مترجم)، تهران: انتشارات سازمان شهرداری‌ها، ماهنامه شهرداری‌ها، شماره 52.##دانایی فرد، حسن؛ الوانی، سید مهدی؛ آذر، عادل (1390). روش‌شناسی پژوهش کیفی در مدیریت: رویکرد جامع. تهران: انتشارات صفار.##رهنورد، فرج‎اله؛ علیپور، حسین؛ دهدار، فرزین؛ خلیلی، حیدر (1398). چارچوب رابطـه حکومـت و مـردم در ایـران: رویکـرد نهادی. مدیریت دولتی، 11(1)، 27 – 46.##شریفیان ثانی، مریم (1380). مشارکت شهروندی، حکمرانی شهری و مدیریت شهری. تهران: انتشارات سازمان شهرداری‌های کشور. فصل‌نامه مدیریت شهری، (8)، 42-55.##شمس، عبدالحمید (1377). نظری بر مبانی نظام مدیریت منطقه‌ای. مدیریت دولتی، (39)، 29-40.##علی مرادی، ظهیر؛ شمس، عبدالحمید؛ جهانگیری، علی (1397). (طراحی مدل ارزیابی خودگردانی محلی در سطح استان‎های جمهوری اسلامی ایران. ‎مدیریت دولتی، 10(4)، 629 -650 .##کاظمیان، غلامرضا؛ صالحی، اسماعیل؛ ایازی، محمدهادی؛ نوذرپور، علی؛ ایمانی جاجرمی، حسین؛ (1392). مدیریت شهری (جلد اول)، تهران: نشرتیسا.##محمدپور، احمد (1389). ضد روش: منطق و طرح در روش شناسی کیفی، جلد (1). تهران: انتشارات جامعه‎شناسان.##محمدزاده سلطانمرادی، هادی؛ فیضی، طاهره؛ گرامی‎پور، مسعود؛ یـداللهی، مهـدی (1398). تبیـین و آسـیب‎شناسـی الگـوی جاری مدیریت دولتی در ایران. مدیریت دولتی، 11 (1)، 1 -26.##مرتضوی، مهدی (1392). مدیریت محلی و حکمروایی شهری. تهران: مرکز مطالعات برنامه‌ریزی شهر تهران.##مقیمی، محمد (1394). اداره امور حکومت‌های محلی (مدیریت شوراها و شهرداری‌ها). تهران:انتشارات سمت.##ویسی، هادی؛ احمدی پور، زهرا؛ قالیباف، محمدباقر (1391). آسیب‌شناسی دولت محلی. تهران: مدرس علوم انسانی ـ برنامه‌ریزی و آمایش فضا. 16(32)، 19-36.##References##Alimoradi, Z., Shams, A., Jahangiri, A. (2018). Designing Local Self-government Evaluation Model in Provincial Level in Islamic Republic of Iran. Journal of Public Administration, 10(4), 629-650. (in Persian)##Andrew, C., &amp; Goldsmith, M. (1998). From Local Government to Local Governance: And Beyond? international political science review, 19(2), 101-117.##Shah, A. &amp; Shah, S. (2006). The New Vision of Local Governance and the Evolving Roles of Local Governments. In Shah, A. (eds). Local Governance in Developing Countries. Washington, D.C.: World Bank.##Barakpour, N., &amp; Asadi, I. (2009). Urban Management and Governance. Art University, Tehran, Iran. (in Persian)##Charmaz, K. (2014). Counstructing grounded theory.Landon: sage publications.##Corbin, J. &amp; Strauss, A. (2008). Basics of Qualitative Research. (Third Edition). London: Sage Publications Inc.##Danai fard, H., Alvani, S.M., Azar, A. (2010). Qualitative Research Methodology in Management: A Comprehensive Approach, Saffar, Tehran, Iran. (in Persian)##Glaser, B. G. &amp; Strauss, A. (1967). The discovery of Grounded Theory.Chicago: Aldine.##Hendriks, F. (2013). Understanding Good Urban Governance: Essentials, Shifts, and values. Urban Affairs Review, 50(4), 553-576.##International Cooperation and DevelopmentEuropean Commission (2016). Supporting decentralisation, local governance and local development through a territorial approach. Luxembourg: Publications Office of the European Union.##Johnston, J. (2003). Culture of Human Geography (Governance) Translator N. Barakpour, Municipality Organization, No. 52, Tehran, Iran. (in Persian)##Kazemian, Gh., Salehi, A., Ayazi, M., Nozarpour, A., Emani, H., Saeedi, N., Abdollahi, M. (2013). Urban Management, Vol. 1. Tisa, Tehran, Iran. (in Persian)##Kloth, C. &amp; Applegate, B. (2004). Inter-Organisition Colaboration&amp; Partnership: A Critical Analisys.  2004 OD Network Annual Conference. Available at: https://www.scribd.com /document/156397997/Inter-organization-Collaboration-and-Partnerships-A-Critical-Analysis.##Meza, O. (2015). From Local Government to LocalGovernance. Available at: https://www.researchgate.net/ publication/287206816.##Miller, K. (2002).Advantages &amp; disadvantages of local government decentralization. Caribbean Conference on Local Government &amp; Decentralization, At the Ocean View International Hotel Georgetown, Guyana, June 25 to 28.##Moghimi, M. (2015). Adminisrration of Local Government (Management of Councils and Municipalities). SAMT, University of Tehran. Tehran, Iran. (in Persian)##Mohammad Pour, A. (2010). Anti Method: Logic and design in qualitative methodology, Vol 1. Sociologists Publications, Tehran, Iran. (in Persian)##Mohammadzadeh Soltanmoradi, H., Feizy, T., Geramipour, M., Yadollahi, M. (2019). Explanation and Pathology of the Current Pattern of Public Administration in Iran. Journal of Public Administration, 11(1), 1-26. (in Persian)##Mortazavi, M. (2013). Local Government and Urban Governance. Tehran City Planning Center. Tehran, Iran, No. 16. (in Persian)##Parhizgar, A., Kazemian, Gh. (2005). Urban Governance Approach and Its Necessity in Managing the Metropolitan Area of Tehran, Quarterly Journal of Economic Research, (16). (in Persian)##Pahizgar, A., Kazemian, Gh. (2005). Urban Governance Approach and Its Necessity in Managing the Metropolitan Area of ​​Tehran, Quarterly Journal of Economic Research, (16), 29-49. (in Persian)##Rahnavard, F., Alipour, H., Dehdar, F., Khalili, H. (2019). The Framework of Government-Citizen Relationship in Iran: An Institutional Approach. Journal of Public Administration, 11(1), 27- 46. (in Persian)##Reid, M. (1999). The Central- Local Government Relations: The Need for a Framework? Political Science, 50(2), 165-181.##Shams, A. (1998). A Commentary on the Basis of Regional Management System. Public Administration (39), 29-40. Tehran, Iran. (in Persian)##Sharifian Thani, M. (2001). Citizen Participation, Urban Governance and Urban Management. Organization of Municipalities. Urban Management Quarterly, (8), 42-55. Tehran, Iran.##(in Persian)##Span, K. C. L., Luijkx, K. G., Schols, J. M. G. A., Schalk, R. (2012).The Relationship Between Governance Roles and Performance in Local Public Interorganizational Networks: A Conceptual Analysis. The American Review of Public Administration, 42(2), 186–201.##Strauss, A. &amp; Corbin, J. (2008). Principles of Qualitative Research Method: Basic Theory, Procedures and Methods. Translations by Biyok Mohammadi. Institute of Humanities and Cultural Studies, Tehran, Iran. (in Persian)##Veisi, H., Ahmadipour, Z., Qalibaf, M. (2012). Local Government Pathology. Moderator of Humanities-Planning and Alignment of space, 16(32), 19-36. (in Persian)##Wilson, R.  H. (2000). Undrestanding Local Governance: an international perspective. Revista de Administração de Empresas, 40(2), 51-63.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارائه الگوی توسعه‌ مرحله‌‌ای حکمرانی شبکه‌ای با استفاده از رویکرد فراترکیب</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Presenting a Phased Development Pattern of Network Governance Using a Meta-synthesis Approach</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: حکومت‌ها به فراخور فضای اجتماعی، سیاسی و اقتصادی نوع حکمرانی خود را تغییر می‌دهند. تحولات سریع در فناوری موجب ایجاد شکل جدیدی از حکمرانی‌ در سازمان‌های دولتی به نام حکمرانی شبکه‌ای شده است. حکمرانی شبکه‌ای به مجموعه‌ای از بازیگران دولتی و غیردولتی اشاره دارد که به‌‌منظور تصمیم‌گیری در رابطه با حل مسائل و مشکلات عمومی، ایجاد ارزش عمومی و ارائه خدمات عمومی با یکدیگر به‌طور رسمی یا غیررسمی تعامل و مشارکت دارند. پژوهش حاضر با هدف ارائه الگوی مرحله‌ای توسعه‌ حکمرانی شبکه‌ای در سازمان‌های دولتی کشور با استفاده از رویکرد فراترکیب انجام شده است. روش: در این پژوهش با استفاده از روش فراترکیب و بازنگری دقیق در موضوع، یافته‌های پژوهش‌های کیفی و کمی مرتبط ترکیب و الگوی حاضر طراحی شد. بر این اساس، 297 پژوهش در حوزه حکمرانی شبکه‌ای ارزیابی شد که در پایان 132 پژوهش انتخاب شده و با تحلیل محتوای آنها ابعاد و کدهای مربوطه استخراج و میزان اهمیت و اولویت هر یک با استفاده از آنتروپی شانون تعیین شد. یافته‌ها: بر اساس یافته‌های پژوهش، کدهای فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات، امنیت سایبری، سودآوری شبکه، مشارکت شهروندان در شبکه، درگیری و تعامل سازنده میان اعضای شبکه، پاسخ‌گویی و چارچوب ساختاری شبکه، چشم‌انداز توسعه شبکه، شرایط فناورانه حاکم بر شبکه و منابع انسانی دارای دانش و مهارت استفاده از فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات،  بین ابعاد 21‌گانه توسعه‌ حکمرانی شبکه‌ای بیشترین ضریب اهمیت را به دست آوردند. نتیجه‌گیری: در این پژوهش، الگوی توسعه حکمرانی شبکه‌ای در چهار مرحله‌ بررسی و شناسایی الزامات شبکه، طراحی شبکه، مشارکت و فعال‌سازی شبکه و توسعه شبکه ارائه شد. از آنجا که تاکنون مدل جامعی برای توسعه حکمرانی شبکه‌ای در سازمان‌های دولتی کشور با توجه به ویژگی‌های خاص و شرایط بومی کشور، ارائه نشده است، این پژوهش می‌تواند الگوی مناسبی برای توسعه حکمرانی شبکه‌ای در سازمان‌های دولتی کشور باشد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: Governments tend to implement different governance types as they face various social, political, and economic conditions. Rapid technological developments have created a new form of governance in governmental administrations called Network Governance. Network governance refers to a set of governmental and nongovernmental parties who interact and participate officially or unofficially in order to make decisions on solving general problems, creating public values and providing public services. This study is aimed at providing a model for the development of network governance in Governmental Organizations using a meta-synthesis approach. Methods: In this research, after conducting a precise review on the subject, a combination of the findings of the quantitative and the qualitative studies was used to design the current pattern. Among a pool of 297 studies in the field of network governance, 132 topics were selected and their content and dimensions were extracted. The Shannon entropy equation was then used to determine the importance and priority of the chosen topics. Results: Based on research’s findings ICT codes, cyber security, network profitability, citizen participation in the network, constructive engagements, interactions between network members, accountability, network structure frameworks, network development perspectives, network-driven technological conditions, knowledge-based human resources, information utilization skills, and communication technologies (ICT), obtained the highest importance among the 21 dimensions of network governance development. Conclusion: In this research, the network governance development model is presented in four stages: the identification of network requirements, the network design, the network activation and participation, and finally the network development. Considering the special characteristics and indigenous conditions of governmental organizations in our country, a specific model for the development of network governance hasn’t been provided yet. Therefore, this research can be considered as a comprehensive and appropriate road map for the development of such governance in governmental organizations in the country.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>203</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>230</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عادله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>دقتی</Family>
						<NameE>Adele</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Deghati</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه مدیریت، دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان، زاهدان، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه مدیریت، دانشکده مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>adele.deghati68@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نورمحمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>یعقوبی</Family>
						<NameE>NourMohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Yaghoubi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد، گروه مدیریت،دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان، زاهدان، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد، گروه مدیریت،دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>yaghoubi@mgmt.usb.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>امین رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کمالیان</Family>
						<NameE>Amin Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Kamalian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت، دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان، زاهدان، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت، دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>kamalian2010@mgmt.usb.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مسعود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>دهقانی</Family>
						<NameE>Masoud</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Dehghani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه ولایت، ایرانشهر، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه ولایت، ایرانشهر،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.dehghani@velayat.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>حکمرانی شبکه‌ای</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>توسعه‌ مرحله‌ای</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رویکرد فراترکیب</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سازمان‌های دولتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بازیگران شبکه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>آقازاده، محمدرضا؛ عسگری، طیبه؛ شاهی، عادله؛ فرهمند، آمنه (1394). طراحی مدل فرایندی تدوین استراتژی سازمان‌های حاکمیتی بر مبنای پارادایم حکمرانی شبکه‌ای. فصل‌نامه مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی، 4(3)، 27- 56.##الوانی، سید مهدی (1388). حکمرانی خوب شبکه‌ای از کنشگران جامعه مدنی. مجله مدیریت توسعه و تحول، 4(1)، 1-5.##ابوالحسنی رنجبر، احمد؛ دانش‌فرد، کرم‌اله؛ فقیهی، ابوالحسن (1396). ارائه الگوی دستور کار خط‌مشی‌های اصلاح نظام اداری در ایران. مدیریت دولتی، 6(4)، 615- 640.##پورعزت، علی اصغر (1393). درآمدی بر روش پژوهش علمی (فراگرد تدوین رساله پژوهشی و دفاع از آن). تهران: انتشارات میدانچی.##جمالی، قاسمعلی؛ نرگسیان، عباس؛ پیران‌نژاد، علی (1396). ارزیابی وضعیت شفافیت پورتال‌های سازمان‌های دولتی (مطالعه موردی: وزارتخانه‌های ایران). مدیریت دولتی، 9(1)، 61- 84.##حاجت‌پور، سارا؛ دانش‌فرد، کرم اله؛ امیرنژاد، قنبر؛ تابان، محمد (1396). ارائه مدلی برای ارزشیابی خط‌مشی‌های عمومی (پس از اجرا) با رویکرد حکمرانی شبکه (مورد مطالعه: سازمان تأمین اجتماعی). فصل‌نامه خط‌مشی‌گذاری عمومی در مدیریت، 7(28)، 13-25.##خواجه نایینی، علی (1393). درآمدی بر مفهوم حکمرانی شبکه‌ای؛ مطلوبیت و چالش‌ها. فصل‌نامه رهیافت‌های سیاسی و بین‌المللی، 6(39)، 129- 155.##دانائی‌فرد، حسن (1392). مدیریت دولتی شبکه‌ای در ایران: خردمایه نظری ـ علمی و استلزامات. پژوهش‌های مدیریت در ایران، 17(2)، 64- 104.##دهقانی، مسعود؛ یعقوبی، نورمحمد؛ موغلی، علیرضا؛ وظیفه، زهرا (1394). ارائه الگوی سه لایه‌ای امکان‌سنجی و استقرار اثربخش مدیریت دانش با استفاده از روش فراترکیب. فصل‌نامه مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی، 3(12)، 108- 123.##زنده‌دل نوبری، بابک؛ آذر، عادل؛ رحمتی، محمدحسین؛ کازرونی، مهرداد؛ قاسمی، احمدرضا (1397). شناسایی پارامترهای اثرگذار بر عوامل ریسک‌پذیر استقرار ERP در ایران با رویکرد نظریه چندزمینه‌ای. فصل‌نامه پژوهش‌های مدیریت عمومی، 11(41)، 5- 28.##سلطانی، فرزانه؛ شاهین، آرش؛ شایمی برزکی، علی (1396). طراحی الگوی تعالی استعداد با استفاده از رویکرد مرور سیستماتیک و فراترکیب کیفی در شرکت گاز استان اصفهان. فصل‌نامه علمی پژوهشی مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، 8(32)، 51- 83.##سلیمی، جلیل؛ مکنون، رضا (1397). فراتحلیل کیفی پژوهش‌های علمی ناظر بر مسئله حکمرانی در ایران. مدیریت دولتی، 10(1)، 1-30.##شهبازی سلطانی، محمد؛ صلواتیان، سیاوش (1396). شناسایی ویژگی‌های معرف مدیر جهادی به روش فراترکیب. فصل‌نامه علمی پژوهشی مدیریت اسلامی، 25(1)، 199- 230.##غلامپور آهنگر، ابراهیم (1395). مروری بر مفهوم حکمرانی شبکه‌ای. تهران: انتشارات مرکز پژوهش‌های مجلس شورای اسلامی.##قوچانی خراسانی، محمدمهدی؛ حسین‌پور، داوود (1396). حاکمیت شبکه‌ای در نهادهای پژوهشی امنیت سایبری. فرایند مدیریت توسعه، 30(1)، 51-80.##قوچانی خراسانی، محمدمهدی؛ حسین‌پور، داوود؛ محمودزاده، ابراهیم؛ الوانی، سید مهدی؛ فیروزآبادی، سید ابوالحسن (1396). الگوی حکمرانی شبکه‌ای با تأکید بر توسعه فرایندهای نوآوری باز در نهادهای تحقیقاتی امنیت سایبری. نشریه علمی پژوهشی بهبود مدیریت، 11(4)، 33- 56.##محمدزاده سلطانمردی، هادی؛ فیضی، طاهره؛ گرامی‌پور، مسعود؛ یداللهی، مهدی (1398). تبیین و آسیب‌شناسی الگوی جاری مدیریت دولتی در ایران. مدیریت دولتی، 11(1)، 1- 26.##نظری، محسن؛ دستار، حسین (1397). عوامل تعیین‌کننده تصویر قیمتی فروشگاهی: رهیافت فراترکیب. تحقیقات بازاریابی نوین، 8(1)، 1-20.##References##Abolhasani Ranjbar, A., Danesh-Fard, K.A., &amp; Faghihi, A.H. (2017). Presenting an Agenda Model for the reform of the administrative system in Iran. Journal of Public Administration, 9(4), 615-640. (in Persian)##Aghazade, M.R., Asgari, T., Shahi, A., &amp; Farahmand, A. (2016). Designing a Process Model for Developing a Strategy for Governance Organizations Based on the Network Rule Paradigm. Journal of Management of Governmental Organizations, 3(4), 27-56.##(in Persian)##Alvani, S.M. (2009). Good governance is a network of civil society activists. Journal of development &amp; Evolution management, 4(1), 1-5. (in Persian)##Ansell, C., &amp; Torfing, J. (2016). Handbook on theories of governance. Cheltenham: Edward Elgar.##Chen, U., &amp; Lee, J. (2017). Collaborative data networks for public service: governance, management, and performance. Journal of Public Management Review, 20(5), 1-19.##Courtney, R. (2017). Network governance in the heritage ecology. Journal of Management and Governance, 22(3), 689- 706.##Dal Molin, M., &amp; Masella, C. (2016). From Fragmentation to Comprehensiveness in Network Governance. Journal of Public Organization Review, 16(4), 493-507.##Danaeefard, H. (2013). Network Public Administration in Iran: Theoretical and Practical Rationales, and Requirements. Management Researches in Iran, 17(2), 69-104.##(in Persian)##Dehghani, M., Yaghoubi, N.M., Mougheli, A.R., &amp; Vazife, Z. (2016). Provide a Three-Layer Feasibility Study and Effective Deployment of Knowledge Management Using the Advanced Method. Journal of Management of Governmental Organizations, 3(12), 108-123. (in Persian)##Fawcett, P., Flinders, M., Hay, C., &amp; Wood, M. (2017). Anti-politics, de-politicization, and governance. Oxford: Oxford.##Fawcett, P., Flinders, M., Hay, C., &amp; Wood, M. (2017). Anti-politics, de-politicization, and governance. Oxford: Oxford.##Gholam-Pour, A. (2017). A Review of the Concept of Network Governance. Tehran: Islamic Consultative Research Center Publications. (in Persian)##Ghouchani Khorasani, M.M., Hosseinpour, D. (2017). Network Governance in Cyber Security Research Institutions. Journal of Management and Development Process, 30(1), 51-80. (in Persian)##Ghouchani-Khorasani, M.M., Hosein-Pour, D., Mahmoud-Zade, E., Alvani, S.M., &amp; Firouz-Abadi, S.A.H. (2017). A network governance model emphasizing the development of open innovation processes in cyber security research institutions. Journal of Management Improvement, 11(4), 33-56. (in Persian)##Hajat-Pour, S., Danesh-Fard, K.A., Amir-Nejad, Gh., &amp; Taban, M. (2018). Providing a model for evaluating public policies (after implementation) with the network governance approach (Case Study: Social Security Organization). Journal of Public Policy Management Quarterly, 7(28), 13-25. (in Persian)##Hajat-Pour, S., Danesh-Fard, K.A., Amir-Nejad, Gh., &amp; Taban, M. (2018). Providing a model for assessing public policies (after implementation) with a network governance approach (Case study: Social Security Organization. Iranian Journal of Public Administration mission, 8(4), 13-25. (in Persian)##Hayes, A., &amp; Scott, T. (2017). Multiplex Network Analysis for Complex Governance Systems Using Surveys and Online Behavior. Policy Studies Journal, 46(2), 1-27.##Hoyng, R. (2016). A socio-technical contract: Network governance and ICT4D in Turkey. Journal of Telematics and Informatics, 33(1), 139-149.##Iborra, S.S., &amp; Saz-Carranza, A., Fernández-i-Marín, X., &amp; Albareda, A. (2017). The Governance of Goal-Directed Networks and Network Tasks: An Empirical Analysis of European Regulatory Networks. Journal of Public Administration Research and Theory, 28(2), 1-23.##Imperial, C., Ospina, S., Johnston, E., O’Leary, R., Thomsen, J., Williams, P., &amp; Johnson, Sh. (2016). Understanding leadership in a world of shared problems: advancing network governance in large landscape conservation. Journal of Frontiers in Ecology and the Enviroment, 14(3), 126-134.##Jacobsen, D.I. (2015). Regional Governance Networks: Filling In or Hollowing Out? Journal of Scandinavian Political Studies, 38(2), 115-136.##Jacobson, D. (2016). How and why network governance evolves: evidence from a public safety network. Journal of Electronic Markets, 26(1), 43-54.##Jamali, Gh. A., Nargisian, A., &amp; Piran-Nejad, A. (2017). Evaluation of the Transparency of Public Organizations Portal (Case Study: Iranian Ministries). Journal of Public Administration, 9(1), 61-84. (in Persian)##Jedd, T., &amp; Bixler, P. (2015). Accountability in Networked Governance: Learning from a case of landscape-scale forest conservation. Journal of Enviromental Policy and Governance, 25(3), 172- 188.##Jensen, L. (2016). The Twentieth-Century Administrative State and Networked Governance. Journal of Public Administration Research and Theory, 27(3), 1-17.##Khaje-Naeini, A. (2015). Income on the concept of network governance; desirability and challenges. Journal of political and international approaches, 6(39), 129-155.##(in Persian)##Laffin, M. (2015). Planning in England: New Public Management, Network Governance or Post-Democracy? International Review of Administrative Sciences, 82(2), 1-19.##Mohammadzadeh Soltanmoradi, H., Feizy, T., Geramipour, M., &amp; Yadollahi, M. (2019). Explanation and Pathology of the Current Pattern of Public Administration in Iran. Journal of Public Administration, 11(3), 1-26. (in Persian)##Namara, R., Karyeija, G.K. &amp; Mubangizi, B. (2015). Network governance and capacity of local governments to deliver LED in Uganda. Commonwealth Journal of Local Governance, 16(18), 82-107.##Nazari, M., &amp; Dastar, H. (2018). Identification of Factors Affecting Overall Store Price Image (OSPI): A Meta Synthesis Approach. Journal of New Marketing Research, 8(1), 1-20.##(in Persian)##Padovani, C., &amp; Pavan, E. (2016). Global governance and ICTs: exploring online governance networks around gender and media. Journal of Global Networks, 16(3), 350-371.##Palomo-Navarro, A., &amp; Navío-Marco, J. (2017). Smart city networks&#039; governance: The Spanish smart city network case study. Journal of Telecommunications Policy, 42(10), 1-9.##Pour-Ezzat, A.A. (2015). An Introduction to Scientific Research Methodology (Development of the Research Resource and its Defense). Tehran: Nomadchi publication, 6(39), 129-155. (in Persian)##Provan, K. Keith, G., and Kenis, P. (2008). Modes of network governance: Structure, management, and effectiveness. Journal of Public Administration Research and Theory, 18(2), 229-259.##Sandelowski, M., &amp; Barroso, J. (2006). Handbook for synthesizing qualitative research. Springer Publishing Company.##Salimi, G., &amp; Maknoon, R. (2018). Qualitative Meta-analysis of Scientific Researches Concerning the Issue of Governance in Iran, Journal of Public Administration, 10(1), 1-30. (in Persian)##Scarlett, L., and McKinney, M. (2016). Connecting people and places: the emerging role of network governance in large landscape conservation. Ecol Environ, 14(3), 116–125.##Shabbazi-Soltani, M., &amp; Salavatiyan, S. (2018). Identifying the characteristics of the jihadist director in a way that goes further. Journal of Islamic Management, 25(1), 199-230.##(in Persian)##Soltani F, Shahin A, Shaemi Barzoki A. (2017). Designing a Talent Excellence Model Using Systematic Literature Review and Qualitative Meta Synthesis in Isfahan province Gas Company. Human Resource Management in Oil Industry, 8 (32), 51-84. (in Persian)##Sørensen, E., &amp; Torfing. J. (2018). The democratizing impact of governance networks: From pluralization, via democratic anchorage, to interactive political leadership. Journal of Public Administration, 96(2), 1-16.##Sørensen, E., and Torfing, J. (2009). Making governance network effective and democratic through metagovernance. Public Administration, 87(2), 234-258.##Ulibarri, N., &amp; Scott, T. (2016). Linking Network Structure to Collaborative Governance. Journal of Public Administration Research and Theory, 27(1), 1-19.##Wang, W. (2015). Exploring the Determinants of Network Effectiveness: The Case of Neighborhood Governance Networks in Beijing. Journal of Public Administration Research and Theory, 26(2), 1-24.##Weller, T., &amp; Tierney, J. (2017). Evidence in the Networked Governance of Regional Decarbonisation: A Critical Appraisal. Journal of Public Administration, 77(2), 1-14.##Yi, H. (2017). Network Structure and Governance Performance: What Makes a Difference? Journal of Public Administration Review, 78(2), 1-11.##Zendehdel Nobari, B., Azar, A., Rahmati, M.H., Kazerooni, M., &amp; Ghasemi, A.R. (2018). Identifying National effective parameters in ERP Implementation Risk Factors in Iran by Multi Grounded Approach. Journal of Public management Research, 11(4), 5-28.##(in Persian)##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>پیامدهای به‌کارگیری رویکرد مدیریت مالی عمومی نوین</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Outcomes of Using New Public Financial Management Approach</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: مدیریت مالی عمومی نوین شامل مجموعه‌ اصلاحاتی در سیستم‌ها، رویه‌ها و قوانین حسابداری، گزارشگری مالی، بودجه‌‌ریزی، حسابرسی و کنترل داخلی به‌منظور استفاده‌ مؤثر و کارا از منابع مالی، ارتقای شفافیت و پاسخ‌گویی در بخش عمومی است. هدف اصلی این پژوهش، بررسی پیامدهای به‌کارگیری رویکرد مدیریت مالی نوین و ارزیابی وضعیت موجود شاخص‌های آن در بخش عمومی کشور است. روش: پژوهش حاضر از نوع پیمایشی است و داده‌های آن بر مبنای پرسش‌نامه‌ محقق‌ساخته‌ای در قالب 6 بخش که در 40 گویه تدوین شده و از طیف پنج گزینه‌ای لیکرت تبعیت می‌کند، جمع‌آوری شده است. نمونه‌ آماری شامل 192 نفر از متخصصان و کارشناسان این حوزه در اداره‌های امور مالیاتی، دیوان محاسبات و حسابرسان دستگاه‌های دولتی است که از طریق نمونه‌گیری قضاوتی انتخاب شدند. به‌منظور انجام تحلیل‌های آماری از آزمون‌های علامت زوج‌نمونه‌ای و فریدمن استفاده شد. یافته‌ها: نتایج آزمون‌های آماری نشان می‌دهد اجرای منسجم اصلاحات مدیریت مالی نوین در بخش عمومی کشور می‌تواند به ارتقای شفافیت، توان پاسخ‌گویی، بهره‌وری، بهبود کیفیت و ارزیابی و نظارت و همچنین کاهش برخی چالش‌ها در مقایسه با وضعیت فعلی آنها منجر شود. نتیجه‌گیری: به‌کارگیری رویکرد مدیریت مالی عمومی نوین متناسب با ویژگی‌های محیطی کشور می‌تواند سبب یکپارچگی سیستم‌های اطلاعاتی، واقع‌بینانه‌تر شدن صورت‌های مالی و سهولت تصمیم‌گیری اعتباردهندگان در فرصت‌های سرمایه‌گذاری و همچنین ارتقای توان پاسخ‌گویی از طریق ارائه‌ گزارش‌هایی در باب عملکرد، ارزیابی توان ایفای تعهدات دولت و بودجه شود. علاوه بر این، به بهبود در مدیریت تخصیص منابع بودجه‌ای، دقت در اندازه‌گیری بهای تمام‌شده‌ خدمات و مدیریت زمان منجر می‌شود و چنانچه اصلاحات بدون در نظر گرفتن ماهیت بخش عمومی کشور اجرا شود، می‌تواند پیامدهای نامطلوبی همچون شکاف طبقاتی، عدم رشد خلاقیت در بخش عمومی، فساد مالی و عملیاتی و تناقض در معیارهای عملکرد را به‌دنبال داشته باشد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: The new public financial management consists of reforms in systems and procedures, basics of accounting, financial reporting, budgeting, auditing, internal controls, and external controls. This novel system was introduced to generate a more efficient and effective use of financial resources and for promoting transparency and accountability. The main objective of this research is to investigate the outcomes of applying the new public financial management and the current situation of its components in Iran’s public sector. Methods: This research was a survey-based study and data was gathered through a researcher-made questionnaire. The questionnaire was divided into six components that were compiled into 40 items and it followed the five-point Likert scale. The statistical sample consisted of 192 experts in Tax administration offices, Supreme auditing courts and public sector auditors which were selected through a judgmental sampling. And, the data was analyzed using statistical applications which performed Friedman and paired sign tests. Results: The results show that utilizing the new public financial management approach can promote and improve transparency, accountability and supervisions. The novel approach can also be used to diminish many of the challenges which we are currently facing. Conclusion: If the new public financial management approach is compatible with the environmental characteristics and infrastructures it could generate reliability in information systems, more realistic financial statements, ease decision making in investments opportunities, increase accountability by presenting performance information, and fulfill the government’s obligations on reports and budgeting. The novel approach can also lead to improvements in the management of resource allocation, accurate public service costs, and time management. If such a reform is implemented without considering the nature of public sectors, it can be followed adverse consequences such as Class stratification, lack of creativity in the public sector, financial and operational corruption, and inconsistency in performance criteria.  </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>231</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>250</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نفیسه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مشکینی</Family>
						<NameE>Nafiseh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Meshkini</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد، گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه بین‌المللی امام خمینی، قزوین، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد، گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>nafiseh.meshkini@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>غلامرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کردستانی</Family>
						<NameE>Gholamreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Kordestani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار، گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه بین‌المللی امام خمینی، قزوین، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار، گروه حسابداری، دانشکده علوم اجتماعی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>kordestani@soc.ikiu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت مالی عمومی نوین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت عمومی نوین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اصلاحات مدیریت مالی عمومی نوین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>الوانی، مهدی (1383). نارسایی‌های ارزیابی عملکرد در مدیریت نتیجه‌گرا. فصل‌نامه مطالعات مدیریت بهبود و تحول، 11(43)، 3-13.##باباجانی، جعفر (1382). مسئولیت پاسخ‌گویی و تحولات حسابداری دولتی موضوع بیانیه‌ 34 (GASB). پژوهش‌نامه علوم انسانی و اجتماعی، 3(8)، 35-61.  ##باباجانی، جعفر (1390). بررسی تطبیقی فراز و فرود ایفا و ارزیابی مسئولیت پاسخ‌گویی مالی از طریق گزارشگری مالی دولتی در سده‌ گذشته، مجله دانش حسابرسی، 11(44)، 37-72.##پوراحمدی، معین؛ مختاریان‌پور، مجید؛ حسنقلی‌پور یاسوری، طهمورث (1397). آسیب‌شناسی اجرای خط‌‌مشی‌ها           خصوصی‌سازی در ایران. مدیریت دولتی، 10(3)، 332-356.##خرمی، قاسم (1395)، بررسی تأثیر حسابرسی عملیاتی بر بودجه‌‌ریزی عملیاتی. فصل‌نامه پژوهش‌های جدید در مدیریت و حسابداری، 2(6)، 179-191.##دانایی فرد، حسن (1395). چالش‌های مدیریت دولتی در ایران. (چاپ دهم). تهران: انتشارات سمت.##رحمان سرشت، حسین؛ موسوی‌کاشی زهره (1394). مدلی برای سنجش اثربخشی خدمات عمومی (آزمونی در بیمارستان‌های دولتی)، مجله چشم‌انداز مدیریت دولتی، 24، 59-76.##رضازاده، جواد (1383). حسابرسی عملیاتی: یک ضرورت ملی. هشتمین همایش سراسری حسابداری ایران، مشهد.##سالارزهی، حبیب‌الله؛ ابراهیم‌پور، حبیب (1391). بررسی سیر تحول در پارادایم های مدیریت دولتی، از پارادایم مدیریت دولتی سنتی تا پارادیم حکمرانی خوب. مدیریت دولتی، 4(9)، 43-62.##طرقی ابوالحسنی، علیرضا؛ ابوالحسنی، صابر (1395)، مدیریت مالی نوین از منظر سیستم حسابداری تعهدی در بخش عمومی. نخستین همایش ملی علوم اسلامی حقوق و مدیریت.##عادل، آذر؛ امیرخانی، طیبه (1391). بودجه‌ریزی عمومی: نهادهای بودجه‌ریزی و بودجه محلی. تهران: انتشارات سمت، ص.ص. 107-227.##کردستانی، غلامرضا؛ معنوی مقدم، امیرهادی (1396)، بررسی مدیریت مالی نوین بخش عمومی، گذشته، حال و آینده. مطالعات حسابداری و حسابرسی، 6 (23)، 17-30.##کردستانی، غلامرضا؛ نصیری، محمود (1388)، کارایی گزاشگری مالی و ارتقای سطح مسئولیت پاسخ‌گویی در بخش عمومی. مجله حسابدار، 25(208 و 209)، 58-65.##کمیته حسابرسی عملیاتی (1380)، سازمان مصوبات کمیته حسابرسی عملیاتی: آشنایی با حسابرسی عملیاتی، شماره 10.##محمدی‌پور، رحمت‌الله؛ احمدی، زهرا (1392)، بررسی نقش حسابداری تعهدی در پیاده‌سازی بودجه‌ریزی عملیاتی و جایگاه حسابرسی عملیاتی، مجله حسابرس، 67، 106-115.##References##Alkaraan, F. (2018). Public financial management reform: an ongoing journey towards good governance. Journal of Financial Reporting and Accounting, 16(4), 585-609.##Alvani, M. (2004). Failure of performance evaluation in results-oriented management. Quarterly Journal of Management Studies in Development and Evolution, 11(43), 3-13. (in Persian)##Adel, A. &amp; Amirkhani, T. (2012). Public Budgeting: Budgeting and Local Budgetary Institutions. Tehran: SAMT Publication, PP. 107-227. (in Persian)##Babajani, J. (2003). Responsibility and Accountability of Governmental Accounting, No. 34 (GASB). Journal of Humanities and Social Sciences, 3(8), 35-61. (in Persian)##Babajani, J. (2011). A comparative review of the ups and downs, and the assessment of Financial accountability through government financial reporting in the past century. Journal of Audit Science, 11(44), 37-72. (in Persian)##Baltaci, M. &amp; Yilmaz, S. (2006). Keeping an Eye on Sub-national Governments: Internal Control and Audit at Local Levels. WBI working paper series. Washington, DC: World Bank, PP. 1-29.##Barton, A. (2009), The use and abuse of accounting in the public sector financial management  reform program in Australia. Journal of accounting, finance and business studies, 45(2), 221-248.##Choi, J.H. (2018). Accrual Accounting and Resource Allocation: A General Equilibrium Analysis.17th Annual Carnegie Mellon Accounting Mini Conference and Junior Accounting Theory Conference for helpful comments, pp 70.##Clark, C. &amp; Menifield, C. E. &amp; Stewart, L. M. (2017). Policy Diffusion and Performance-based Budgeting. International Journal of Public Administration, 41(7), 528-534.##Danaiee fard, H.  (2017). Challenges of Governmental management in Iran. (10 ed). Tehran: SAMT Publishers. (in Persian)## Dittenhofer, M. (2001). Performance auditing in governments. Managerial Auditing journal, 16(8), 438-442.##Garcia-Sanchez, I.M. &amp; Beatriz-Cuadrado, B. (2016). New Public Financial Management. Springer International Publishing Switzerland, 1-18. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-31816-5_2323-1.##Hope, K.R. (2001). The new public management: context and practice in Africa. International Public Management Journal, 4(2), 119-134.##Hughes, J. (2007). Local government internal controls to ensure efficiency and integrity (chapter 5 of book). Local public financial management (public sector governance and accountability service, Washington, The World Bank, 160-179.##Kordestan, Gh. &amp; Nasiri, M. (2009). Efficiency of financial reporting and Promotion of accountability in the public sector. Journal of Accounting, 25(208-209), 58-65. (in Persian)##Kordestani, Gh. &amp; Manavi Moghaddam, A.H. (2017). Reviewing the New Public Financial Management, Past, Present and Future. Accounting and Auditing Studies, 23, 17-30. (in Persian)##Khorrami, Q. (2016). Investigating the impact of Operational Audit on Operational budgeting. Quarterly Journal of New Research in Management and Accounting, 6(23), 17-30. (in Persian)##Larbi, A.G. (1999). The New Public Management Approach and Crisis States. UNRISD Discussion paper, 112, 1-37.##Matthew, A. &amp; McNaught, T. &amp; Samji, S. (2018). Opening Adaptation windows On to Public Financial Management Reform Gaps in Mozambique, CID Faculty Working Paper. PP. 341.##Mohammadipour, R., &amp; Ahmadi, Z. (2013), Investigating the Role of Accrual Accounting in Implementing Operational Budgeting and role of operational auditing. Auditorium Journal, 67, 106-115. (in Persian)##Nyamita M. O., Dorasamy, N. &amp; Garbharran, H.L. (2015). A review of public sector financial management reforms: an international perspective. Public and Municipal Finance, 4(2), 25-37.##Poorahmadi, M., Mokhtarianpour, M., &amp; Hassan Gholipour, T. (2018). Pathology of the Implementation of Privatization Policies in Iran. Journal of Public  Administration, 10(3), 333-356. (in Persian)##Parker, L. D. &amp; Jacobs, K. &amp; Schmitz, J. (2019). New public management and the rise Of public sector performance audit: Evidence from the Australian case. Accounting, Auditing &amp; Accountability Journal, 32(1), 280-306.Rahman Seresht, H. &amp; Mosavikashi, Z. (2014). A Model for Measuring the Effectiveness Of Public Services (A Test in Public Hospitals). Journal of Public Administration Outlook, 24, 59-76. (in Persian)##Rezazadeh, J. (2004), Operational Auditing: A Necessity of Nationality. at the 8th Iranian Accounting Conference, Mashhad. (in Persian)##Salarzehi, H., Ebrahimpour, H. (2013). Paradigms of Public Administration: From Traditional Public Administration to Good Governance. Journal of Public management of Tehran University, 4(9), 43-62. (in Persian)##Tabrizi, J. S., Hagh Goshayie E., Doshmangir, L., &amp; Yousefi, M. (2018). New public management in Iran&#039;s health complex: a management framework for Primary health care system. primary health care research and development, 19(3), 264-276.##Torghi Abolhasani, A. &amp; Abolhasani, S. (2015). Modern financial management from The Perspective of the accrual accounting system in the public sector. The first National Conference on Islamic law and management. (in Persian)##Wynne, A. (2003). Do Private Sector Financial Statements provide a suitable model for public Sector Accounts? Paper presented at the European group of public Administration. Oeiras Portugal Conference “public Law and Modernizing the state, PP. 6-25.##Yapa, P.W.S., Ukwatte, S.L. (2015). The new public financial management (NPFM) and accrual accounting in Sri Lanka. In (ed), the public sector accounting, accountability auditing in emerging economics, research in accounting in emerging economics, Emerald Group publishing limited, 50, 7-50.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>شناسایی مؤلفه‌های سیستم تأمین منابع انسانی در راستای ارتقای‌ سلامت نظام اداری</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Identifying Components of Staffing System to Develop Administrative Integrity</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: یکی از عوامل دخیل و مؤثر در توسعه کشور، نظام اداری سالم و کارآمد است؛ چراکه نظام اداری، سیستم تنظیم‌کننده کلیه فعالیت‌ها برای نیل به اهداف از پیش تعیین‌شده و ابزاری برای پیاده‎سازی برنامه‌های توسعه محسوب می‌شود. از سوی دیگر، از جمله عوامل تهدید‎کننده سلامت اداری در ایران، عوامل اداری و مرتبط با نظام مدیریت منابع انسانی است. از این رو، به‌دلیل اهمیت و نقشی که سیستم‌های منابع انسانی در ارتقای سلامت اداری و پیشگیری از فساد اداری دارند، در پژوهش حاضر به‌دنبال شناسایی مؤلفه‌های سیستم تأمین منابع انسانی در راستای ارتقای سلامت نظام اداری در سازمان‌های دولتی خواهیم بود. روش: پژوهش حاضر در چارچوب رویکرد کیفی و با استفاده از روش تحلیل تم صورت گرفته است و برای استخراج مؤلفه‌های سیستم تأمین منابع انسانی در راستای ارتقای سلامت نظام اداری با 19 نفر از متخصصان سازمان اداری و استخدامی کشور با استفاده از شیوه نمونه‌گیری هدفمند مصاحبه انجام شده است. یافته‌ها: مؤلفه‌های سیستم تأمین منابع انسانی در راستای ارتقای سلامت نظام اداری در قالب 6 تم اصلی، 16 تم فرعی و 67 مفهوم استخراج شد و یافته‌ها نشان داد که مؤلفه‌های سیستم تأمین منابع انسانی در راستای ارتقای سلامت نظام اداری عبارت‎اند از: شفافیت، پاسخ‌گویی، شایسته‌سالاری، عدالت‌محوری، قانون‌محوری و کنترل داخلی. نتیجه‌گیری: سیستم تأمین نیرو در سازمان‌های دولتی در راستای ارتقای سلامت نظام اداری بایستی از مقررات، رویه‌ها و اقدامات شفاف برخوردار بوده و پاسخ‎گوی اقدامات صورت گرفته باشد و اصل شایسته‌سالاری و عدالت‌محوری را در جذب، انتخاب و استخدام در اولویت قرار دهد. همچنین اثربخشی سیستم تأمین نیرو در راستای ارتقای سلامت اداری، در گرو تبعیت رویه‌ها از قوانین و مقررات و کنترل داخلی فرایندهاست.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: Administrative integrity and efficiency are two factors that can play a major role in the development of a country. This is mainly due to the fact that administrative systems could be used to regulate activities in order to achieve specific goals and implement development plans. On the other hand, the human resource management system is one of the threatening factors to administrative integrity in Iran. Considering the role and importance of human resource systems in administrative integrity and corruption prevention, we&#039;re going to identify the components and the basis of a staffing system which could be used develop administrative integrity in public organizations. Methods: This qualitative research uses a thematic analysis in order to identify patterned meanings across our dataset. The data has been gathered through interviewing 19 administrative and recruitment organization experts using a Purposive sampling method. Results: The ideal criteria of a staffing system which could develop administrative integrity are divided into 6 main themes, 16 subsidiary themes, and 67 concepts. The results showed that a staffing system will result in administrative integrity if it consists of 6 characteristics: transparency, accountability, meritocracy, justice, legality and internal control. Conclusion: If staffing systems in public organizations are intended to develop administrative integrity, the system is required to have transparent regulations, procedures, and actions. It is also necessary for the system to be accountable for its actions and to prioritize meritocracy and justice in the recruitment of its employees. Likewise, the effectiveness of a staffing system to develop administrative integrity depends on the legal procedures, regulations and internal control of the processes.  </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>251</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>284</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ایمانی</Family>
						<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Imani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>imani66@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>آرین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قلی پور</Family>
						<NameE>Aryan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Gholipour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران،ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>agholipor@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عادل</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>آذر</Family>
						<NameE>Adel</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Azar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد، گروه مدیریت، دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد، گروه مدیریت، دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>azara@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی اصغر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>پورعزت</Family>
						<NameE>Ali Asghar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Pourezzat</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد، گروه مدیریت دولتی،دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد، گروه مدیریت دولتی،دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>pourezzat@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تأمین منابع انسانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت منابع انسانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سلامت نظام اداری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سازمان‌های دولتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تحلیل تم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>ابویی اردکان، محمد؛ لبافی، سمیه؛ آذرپور، سمانه؛ جلال‌پور، مهدیه (1393). شناسایی عوامل حیاتی موفقیت تفکر راهبردی در دیدگاه مدیران سازمان‎های فرهنگی شهر اصفهان. فصلنامه مدیریت اجرایی، 6 (11)، 13-34.##ابیلی، خدایار (1385). ضرورت بحث درباره توسعه شایسته‌سالاری در سازمان‌ها، مقالات مدیریت، تهران.##استخدام بی‌ضابطه در شهرداری محور اصلی نشست شورای اسلامی تبریز، 14/8/1396، خبرگزاری جمهوری اسلامی.##امیرپناهی، امیر (1393). سلامت و فساد اداری، کنگره بین‌المللی فرهنگ و اندیشه دینی، قم.##امیری، مجتبی؛ نرگسیان، عباس؛ بحری رودپشتی، الناز (1394). سنجش سلامت و فساد اداری در شهرداری تهران.‎ مطالعات رفتار سازمانی،‎ 4 (4)، 65-96.‎##پارتی‌بازی در استخدام‌های وزارت نفت، 6/6/1396، روزنامه آرمان، شماره 3404، صفحه 8.##تقوی، مهدی؛ نیکومرام، هاشم؛ غفاری، فرهاد؛ طوطیان، صدیقه (1390). رابطه فساد اداری و رشد اقتصادی در کشور‌های عضو اپک.‎ فصلنامه مدیریت، 8 (21)، 88-102.##تقی زاده، هوشنگ؛ سلطانی فسقندیس، غلامرضا (1396). بررسی نقش احساس عدالت سازمانی در گرایش افراد به فساد در سازمان. مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی، 15 (3)، 529-550.##حقیقی، محمدعلی؛ احمدی، ایمان؛ رامین مهر، حمید (1388). بررسی تأثیر عدالت سازمانی بر عملکرد کارکنان. مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی، 7 (20)، 79- 101.##رفیع پور، فرامرز (1377). توسعه و تضاد. تهران: شرکت سهامی انتشار.##رهنورد، فرج اله (1391). معماری نظام اداری در پرتو سیاست‌های کلی ابلاغی. فصلنامه مدیریت توسعه و تحول، 10، 15-22.##زاهدی، شمس‌السادات؛ محمدنبی، سینا؛ شهبازی، مهدی (1388). بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر کاهش فساد اداری (مطالعه موردی در شهرداری تهران).‎ مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی، 7 (20)، 29-55.‎##زرندی، سعید؛ معدنی، جواد (1395). طراحی و تبیین مدل مطلوب فرهنگ سازمانی اسلامی برای مقابله با فساد اداری در سازمان‎ها. مطالعات رفتار سازمانی، 5 (2)، 85- 117.##سجادی، حانیه‌سادات؛ حلاجی، فرشاد؛ معروف، ناصر (1394). بررسی سلامت اداری از دیدگاه کارکنان شاغل در بیمارستان‌های آموزشی شهر اصفهان.‎ پژوهش‌های سلامت‌محور،‎ 1 (2)، 123-132.##‎سر کار گذاشتن قانونی، 23/12/1395، روزنامه قانون، شماره 892، صفحه 5.##سکاران، اوما (1390). روش‌های تحقیق در مدیریت، ترجمه محمد صائبی و محمود شیرازی. تهران: انتشارات مرکز آموزش مدیریت دولتی.##سلطانی، ایرج (1381). نگاهی به نقش توسعه منابع انسانی در سلامت نظام اداری. تحول اداری، (35 و 36)، 95- 106.##سید‌جوادین، سیدرضا؛ حسنقلی‎پور، طهمورث؛ آسترکی، سامان (1395). بررسی تأثیر شادی بر سلامت اداری با اثر میانجی کیفیت‌زندگی‌کاری کارکنان.‎ مطالعات رفتار سازمانی،‎ 5 (2)، 1-24.‎##شیخ اسمعیلی، سامان؛ حسنی، کاوه؛ نرگسی، سیامک (1391). شایسته‌سالاری ادراک شده مدیران و توانمندسازی شناختی کارکنان. فرایند مدیریت و توسعه، 28 (1)، 117-139.##طالقانی، غلامرضا؛ طباطبایی، زهرا؛ غفاری، علی (1393). بررسی عوامل فردی و سازمانی موثر بر فساد اداری در شعب بانک سپه استان قم. مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی، 12(2)، 235-253.##طبری، مجتبی؛ محمدی، حامد (1387). موانع توسعه نظام اداری در کشورهای در حال توسعه. اطلاعات سیاسی ـ اقتصادی، (247 و 248)، 252-261.##قادری، مهدی (1388). فساد اداری در ایران، تحلیلی جامعه‌شناختی. مجله معرفت، (138)، 105- 118.##محمدپور، احمد (1392). روش تحقیق کیفی ضد روش 1 (منطق و طرح در روش شناسی کیفی). تهران: انتشارات جامعه‌شناسان. (چاپ اصلی 1390).##مدیریت و برنامه‎ریزی کشور (1380). برنامه مبارزه با فساد و ارتقای سلامت در نظام اداری (حکومت). تهران: انتشارات سازمان مدیریت و برنامه‎ریزی کشور، نشر زحل.##معاونت اجتماعی و اطلاع‌رسانی قوه قضائیه (1380). علل بروز مفاسد اقتصادی و راه‌کارهای مبارزه با آن. تهران: انتشارات قوه قضائیه.##معمارزاده طهران، غلامرضا؛ نجفی، مهناز (1396). شناسایی عوامل اثرگذار بر تحول سلامت اداری.‎ فصلنامه مدیریت توسعه و تحول، (30)، 41-48.‎##میرمحمدی، سید محمد؛ حسن‎پور، اکبر (1390). نظام اداری ایران، تحلیلی بر مشکلات و چالش‌ها. چشم‎انداز مدیریت دولتی، (8)، 9-22.##References##Abili, Khodayar (2002). Necessity of discussion on development of meritocracy in organizations, management papers, Tehran. (in Persian)##Aboyee Ardakan, M., Labbafi, S., Azarpour, S., Jalalpour, M. (2015). Identification the critical keys of success of strategic thinking from point of the managers of cultural organizations of Isfahan. Journal of executive management, 6 (11), 13-34. (in Persian)##Amiri, M., Nargesian, A., Bahri Roudposhti, E. (2016). Evaluation of administrative integrity and corruption in municipality of Tehran. Studies of organizational behavior, 4 (4), 65-96. (in Persian)##Amirpanahi, A. (2015). Administrative integrity and corruption. International congress of religion culture and thinking, Qom. (in Persian)##Antonakas, N. P., Giokas, A. E., &amp; Konstantopoulos, N. (2013). Corruption in Tax Administration: Interviews with Experts. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 73, 581-589.##Ashforth, B. E., Gioia, D. A., Robinson, S. L., &amp; Trevino, L. K. (2008). Re-viewing organizational corruption. Academy of Management review, 33(3), 670-684.##Ashour, A. S. (2004). Integrity, transparency and accountability in public sector human resources management.‎ Alexandria University, Egypt.##Bernardin, H. J., &amp; Cooke, D. K. (1993). Validity of an honesty test in predicting theft among convenience store employees.‎ Academy of management journal,‎ 36(5), 1097-1108.##Brunetti, A., &amp; Weder, B. (2003). A free press is bad news for corruption.‎ Journal of Public economics,‎ 87(7), 1801-1824.##Chene, M. (2015). Corruption and anti-corruption practices in human resource management in the public sector. Bergen: Chr. Michelsen Institute-U4 Anti-Corruption Resource Centre.##Creswell, J. W., &amp; Miller, D. L. (2000). Determining validity in qualitative inquiry. Theory into practice, 39(3), 124-130.##Day, D. V., Shleicher, D. J., Unckless, A. L., &amp; Hiller, N. J. (2002). Self-monitoring personality at work: A meta-analytic investigation of construct validity. Journal of Applied Psychology, 87(2), 390.##Deloitte. (2008). Taking the Reins: HR&#039;s opportunity to play a leadership role in governance, risk management and compliance. Midtown: Manhattan: Deloitte Consulting.##Dion, M. (2010). Corruption and ethical relativism: what is at stake?‎ Journal of Financial Crime,‎ 17(2), 240-250.##Doig, A., &amp; Riley, S. (1998). Corruption and anti-corruption strategies: Issues and case studies from developing countries.‎ Corruption and integrity improvement initiatives in developing countries,‎ 45- 62.##Gans-Morse, J., Borges, M., Makarin, A., Mannah Blankson, T., Nickow, A., &amp; Zhang, D. (2017). Reducing Bureaucratic Corruption: Interdisciplinary Perspectives on What Works. Available at SSRN: https://ssrn.com/abstract=2930520.##Ghaderi, M. (2010). Administrative corruption in Iran; a sociological analysis. Journal of Maarefat, 138, 105-118. (in Persian)##Haan, I., Benner, H. (2008). A Tool to Assess the Integrity of Public Sector Organization. International Journal of Auditing.##Haghighi, M.A., Ahmadi, I., Ramin Mehr, H. (2010). Investigating effect of organizational justice on employee performance. Journal of organizational culture, 7 (20), 79- 101.##(in Persian)##Heslin, P. A., &amp; Vande Walle, D. (2011). Performance appraisal procedural justice: The role of a manager’s implicit person theory. Journal of Management, 37(6), 1694-1718.##Holbrook, R. L. (2002). Contact points and flash points: conceptualizing the use of justice mechanisms in the performance appraisal interview. Human Resource Management Review, 12(1), 101-123.##Illegal employment in municipality: the core topic of Islamic council of Tabriz, November 5, 2017, Islamic Republic News. (in Persian)##Islam, K. A., Wangdi, T., Thinlay, D., Tharchen, S., Sambath, S. A. R., Heng, T. O. N. G. &amp; Nan, W. A. N. G. ADB/OECD Anti-Corruption Initiative for Asia and the Pacific.##Klitgaard, R. (1988).‎ Controlling corruption. University of California Press.##Kvale, S. (1996). An introduction to qualitative research, softcover publisher: sage publications.##Kwon, I. (2014). Motivation, discretion, and corruption. Journal of Public Administration Research and Theory, 24(3), 765–794.##Lee, K., Ashton, M. C., &amp; de Vries, R. E. (2005). Predicting workplace delinquency and integrity with the HEXACO and five-factor models of personality structure. Human performance, 18(2), 179-197.##Matei, L., &amp; Matei, A. I. (2009). Corruption in the Public Organizations-Towards a Model of Cost-Benefit Analysis for the Anticorruption Strategies. Presented at First Global Dialogue &#039;Governing Good and Governing Well&#039;: The First Global Dialogue on Ethical and Effective Governance, 28-30 May 2009, Amsterdam, The Netherlands. Available at SSRN: https://ssrn.com/abstract=1405209.##Memarzadeh Tehran, Gh., Najafi, M. (2018). Identifying factors affect development of administrative integrity. Journal of development administration, 30, 41-48. (in Persian)##Meyer, M., Roodt, G., &amp; Robbins, M. (2011). Human resources risk management: governing people risks for improved performance: opinion paper. SA Journal of Human Resource Management, 9(1), 1-12.##Mir Mohammadi, S.M., Hasanpour, A. (2012). Administrative system of Iran; an analysis of problems and challenges. Public administration perspective, 8, 9-22. (in Persian)##Misangyi, V. F., Weaver, G. R., &amp; Elms, H. (2008). Ending corruption: The interplay among institutional logics, resources, and institutional entrepreneurs.‎ Academy of Management Review,‎ 33(3), 750-770.##Mohammadpour, A. (2014). Research method; anti method (philosophy and plan in qualitative methodology). Vol 1, Tehran: Jameeshenasa press, second edition. (in Persian)##Nepotism in employment of oil ministery, August 28, 2017, Arman newspaper, 3404, 8.##(in Persian)##Olken, B. A. (2007). Monitoring corruption: evidence from a field experiment in Indonesia.‎ Journal of political Economy,‎ 115(2), 200-249.##Ones, D. S., Viswesvaran, C., &amp; Schmidt, F. L. (1993). Comprehensive meta-analysis of integrity test validities: Findings and implications for personnel selection and theories of job performance.‎ Journal of applied psychology,‎ 78(4), 679.##Plan and management organization (2002). Fighting corruption and development of administrative integrity plan (government). Tehran: Plan and management organization press, Zohal press, second edition. (in Persian)##Poocharoen, O. O., &amp; Brillantes, A. (2013). Meritocracy in Asia Pacific: Status, issues, and challenges. Review of Public Personnel Administration, 33(2), 140-163.##Putting others on legally, March 13, 2017, Ghanoun newspaper, 892, 5. (in Persian)##Rafei Pour, F. (1997). Development and antithesis. Tehran: Stock company of Enteshar press. (in Persian)##Rahnavard, F. (2013). Architecture of administrative system under the aegis of generic policy proclamation. Journal of development, 10, 15-22. (in Persian)##Sajjadi, H.S., Hallaji, F., Maarouf, N. (2016). Investigating administrative integrity from viewpoint of employees of educational hospitals of Isfahan. Health based researches, 1 (2), 123-132. (in Persian)##Sekaran, U. (2011). Research methods in management (trans. by Mohammad Saebi and Mahmoud Shirazi). Tehran: institute of public administration education. (in Persian)##Seyyed Javadein, S.R., Hasangholipour, T., Astaraki, S. (2017). Investigating effect of happiness on administrative integrity including mediaton effect of employees’ quality of work life. Organizational behavior studies, 5 (2), 1-24. (in Persian)##Shah, A. (Ed.). (2007).‎ Performance accountability and combating corruption. World Bank Publications.##Sheykh Esmaeili, S., Hasani, K., Nargesi, S. (2013). Perceived meritocracy of managers and psychological empowerment of employees. Journal of process of management and development, 28 (1), 117- 139. (in Persian)##Social and information assistance of judicature (2012). Causes of economical corruption and ways of fighting it. Tehran: judicature press. (in Persian)##Soltani, I. (2003). A view on the role of human resource development in administrative integrity. Administrative development, 35-36, 95-106.##Sullivan, J. D. (2009). The moral compass of companies: Business ethics and corporate governance as anti-corruption tools. Global Corporate Governance Forum.##Tabari, M., Mohammadi, H. (2009). Obstacles of administrative development in developing coutries. Economical- political information, 247-248, 252-261. (in Persian)##Taghizadeh, H., Soltani Fesghendis, Gh. R. (2018). Investigating the role of perceived organizational justice in people intention to corruption in organization. Journal of organizational culture, 15 (3), 529- 550. (in Persian)##Taleghani, Gh., Tabatabaei, Z., Ghaffari, A. (2015). Investigating individual and organizational factors affect administrative corruption in branches of bank Sepah in Qom. Journal of organizational culture, 12 (2), 235-253. (in Persian)##Tanzi, V. (1998). Corruption around the world: Causes, consequences, scope, and cures.‎ Staff Papers,‎ 45(4), 559-594.##Taghavi, M., Nikoumaram, H., Ghaffari, F., Toutian, S. (2012). Relation between administrative corruption and economic development in OPEC members. Journal of Management, 8 (21), 88- 102. (in Persian)##Vinayan, J. (2015). Vulnerability of HR Systems and Practices to Corruption: A Review and Research Agenda. Editorial Team, 7(1), 25.##Wei, S. J. (1999). Corruption in economic development: Beneficial grease, minor annoyance, or major obstacle?Policy Research Working Paper Series 2048, The World Bank.##Zahedi, Sh., Mohammad Nabi, S., Shahbazi, M. (2010). Investigating factors affect decreasing administrative corruption (case study in municipality of Tehran). Journal of organizational culture, 7 (20), 29-55. (in Persian)##Zarandi, S., Maadani, J. (2017). Designing a model of Islamic organizational culture against administrative corruption in organizations. Organizational behavior studies, 5 (2), 85-117. (in Persian)##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>فهم پدیده بی‌حسی سازمانی و شناسایی عوامل شکل‌دهنده آن به روش آمیخته</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Understanding the Phenomenon of Organizational Insentience and Identifying its Fusion Factors in a Mixed Method Way</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: هدف پژوهش حاضر، فهم ماهیت و عوامل شکل‌دهنده بی‌حسی سازمانی در سازمان‌های دولتی بوده است. روش: روش به‌کاررفته در پژوهش، روش آمیخته بوده است. روش‌های آمیخته دارای دو بخش کیفی و کمی هستند. بخش کیفی با استفاده از روش گرندد تئوری و بخش کمی با استفاده از مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری انجام گرفته است. ابزار جمع‌آوری اطلاعات در بخش کیفی مصاحبه‌های نیمه‌ساختاریافته بوده که متن آنها در سه مرحله کدگذاریِ باز، محوری و انتخابی کدگذاری شد و در بخش کمی، پرسش‌نامه محقق ساخته‌بوده که روایی و پایایی آن بررسی شده است. یافته‌ها: با توجه به کدهای احصاشده از مصاحبه‌ها و استخراج کدها با استفاده از نرم‌افزار MaxQda2018، تعداد 196 کدِ باز، 20 مقوله محوری و در نهایت 7 مقوله اصلی استخراج شدند. از این میان، ابعاد ترس سفید، خاموشی سازمانی، کرختی سازمانی و بی‌میلی سازمانی مربوط به متغیر بی‌حسی سازمانی (پدیده محوری) و ابعاد خطاهای ادراکی ـ حسی، رویدادهای حسی و نقش‌های نامتعارف مدیران دولتی، مربوط به شرایط علی تأثیرگذار بر پدیده محوری شناسایی شدند. نتیجه‌گیری: با توجه به یافته‌های بخش کیفی (کدهای شناسایی‌شده)، تأیید ارتباط ابعاد با متغیرها و مدل معادلات ساختاری پژوهش که با استفاده از نرم‌افزار Smart PLS3 انجام گرفت، مشخص شد شرایط علی با ضریب اثر و ضریب معناداری قابل ‌قبول، بر پدیده بی‌حسی سازمانی اثر می‌گذارند و معیارهای GOF، Q2، Rsquare و Fsqare برای مدل ساختاری و مدل‌های اندازه‌گیری محاسبه شد که همگی مقادیر مجاز و قابل ‌قبولی داشتند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: This research is aimed at understanding the nature of organizational numbness in governmental organizations and the factors influencing it. Methods: This Mixed-methods research uses a systematic integration of quantitative and qualitative data. The qualitative part is performed using the Grounded theory and quantitative part utilizes a structural equation modeling. The qualitative part used semi-structured interviews for its data collection and a combination of open coding, axial coding, and selective coding was used for the analysis of the data. On the other hand, a researcher made questionnaire was used for the quantitative section while the validity and reliability of the survey had already been investigated. Results: 7 major categories were identified using 196 open codes and 20 axial codes. The data analysis software MaxQda 2018 has been used used to analyze the surveys data and extract the codes. Meanwhile, the dimensions of white fear, organizational blackout, insentience, and reluctance related to the organizational numbness variable (the axial phenomenon) and the dimensions of perceptual-sensual errors, sensual events and unconventional roles of government executives, related to the causative conditions affecting the axial phenomenon were identified. Conclusion: Based on the findings of the qualitative part and the confirmation of the relationship between dimensions and variables using the identified codes it was determined that causal conditions with acceptable effect coefficients and significance coefficients affect the phenomenon of organizational numbness. The GOF, Q2, Rsquare and Fsqare criteria for the structural model and the measurement models were calculated using the Smart PLS 3 software. It is also worth to mention that all of the mentioned variables had allowed and acceptable values.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>285</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>308</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>احمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خمش آیا</Family>
						<NameE>Ahmad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khamshaya</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه ایلام، ایلام، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ahmadkhamshaya@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>اردشیر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شیری</Family>
						<NameE>Ardeshir</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Shiri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی دانشگاه ایلام، ایلام، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>shiri_ardeshir@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>یاسینی</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Yasini</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه مدیریت آموزشی، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه ایلام، ایلام، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه مدیریت آموزشی، دانشکده ادبیات</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hivayasini@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بی‌حسی سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بی‌میلی سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ترس سفید</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خاموشی سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کرختی سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>آستیون، هلملینگ؛ وقفی پور، شهریار (1387). آدورنو هگل و آگاهی معذب (نقد). ترجمه: شهریار وقفی پور. هنر و معماری، (19)، 179- 186.##اسفیدانی، محمد رحیم؛ محسنین، شهریار (1396). معادلات ساختاری مبتنی بر رویکرد حداقل مربعات جزئی. تهران: مهربان نشر.##بازرگان، عباس (1387). مقدمه‌ای بر روش‌های تحقیق کیفی و آمیخته، رویکردهای متداول در علوم رفتاری، تهران: دیدار.##پورعزت، علی اصغر؛ قربانی، علی؛ عبدی، جهان؛ نجار شمس، فاطمه (1397). بازنمایی سیستم تاراج نوین در قالب سوداگری اداری. مدیریت دولتی، 10 (2)، 209-226.##خمش آیا، احمد؛ شیری، اردشیر؛ یاسینی، علی (1397). فهم فرایند بی‌حسی سازمانی: الگویی برخاسته از نظریه داده‌بنیاد (مورد مطالعه: سازمان‌های دولتی استان بوشهر). پایان‎نامه کارشناسی ارشد در رشته مدیریت دولتی، گرایش تحول، دانشگاه ایلام.##داوری، علی؛ رضازاده، آرش (1393). مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری با نرم‌افزار انتشارات جهاد دانشگاهی (چاپ اول). تهران: جهاد دانشگاهی.##رحمان سرشت، حسین (1386). تئوری‌های سازمان و مدیریت از تجددگرایی تا پساتجددگرایی (جلد دوم: دوران پساتجددگرای و پست مدرنیسم). تهران: دوران.##روشندل اربطانی، طاهر؛ فرهنگی، علی اکبر؛ ربیعی، علی؛ رادفر، سودابه (1396). شناسایی عوامل مؤثر بر توانمندسازی منابع انسانی در سازمان‌های ارتباطاتی و رسانه‌ای دولتی. مدیریت دولتی، 9 (3)، 517-538.##سبحانی فرد، یاسر (1395). مبانی و کاربرد تحلیل عاملی و مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری. تهران: دانشگاه امام صادق (ع).##سرمد، زهره؛ بازرگان، عباس؛ حجازی، اله (1390). روش‌های تحقیق در علوم رفتاری (چاپ بیست و دوم). تهران: نشر آگه.##سلاطی، مریم؛ احمدی فرد، مریم؛ عدن‎ور، مریم؛ مؤمنی، فریبا (1395). تأثیر نوآوری و رهبری تحول آفرین بر عملکرد بازاریابی شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان. فصل‌نامه اختصاصی تبلیغات و بازاریابی، 2 (4).##سهروردی (شیخ اشراق) (1388). شهاب الدین یحیی بن حبش بن امیرک، التلویحات اللوحیه و العرشیه، تصحیح و مقدمه نجفقلی حبیبی؛ چاپ 1، تهران: مؤسسه پژوهشی حکمت و فلسفه ایران.##شعیری، حمیدرضا (1384). بررسی نقد بنیادی ادراک حسی در تولید معنا. فلسفه و کلام، (49 و 46)، 131-146.##عباس‎پور، عباس؛ رحیمیان، حمید؛ غیاثی ندوشن، سعید؛ نرگسـیان، جـواد (1397). ارائـه مـدل انتخـاب کارکنـان مسـتعد در سازمان‌های دولتی. مدیریت دولتی، 10 (4)، 605-628.##فراستخواه، مقصود (1396). روش تحقیق کیفی در علوم اجتماعی با تأکید بر نظریه برپایه (چاپ چهارم). تهران: نشر آگاه.##ملک‌زاده، غلامرضا؛ ادیب زاده، مرضیه؛ غلامی، محمد (1397). نقش میانجی سکوت‌گرایی اجتنابی در رابطه میان جو مدیریت خطا و رفتار یادگیری با عملکرد فردی. مدیریت دولتی، 10 (4)، 651-677.##References##Aguinis, H., &amp; Glavas, A. (2017). On corporate social responsibility, sensemaking, and the search for meaningfulness through work. Journal of Management, 20(10), 1-30.##Barclay, D., Higgins, C., Thompson, R. (1995). The Partial Leastn Squares (PLS) Approach to Causal Modeling: Personal Computer Use as an Illustration. Technology, Technology studies: special issue on research methodology, 2(2), 284-324.##Berthod, O., &amp; Müller-Seitz, G. (2017). Making Sense in Pitch Darkness: An Exploration of the Sociomateriality of Sensemaking in Crises. Journal of Management Inquiry, DOI: 1056492616686425.##Ciavolino, E., &amp; Nitti, M. (2010). High-order constructs for the structural equation model. In V meeting on dynamics of social and economic systems (pp. 1-5).‏##Cronbach, L. J. (1951). Coefficient alpha and the internal structure of tests. Psychometrika, 16, 297-334.##‏de Graaff, M. C., Giebels, E., Meijer, D. J., &amp;Verweij, D. E. (2016). Sensemaking in Military Critical Incidents: The Impact of Moral Intensity. Business &amp; society, DOI: 0007650316680996.##De Luca Picione, R., &amp; Freda, M. F. (2016). Possible use in psychology of threshold concept in order to study sensemaking processes. Culture &amp; Psychology, 22(3), 362-375.##Fornell, C., &amp; Larcker, D. F. (1981). Evaluating structural equation models with unobservable variables and measurement error. Journal of marketing research, 18(1), 39-50.‏##Glaser, B. G., &amp; Strauss, A. L. (1965). Discovery of substantive theory: A basic strategy underlying qualitative research. American Behavioral Scientist, 8(6), 5-12.‏##Glaser, B., &amp; Strauss, A. (1967). The discovery ofgrounded theory. London: Weidenfeld and Nicholson, 24(25), 288-304.‏##Glaser, B. G., Strauss, A. L., &amp; Strutzel, E. (1968). The discovery of grounded theory; strategies for qualitative research. Nursing research, 17(4), 364.‏##Ivancevich, J. M., &amp; Javier, J. F. (2005). Administración de recursos humanos. Atlas, S.A.##Kline, R. B. (1998). Principles and Practice of Structural Equation Modeling. New York, Guilford Press.##Krejcie, R. V., &amp; Morgan, D. W. (1970). Determining sample size for research activities. Educational and psychological measurement, 30(3), 607-610.‏##Lawshe, C. H. (1975). A quantitative approach to content validity. Personnel psychology, 28(4), 563-575.‏##Magner, N., Welker, R. B., Campbell, T. L. (1996). Testing a model of cognitive budgetary participation -processes in a latent variable structural equations framework. Accounting and Business Research, 27(1), 41-50.##Maitlis, S., &amp; Christianson, M. (2014). Sensemaking in organizations: Taking stock and moving forward. Academy of Management Annals, 8(1), 57-125.##Nunnaly, J. (1978). Psychometric theory, New York: McGraw-Hill.##Shultz, K. S., Whitney, D. J., &amp; Zickar, M. J. (2013). Measurement theory in action: Case studies and exercises. Routledge##Taylor, J. R., &amp; Van Every, E. J. (2010). The situated organization: Case studies in the pragmatics of communication research. Routledge.##Tenenhaus, M., Silvano, A., Vinzi, V. E. (2004). A global Goodness–of–Fit index for PLS structural equationmodeling. Available in: https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/cfdb/0d4ec08d6eb4721787c 795c092b36cb3805f.pdf.##Waltz, C. F., &amp; Bausell, B. R. (1981). Nursing research: design statistics and computer analysis. (1st ed.): Davis FA.‏##Weick, K. E. (1995). Sensemaking in organizations (Vol. 3). Sage.##Weick, K. E. (2001). Making sense of the organization (vol. 1). Malden, MA: Blackwell Publishers.##Weick, K. E. (2010). Reflections on enacted sensemaking in the Bhopal disaster. Journal of Management Studies, 47(3), 537-550.##Weick, K. E. (2012). Organized sensemaking a commentary on processes of interpretive work. Human Relations, 65(1), 141-153.##Weick, K. E., Sutcliffe, K. M., &amp;Obstfeld, D. (2005). Organizing and the process of sensemaking. Organization science, 16(4), 409-421.‏##Werts, C.E., Linn, R.L., Jöreskog, K.G. (1974). Intraclass Reliability Estimates: Testing Structural Assumptions. Journal of Educational and Psychological Measurement, 34(1).##Wetzels, M., Odekerken-Schröder, G., &amp; Van Oppen, C. (2009). Using PLS path modeling for assessing hierarchical construct models: Guidelines and empirical illustration. MIS quarterly, 33(1), 177-195.‏##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>طراحی مدل آشفتگی ـ پویایی توسعه بهره‌وری منابع انسانی صنعت نفت ایران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Modeling the Disturbance-Dynamics Model of Human Resources Development in Iran&#039;s Oil Industry</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: صنعت نفت مهم‌ترین و استراتژیک‌ترین صنعت ایران است و در اقتصاد کشور نقش مسلط را بازی می‌کند. از آنجا ‌که عنصر اصلی ایجاد و توسعه بهره‌وری، سرمایه انسانی است، توسعه بهره‌وری سرمایه انسانی در این صنعت، می‌تواند در راستای رسیدن به رشد اقتصادی و اهداف بلندمدت کشور گام‌های بلندی بردارد. در برنامه‌ریزی توسعه بهره‌وری منابع انسانی، مدیران و برنامه‌ریزان این حوزه از یک ‌طرف با پیچیدگی نیروی انسانی (سیستم‌های چندذهنی) و از طرف دیگر با روابط روان‌شناختی و مسائل اجتماعی ـ فرهنگی (نگرش سیستمی) مواجه‎اند. چنانچه مسئله بهره‌وری منابع انسانی را در صنعت نفت، مسئله‌ای از نوع آشفتگی در نظر بگیریم، این پژوهش به مدل‌سازی، شبیه‌سازی و سیاست‌گذاری سیستم بهره‌وری منابع انسانی صنعت نفت با بهره‌گیری از صورت‌بندی نظم آشفته و پویایی سیستم می‌پردازد. روش: روش‌شناسی پژوهش با الهام از تفکر سیستمی انتقادی تحقیق در عملیات و روش‌شناسی چندگانه (سیستمی از روش‌شناسی‌های سیستمی)، نخست با بهره‌گیری از موانع توسعه ایکاف/ قراجه داغی، به تعبیه اصولی برای ساختاردهی آشفتگی مسئله و سپس به مدل‌سازی با استفاده از رویکرد پویایی سیستم می‌پردازد. یافته‌ها: یافته‌های مدل، با توجه به وضعیت موجود نشان می‌دهند توجه ناکافی به شفافیت ساختار صنعت نفت در بعد قدرت و بهره‌گیری از سرمایه‌های فکری و انسانی در بعد ارزش و انگیزش کارکنان در بعد زیبایی سبب شده است که به بهره‌وری منابع انسانی صنعت، آسیب‌های فراوانی وارد شود. نتیجه‌گیری: اعمال سیاست‌های ترکیبی در سه زیرنظام ارزش، قدرت و زیبایی به‌عنوان بهترین دسته راهکار برای بهبود بهره‌وری منابع انسانی صنعت نفت انتخاب شد و نشان داده شد که برنامه‌ریزی برای افزایش سرمایه‌های فکری و انسانی، شفافیت ساختاری نظام صنعت نفت و نظام انگیزشی کارکنان صنعت نفت، بر افزایش میزان ارزش ‌افزوده منابع انسانی و بهبود بهره‌وری منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت اثرهای شایان‌ توجهی دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: The oil industry is the most important and strategic industry in Iran and plays a dominant role in the economy of the country. Human capital is the main element in the creation and development of productivity, therefore the development of human capital productivity in this industry can be a major step towards achieving economic growth and long-term goals of the country. In planning the development of human resource efficiency, managers and planners have to cope with the complexity of human resources (systems of multidimensional systems) and, psychological relations and socio-cultural issues (systemic attitudes). Considering the fact that, human resource utilization in the oil industry is a turbulent issue, this research aimed at modeling, simulating and strategizing the human resources system of the oil industry using the formulation of a turbulent order and the dynamics of the system. Methods: The research’s methodology is inspired by the critical system thinking of research in multiple operations and methodologies (a system of systematic methodologies). This is primarily done using the barriers to the development of Ackoff / Gharage Daghie, the principled embedding of the structure of the problem turmoil, and then into modeling using the dynamics of the system. Results: The findings of the model show that insufficient attention to the transparency of the structure of the oil industry in terms of power and the use of intellectual and human capital in dimensions of value and motivation of staff in cosmetic aspects have caused damage to the abundance of human resources in the industry. Conclusion: The application of hybrid policies in the three sub-systems of value, strength, and beauty were selected as the best way to improve the productivity of human resources in the petroleum industry. It was shown that plans for increasing intellectual and human capital, structural transparency in the oil industry, and the incentivizing systems of workers have significant effects on increasing the value of human resources and improving its productivity in the oil industry.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>309</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>338</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مهرگان</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mehregan</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد، گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد، گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکده مدیریت،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mehregan@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهناز</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حسین زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Mahnaz</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hosseinzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکده مدیریت،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mhosseinzadeh@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نیما</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ربیعی سروندی</Family>
						<NameE>Nima</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rabie Servandi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>انشجوی دکتری، گروه مدیریت تحقیق در عملیات، گروه مدیریت صنعتی، پردیس کیش، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>انشجوی دکتری، گروه مدیریت تحقیق در عملیات،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>rabiee@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آشفتگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بهره‌وری منابع انسانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نگرش سیستمی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پویایی سیستم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>آذرمند، حمید (1395). سوءتفاهمی به نام بهره‌وری در برنامه‌های پنج‌ساله. تهران: روزنامه دنیای اقتصاد.##ابطحی، حسین، کاظمی، بابک (1379). بهره‎وری. تهران: مؤسسه مطالعات و پژوهش‌های بازرگانی.##ابوالعلائی، بهزاد (1395). مدیریت عملکرد: راهنمای مدیران برای ارزیابی و بهبود عملکرد کارکنان. تهران: انتشارات سازمان مدیریت صنعتی.##افتخار، سید فراز (1394). مدیریت استعداد در صنعت نفت و گاز. کنفرانس مدیریت و اقتصاد در قرن 21. تهران: انجمن اقتصاد انرژی.##امینی، علیرضا؛ فرهادی کیا، علیرضا (1390). ارزیابی تحولات شاخص‎های بهره‌وری در بخش نفت و توصیه‌هایی برای بهبود بهره‌وری در برنامه پنجم توسعه. وزارت نفت. شماره 1.##ایکاف، راسل (1375). برنامه‎ریزی تعاملی، مدیریت هماهنگ با تحول برای ساختن آینده سازمان. (مترجم خلیلی شورینی)، تهران: نشر مرکز.##جکسون، م. (1391). تفکر سیستمی کل‌گرایی خلاق برای مدیران: رویکردهای سیستمی، نقد و بررسی آنها کاربردشان. (مترجم: ناصر شریعتی)، تهران: انتشارات سازمان مدیریت صنعتی.##خاکی، غلامرضا (1380). ارزش ‌افزوده، تهران: مؤسسه مطالعات و بهره‌وری.## رعنایی کردشولی، حبیب‌الله، غفارنیا، احمد (1395). اندازه‌گیری بهره‌وری منابع انسانی در شرکت ملی نفت ایران (مطالعهموردی: شرکت پایانه‌های نفتی ایران). فصل‌نامه مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، 4(13)، 9-32.##سازمان برنامه‌وبودجه (1397) بخش‌نامه بودجه سال 1398 کل کشور. تهران: سازمان برنامه‌وبودجه کشور، مرکز اسناد، مدارک و انتشارات.##سازمان بهره‌وری آسیایی (2018). گزارش سالیانه بهره‌وری آسیایی،دانشگاه کیو، ژاپن، توکیو.##سازمان ملی بهره‌وری ایران (1397). گزارش شاخص‌های بهره‌وری کشور 1384-1396. تهران: سازمان ملی بهره‌وری.##شجاعی، سید سعید؛ جمالی، غلامرضا؛ منطقی، نیکزاد (1395)، تابستان. شناسایی عوامل مؤثر بر بهره‌وری، تهران، ایران، فصل‌نامه پژوهش‌های مدیریت منابع انسانی (2)8، 161-181.##طاهری، شهنام (1387). بهره‌وری و تجزیه ‌و تحلیل آن در سازمان (جلد 6). تهران: نشر هستان.##طیبی، محمدرضا؛ واهبی، آرزو؛ نور نژاد، وحید (1397). بررسی رابطه فکری و بهره‌وری در صنایع تولیدی ایران. فصل‌نامه مدیریت بهره‌وری، 12(4)، 37- 59.##علی پور، لزیم؛ سبحان الهی، محمدعلی؛ غنبر طهرانی، نسیم؛ یوسفی نژاد، وحید (1394). بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر بهره‌وری نیروی انسانی و تأثیر آن بر پیشرفت پروژه با استفاده از رویکرد پویایی‌شناسی سیستم‌ها مطالعه موردی: شرکت تولید، بهره‌برداری و تعمیرات سد و نیروگاه شهید عباسپور. کنفرانس بین‌المللی دست‌آوردهای نوین پژوهشی مدیریت حسابداری اقتصاد.##قراجه داغی، جمشید (1394). تفکر سیستمی: مدیریت آشفتگی و پیچیدگی پلتفرمی برای معماری کسب‌وکار (نسخه 3). مترجم: خلیلی شورینی. تهران: انتشارات سازمان مدیریت صنعتی.##قلی‎پور، رحمت‎اله (1392). چالش‌های نظام اداری: بررسی موردی ایران (جلد 3). تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه تهران.##کیانی، ندا؛ رادفر، رضا (1394).شناسایی و رتبه‌بندی عوامل مؤثر بر بهره‌وری سازمان با استفاده از مدل دیماتل. فصل‌نامه مدیریت بهره‌وری، 9 (35)، 111-130.##کینی، رالف (1381). تفکر ارزشی راهی به‌سوی تصمیم‌گیری خلاق. (مترجم: عقیل ملکی فر).تهران: چاپ نگارش.##محسـنی، علیرضـا؛ زنجـانی، حبیب‌الله و طالقـانی، متـین (1391). بیگـانگی از کـار و تأثیر آن بر بهره‌وری نیروی کار. ماه‌نامه مهندسی مدیریت، 5(87)، 47- 81.##محمدی زاده، محمد حسین؛ صادقیه، احمد؛ مصطفایی پور، علی (1392). مدل‌سازی بهره‌وری نیروی انسانی در صنعت نفت با رویکرد پویایی‌شناسی سیستم. دومین کنفرانس ملی مهندسی صنایع و سیستم‌ها. تهران.##محمودی، زیرار؛ صیادی، احمد رضا؛ رجب‎زاده قطری، علی (1395). ارائه مدل پویایی ارزیابی بهره‌وری نیروی کار معادن مطالعه موردی: مجتمع معدنی و صنعتی چادرملو. مدیریت صنعتی، 8 (2)، 287-308.##مشایخی، علینقی (1397). تفکر سیستمی در طول زمان. تهران: آریانا قلم.##مشایخی، علینقی (1397). پویاشناسی سیستم‌ها. تهران: آریانا قلم.##مهرگان، محمد رضا؛ حسین زاده، مهناز (1395). مبانی نظری تحقیق در عملیات. تهران: نشر کتاب دانشگاهی.##نژاد ایرانی، فرهاد؛ دادجویان، علی‌رضا (1397).بررسی تأثیر ارزش‌آفرینی استراتژیک سرمایه انسانی بر بهره‌وری نیروی انسانی. فصل‌نامه مدیریت بهره‌وری، 12(4)، 235-269.##وزارت نفت. (1379). چالش‌های توسعه در صنعت نفت ایران. گزیده مقالات مطبوعات. تهران: چاپ سحاب.##هیوز، آون (1397). مدیریت دولتی نوین. (مترجمان: الوانی، سید مهدی، خلیلی شورینی، سهراب و معمار زاده، غلامرضا). تهران: انتشارات مروارید.##References##Abolalaee, B. (2017). Performance Management: A guide for managers to evaluate and improve employee performance. Tehran:Industrial Managment Organization press. (in Persian)##Abtahie, H., Kazemie, B. (2000). Productivity.Tehran: Institute for Trade Studies and Research press. (in Persian)##Ackoff, R. (1996). Interactive planning, coordinated management with transformation to build the organization&#039;s future. (S. Khalilie Shavarinie, Trans.) Teharan: Markaz press.##(in Persian)##Alipour, L., Sobhan ellahie, M. A., Ghanbar Tehranie, N. &amp; Yousefie Neghad, V. (2015). Investigating Factors Affecting Human Resource Efficiency and Its Impact on Project Progress Using the Dynamic Systems Approach Case Study: Abbaspour Power Plant. International Conference on New Achievements in Management Research and Accounting and Economics. Tehran. (in Persian)##Aminie, A., Farhadie kia, A. (2012). Evaluating changes in productivity indicators in the oil sector and recommendations for improving productivity in the fifth development plan. NIOC. Tehran: nioc press. (in Persian)##APO Productivity Data Book (2018). Productivity. Japan, Tokyo: Keio University Press.##Azaramand, H. (2016). Misunderstanding of productivity in the five-year plan, Tehran: Donyaye Eghtesad newspaper. (in Persian)##Eftekhar, S. (2016). Talent Management in Oil and Gas Industry. Management and Economics in the 21st Century. Tehran: Association of Energy Economics. (in Persian)##Gharajedaghi, J. (2011). System Thinking: Managing chaos and comlexity platform for designing business atchitecture. (S. Khalili Shavarinie, Trans.) Tehran: industrial management organization press. (in Persian)##Gharjedaghi, J. (1986). A prologue to national development planning. New port, CT; Greenwood press.##Gholipour, R. (2013). Challenges of the administrative system of Iran case study. Tehran: Tehran University press. (in Persian)##Hughes, O. E. (2018). Newly Managed Public Administration: A Strategic Approach to the Thoughts, Concepts and Theories. (Alvanie, Khalili Shavarinie, Memarian, Trans). Tehran: Morvared Press. (in Persian)##Iran Oil Industry (2018). Challenges for development in the Iranian oil industry. Selection of press articles. Tehran: Sahab press. (in Persian)##Jackson, M. (2003). System Thinking: Creative holism for managers (4th ed). (T. Naser Shariatie; Trans.) Tehran: Industrial Managment Organization. (in Persian)##Kazaz, A., Ulubeyl, S., Acicara, T. &amp; ER, B. (2016).Factors Affecting Labor Productivity. Procedia Engineering, 164, 28-34.##Keeney, R. (1992). Value-Focused Thinking: A Path to Creative Decision making. (A. Malekifard, Ed.). Tehran: Harvard University Press. (Karaneh elm Press Iran).##(in Persian)##Khakiie, GH. (2001). Value Added. Tehran: Institute Of Studies and Productivity Press.##(in Persian)##Kianie, N. &amp; Radfar, R. (2016). Identification and ranking of factors affecting organizational productivity using the Demettel model. Quarterly Journal of Productivity Management, 9 (35), 111-130. (in Persian)##Kinfemichael, M. B. (2019). Convergence of labor productivity across the US states. Economic Modelling, 76, 270-280.##Karimie Shahabie, A., Memarzadeh, A., Alvanie, S.A., Modirie, M. (2014). Designing a Productivity Model in Government Organizations. Quarterly Journal of Productivity Management, 10, 37 7-27. ##Mahmoodie, Z. &amp; Sayadie, A., Ghatarie, A. (2016). Presentation of Dynamic Mine Productivity Assessment (Case Study: Chador Malu Industrial Complex). Industrial Management Press, 8(12), 287-308. (in Persian)##Mashaekhie, A. (2018). System thinking over time. Tehran: Ariana Ghalam. (in Persian)##Mashayehkie, A. (2018). System thinking during the year. Tehran: aryana ghalam press.##(in Persian)##Mehrgan, M. &amp; Hoseinzadeh, M. (2017). Theoretical Basics of Operational Research (Vol. 1). Tehran:University Book Press. (in Persian)##Mohammad Zadeh, M., Sadeghieh, A. &amp; Mostafaei Pour, A. (2013). Modeling the productivity of manpower in the oil industry with the system dynamics approach. Second National Conference on Industrial Engineering and Systems. (in Persian)##Mohsenie, A., Zanjanie, H., Taleghanie, M. (2012). The alienation of work and its confirmation of labor productivity, Management Engineering Monthly, 5(87)47-81 (in Persian)##Nasirzadeh, F. &amp; Nojedehi, P. (2013). Dynamic modeling of labor productivity in construction projects. International Journal of Project Management, 31, 903-911.##National Iranian Productivity Organization. (2018). Country Productivity Indicators Report. Tehran: National Iranian Productivity Organization. (in Persian)##Nejad Eranie, F. Dadjoyan, A. (2018). Investigating the Effect of Strategic Human Capital Markets on Labor Productivity. Quarterly Journal of Productivity Management,12(47), 235-269. (in Persian)##Organization, Planning and Budget (2018). General Budget. Tehran: Organization, Planning and Budget.##Ranaiee Kord sholie, H., Ghafarnia, A. (2016). Measurement of Human Resources Productivity at National Iranian Oil Company (Case Study: Iranian Oil Terminals Company). Quarterly Journal of Human Resource Management in Oil Industry, 4(13), 9-32.##(in Persian)##Shojaee, S. S., Jamalie, Gh., Manteghie, N. (2015). Identify Effective Factors on Productivity. Quarterly journal of human resource management research, 2(8), 161-181. (in Persian)##Solminihac, H. D. (2017). Copper Mining Productivity: Lessons from Chile. Journal of Policy Modeling, 40(1), 182-193.##Taebiee, M.R., Vahebie, A., Noor Nejad, V. (2018). Investigating the Relationship Between Intellectual Capital and Productivity in Iran&#039;s Manufacturing Industries. Quarterly Journal of Productivity Managemen, 12(4), 37-59. (in Persian)##Taheri, Sh. (2008). Productivity Analysis Organization. Tehran: Hastan press. (in Persian)##Yépez, C. (2017). Financial conditions and labor productivity over the business cycle. Economics Letters, 150, 34-38.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر رفتارهای مخرب نظارتی بر تسهیم دانش با توجه به نقش میانجی خستگی عاطفی و نقش تعدیلی عدالت سازمانی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Effect of Destructive Supervisory Behaviors on Knowledge Sharing on the Role of Mediator of Emotional Exhaustion and the Moderating Role of Organizational Justice</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: هدف از اجرای این پژوهش بررسی تأثیر رفتارهای مخرب نظارتی بر تسهیم دانش با توجه به نقش میانجی خستگی عاطفی و نقش تعدیلی عدالت سازمانی در میان کارکنان شرکت برق در شهرستان مشهد است. روش: پژوهش پیش­ رو از نظر هدف کاربردی و از نظر ماهیت و روش، از نوع پژوهش‌های توصیفی ـ پیمایشی است. جامعه آماری این پژوهش، کارکنان شرکت برق شهرستان مشهد هستند. با استفاده از روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی ساده، پرسش‌نامه‌های استانداردی بین 150 نفر از کارکنان توزیع شد. روایی و پایایی پرسش‌نامه‌ها به‌ترتیب از طریق تحلیل عاملی تأییدی و ضریب آلفای کرونباخ به تأیید رسید و به‌منظور تحلیل داده‌ها از مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری و نرم‌افزار اسمارت پی.ال.اس استفاده شد. یافته‌ها: نتایج پژوهش نشان داد، رفتارهای مخرب نظارتی بر خستگی عاطفی اثر مثبت (537/10 = t) و بر تسهیم دانش اثری منفی (164/4= t) دارد و خستگی عاطفی نیز بر تسهیم دانش اثر منفی (202/3 = t) می‎گذاد. همچنین یافته‌های پژوهش حاکی از آن بود که خستگی عاطفی تأثیر رفتارهای مخرب نظارتی بر تسهیم دانش را میانجی‌گری می‌کند (059/3= z) و علاوه بر این نیز، عدالت سازمانی تأثیر رفتار مخرب نظارتی بر تسهیم دانش را تعدیل می‌کند (231/2= t). نتیجه‌گیری: نتایج این پژوهش بر این موضوع تأکید می‎کند که بسیاری از شرکت‎ها همواره سیاست‌ها و رویه‌هایی برای الهام‌بخشیدن به کارکنان به‌منظور به اشتراک‌گذاشتن دانش داشته‌اند، برای مثال از طریق توسعه فرهنگ اشتراک دانش یا اقدامات سخت‌افزاری مدیریت دانش، اما تا زمانی که رفتارهای نظارتی سرپرست، مخرب و نا‎صحیح باشد، این رویه‌ها و سیاست‌ها به نتیجه نخواهد رسید. بنابراین سازمان‌ها باید از اهمیت و عواقب مضر رفتارهای نظارتی مخرب که می‎تواند کارکنان را از ایجاد روابط با کیفیت با سرپرستان و به اشتراک گذاشتن دانش منع کند، آگاه باشند و همواره علت بروز این رفتارها را از سوی سرپرستان پیگیری کنند و با اجرای پیشنهادهایی که در این پژوهش به آن‎ها اشاره شده است، به تسهیم دانش کمک کنند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective:To investigate the effect of supervisory destructive behaviors on knowledge sharing concerning the mediating role of emotional exhaustion and the moderating role of organizational justice among the employees of the power company in Mashhad. Methods: The following research is a descriptive-survey methodologically and applied research in terms of purpose. The statistical population of this research was the 150 employees of the Mashhad city power company who were selected by simple random sampling method. To collect the data, a questionnaire was used and SPSS and Smart-PLS were used to analyze the information for testing hypotheses. Results: Supervisory destructive behaviors have a positive effect on emotional exhaustion (t=10.357) and negative effect on knowledge sharing (t=4.164) and emotional exhaustion on knowledge sharing (t=3.202). It has also been found that emotional exhaustion mediates the effect of supervisory destructive behaviors on knowledge sharing (z=3.059) and organizational justice moderates the effect of supervisory destructive behaviors on knowledge sharing (T=2.231). Conclusion: The results of this research emphasize that although many companies always have policies and procedures to inspire employees to share knowledge, for example, through developing a knowledge-sharing culture or knowledge management tools, all of these procedures and policies will fail as long as supervisory behavior is destructive and inaccurate. Therefore, organizations should be aware of the importance and consequences of destructive supervisory behaviors that can prevent employees from establishing quality relationships with supervisors and sharing knowledge.  </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>339</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>354</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عطیه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سبزی</Family>
						<NameE>Atieh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sabzi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، آموزش عالی عطار، مشهد، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، آموزش</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sabziatieh@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>یوسف</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رمضانی</Family>
						<NameE>Usef</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ramezani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه مدیریت، آموزش عالی عطار، مشهد، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه مدیریت، آموزش عالی عطار، مشهد،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>usef_ramzini@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عاطفه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سجاد</Family>
						<NameE>Atefeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>sajjad</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه خوارزمی تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>atefeh.sajjad@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تسهیم دانش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خستگی عاطفی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رفتارهای مخرب نظارتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عدالت سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>اندکازلکی، مهری (1390). رابطه عدالت سازمانی با ابهام و تعارض نقش و فرسودگی شغلی کارکنان بیمارستان‌های اهواز. پایان­نامه کارشناسی ارشد گرایش صنعتی و سازمانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، دانشکده علوم تربیتی ـ گروه روان‌شناسی، واحد مرودشت.##گل‌پرور، محسن؛ کرمی، مهرانگیز؛ جوادیان، زهرا (1390). بی‌عدالتی سازمانی ادراک‌شده و رفتارهای مخرب، رویکرد شناخت مرجع. پژوهش‌های روان‌شناسی اجتماعی، 1(2)، 44- 67.  ##مرزوقی، رحمت اله؛ حیدری، الهام (1394). سنجش روابط علی تخطی نظارتی، ادراک از عدالت سازمانی و رفتار تسهیم دانش (مطالعه موردی کارکنان دانشگاه علوم پزشکی شیراز)، فصل‌نامه مدیریت سلامت، 19(64)، 107-126.##مشیری، کیوان؛ آقایی، نجف؛ پورسلطانی زرندی، حسین؛ قربانی، مهدی (1391). ارتباط بین عدالت سازمانی ادراک‌شده با فرسودگی شغلی و تمایل به ترک خدمت کارکنان اداره کل ورزش و جوانان استان تهران، فصل‌نامه پژوهش در مدیریت ورزشی و رفتار حرکتی، 4(7)، 65- 77.  ##هومن، حیدرعلی (1393). مدل­یابی معادلات ساختاری با کاربرد نرم­افزار لیزرل (با اصلاحات). (چاپ ششم)، تهران: انتشارات سمت.##References##Almeida, M.V., Soares, A.L. (2014). Knowledge sharing in project-based organizations: Overcoming the informational limbo. International Journal of Information Management, 34(6), 770 – 779.##Andkazolki, M. (2011). The relationship of organizational justice with ambiguity and conflict of role and burnout among Ahwaz hospitals staff. M.A. Thesis, industrial and organizational field, Islamic Azad University, Faculty of Educative Sciences - Department of Psychology, Marvdasht. (in Persian)##Arechaederra, D. P., Briones, E., Lind, A., Ortiz, L. G. (2014). Perceived organizational justice in care services: creation and multi-sample validation of a measure. Social Science &amp; Medicine, 102, 26-32.##Aryee, S., Sun, L. Y., Chen, Z. X., &amp; Debrah, Y. A. (2008). Abusive supervision and contextual performance: The mediating role of emotional exhaustion and the moderating role of work unit structure. Management and Organization Review, 4(3), 393-411.##Cabrera, A., Collins, W. C., &amp; Salgado, J. F. (2006). Determinants of individual engagement in knowledge sharing. International Journal of Human Resource Management, 17(2), 245–264.##Cole, M. S., Bernerth, J. B., Walter, F., &amp; Holt, D. T. (2010). Organizational justice and individuals&#039; withdrawal: Unlocking the influence of emotional exhaustion. Journal of Management Studies, 47(3), 367–390.##Colquitt, J. A. (2001). On the dimensionality of organizational justice: A construct validation of a measure. Journal of Applied Psychology, 86(3), 356–400.##Fried, A. L., &amp; Fisher, C. B. (2016). Moral stress and job burnout among frontline staff conducting clinical research on affective and anxiety disorders. Professional Psychology: Research and Practice, 47(3), 171-180.##Godden, J. (2012). BASW/CoSW England research on supervision in social work, with particular reference to supervision practice in multidisciplinary teams: England Document. Birmingham: BASW/CoSW.##Golparvar, M., Karami, M., &amp; Javadian, Z. (2011). Perceived organizational injustice and malicious behaviors, reference recognition approach. Journal of Social Psychology Research, 1 (2), 21-32. (in Persian)##Harris, K. J., Kacmar, K. M., &amp; Zivnuska, S. (2007). An investigation of abusive supervision as a predictor of performance and the meaning of work as a moderator of the relationship. The Leadership Quarterly, 18(3), 252–263.##Kim, S. L., Lee, S., Park, E., &amp; Yun, S. (2015). Knowledge sharing, work–family conflict and supervisor support: Investigating a three-way effect. The International Journal of Human Resource Management, 26(19), 2434–2452.##Lavelle, J. J., Rupp, D. E., &amp; Brockner, J. (2007). Taking a multifoci approach to the study of justice, social exchange, and citizenship behavior: The target similarity model. Journal of Management, 33(6), 841–866.##Lee, S., Kim, S.L., Yun, S. (2017). A moderated mediation model of the relationship between abusive supervision and knowledge sharing. The Leadership Quarterly, Available online 12 September 2017.##Marzoughi, R.A. &amp; Heydari, E. (2015). Evaluating the cause and effect relationships of regulatory oversight, perception of organizational justice and knowledge sharing behavior (case study of Shiraz University of Medical Sciences). Quarterly Journal of Health Management, 19(64), 102-114 (in Persian)##Maslach, C., &amp; Jackson, S. E. (1981). The measurement of experienced burnout. Journal of Occupational Behavior, 2, 99–113.##Maslach, C., Schaufeli, W. B., &amp; Leiter, M. P. (2001). Job burnout. Annual Review of Psychology, 52(1), 397–422.##Moshiri, K., Aghaee, N., Poursoltani Zarandi, H. &amp; Ghorbani, M. (2012). Relationship between perceived organizational justice with job burnout and the desire to quit staff of the general administration of sports and youth of Tehran province. Quarterly journal of research in sports management and motor behavior, 7(23), 65-77 (in Persian)##Nesheim, T., Gressgård, L. J. (2014). Knowledge sharing in a complex organization: Antecedents and safety Effects. Safety Science, 62(4), 28– 36.##Schepers, P., &amp; Van den Berg, P. T. (2007). Social factors of work-environment creativity. Journal of Business and Psychology, 21(3), 407–428.##Srivastava, A., Bartol, K. M., &amp; Locke, E. A. (2006). Empowering leadership in management teams: Effects on knowledge sharing, efficacy, and performance. Academy of Management Journal, 49(6), 1239–1251.##Tepper, B. J. (2000). Consequences of abusive supervision. Academy of Management Journal, 43(2), 178–190.##Tepper, B. J. (2007), Abusive supervision in work organizations: Review, synthesis, and directions for future research. Journal ofManagement, 33(3), 261–289.##Tepper, B. J., Moss, S. E., &amp; Duffy, M. K. (2011). Predictors of abusive supervision: Supervisor perceptions of deep-level dissimilarity, relationship conflict, and subordinate performance. Academy of Management Journal, 54(2), 279–294##Wang, S., &amp; Noe, R. A. (2010). Knowledge sharing: A review and directions for future research. Human Resource Management Review, 20(2), 115–131.##Wu, T. Y., &amp; Hu, C. (2009). Abusive supervision and employee emotional exhaustion dispositional antecedents and boundaries. Group &amp; Organization Management, 34(2), 143–169.##Xu, A. J., Loi, R., &amp; Ngo, H. Y. (2016). Ethical leadership behavior and employee justice perceptions: The mediating role of trust in organization. Journal of BusinessEthics, 134(3), 493–504.##Yagil, D. (2006). The relationship of abusive and supportive workplace supervision to employee burnout and upward influence tactics. Journal of Emotional Abuse, 6(1), 49–65.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				