<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An Investigation of Organizational Ambidexterity dominant element in the scientific and technological organizations (Case study: ICECR)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی مدل چیره‎دستی در سازمان‎های علمی و فناورانه بر مبنای نظریه‌پردازی داده‌بنیاد (مطالعۀ موردی: جهاد دانشگاهی)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>33</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>54</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">57501</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2016.57501</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>پورعابدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار مدیریت منابع انسانی، جهاد دانشگاهی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study aims to achieve a theory in the field of organizational ambidexterity and has been done to better understand this phenomenon in scientific and technological organizations. The research Method is based on qualitative Study and relying on Grounded Theory, in Data collection unstructured and semi-structured research interviews was used and for Data Analysis paradigm model Clarified by Strauss and Corbin was applied. By Using Theoretical Sampling and using sampling techniques targeted (Purposive) Sampling and application of Snowball (chain) and Purposive Sampling was carried out on the basis of 16 interviews with administrators, faculty and Academic Experts of ACECR Which were Experienced in the field of Exploitation and Exploration and are Expert in both Fields. Analysis of Interview Data in The Process of Open Coding, Axial Coding and Selective Coding emerged in a theory in the field of ambidexterity in which architecture of Ambidexterity based on Committed Intelligence, Engineering Exploration and Technology-Based Exploration were Selected as Main Concepts Orienting to Ambidextrous</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر با هدف دستیابی به نظریه­ای در حوزۀ چیره‎دستی سازمانی به‎منظور درک بهتر این پدیده در سازمان‎های علمی و فناورانه اجرا شده است. روش تحقیق به‎صورت کیفی و مبتنی بر نظریه­پردازی داده­بنیاد است. برای گردآوری اطلاعات از مصاحبه‎های نیمه‎ساختاریافته استفاده شد و تجزیه‎وتحلیل اطلاعات به روش اشتراس و کوربین و مدل پارادایمی انجام گرفت. نمونه­گیری به روش نمونه‎گیری نظری بود و با بهره‎مندی از تکنیک‎های هدفمند (قضاوتی) و گلوله برفی (زنجیره‎ای) انجام شد که بر مبنای آن 16 مصاحبه با مدیران، اعضای هیئت علمی و خبرگان جهاد دانشگاهی که در هر دو حوزۀ پژوهش و بهره‎برداری تجربه و تخصص داشتند، صورت گرفت. نتایج تحلیل داده‎های به‎دست‎آمده از مصاحبه­ها طی فرایند کدگذاری باز، محوری و انتخابی، به ایجاد نظریۀ داده­بنیاد در حوزۀ چیره‎دستی برای سازمان‎های علمی و فناورانه منجر شد که بر مبنای آن معماری فرآیند‎هایی چیره‎دستی مبتنی بر بهره‎گیری از هوشمندی متعهدانه در کنار مهندسی پژوهش و بهره‎برداری فناورانه، به‎عنوان مفاهیم اساسی دستیابی به چیره‎دستی معرفی شدند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">چیره‎دستی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازمان‎های علمی و فناورانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظریه‎پردازی داده‎بنیاد</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_57501_c930c8cb00de3e4535e4e587e5e9a893.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
