<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>6</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The study of the influence of sacred ethical values on decision making, decision difficulty and the related emotions (Case study: in faculty of humanities of university of Guilan)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر ارزش‌های مقدس اخلاقی بر تصمیم‌گیری، دشواری تصمیم و احساسات ناشی از تصمیم‏گیری 
(مطالعه‌ی موردی: در دانشکده علوم انسانی دانشگاه گیلان)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>93</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>202</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">22431</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد رحیم</FirstName>
					<LastName>رمضانیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت دانشگاه گیلان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>صادقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه علوم تربیتی دانشگاه</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>پورجهانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت صنعتی دانشگاه</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The concept of decision making, factors influencing it and the related outcomes have always attracted researchers. The purpose of this study is to investigate the effect of sacred values on decision making, decision difficulty and the resulting negative emotions. Thus, a sample of 288 students from the University of Guilan were chosen as subjects and were required to complete a standard questionnaire in order to assess these concepts. This questionnaire contained three trade-offs: tragic (two conflicting sacred values), taboo (a sacred value against a secular value) and routine (two conflicting secular values). The independent variables of this study are sacred values and the types of trade-off and the dependent variables include negative emotions and decision difficulty. As expected, the subjects regarded the tragic trade-off as more difficult than the other two trade-offs and more negatively emotion-laden as well. But contrary to expectations, the subjects did not consider the taboo trade-off to be easier than the routine one. Moreover, in some cases the female students considered the situations to be more difficult and more negatively emotion-laden. The results support the belief that sacred values influence decision making and the resultant issues.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مقوله تصمیم‏گیری، عوامل تأثیر گذار بر آن و نتایج حاصل از اتخاذ تصمیم همواره مورد علاقه پژوهشگران بوده است. هدف این پژوهش، شناسایی تأثیر ارزش‌های اخلاقی بر تصمیم‏گیری، دشواری تصمیم و احساسات منفی ناشی از آن است. بر این اساس تعداد 288 نفر از دانشجویان دانشگاه گیلان به‌عنوان نمونه انتخاب و پرسشنامه استانداردی جهت سنجش این مقولات به آن‌ها داده شد. این پرسشنامه شامل سه بده بستان تراژیک (دو ارزش اخلاقی در مقابل هم)، تابو (یک ارزش اخلاقی در مقابل یک ارزش دنیوی) و عادی (دو ارزش دنیوی در مقابل هم) است. متغیرهای مستقل تحقیق، ارزش‌های اخلاقی و نوع بده بستان و متغیرهای وابسته، احساسات منفی و دشواری تصمیم هستند. همان‌طور که انتظار می‌رفت، پاسخگویان بده بستان تراژیک را نسبت به دو بده بستان دیگر دشوارتر و حاوی احساسات منفی بیشتر درک کرده‌اند. اما بر خلاف انتظار، پاسخگویان بده بستان تابو را نسبت به بده بستان عادی آسان‌تر درک نکرده‌اند. همچنین دانشجویان دختر نسبت به دانشجویان پسر در برخی موارد موقعیت‌ها را دشوارتر و حاوی احساسات منفی بیشتر دانسته‌اند. نتایج، این عقیده را پشتیبانی می‌کند که ارزش‌های اخلاقی بر تصمیم‏گیری و مقوله‌های منتج از آن تأثیرگذار است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">احساسات منفی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزش‌های مقدس اخلاقی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تصمیم‏گیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دشواری تصمیم</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_22431_2606b4a114de558f30490171283d22b4.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
