<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Surveying the Role of Social Media on Citizens&#039; Participation in the Participatory Budgeting Process</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی نقش رسانه‌های اجتماعی بر مشارکت شهروندان در فرایند بودجه‌بندی مشارکتی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>355</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>376</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">71835</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2019.271465.2446</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سمیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>پورحسن</LastName>
<Affiliation>مربی، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشکده مدیریت، اقتصاد و حسابداری، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اسفندیار</FirstName>
					<LastName>فرجوند</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت، اقتصاد و حسابداری، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt; Citizens’ awareness and participation play a significant role in the improvement of public affairs’ administration and the quality of governmental decisions and policies. The present research aims to explore and theorize the citizens’ participation in the budgeting process. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt; 18 theoreticians and researchers in the fields of political sciences, social sciences and public administration participated in this grounded-theory based qualitative research. They were selected based on the purposive and snowball sampling methods. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt; The results of the data analysis showed that political awareness of citizens includes cyber political awareness, political empowerment of citizens, knowledge of using cyber networks, familiarity with political tools, citizens’ awareness of political presence on cyber networks, citizens’ cyber activities in parties, and debating on cyber social networks. Furthermore, political/local awareness of citizens includes citizen’s awareness of local priorities, citizens’ awareness of local expenditure, citizens’ awareness of local problems, and knowledge about local investment that are all  emerged within the framework of citizens’ cyber participation. Moreover, political participation of citizens involves their budget participation and political/cyber participation. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt; Owing to the necessity of social interactions of citizens on the cyberspaces, local and indigenous social networks should be developed in Iran in order to reinforce the interactions among the citizens and such networks should be supported by the relevant practitioners and organizations accordingly.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;هدف:&lt;/strong&gt; آگاهی و مشارکت شهروندان در بهبود اداره امور عمومی و ارتقای کیفیت تصمیم‌ها و سیاست‌های دولت نقش شایان توجهی دارد. در پژوهش حاضر تلاش شده است، مشارکت شهروندان در حوزه بودجه‌ریزی از لحاظ نظری بررسی شود.&lt;br /&gt; روش: این پژوهش از نوع کیفی و مبتنی بر رویکرد نظریه‌پردازی داده بنیاد است. در این پژوهش 18 نفر از صاحب‌نظران و محققان حوزه‌های علوم سیاسی، اجتماعی و مدیریت دولتی مشارک کردند که به روش نمونه‌گیری هدفمند و گلوله برفی انتخاب شدند.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;یافته‌ها&lt;/strong&gt;: نتایج تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها نشان داد که آگاهی سیاسی شهروندان، عبارت‌اند از: آگاهی سیاسی مجازی، توانمندی سیاسی شهروندان، دانش استفاده از شبکه‌های مجازی، آشنایی با ابزارهای سیاسی، آگاهی شهروندان از حضور سیاسی در شبکه‌های مجازی، فعالیت‌های مجازی شهروندان در احزاب و تبادل نظر در شبکه‌های اجتماعی مجازی. همچنین آگاهی سیاسی/ محلی شهروندان عبارت‌اند از: آگاهی شهروندان از اولویت‌های محلی، آگاهی شهروندان از هزینه‌های محلی، آگاهی شهروندان از مشکلات محلی، آگاهی از سرمایه‌گذاری‌های محلی و... که در قالب مقوله محوری مشارکت مجازی شهروندان پدیدار شده است. همچنین مشارکت سیاسی شهروندان شامل مشارکت بودجه‌ای شهروندان و مشارکت سیاسی/ مجازی شهروندان است.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;نتیجه‌گیری&lt;/strong&gt;: با توجه به ضرورت تعاملات اجتماعی شهروندان در فضای مجازی، باید به‌منظور تقویت تعامل میان شهروندان، راه‌اندازی شبکه‌های اجتماعی بومی در کشور در دستور کار قرار گیرد و از سوی دست‌اندرکاران و سازمان‌های مربوطه حمایت شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رسانه‌های اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرایند بودجه‌بندی مشارکتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشارکت شهروندان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_71835_3123d7525c87af6726aadfd12b62f407.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Classification of Governance Features through Policy Networks Using Meta-synthesis Method</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طبقه‌بندی ویژگی‌های حکمرانی از طریق شبکه‌های خط‌‌مشی با استفاده از روش فراترکیب</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>377</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>402</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">72149</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2019.284439.2581</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهره</FirstName>
					<LastName>کریم میان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید سپهر</FirstName>
					<LastName>قاضی نوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، گروه مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات، دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدمهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>ذوالفقار زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>30</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt; From the perspective of governance, the concept of “policy network” focuses on inter-organizational relations, structures, processes, and interactions that policy-making process takes place through them.  In public policy literature, this approach to policy networks is based on studying governance through policy networks. This article, provides a comprehensive classification of the features of this type of governance using meta-synthesis method. The purpose of this paper is to identify and classify governance features through policy networks. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt; In this study, 468 related articles and researches conducted between 1970 and 2018 were selected from the Web of Science citation index. Finally, 55 articles were evaluated for the purpose of the study using the meta-synthesis method and selection criteria. This research is qualitative and is conducted within the interpretive paradigm with the aim of exploring the features of governance through policy networks. This is an applied research in terms of purpose. It is also a cross-sectional study in terms of data collection. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt; The features of this kind of governance (Governance trough Policy Networks) can be divided into four general categories of &quot;promoting coordination, coherence and integration&quot;, &quot;strengthening communications, building trust and increasing participation&quot;, &quot;policy learning improvement&quot;, and &quot;facilitating policy implementation&quot;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt; It is concluded that the researchers have conducted more studies regarding the two aspects of &quot;promoting coordination, coherence and integration&quot;, &quot;strengthening communications, building trust and increasing participation&quot;. Considering the importance of policy learning and policy implementation issues, future research can pay more attention to the two dimensions of &quot;policy learning improvement&quot;, and &quot;facilitating policy implementation&quot;. And finally, the findings of this study can be used to apply new approaches for improving governance in various policy areas.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;هدف:&lt;/strong&gt; این مقاله با بهره‌گیری از روش فراترکیب، به‌دنبال ارائه دسته‌بندی جامعی از ویژگی‌های حکمرانی در مطالعات این حوزه است.&lt;br /&gt; روش: روش فراترکیب، انتخاب 468 مقاله و پژوهش مرتبط در سال‌های 1970 تا 2018 از نمایه استنادی Web of Science است که با به‌کارگیری این روش در نهایت 55 مقاله نهایی مبنای استخراج یافته‌ها قرار گرفتند. این پژوهش، کیفی بوده و در پارادایم تفسیرگرایی با هدف اکتشاف ویژگی‌های حکمرانی از طریق شبکه‌های خط‌مشی انجام شده و از دیدگاه هدف، پژوهشی کاربردی است. همچنین جمع‌آوری داده‌ها از نظر زمان پژوهشی مقطعی است.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;یافته‌ها&lt;/strong&gt;: ویژگی‌های این رویکرد جدید به حکمرانی (حکمرانی از طریق شبکه‌های خط‌مشی) را می‌توان در چهار دسته‌ کلی «ارتقای هماهنگی، انسجام و یکپارچگی»، «تقویت ارتباطات، ایجاد اعتماد و افزایش مشارکت»، «افزایش یادگیری خط‌مشی» و «تسهیل پیاده‌سازی خط‌مشی‌ها» جای داد. همچنین هر یک از این چهار دسته، زیربخش‌هایی دارند.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;نتیجه‌گیری&lt;/strong&gt;: درباره موضوعات «ارتقای هماهنگی، انسجام و یکپارچگی» و «تقویت ارتباطات، ایجاد اعتماد و افزایش مشارکت»، محققان پژوهش‌های بیشتر و متنوع‌تری داشته‌اند و درباره موضعات «افزایش یادگیری خط‌مشی» و «تسهیل پیاده‌سازی خط‌مشی‌ها» پژوهش کمتری‌ انجام داده‌اند و ابعاد مختلف آنها دیده نشده است. بر این اساس و با توجه به اهمیت موضوعات یادگیری خط‌مشی و پیاده‌سازی خط‌مشی‌ها، پژوهش‌های آتی می‌توانند به دو بعد اخیر توجه بیشتری داشته باشند. یافته‌های این مطالعه می‌تواند برای به‌کارگیری رویکردهای جدید در راستای بهبود حکمرانی در حوزه‌های خط‌مشی مختلف مفید واقع شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شبکه خط‌مشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حکمرانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حکمرانی از طریق شبکه‌های خط‌مشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فراترکیب</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_72149_a3ba6b1ed71b62792b86bda495bbd466.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Developing a Framework to Explain the Public Policies Capture Using Thematic Analysis and Interpretive Structural Modeling (ISM)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارائه چارچوبی برای تبیین تسخیر خط‌مشی‌های عمومی با کاربست روش تحلیل مضمون و مدل‌سازی ساختاری ـ تفسیری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>403</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>430</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">72047</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2019.277891.2513</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>ابراهیمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده اقتصاد، مدیریت و علوم اداری، دانشگاه سمنان، سمنان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>عین علی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده اقتصاد، مدیریت و علوم اداری، دانشگاه سمنان، سمنان، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>12</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt;Capturing policies can be defined as the result or the process by which public decisionsover laws, regulations or policies are consistently or repeatedly directed awayfrom the public interest and towards the interests of a narrow interest group orperson, by the intent and action of this group or person. The purpose of this study is to present a framework to explain the public policies capture. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt; In this research, two methods of qualitative analysis including thematic analysis and interpretive structural modeling have been used.In thethematic analysis section of the research, all the existing contents on the public policies capture have been analyzed and carefully reviewed.In order to implement interpretive structural modeling, the views of 12 experts were received in the form of a questionnaire and the research was based on them. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt; In the first step, using theme analysis method, the thematic network of the public policies capture with 157 basic themes, 43 organizing themes and 7 global themes were extracted. In the second step, using interpretive structural modeling and paired communication, the relationships between the general themes were identified and general themes prioritized within six levels. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt; The ultimate model represents the levels of the framework of public policies capture including the factors affecting the policies capture, the substrate of policies capture, the policies capture tools, the policies capture actors, the intervening conditions in the policies capture, consequences of policies capture and preventive strategies  to policies capture. &lt;br /&gt; </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;هدف:&lt;/strong&gt; تسخیر خط‌مشی می‌تواند نتیجه یا فرایندی تعریف شود که در آن تصمیم‌های عمومی در رابطه با قوانین، مقررات و خط‌مشی‌ها، به‌واسطه اقدام‌ها و تلاش‌های یک گروه یا فرد خاص، به‌طور مداوم و مکرر از منافع عمومی دور شود و منافع آن گروه یا فرد را تأمین کند. هدف پژوهش حاضر، ارائه چارچوبی برای تبیین تسخیر خط‌مشی‌های عمومی است.&lt;br /&gt; روش: در این پژوهش، از دو روش کیفی تحلیل مضمون و مدل‌سازی ساختاری ـ تفسیری استفاده شده است. در بخش تحلیل مضمون پژوهش، کلیه متون موجود در خصوص تسخیر خط‌مشی‌های عمومی، به‌دقت تحلیل و بررسی شدند. برای اجرای روش‌شناسی مدل‌سازی ساختاری ـ تفسیری نیز، نظر 12 نفر از خبرگان در قالب پرسش‌نامه دریافت ‌شد و مبنای پژوهش قرار گرفت.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;یافته‎ها&lt;/strong&gt;: در گام نخست، با بهره‌گیری از روش تحلیل مضمون، شبکه مضامین تسخیر خط‌مشی‌های عمومی با 157 مضمون پایه، 43 مضمون سازمان‌دهنده و هفت مضمون فراگیر استخراج شد. در گام دوم نیز با بهره‌گیری از مدل‌سازی ساختاری ـ تفسیری و برقراری ارتباطات زوجی، روابط بین مضامین فراگیر کشف و در شش سطح اولویت‌بندی شدند.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;نتیجه‌گیری&lt;/strong&gt;: مدل نهایی، نمایانگر سطوح چارچوب تسخیر خط‌مشی‌های عمومی، شامل عوامل مؤثر بر تسخیر خط‌مشی‌، بسترهای تسخیر خط‌مشی، ابزارهای تسخیر خط‌مشی، بازیگران تسخیر خط‌مشی، شرایط مداخله‌گر در تسخیر خط‌مشی، پیامدها و نتایج تسخیر خط‌مشی و راهکارهای جلوگیری از تسخیر خط‌مشی است.&lt;br /&gt;  </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خط‌مشی‌گذاری عمومی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تسخیر خط‌مشی‌های عمومی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل مضمون</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل‌سازی ساختاری ـ تفسیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت دولتی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_72047_d12e33cb7cd78573348bc7562873a6a2.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Political Sensitivity and Compensation for Senior Managers: An Analysis of the Mediating and Moderating Role of Political Networking and Institutional Pressure in State Ministries in Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>حساسیت سیاسی و جبران خدمت مدیران ارشد: تحلیل نقش میانجی و تعدیل‌‌گر شبکه‌سازی سیاسی و فشار نهادی در وزارتخانه‌های دولتی ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>431</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>454</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">72486</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2019.286531.2603</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>سپهوند</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده علوم اقتصادی، دانشگاه لرستان، خرم‌آباد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>راضیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>باقرزاده خداشهری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده علوم اقتصادی، دانشگاه لرستان،خرم‌آباد،ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مسعود</FirstName>
					<LastName>سپه وند</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده علوم اقتصادی، دانشگاه لرستان، خرم‌آباد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt;Compensation for sensitive political careers has always been a topic of discussion for academicians, policymakers and social activists. The subject of this article is the assumption that the parameters affecting the compensation of such services are based on an equality-based or equity-based approach and are the result of the risks or responsibilities underlying within the organizational positions. Therefore, the purpose of this study is to investigate the impact of political sensitivity on the compensation of senior managers in Iranian state ministries with the mediating role of political networking and the moderating role of institutional pressure. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt; The present study is applied in terms of purpose and correlational descriptive in terms of data collection. In this study, 471 senior managers of 18 state ministries were considered as the statistical population at the level of Deputy Minister or Chief of General Staff and then 234 senior managers were selected based on simple stratified sampling method using Cochran formula. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt; Political sensitivity has a significant direct impact on compensation for senior managers&#039; services. It is also proved effective indirectly and through the mediating variable of political networking in which sensitive political office holders manage stakeholders and participate in power and coalition network which will finally affect their service compensation. However, the institutional pressure resulted from social norms moderates the relationship between political sensitivity and compensation. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt; Political sensitivity is one of the most important factors affecting the compensation of senior managers that affect the compensation of senior managers either directly or through political networking and forced, imitative and normative institutional pressures. Research results in the areas of political sensitivity, institutional pressures, and political networking develop theoretical innovations and help managers, institutions, and executive parties understand how political sensitivity affects senior managers&#039; compensation emphasizing political networking and institutional pressure. &lt;br /&gt; </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;هدف:&lt;/strong&gt; جبران خدمات مشاغل سیاسی حساس همواره محل بحث دانشگاهیان، سیاست‌گذاران و فعالان اجتماعی بوده است. اینکه پارامترهای اثرگذار بر جبران خدمات این گونه مشاغل بر اساس رویکرد تساوی محور یا عدالت ‌محور بوده و ناشی از مخاطرات یا مسئولیت‌های نهفته در پست سازمانی باشد، موضوع این مقاله است. بنابراین، هدف از اجرای این پژوهش، بررسی تأثیر حساسیت سیاسی بر جبران خدمات مدیران ارشد وزارتخانه‌های دولتی ایران با نقش میانجی شبکه‌سازی سیاسی و نقش تعدیل‌گر فشار نهادی است.&lt;br /&gt; روش: روش پژوهش از نظر هدف، کاربردی و از نظر نحوه جمع‌آوری داده‌ها، توصیفی از نوع همبستگی است. جامعه آماری این پژوهش، مدیران ارشد 18 وزارتخانه دولتی در سطوح معاون وزیر یا مدیران کل ستادی به تعداد 471 نفر بودند که با روش نمونه‌گیری طبقه‌ای ساده و بر اساس فرمول کوکران، حداقل نمونه لازم 234 نفر تعیین شد.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;یافته ها&lt;/strong&gt;: حساسیت سیاسی هم بر جبران خدمات مدیران ارشد تأثیر مستقیم و معناداری می‌گذارد و هم به‌طور غیرمستقیم و از طریق متغیر میانجی شبکه‌سازی سیاسی که در آن متصدیان پست‌های حساس سیاسی با مدیریت ذی‌نفعان و عضویت در شبکه قدرت و ائتلاف بر جبران خدمت خود اثر می‌گذارد. با این حال فشار نهادی ناشی از فراهنجارهای اجتماعی رابطه حساسیت سیاسی و جبران خدمت را تا حدی تعدیل می‌کند.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;نتیجه‌گیری&lt;/strong&gt;: حساسیت سیاسی یکی از عوامل مهم تأثیرگذار بر جبران خدمات مدیران ارشد است که هم از طریق مستقیم و هم از طریق شبکه‌سازی سیاسی و فشارهای نهادی اجباری، تقلیدی و هنجاری بر جبران خدمات مدیران ارشد اثر می‌گذارد. نتایج پژوهش در حوزه مباحث حساسیت سیاسی، فشارهای نهادی و شبکه‌سازی سیاسی، نوآوری‌های تئوریکی به‌همراه داشته و به مدیران، نهادها و بخش‌های اجرایی در درک چگونگی تأثیرگذاری حساسیت سیاسی بر جبران خدمات مدیران ارشد با تأکید بر شبکه‌سازی سیاسی و فشار نهادی کمک می‌کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جبران خدمت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حساسیت سیاسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شبکه‌سازی سیاسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فشار نهادی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیران ارشد وزارتخانه‌های دولتی ایران</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_72486_f0d3d21297a5cf0b88f6759e5c1c695f.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Goal-Free Evaluation of Iran Wheat Policy</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزشیابی آزاد از هدف خط‌‌مشی‌ گندم جمهوری اسلامی ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>455</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>480</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">71744</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2019.280756.2542</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرتضی</FirstName>
					<LastName>تیموریان</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد، گروه مدیریت دولتی و سیاست‌گذاری عمومی، دانشکده معارف اسلامی و مدیریت، دانشگاه امام صادق علیه‌السلام، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید مجتبی</FirstName>
					<LastName>امامی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه مدیریت دولتی و سیاست‌گذاری عمومی، دانشکده معارف اسلامی و مدیریت، دانشگاه امام صادق علیه‌السلام، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>12</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt; Policies are often evaluated based on their goals, but public program &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;evaluation &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;studies indicate that evaluation of the goal itself is important, even more than &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;reaching &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;the goals. The Scriven &quot;goal-&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;free &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;evaluation&quot; approach is the root of such primary focus on goal evaluation. One of the important policies of each country is its agricultural policy, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;and wheat is considered as the most important basic product in Iran. The aim of this &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;paper is to conduct a goal-free evaluation &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;of wheat policy based on social, economic, and political values &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;and conditions in Iran. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt; The research data were collected through interviews and reviewing the literature. The data &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;were then analyzed based on the context evaluation method in the comprehensive evaluation &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;approach (CIPP) &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;and utilizing the deductive theoretical thematic analysis method.
&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt; A hierarchy of objectives of wheat policy goals is presented using the means-end diagram. By using objectives tree diagram, it is possible to analyze alternative strategies for self-sufficiency. By identifying the needs of farmers and people, the underlying context components of wheat policy are analyzed in terms of issues, assets, and opportunities.
&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt; The results indicated a kind of displacement of goals in key wheat &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;programs, a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;pause at the specific level of the means–end chain (i.e. stopping wheat &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;imports), and staying &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;away from moving towards higher values and goals, and limiting the scope of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;goals to increase &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;wheat production. The link between the consequences of weakness in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;accuracy, depth, and breadth of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; goals in such programs with other issues such as lack of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;management and shortage of water resources, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;are causes of questioning the overall policy &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;orientation of wheat in the country.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‎ &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;This research innovation is applying one of the classic evaluation model for evaluating an important real policy in Iran and presenting its efficiency.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;هدف:&lt;/strong&gt; اغلب، خط‌مشی‌ها را مبتنی بر اهدافشان ارزشیابی می‌کنند؛ اما بررسی‌های ارزشیابی برنامه‌های عمومی نشان ‏می‌دهد که ارزشیابیِ خودِ هدف، بیش و پیش از رسیدن خط‌مشی‌ها به اهداف اهمیت دارد. سرمنشأ این توجه ‏اساسی به ارزشیابی هدف، رویکرد «ارزشیابی آزاد از هدف» اسکریون است. یکی از خط‌مشی‌های مهم هر ‏کشور، خط‌مشی در قبال محصولات اساسی کشاورزی است و گندم، مهم‌ترین محصول اساسی ایران به‌شمار می‌رود. هدف از مقاله حاضر، ارزشیابی آزاد از هدفِ خط‌مشی گندم، متناسب با ارزش‌ها و اقتضاهای ‏اجتماعی، اقتصادی و سیاسی جمهوری اسلامی ایران است.&lt;br /&gt; روش: داده‌های پژوهش که از طریق مصاحبه و مرور اسناد گردآوری ‌شده‌اند با استفاده از روش ارزشیابی زمینه ‏در رویکرد جامع ارزشیابی ‏CIPP‏ استافل‌ بیم و ‏بهره‌گیری از روش تحلیل مضمون نظریه‌محور (قیاسی) تحلیل شد.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;یافته‌ها&lt;/strong&gt;: با استفاده از نمودار وسیله ـ هدف، سلسله‌مراتبی از اهداف خط‌مشی گندم ارائه شده است. با استفاده از نمودار درخت اهداف، امکان تحلیل راهبردهای بدیل برای خودکفایی فراهم شده است. با شناسایی نیازهای کشاورزان و مردم، مؤلفه‌های زمینه‌ای خط‌مشی گندم در قالب مسائل، داشته‌ها، فرصت‌ها تحلیل شده است.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;نتیجه‌‌گیری&lt;/strong&gt;: نتایج پژوهش بیانگر نوعی از ‏جابه‌جایی اهداف در برنامه‌های کلیدی گندم کشور، توقف در سطحی از زنجیره وسیله ـ ‏هدف، یعنی قطع ‏واردات گندم و بازماندن از ادامه حرکت به‌سمت ارزش‌ها و اهدافِ مهم‌تر و نیز محدود شدنِ ‏دامنه ‏اهداف به افزایش تولید گندم است. پیوند عواقب برآمده از ضعف در دقت، عمق و وسعت اهداف این برنامه‌ها ‏با ‏مسائلی مانند نداشتن مدیریت و کمبود منابع آبی، دست‌مایه واکاوی کردن کل جهت‌گیری خط‌مشی گندم ‏کشور شده است.‏ نوآوری پژوهش حاضر، کاربست یکی از مدل‌های کلاسیک ارزشیابی در یک خط‌مشی مهم و واقعی کشور و نشان‌دادن کارآمدی آن است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزشیابی خط‌مشی عمومی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خط‌مشی گندم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزشیابی آزاد از هدف</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزشیابی ‏CIPP</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنجیره وسیله ـ ‏هدف</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_71744_7357269d989847d8d84bc02b854e8194.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identifying the Underlying Components of Organizational Ideology</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی مؤلفه‌های شکل‌دهنده ایدئولوژی سازمانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>481</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>508</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">72652</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2019.284006.2574</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اکبر</FirstName>
					<LastName>بیات</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری، گروه مدیریت دولتی، واحد ملایر، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، ملایر، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt; The present study aims at understanding and designing a Model of organizational ideology to identify its underlying components.This can provide the managers with a good configuration of Missionary-oriented organization framework. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt; In order to achieve this goal, in the qualitative stage, while reviewing the subject literature through Thematic Analysis approach, the effective criteria were also identified using MAXQDA software. In the next step, the identified factors were categorized into new dimensions of classification using the Fuzzy-TISM modeling approach and the levels of the components and the relationships among them wrer determined. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt; The analysis of the data led to the formation of fourteen organizing themes and three inclusive themes such as cultural components, behavioral components, and structural components. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt; Finally, it was concluded that when organizational ideology becomes stronger, it can create a specific organizational structure called a Missionary-oriented organization; on the basis that the cultural components are at the lowest level and affect the behavioral components and ultimately the structural components. Therefore, the organizing values and norms and assimilation are at the lowest levels among the cultural components and they affect all the other themes. These elements are key players in organizational ideology that should be considered by Missionary-oriented organizations.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;هدف:&lt;/strong&gt; هدف اصلی پژوهش حاضر، فهم و طراحی الگوی ایدئولوژی سازمانی برای شناسایی مؤلفه‌های شکل‌دهنده آن است تا از این طریق مدیران بتوانند برای ساختار سازمان‌های مأموریت‌محور، پیکربندی مطلوبی ایجاد کنند.&lt;br /&gt; روش: به‌منظور رسیدن به این هدف، در مرحله کیفی ضمن بررسی ادبیات موضوع با روش تحلیل مضمون، معیارهای مؤثر با استفاده از نرم‌افزار MaxQDA شناسایی شد. در مرحله بعدی، معیارهای شناسایی شده، با استفاده از رویکرد TISM فازی در ابعاد جدیدی دسته‌بندی و سطوح مؤلفه‌ها و روابط بین آنها، مشخص شدند.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;یافته‌ها&lt;/strong&gt;: تجزیه ‌و تحلیل داده‌ها، به شکل‌گیری 14 مضمون سازمان‌دهنده و سه مضمون فراگیر شامل مؤلفه‌های فرهنگی، مؤلفه‌های رفتاری و مؤلفه‌های ساختاری منجر شد.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;نتیجه‌گیری&lt;/strong&gt;: وقتی ایدئولوژی سازمانی قوی ‌شود، ساختار سازمانی خاصی ایجاد می‌کند که به آن سازمان مأموریت‌محور گفته می‌شود، بر این اساس که مؤلفه‌های فرهنگی در پایین‌ترین سطح قرار می‌گیرند و بر مؤلفه‌های رفتاری و ساختاری اثر می‌گذارند. بنابراین، از میان مؤلفه‌های فرهنگی مضمون سازمان‌دهنده ارزش‌ها و هنجارها و همانندسازی در سطح بسیار پایین قرار دارند و بر تمامی مضامین دیگر اثر می‌گذارند. این عناصر، در ایدئولوژی سازمانی بازیکنان کلیدی هستند و سازمان‌های مأموریت‌محور باید به آنها توجه کنند.&lt;br /&gt;  </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ایدئولوژی سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مربع ایدئولوژیک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازمان‌های مأموریت‌محور</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل مضمون</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل‌سازی ساختاری تفسیری کل فازی (FTISM)</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_72652_1e00434d72c5091aa4da1aabd7889de3.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Sensemaking: Concept Analysis and Implications for Human Resource Management</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>معناسازی: تحلیل مفهومی و کاربست‌ها در مدیریت منابع انسانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>509</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>529</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">70851</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2019.268468.2405</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>هادی</FirstName>
					<LastName>عارف</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت منابع انسانی، گروه مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>سیدجوادین</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، گروه مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی اصغر</FirstName>
					<LastName>پورعزت</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>قنبر</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمد الیاسی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، گروه توسعه کارآفرینی، دانشکده کارآفرینی، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>31</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt;The aim of this study is to investigate the nature and application of the sensemaking concept. Applying this framework to analyze human resource management issues can drastically enhance the extant knowledge of those issues and increase the effectiveness of HR practices. However, almost no research has been done -inside Iran- on human resource management and sensemaking. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt; Conceptual analysis is the primary research approach for this paper. Suddaby conceptual analysis methodology forms the basis of our analyses. According to this model,  we can clarify the meaning of the concepts through conducting four operations on concepts,: defining the concept, demarcating the concept against other related concepts, specifying the scope conditions of the concept and finally illustrating the logical coherence of the concept. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt; The main findings of this study include clarifying the nature of sensemaking, comparing it to similar concepts such as sensegiving, interpretation and action, specifying its place, time and value scope and illustrating its logical consistency by applying it to the ‘strength of HR systems’ theory. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt; Sensemaking perspective constitutes a conceptual basis for doing innovative research on HR related areas such as human resources change projects, recruitment and selection, employee socialization, sensemakig competence and sensegiving competence. Applying sensemaking perspective on these areas could enhance the existing understanding of such concepts.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;هدف:&lt;/strong&gt; هدف این پژوهش معرفی و مشخص‌کردن چیستی معناسازی و کاربردهای این مفهوم در مدیریت منابع انسانی است. به‌کارگیری آن برای تحلیل موضوعات مدیریت و به‌ویژه مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانش موجود به این موضوعات را به نحو چشمگیری افزایش می‌دهد و بر اثربخشی اقدامات منابع انسانی می‌افزاید.&lt;br /&gt; روش: تحلیل مفهومی، رویکرد اصلی این پژوهش است. در این رابطه، روش‌شناسی تحلیل مفهومی سودابی مبنای کار قرار گرفته است. در این مدل با انجام چهار عمل روی مفاهیم، می‌توان چیستی آنها را مشخص و معنای آنها را شفاف کرد. این چهار عمل عبارت‌اند از: تعریف، مقایسه با مفاهیم مشابه، مشخص ساختن حدود مفهوم و نمایش انسجام منطقی مفهوم مدنظر.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;یافته‌ها&lt;/strong&gt;: شفاف‌سازی چیستی معناسازی؛ مقایسه و برشمردن تفاوت‌های آن با مفاهیم مشابه همچون معنادهی؛ تفسیر و کنش؛ مشخص‌ساختن حدود مکانی، زمانی و ارزشی این مفهوم و نشان‌دادن انسجام منطقی معناسازی با به‌کار بستن آن در نظریه نیروی سیستم‌های منابع انسانی یافته‌های اصلی این پژوهش است.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;نتیجه‌گیری&lt;/strong&gt;: چشم‌انداز معناسازی، بنیان مفهومی مناسبی برای اجرای پژوهش‌های نوآورانه در موضوعات منابع انسانی همچون پروژه‌های تغییر منابع انسانی، کارمندیابی و انتخاب، جامعه‌پذیری کارکنان، شایستگی معناسازی و شایستگی معنادهی است. فهم موجود از این موضوعات از طریق به‌کارگیری چشم‌انداز معناسازی بهبود پیدا خواهد کرد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معناسازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت منابع انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل مفهومی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_70851_3599f0b6a13e9f685a1d057eabb5d4ad.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
