<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Presentation of an Effective Public Policy Implementation Model in the Ministry of Economic Affairs (Case Study: Islamic Republic of Iran Customs Administration)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>الگویی برای اجرای اثربخش خط‎مشی‎های عمومی در وزارت امور اقتصادی و دارایی (مطالعۀ موردی: گمرک جمهوری اسلامی ایران)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>591</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>614</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">65419</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2018.252928.2221</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمود</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسعدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی خوراسگان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهربان</FirstName>
					<LastName>هادی پیکانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی اصفهان واحد خوراسگان، اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>رشیدپور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علوم وتحقیقات اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;span&gt;The present study aims to rank the affective factors on the effective implementation of Public Policies and to design and propose an Effective Public Policy Implementation model based on the dimensions and parameters in the Islamic Republic of Iran Customs Administration. This study is exploratory in nature and uses a combination of qualitative and quantitative methods (mixed-method). Initially, qualitative and, more specifically, categorical (inductive) content analysis methods were utilized to collect data purposefully from the hard copy and electronic resources in the field of public policy implementation. Then, in the second phase, a researcher-made questionnaire was used to determine the dimensions, indices and parameters of public policy implementation using Delphi technique. Later on, the model was evaluated through confirmatory factor analysis. Data analysis was conducted within two descriptive levels using statistical indices of mean and standard deviation and one inferential level using LISREL and SPSS22 computer software. Confirmatory factor analysis and structural equation modeling were applied as well. The proposed model was confirmed and its absolute fit index was calculated to be 0.58. This value confirms that the fit index of the proposed model was approved. In conclusion, the present study introduces a new model for effective implementation of public policy in the Customs Administration of Islamic Republic of Iran.&lt;/span&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف این پژوهش، رتبه‎بندی عوامل مؤثر بر اجرای اثربخش خط‎مشی‎های عمومی و ارائۀ الگویی برای اجرای اثربخش خط‎مشی‎های عمومی در گمرک جمهوری اسلامی ایران است. این تحقیق از نظر هدف، اکتشافی و از نظر روش، تلفیقی از روش‎های کیفی و کمی (آمیخته) است. در مرحلۀ اول، به‎کمک روش کیفی از نوع تحلیل محتوا، اطلاعات از منابع مکتوب و الکترونیکی در حوزۀ اجرای خط‎مشی عمومی جمع‎آوری شدند و در مرحلۀ دوم، به‎منظور تعیین ابعاد، مؤلفه‎ها و شاخص‎های اجرای خط‎مشی عمومی، از تکنیک دلفی استفاده شد. داده‎های پژوهش نیز، با استفاده از تحلیل عاملی تأییدی مرتبه‎های اول و دوم و مدل معادلات ساختاری به روش تحلیل عاملی تأییدی مرتبۀ سوم در نرم‎افزار SPSS 22 و Smart PLS تجزیه و تحلیل شدند و سازۀ الگو طبق تجزیه و تحلیل‎های به‎عمل آمده، به تأیید رسید. در مجموع، این تحقیق الگوی جدیدی برای اجرای اثربخش خط‎مشی عمومی در گمرک جمهوری اسلامی ایران معرفی کرده است. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اجرای خط‎مشی عمومی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خط‎مشی‎گذاری عمومی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رویکردهای اجرا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عوامل مؤثر بر اجرای اثربخش خط‎مشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نسل های اجرا</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_65419_7d12333c3bb56744dd949e686ded95c7.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
