<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>7</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Comprehensive Model for evaluating the knowledge sharing in governmental project-based organizations according to the human, organizational and technical aspects</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارایه مدلی جامع برای ارزیابی تسهیم دانش در سازمان‎های پروژه محور دولتی بر مبنای عوامل انسانی، سازمانی و فنی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>95</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>114</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">23710</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بابک</FirstName>
					<LastName>سهرابی</LastName>
<Affiliation>1-دانشیار دانشکده مدیریت ، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سکینه</FirstName>
					<LastName>فروزنده</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده حسابداری و مدیریت، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ایمان</FirstName>
					<LastName>رئیسی وانانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Nowadays, the utilization of organizational knowledge and sharing it with other employees in governmental project-based organizations, have become a strategic source of gaining and preserving competitive advantage. Acquiring competitive advantage requires means and approaches that make the governmental project-based organizations capable of improving their knowledge sharing performance and gaining a better position. The initial goal of this paper is to comprehensively review the international literature on knowledge sharing and to present an applied model for measuring the knowledge sharing capability through the identification of the most approved and practical measurement indicators including human, organizational and technical factors. According to the statistical analysis and subsequent results, these factors are all influential on knowledge sharing in the governmental projects. Afterwards, the final approved model has been evaluated in one of the branches of the ministry of commerce as one of the most project-based governmental organizations. The statistical results have shown some weaknesses in the performance of knowledge sharing for which a comprehensive set of guidelines and recommendations have been provided. Finally, a set of guidelines for improving the knowledge sharing performance in project-based organization have been addressed and some suggestions for the future endeavors have also been provided for the interested audience.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه استفاده از دانش سازمانی و تسهیم مؤثر آن بین کارکنان دولتی، به منبعی راهبردی برای دستیابی به مزیت رقابتی و حفظ آن تبدیل شده است. برای دستیابی به چنین مزیتی، سازمان‎های دولتی نیازمند راهکارهایی هستند که آن‎ها را قادر به بهبود عملکرد تسهیم دانش نموده و در دستیابی به موقعیت بهتر یاری رسانند. بر این اساس هدف اولیه این پژوهش عبارت است از مرور ادبیات بین‎المللی پژوهش در حوزه تسهیم دانش و شناسایی عواملی که بر عملکرد تسهیم دانش در سازمان‎های دولتی مبتنی بر پروژه مؤثر هستند. این عوامل در این پژوهش به سه دسته عوامل فردی، سازمانی و فنی تقسیم‎بندی شدند. با توجه به نتایج آماری به‎دست آمده عوامل فردی، سازمانی و فنی بر تسهیم دانش مؤثر هستند. یکی از سازمان‎های بزرگ دولتی نیز به‎عنوان سازمان مورد بررسی انتخاب شد و توسط آزمون‎های آماری بررسی شده و شرایط تسهیم دانش در این سازمان مشخص شده است. در نهایت پیشنهادهایی برای بهبود عملکرد تسهیم دانش در سازمان‎های پروژه‎ای ارایه شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بهبود عملکرد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تسهیم دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دولت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازمان پروژه‎ای</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_23710_0e94064626f2407f49d71de413a761e2.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
