<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Contingency Model for Identifying Public Issues in Iran&#039;s Policy-Making Process with an Emphasis on Triggering</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>الگوی اقتضایی شناسایی مسائل عمومی در فرایند خط‌مشی‌گذاری ایران با تأکید بر عوامل پیش‌ران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>530</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>556</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">73160</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2019.287617.2613</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>سلیمانی خوئینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه مدیریت دولتی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کرم‌اله</FirstName>
					<LastName>دانش‌فرد</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، گروه مدیریت دولتی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نجف‌بیگی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، گروه مدیریت دولتی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt; Public issues are a widespread phenomenon and the weakness in their presence has led to inefficiency in government policies. Utilizing a comprehensive and contingent model for identifying public issues enables the country to fully identify priorities and strategies by knowing all the tools for controlling barriers and problems. This study presents a contingency model for the identification public issues in Iran. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt; In this study, content analysis has been employed, and 16 in-depth interviews with experts are used to answer the research questions. For data analysis, coding is done in three stages of basic, organizing, and pervasive theme network. Then, the designed model is tested by Delphi method &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt; The data analysis resulted in 66 basic themes, 24 organizing themes, 6 pervasive themes, and the theoretical model formation has been validated with two rounds of Delphi method. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt; State actors, non-state actors, subject sensitivity, subject area, time course of event occurrence, and event-related costs affect the process of identifying public issues in Iran. Government actors are comprised of the government (executive branch), the Islamic Consultative Assembly (legislature) and constitutional individuals and entities. Non-state actors include stakeholder groups. The sensitivity of the subject includes the negative impact of the subject on community sentiment, unforeseen and critical incident, previous negative public experience, subject strength and aging and environmental issues. Subject area includes geographical extent, number of people involved, public awareness, and issues and consequences of foreign and international activities. The time course of the event includes economic crises, military and terrorist threats, natural or abnormal accidents, long history of problems, social changes and technological breakthroughs. The event-related costs include creating a significant opportunity cost for political decisions, financial damages, life damages and threats to human health, and the negative impact of a situation or phenomenon on people.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;هدف:&lt;/strong&gt; مسائل عمومی، پدیده‌ای وسیع و گسترده هستند و ضعف در شناسایی آنها موجب ناکارآمدی سیاست‌های دولتی می‌شود. بهره‌گیری از الگویی جامع و اقتضایی برای شناسایی مسائل عمومی، این امکان را برای کشور فراهم می‌کند تا به تعیین و اجرای کامل اولویت‌ها و راهبردها بپردازد. این پژوهش الگوی اقتضایی شناسایی مسائل عمومی در ایران را ارائه می‌دهد.&lt;br /&gt; روش: در این پژوهش از تحلیل مضمون اسـتفاده شـده و بـرای پاسـخ بـه پرسـش‌هـای پـژوهش، 16 مصـاحبه عمیـق بـا صاحب‌نظران    انجام گرفته است. برای تحلیل داده‌ها، طی سه مرحله شبکه مضامین پایه، سازمان‌دهنده و فراگیر به کدگذاری انجام گرفت و پس از آن، الگوی طراحی‌شده با روش دلفی آزمایش شد.&lt;br /&gt; یافته‌ها: تحلیل داده‌ها در نهایت به احصای 66 مضمون پایه، 24 مضمون سازمان‌دهنده، 6 مضمون فراگیر و شکل‌گیری الگوی نظری انجامید و با دو دور روش دلفی تأیید شد.&lt;br /&gt; نتیجه‌گیری: نتایج نشان می‌دهد که بازیگران دولتی شامل دولت (قوه مجریه)، مجلس شورای اسلامی (قوه مقننه) و افراد و نهادهای قانون اساسی، بازیگران غیردولتی شامل گروه‌های ذی‌نفع و گروه‌های ذی‌نفوذ و همچنین حساسیت موضوع، قلمرو موضوع، مقطع زمانی وقوع رویداد و هزینه ایجادشده از طریق رویداد بر فرایند شناسایی مسائل عمومی در ایران تأثیرگذار هستند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوی اقتضایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خط‌مشی‌گذاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شناسایی مسئله</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مسئله عمومی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_73160_9d3fa3634ff5ff6a90908b3933d96873.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
