<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>8</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Designing the model of competent organizational culture for customer – based companies</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی مدل فرهنگ سازمانی شایسته برای شرکت‌های مشتری‎محور</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>57</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>74</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">24789</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>زارعی متین</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، پردیس قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>غلامرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>جندقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، پردیس قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>خنیفر</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، پردیس قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فائزه</FirstName>
					<LastName>حیدری</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه تهران، پردیس قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Today, the real customer oriented must be the prevailing aspect of organizational culture and its requisite would be the real transition in the culture of organizations and the basic attention to customer as the most eminent value and the most important organizational commitment. Therefore, the current research has been occomplished in order to explain all relative dimensions and elements of the competent organizational culture in all customer – based companies and produce a kind of suitable model for their performance. For this reason, first of all the research literature was studied comprehensively and then dimensions and elements of competent organizational culture were extracted. Then, all of them were confirmed according to the opinions of the professors and experts. After that , an original conceptual model was presented for accomplishing the relative research to competent organizational culture in customer – based companies according to these dimensions</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه صاحبنظران مدیریت و مدیران اجرایی بر اهمیت و نقش به‌سزای فرهنگ سازمانی در راستای تحقق اهداف و پیشبرد امور سازمان‌ها واقف بوده؛ بنابراین، درصدد شناسایی و نیز چگونگی به‌کارگیری روش‌هایی مفید جهت تقویت جنبه‌های مثبت آن هستند. به‌طور کلی می‌توان گفت، یکی از مشکلاتی که بر سر راه مدیران سازمان‌ها برای شناخت ابعاد فرهنگی وجود دارد، انتخاب چارچوب مفهومی یا مدلی جامع، درست و عمیق از فرهنگ سازمانی است. به این منظور در پژوهش حاضر در آغاز به مطالعه‌ی گسترده ادبیات پژوهش پرداخته و بر پایه آن ابعاد و مؤلفه‌های فرهنگ سازمانی شایسته استخراج شده است. سپس به‌منظور تعیین میزان مناسب بودن این ابعاد و مؤلفه‌ها از نظرهای استادان و صاحبنظران مدیریت استفاده شده است. در نهایت با بهره‌گیری از ادبیات پژوهش و همچنین ابعاد و مؤلفه‌های شناسایی شده مدلی برای فرهنگ سازمانی شایسته در شرکت‌های مشتری‎محور ارایه شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شرکت مشتری‎محور</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرهنگ سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرهنگ سازمانی شایسته</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرهنگ مشتری‎محور</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشتری‎محوری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_24789_ba21306d85240c8daf79fa943ea79983.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
