<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Recognizing and categorizing challenges for implementing human resources strategy in Khorasan Regional Electric Company</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی و دسته‌بندی موانع و چالش‌های پیاده‌سازی برنامۀ راهبردی منابع انسانی در شرکت برق منطقه‌ای خراسان به روش کیو</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>89</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>109</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">52514</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2015.52514</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدعلی</FirstName>
					<LastName>شاه حسینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت دانشکدة مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>نارنجی ثانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری مدیریت آموزشی، دانشکدة مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>صفورا</FirstName>
					<LastName>فلاح کریمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد MBA، مؤسسة آموزش عالی مهر البرز، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study is to recognize and categorize the barriers for implementing human resources strategy in “Khorasan Regional Electric Company”. Q-methodology has been applied as a mixed method in this study. 30 managers and experts of “Khorasan Regional Electric Company” have taken part in filling up the questionnaire in this study. Developing concourse, evaluating and summarizing the concourse and considering experts’ comments, Q-sorting was done. After Q-sorting and filling up the questionnaire by the participants, the information was analyzed using factor analysis. Analysis of the answers showed that 12 distinct subjective perspectives can be identified regarding the barriers for implementing strategic human resource plan in “Khorasan Regional Electric Company” among the participants. Then, prioritization and categorization of barriers was conducted. Finally, some strategies were identified and proposed to “Khorasan Regional Electric Company”, for dealing with the barriers in order to implement strategic human resource plan in the company.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از انجام این پژوهش، شناسایی چالش‌های پیاده‌سازی راهبرد‌های منابع‌انسانی در شرکت برق منطقه‌ای خراسان و دسته‌بندی این چالش‌هاست. در انجام این پژوهش، از روش کیو به­عنوان یکی از روش‌های آمیختة اکتشافی استفاده شد. شرکت‌کنندگان این پژوهش، مدیران و کارشناسان شرکت برق منطقه‌ای خراسان بودند. با ایجاد فضای گفتمان، ارزیابی و جمع‌بندی فضای گفتمان انجام شد و با استفاده از نظرهای خبرگان، عبارت­های کیو انتخاب شدند. بعد از مرتب‌سازی عبارت­ها و تکمیل پرسشنامة کیو به­وسیلة شرکت‌کنندگان، داده‌ها با روش تحلیل عاملی کیو تحلیل شد. تحلیل داده‌ها نشان داد که می­توان دوازده الگوی ذهنی متمایز را در میان شرکت‌کنندگان تحقیق در مورد چالش‌های پیاده‌سازی راهبرد‌های منابع انسانی در شرکت مورد مطالعه، شناسایی کرد. سپس راهکارهایی مانند «اولویت‌دهی به برنامه‌ریزی منابع انسانی نسبت به برنامه‌ریزی منابع غیر انسانی» پیشنهاد شد تا شرکت بتواند در پیاده‌سازی راهبرد‌های منابع انسانی از این پیشنهادها استفاده کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">برنامه‌ریزی راهبردی منابع انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">راهبرد منابع انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش کیو</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_52514_53411e8228a6f57d4d197943df3923ad.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
