<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Organizational Parameters Affecting Work-Life Balance Employees of an Automotive Parts' Manufacturer]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Asadi, Aryoo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Fayyazi, Marjan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hasangholipour Yasory, Tahmores]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organizational Flexibility]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organizational Support]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Supervisor Support]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Work–Life Balance]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Workload]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This study has been conducted to find solutions forincreasing work–life balance of employees of an automotive partsmanufacturer. For this reason by reviewing the literature we foundtwo main groups of parameters affecting WLB, including individualparameters (e.g. sex, age) and organizational parameters. We focusedon the second group in this study. We considered four parametersincluding workload, organizational flexibility, organizational support,and supervisor support as organizational parameters. About 411employees out of 840 participated in the study and we measured theamount of their work-life balance. By using SPSS software andmultiple regression and Pearson correlation techniques we found outthat there is a meaningful relationship between WLB and all fourorganizational parameters. While there is a strong positive relationshipbetween WLB and organizational flexibility, this relationship isnegative between WLB and workload.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_50772_28e0cd1f2d24b28043ce19c1153b124f.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.50772]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Influence of Trust on Flourishing Innovation: Study of Pardis Science &amp; Technology Park in Tehran]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Kharazmi, Omid Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Nedai, Amin]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[trust]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Systems thinking]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[TEHRAN]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pardis Technology Park]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This research aims at defining effective causes of trust andsurveying trust effect on innovation enhancement in Iran and Tehrandistrict, through a case study of Pardis Science and Technology Park.This research concentrates on systems thinking approach. Researchsample was based on 105 people located in the mentioned area with64 sample. Data was analyzed with SPSS and Lisrel software in orderto extract key important factors which have an impact on trust andalso investigate impact of trust on degree of innovativeness in cities.In the next stage, qualitative method was employed and interviewswere conducted with 8 people in this field. Data were analyzed basedon theme analysis method and the final system was designed withVensim Modeling Technique. Results indicate that many factorsinfluence on trust formation in cities which consequently have aneffect on innovation indexes.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_52153_e3ed428bc8ce646ab4000bd404259c80.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.52153]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Identifying the Components of the Innovative Organizations in Order to Achieve the Vision of Iran, 1404 (Case Study: The Universities of Ilam Province)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Delkhosh, Esmail]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Taban, Mohammad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mobaraki, Mohammad Hasan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Nasrollahi, Kamal]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Creative Organization]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Universities of Ilam]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Vision of Iran (1404)]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This study is conducted in universities located in Ilam provinceto identify the factors affecting creative organization. The research methodis mixed, in that, statistic sample in qualitative section consists of expertsand in quantitative section consists of employees, professors, and top andmiddle managers in universities (Payam-e-noor University, MedicalSciences University, Azad University and the University of Ilam). Thepopulation of the statistic sample in qualitative section is 20 and inquantitative section are 174. To analyze the data, Kendall's Coefficient ofConcordance, Confirmatory factor analysis, conforming analyzes andplacement test of Freedman are used. The results of the study show thatamong 9 identifying factors, 7 are organizational (internal research anddevelopment, External research and development, motivational factors,structural factors, strategic thinking, main competencies of humanresources, organizational empowerment) and 2 are native, Iranian-Islamiccomponents (intellectual directing and knowledge exchange).]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_50763_6c9e11b01324d490c301cd06d0e10a4f.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.50763]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[E-Governance in Municipalities: Studying the Iranian Municipalities’ Portals]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ebadi, Naghmeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Piranejad, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[E-Governance]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Information and Communication Technologies]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Municipality]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Portal]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Governing includes administrative and political processesand mechanisms which provide the conditions for citizens and socialgroups to discuss their interests reduce the differences and ensure theirrights. In the age of information and communication technologies, inorder to achieve this aim, public institutions are constrained to havedigital portals. These portals must comply with some standards whichare provided by national/ international organizations. These standardsinclude being user-friendly, respecting privacy, and providing thecitizens with the ability of participation in the governance. Here,municipalities’ portals are regarded as gates that can provide thecitizens with the most information about cities. In this paper, westudied 30 portals of Iranian municipalities in order to explore thestrengths and weaknesses of the portals. For this aim, the UnitedNations check list was used. The results of mean scores show that theportals are in low maturity level and need more attention. At the endsome recommendations are provided in order to improve the qualityand quantity of the portals.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_50766_2f06d6acf091ff1fae12ff9d34760b20.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.50766]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Effect of Ethical Leadership on Organizational Adaptive Capacity(The Case Study: Employees of Tabriz University)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Abbaszaded, Mohammad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Boudaghi, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[ethical leadership]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[organizational adaptive capacity]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Shared Power]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[One of the fundamental issues in organizations is theadaptive capacity. Therefore, the present study aims at assessing theadaptive capacity of employees to test its relationship with ethicalleadership. The method of research was survey and the measuring toolwas a closed questionnaire. The population consisted of 716employees of Tabriz University in 2012 from which 239 employeeswere selected through Cochran formula and stratified randomsampling method in relation to the levels of their classes. According tothe results of regression analysis, the influence of role clarity,orientation of people, ethical conduction and ethical leadershipconstruct was respectively significant on the dependent variable (theorganizational adaptive capacity) and these variables could explain63% of variations in the dependent variable.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_50770_ee4dc77b797ea7153c0b5a45a655528a.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.50770]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Assessing the Social Impact of Repairing and Reconstructing Minarets of Mosques Located in the 9th Region of Municipality of Tehran]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghasemi, Ahmad Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghorbani, Sanaz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Islamic Architecture]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Minarets of Mosques (Goldasteh)]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social Impact Assessment (SIA)]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Minarets of mosques (called ‘Goldasteh’ in Persian) areone of the artifacts of Iranian Islamic culture. Thus repairing andreconstructing the minarets of mosques could have considerableoutcomes for expanding Islamic architecture and urban beautification.This research tries to investigate “the social-environmental impact ofrepairing and reconstructing minarets of mosques located in the 9thregions of municipality of Tehran”. The research is organized basedon the ten-step social impact assessment model and it uses bothqualitative (deep interviews and observation) and quantitative (survey)methods to answer research questions. The results of the researchreveal that repairing and reconstructing minarets of mosques can havesocial, cultural and environmental impacts such as urbanbeautification, developing Iranian Islamic architecture, attractingcitizens (adults) to mosques, citizens’ satisfaction and etc. On theother hand, the negative impact can be ignoring neighbors’ rights andmosques’ priorities. In addition, it may cause urban management tobecome an arena of political competitions among interest groups.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_50757_9f36e371077f00575345c016cf155acf.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.50757]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Investigating the Effectiveness of Organizational Factors and Management of Deviant Workplace Behavior (A Survey on the Staff of Civil Servant Pension Fund)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghodratipoor, Morteza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hassanmoradee, Narges]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Civil Servent Pension Fund]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Deviant workplace Behavior]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[management]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[organizational factors]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Evaluating the impact of organizational factors andmanagement of deviant workplace behavior is an important issue. It helpsto explain the situation to senior managers in order to plan and makedecision to prevent or mitigate such a behavior. This study evaluates theimpact of organizational factors and management (unfair laws,organizational culture, compensation/ remuneration structure, negative andcynical attitude, and ambiguity of job performance) on deviant workplacebehavior (work deviation, political deviation, financial deviation, andpersonal aggression). The surrent study is an applied developmentalresearch in terms of purpose and a descriptive survey in terms of nature.The findings of the study which are the results of data collected from asample of 170 employees and directors of Civil Servant Pension Fund inTehran, show that employees distrust, negative and cynical attitudes,ambiguity of job performance, compensation/ remuneration structure,unfair laws, and organizational culture have the greatest impact on deviantworkplace behavior respectively. We recommend that senior managers planfor building trust among employees and identifying other factors affectingdeviant workplace behavior.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_50756_a1de3e06d8f746e1225e5dcb8c8ce4f2.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.50756]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Investigating the Impact of impostor Phenomenon on Family-Work Conflict with Mediating Role of Perfectionism]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Gholipour, Aryan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Yousefi Amiri, Mazaher]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Imani, Hossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Abdollahzade, Amirhossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Family - work Conflict]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Impostor Phenomenon]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Perfectionism]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Self-perception is a determinant factor in everyone’s personaland organizational success. One of the effective components that affectpeople’s self-perception is the Impostor Phenomenon which has multipleconsequences on organizations and their staff. Hence investigating andidentifying the consequences of Impostor Phenomenon is highlyimportant. Accordingly in this research, the impact of impostorphenomenon on work and life conflict with mediating role ofperfectionism has been investigated. In order to collect data, theemployed students of Tehran University were chosen as the populationand 250 questionnaires were distributed among them 176 of which werecompleted and returned to the researchers. The study results using thepath analysis method show that The Impostor Phenomenon affects“negative perfectionism” directly and “family and work conflict”indirectly (􀈙= 0.340). The results also show that there is no relationshipbetween Impostor Phenomenon and “positive perfectionism”. It’s notedthat “negative perfectionism” has the greatest effect (􀈙= 0.517) onstudents’ “family and work conflict”.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_52154_ef5a57619c08e453b9b93942b30be2e7.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.52154]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Analyzing the Critical Success Factors in New Service Development (NSD) Using Structural Equations Model (Case Study: Region 1 of Municipality of Tehran)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Allah Mirghafoori, Seyed Habib]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Shafiee Roodposhti, Maysam]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Malekshahi, Fatemeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Critical Success Factors]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Municipal Services]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[New Service Development]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Service]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Globalization and high pace of technological processes,achieved by information technology, increase the pressure on private andpublic organizations to compete for providing new services. The servicesector accounts for the largest employment growth and value-added indeveloped economies. Therefore, extensive studies on developing newservices and their success factors have become more important. In thisregard, the present study is carried out with the purpose of investigatingcritical success factors and presenting a model for new service development.The population of this study consists of two groups; the first group includesmanagers and experts of municipality for identifying CSFs and the secondgroup includes citizens of region 1 of Tehran in order to evaluate theperformance of municipality in NSD. For collecting data, two questionnairesof identifying CSFs and evaluating the performance are used. Structuralequations model and Topsis and Vikor decision making techniques areemployed to examine the questions. For presenting obvious and practicalresults, CSFs that are confirmed in the model are included in importanceperformancematrix and are divided into 4 sections the most important ofwhich are those located in the second quarter. Therefore, municipality mustimprove its performance in these items to successfully develop its services.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_52155_ee30c4de63ec03f5b213e1cbf162f882.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.52155]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Role of Intellectual Capital in Facilitating Knowledge Management Practices]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Nikoukar, Gholamhossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Asgari, Naser]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Gholami, Mehrdad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Rahimi, Ehsan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Human capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Intellectual Capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Knowledge Management]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[relational capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Structural Capital]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Successful implementation of knowledge management fororganizations requires a systematic and comprehensive perspective aboutvarious organizational factors. Appropriateness of these factors and theirintegration and coordination is a vital perquisite for implementingknowledge management effectively. The primary purpose of the researchis investigating the effect of three fundamental aspects of intellectualcapital– human capital, structural capital and relational capital– on fourstages of knowledge management practices (knowledge creation, storage,application and sharing). The data collection instrument is questionnaireand the research method is descriptive and corelational. The populationstudied in the research consists of managers and senior experts of thegovernment state of one of the south states of Iran. A sample of 120subjects was selected by simple random sampling. Data obtained isanalyzed using correlation coefficient method and structural equationsmodeling. According to the research findings there are significantrelationships between these intellectual assets and knowledgemanagement practices. These findings support the necessity of preparingthe perquisites of effective implementation of knowledge management.Accordingly, an organization characterized by more developedintellectual capitals can benefit from knowledge management initiatives.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_51379_1d095a7e93dfeaf063797846d873aef3.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.51379]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[English Abstracts]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					
			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_52156_41271cb581c4f64df0dfcdf64264d0b7.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.52156]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>