<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>9</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Paradigms of Public Administration: From Traditional Public Administration to Good Governance</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی سیر تحول در پارادایم‎های مدیریت دولتی : 
از پارادایم مدیریت دولتی سنتی تا پارادایم حکمرانی خوب</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>43</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>62</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">28723</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2012.28723</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حبیب‎ا..</FirstName>
					<LastName>سالارزهی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حبیب</FirstName>
					<LastName>ابراهیم پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکده علوم انسانی، دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Since the evolution of Public administration as an academic and scientific discipline, different competitive approaches have come forward in this area. Public administration as a profession, a scientific field and a political process; or, public administration as an area totally distinguished from business management; and legal, political and administrative approaches towards public administration have resulted into accumulation of irrelevant theories and concepts in public administration realm, engulfing this subject into identity crisis. In order to emancipate this field from its present identity crisis various scholars of public administration have attempted to regularize and organizing the concepts and theories of this field. The present work is an investigation in theories and paradigms of public administration; and the writers have tried to study the evolutionary process of public administration from inception to its present situation. In this regard, the concepts and theories of public administration have categorized into three paradigms: Traditional Public Administration paradigm, New Public Management paradigm and finally the new paradigm of Good Governance. To be noted, in this typology, these paradigms have gradually come into being since ninetieth century in a chronicle order and after transformation, new paradigms have replaced the previous ones.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">اداره امور عمومی به عنوان یک حوزه علمی بین رشته‎ای در طی سال‎های پایانی قرن نوزدهم به مجموعه رشته‎های آکادمیک دانشگاهی اضافه گردید و بنیان‎های اولیه نظری مدیریت دولتی به صورت پراکنده و ناهمگون تحت تأثیر کاوش مباحث کشور داری و اداره امور عمومی از رشته‎های علوم انسانی بویژه فلسفه، علوم سیاسی، جامعه شناسی و اقتصاد به عاریت گرفته شد. گستردگی و پراکندگی حوزه اداره امور عمومی از یک سو و طفولیت حوزه علمی مدیریت دولتی در سال‎های پایانی قرن نوزدهم، ماهیت این رشته نوپا را با بحران هویت مواجه ساخت و به طرح نظریه و ایده‎های مختلف و رقیب در فلمرو اداره امور عمومی منجر گردید. مقاله حاضر کنکاشی در مسیر تحول در ادبیات مدیریت دولتی و تلاشی در راستای یکپارچه سازی و انسجام بخشیدن به مبانی نظری اداره امور عمومی است. در مقاله حاضر سعی بر است تا نظریه‎ها و اندیشه‎های صاحبنظران مدیریت دولتی در فاصله زمانی دهه‎های پایانی قرن نوزدهم تا آغاز هزاره‎ی سوم در سه پارادایم مدیریت دولتی کلاسیک، مدیریت دولتی نوین و حکمرانی خوب قالب گذاری گردد در این سنخ شناسی، پارادایم‎ها بر اساس ترتیب زمانی از اواخر قرن نوزدهم به تدریج شکل گرفته اند و پس از دگرگونی، پارادایم‎های جدید جایگزین پارادایم‎های قبلی شده اند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پارادایم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حکمرانی خوب.</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت دولتی سنتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت دولتی نوین</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_28723_9118156ee4bd3a1607dc25e3c5263e69.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
