<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Identify Strategies of the Empowerment for Iran Parliament Members</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Marjan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Fayyazi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof., Human Resource Management, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mohamad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">haghshenas</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc. Student, Executive Management،  Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The aim of this study Identify strategies of the empowerment for Iran parliament members. The aim is to answer to this question that: How to improve and promote delegates&#039; abilities? For data collection, deep interviews with 24 members of the experts (9 experienced representative, 11 experienced managing of representative offices in the Parliament and 4 scientific Chartered) have been done. Information obtained from qualitative research methods of data analysis tools. Themes to the results of the analysis process identified three main strategies, including: delegate&#039;s Personal empowerment, Structural and organizational empowerment and social empowerment. And for each of the strategies, in terms of analyzing the contents of the interview, has a set of solutions tabloid which can be used as a plan of action to increase the capabilities of delegates.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>9</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>34</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_63088_b3a15e552ff61d006a58f7b949a5a58c.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2017.235359.2032</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Identify and codify appropriate features for verification competencies of Science, Research and Technology Minister of Republic Islamic of IRAN</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Roshanak</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Kavousi Khameneh</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc of Public Administration, Faculty of Management, Tehran University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali Asghar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Pourezzat</namePart>
				<affiliation>Prof. of Public Administration, Faculty of Management, Tehran University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Tayebeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Abbasi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof. of Public Administration, Faculty of Management, Tehran University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The primary goal of the Islamic Republic of Iran is to achieve the development. So, the establishment of meritocracy is considered, as the most effective action in the development program.The first step in this field is to identify manager’s key competencies. Numerous studies have been conducted in this area till now, which any have tried to provide an approach to develop the competency model of human resource. This study reviews the theoretical basis of manager’s competency and using experts management experience in the country offers the framework of the competencies of the Minister of Science, Research and Technology. The Research method is thematic analysis and research data collecting method is interviews with 14 experts. The results of the interviews are categorized in seven major themes including conceptual skills, human skills, technical skills, personal characteristics, the administration and management experiences, values and attitudes, knowledge and awareness.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>9</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>35</start>
					<end>60</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_63089_75b2165e052522495edd4e5fe4e082fb.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2017.226047.1923</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Evaluation of Transparency of Governmental Portals (Ministries of Iran)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ghasemali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Jamali</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc. of Public Administration, Faculty of Management, Tehran University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">abbas</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">nargesian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Public Administration, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Pirannejad</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Public Administration, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>reduce corruption, public trust and establishing a democratic society is one of the key terms in directing the performance of employees and government agencies. There is a mechanism for this vision and it&#039;s called transparency. Information is a critical issue for the survival of democracy. With transparency, information between government and citizens established its strong balance until emerging its effective role. With regard to the neccessity of using the internet in transparency, an statistic- mode rivision is developed in order to assess 18 govermental web sites. This research is field research, strategy research, survey and data collection and analysis is a descriptive comparative relationships between variables. The results show that the issue of transparency isnt found its position among the authorities and Web sites ministries are in the transparency initial stage and they the great attention is needed to paid to transparency.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>9</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>61</start>
					<end>84</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_63090_14a56b92fdb599a0b6dd10d4462ce36f.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2017.230125.1964</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Explaining the effect of organizational trust and organizational health on resistance to change in the government employees by considering the mediated role of organizational commitment
 (The case: Municipality of Ahvaz)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Jeiran</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof. in Management, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz, Ahvaz, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nadaf</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof. in Management, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz, Ahvaz, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sara</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Safarian</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc. Student in Management, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz, Ahvaz, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Abstract: The change is only constant element in life and business, but during the emplementation process of change, Organizations, especially government agencies, dealing with a some of challenges that resistance to change is one of the most important ones. Many factors affect on resistance to change. Two factors: trust and organizational health can help the organization to achieve change goals. On the other hand, the researchers have noted in their study the mediating role of organizational commitment. The aim of this study was to evaluate the effect of trust and organizational health on resistance to change with the mediating role of organizational commitment in the municipality of Ahvaz. This applied research, have been implemented on a random sample of 211 members of employees of Municipality. Results of the analysis the data collected through questionnaires, using Structural Equation Modeling techniques and software pls indicate that Organizational Trust has a significant negative effect on resistance to change but negative effect of organizational health on the resistance to change is not significant. As well as results of Sobel test, significantly confirmed the mediating role of organizational commitment in the impact of trust on resistance to change.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>9</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>85</start>
					<end>106</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_63091_f3bb780e59bd26713ada911607aaaa0a.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2017.231834.1980</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Analysis of the policy of “executive solutions to expand the culture of Ifaf and Hijab”: implementation pathology by use of Delphi fuzzy method</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">rahmatollah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">gholoipour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Prof. of Public Administration, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">vahid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">beygi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. Candidate in Public Administration, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">ali asghar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">saadabadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. Candidate in Science and Technology Policy Making, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Supreme council of cultural revolution ratified the policy of “executive solutions to expand the culture of Ifaf and Hijab” in 1384 and determined executive responsibility for 26 institutions and organizations, but after 9 year from authorization, the policy isn’t completely implemented and there exist multiple barriers in this way. In this research, barriers of implementing the policy by interviewing with cultural and policy making domains experts and using thematic analysis method is analyzed and 52 subsidiary themes and 4 main themes of barriers related to the policy, barriers related to the implementers, structural and managerial barriers and finally environmental barriers is recognized. Then 49 barriers were determined by using Delphi fuzzy method. Descriptive Prioritize of result shows that the most important barriers are related to the policy and the least important barriers are related to implementers.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>9</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>107</start>
					<end>136</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_63092_42040eee2295925ea785fbd01d5a18f0.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2017.123882.1408</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>HRD Matrix: Understanding the Duality of Structure and Agency in Human Resource Development</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Asghari Sarem</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. Candidate in Human Resource Management.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">حسن</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">دانایی فرد</namePart>
				<affiliation>استاد گروه مدیریت دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">آرین</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">قلی پور</namePart>
				<affiliation>استاد گروه مدیریت دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">علی اصغر</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">فانی</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Achieving to human resource development (HRD) goals is depend on to match human and organization through learning. But there is a question, how we can match them and what is the role of agency and structure in this process? The purpose of this paper is to present a typology model in HRD. In this paper, the features of agency and structure of HRD, by using critical incident technique, were identified. Participants were consisted of Mapna company managers. The “HRD Matrix” have two dimensions or two strategic refrence points. In this paper we will identify four status in the HRD matrix that is created by these two strategic refrence point. The last but not least, we will explain and understand the duality of structure and agency in HRD.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>9</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>137</start>
					<end>168</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_63093_70b04a8c8a33e886e863c8e6654f020f.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2017.212341.1781</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Narrative analysis of  ICT Labor Market mismatch in Iran</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Gholam Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Tabarsa</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Prof., Faculty of Management and Accounting, Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hamidreza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">FartookZadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Prof., Faculty of Management, Malek Ashtar University of Technology, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Somayeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghojavand</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. Candidate in Systems Management, Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Meisam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">RajabiNohouji</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. Candidate in Public Policy, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>human resource challenge is one of the major issues in ICT industry which affects on the industry success. Despite large number of graduates in this sector, there is great demand to attract them. However unemployment is high that imply skill mismatch in the industry between skills supplied by labors and skills demanded by employers. Regarding to the dynamics of research problem, three layer analyses was used to problem recognition and existing nodes among actors. In this regard 23 experts were interviewed by snowball sampling and assumption, structure and behaviors of actors were analyzed. Accordingly a narrative of research problem was evolved. Ultimately policies were made for improving problem through focus group.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>9</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>169</start>
					<end>191</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_63094_0987eb604bca0203396c2712c0925ca5.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2017.225614.1919</identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>