<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Table  of Content</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract></abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>4</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_66822_7826830b7698d9b95829d7f5cf896fba.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2018.66822</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Qualitative Meta-analysis of Scientific Researches Concerning the Issue of Governance in Iran</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Jalil</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Salimi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. Student, Technology Foresight Group, Amirkabir University of Technology, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Maknoon</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associated professor Technology foresight group, Department of management, science and technology, Amirkabir University of Technology (Tehran Polytechnic)</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Lack of aboriginal governance model, which is appropriate to national, cultural and ideological circumstances of Iran, is one of the most important problems in the development process of Iran. This paper used Meta-Analysis Method (MAM) to combine the findings of other researches and tries to take a step forward in developing the Iranian Governance model. In this study, 68 articles and reports about governance issues published in the period from 2003 to 2015 have been studied. These articles have been obtained from the four main scientific databases in two main parts including descriptive finding and analytic qualitative finding. In the descriptive part, we used six indicators for description of the articles includes types of article, publishing period, typology, researchers’ gender, geographical distribution, and research methods. Quiddity, knowing why and knowing how were the three main indicators, due to the Belicky&#039;s research, for the analytical part. The results of the meta-analysis showed that Iranian researches in the field of governance are in the scope of knowing why and their articles are more about quiddity of governance and why governance models are needed. Although there are some serious criticisms for this theory, “Good governance” is the dominant theory among Iranian researchers. Some researchers have developed “Islamic Good Governance” models but these recommendations seem too intellectual and theoretical and because of the paradoxical roots they will not be very useful.  </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>30</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_65643_a2f59e34e5e9f9a41a782d20241269ca.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2018.228757.1945</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Deadly Sins in Public Budgeting of Iran</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mir Yagob</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Saied Rezaei</namePart>
				<affiliation>ph.d</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali Asghar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Pourezzat</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor of Public Adminitration Group, University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mojtaba</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Amiry</namePart>
				<affiliation>faculty of management, university of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Adel</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Azar</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Budgeting is a pervasive activity in the governmental system across the world; in a way that “The Budget” as a product of allocation process goes beyond the political rhetoric, representing the real priorities and preferences of each government in the social realm. However, budgeting as a part of political system has a set of recurring issues and problems that reduce the effectiveness of budgeting system in achieving the considered goals; in this study we called those problems, “deadly sins”. To identify these deadly sins in budgeting, the qualitative method of theme analysis has been used and data collection was done through interviews. According to the finding of the study, ten deadly sins in Iran budgeting process are: “Disconnection of budget relations with upstream documents”, “Distortion strategies of the facts”, “Rule of organizational life”, “Lack of theoretical basis”, “Extreme idealism and lack of pragmatism”, “Abundance of budgetary and non-budgetary orders”, “Multiplicity of sundry rows”, “violation of budget principals”, “lack of process transparency” and “lack of accountability”. Obviously, by improving each of these factors, the budget can be set in the right direction and the national goals and objectives mentioned in the upstream documents, in particular the vision document and development plans, can be achieved easier.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>31</start>
					<end>58</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_65637_83fddd3145b8f57fd33b53ca16b5f97f.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2018.247589.2143</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Modeling Contingency Governance for Effectiveness Implementation of the General Policies of Article (44) of the Constitution</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Oghbaei Jazani</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD in Public Administration, Islamic Azad University, Isfahan Branch, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Akbar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Etebarian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associated Prof. of Public Administration, Islamic Azad University, Branch, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehraban</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hadi Peykani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof. of Public Administration, Islamic Azad University, Branch, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The purpose of this study is to design a contingency governance model for the effective implementation of the general principles of constitution (Article 44) in the country. In this research, the concepts, dimensions, components and indicators were reflected in the management books and the items of the questionnaire were also compiled from the approved indicators of the experts. The current state of effective implementation of the general principles of Article 44 of the constitution was examined by a single-sample T test and it was revealed that the public sector is in a rather favorable situation compared to the other two sectors. The results of the simple linear regression test showed that the public sector was 42.8%, the cooperative sector was 31.4%, and the private sector was 35.6% effective on the overall policy implementation of this principle of the constitution. Multiple linear regression analysis also indicated that the triple sections of predictor variables had 84.7% effect on the criterion variable. Artificial nural network model approved the results of the linear regression test, so it is expected that public sector continues to bypass the other two sectors as regards with the implementation effectiveness.  </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>59</start>
					<end>88</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_65635_9b321e826bea5d99a99affc15704dac3.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2018.252875.2229</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Survey and Exploration on the Organizational Civilization in Iran Governmental Organizations</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammadjafar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Zarrinnegar</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Student, Behavioral Management, Tarbiat Modares University, , Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali Asghar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Fani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Prof. in Management, Tarbiat Modares University, , Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hasan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Danaeefard</namePart>
				<affiliation>Prof. in Management, Tarbiat Modares University, , Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Jalil</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Delkhah</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof. in management, Tarbiat Modares University, , Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The present study seeks to design a model for organizational civilization in governmental organizations. This research is practical in terms of its fundamental purpose and it is mixed-exploratory in nature. The statistical population in the qualitative section includes the experts in human resources and organizational behavior. Purposeful and snowball sampling methods were used to identify the experts. Due to the adequacy of data, 20 experts participated in this study. To test the model, 384 employees of governmental agencies were selected using available method. The data were analyzed using data-driven theory and the structural equation approach. The data were collected through deep interviews along with a 49-item questionnaire. The data-based results indicated the fact that the determination of the goals and leadership of organizational civilization was identified and established in relation to causal circumstances. Regarding the main phenomenon, organizational civilization, and regarding the interventionist conditions, the perfectionist organization was established. The governing body of organizational culture and the desirable actions of empowering human resources management were determined and identified in relation to the main strategy of sociocracy, adhocracy, technocracy, and meritocracy. The main outcome of this model is the civilized organization, and the results obtained from the partial least squares model were approved and the relations were correctly designed.  </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>89</start>
					<end>108</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_65614_483aaa81cb273798719bffe9b6b6eb0b.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2018.254503.2239</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Explaining the Structural Factors Influencing the Formation of Policy Networks; (A Survey on Iranian Entrepreneurship System)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Safari Dashtaki</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D., Public Management, Islamic Azad University, Deylam Branch, Deylam, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Zare</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof., Dep. of Public Management, Payame Noor University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nikbakhsh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof, Public Management, Islamic Azad University, Deylam Branch, Deylam, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This research aims to identify the structural factors influencing the formation of policy networks in entrepreneurship system of Iran; therefore, this study is a developmental as regards with its objective. The researchers used a mixed method research in two stages, including identifying the indicators through theme analysis of the subject and testing it through a correlational survey method. The statistical population of the research includes the employees of the Iranian entrepreneurship system. Based on multistage cluster sampling, the sample size was decided to be 833and the data were collected using a researcher-madequestionnaire. The results of this study showed that decentralized organizational structure, interactive strategy, performance evaluation system based on social approach, integrated information and communication infrastructure, flexible payroll system, network supportive educational and research system, and high convergence in goals and interests have a positive effect on formation of policy networks in Iran&#039;s entrepreneurship system.    </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>109</start>
					<end>136</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_65652_b24b3a801fd9aa92e4f416c32ca488c0.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2018.253432.2227</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Analysis of Tax-Related Policy Making in the VAT System of Iran</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sheikhhassani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. Student in Public Management, Science and Research Branch, Islamic Azad University,
Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abolhassan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Faghihi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Prof. in Public Management, Faculty of Management and Economics, Islamic Azad University,
Science and Research Branch, , Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Karamollah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Daneshfard</namePart>
				<affiliation>Prof. in Public Management, Faculty of Management and Economics, Islamic Azad University,
Science and Research Branch, , Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The numerous letters, directives, and related laws and regulations, as well as the existence of various controversies and opinions of various individuals and groups since the introduction of the Value Added Tax Act in Iran, indicate that there is likely to be a problem on the path to the policy making and tax policies in the VAT system in Iran. In this study, using a qualitative approach and a case study strategy, to the process of making or selection of tax-related decisions has been analyzed. The findings showed that, despite the fact that tax policies should follow or be in line with the tax principles, in some cases and for various reasons, these principles are ignored or neglected. Therefore, the compatibility of that decision with the existing tax-related principles should be examined before making any decision in this area.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>137</start>
					<end>160</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_66174_2ac947788a306b1a3d8d79fbb66f5d73.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2018.255215.2246</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Investigating the Effect of Managers' Power Resources on Emotional Commitment of Employees Considering the Mediating Role of Personality Characteristics of Entrepreneurship</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Yusef</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Beigzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD. Student in Public Management, Bonab Branch, Islamic Azad University, , Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Farhad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mahbobkah</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD. Student in Public Management, Bonab Branch, Islamic Azad University, , Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The main objective of this research is to determine the effect of managers&#039; power resources (Legitimate, Reward, Coercion, Referent and Expertise) on the emotional commitment of the employees considering the mediating role of personality characteristics of entrepreneurship among the employees of government departments in West Azarbaijan Province. The standard questionnaire was the measurement tool and Structural equation modeling with partial least squares and Smart pls2 software were used to analyze the data and propose the structural model. The results showed that the power of referent, reward and expertise of managers and personality characteristics of entrepreneurship of employees have a positive and significant effect on emotional commitment of employees. Also, results indicated that personality characteristics of entrepreneurship have a mediating role in the relationship between the power of managers (Referent and Expertise) and emotional commitment of employees. In addition, the proposed model is apt enough and can be used to increase the emotional commitment of manpower in governmental departments. Other results showed that managers&#039; power and personality traits of entrepreneurship can predict employees&#039; emotional commitment at the appropriate level.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>161</start>
					<end>185</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_65636_fb088ec34cff6732f84afc1d1c130f13.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2018.251737.2207</identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>