<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Explanation of Model of Human Resource Development in Order to Achievement Media Reputation : Case Study IRIB</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تبیین مدل توسعة منابع انسانی به منظور دستیابی به شهرت رسانه‌ای                   (مورد مطالعه: واحد مرکزی خبر)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>139</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>156</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">50395</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2013.50395</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>طاهر</FirstName>
					<LastName>روشندل اربطانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکدة مدیریت دانشگاه تهران،  ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>شریفی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکدة مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>نرگسیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکدة مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The current age is called the Information Age. This has caused various media outlets to make efforts in this competitive environment (i.e. media competition) to have a larger share of the world audience. This is only possible when the media can play out an active and distinguished role in the society. In this competitive space, what makes a particular media form in the world distinguished is their reputation. The human resources of a media outlet are among the most important and advantageous aspects of competition. The present paper aims to study the role of development of human resources as the most important factor affecting the public acceptability of the Islamic Republic of Iran (IRIB)&#039;s Central News Unit. The outcome of actions, capabilities, abilities, skills and knowledge of news media staff are disseminated in the information market, causing the media to achieve fame. The paper attempts to examine the role of media&#039;s reputation as the most important factor affecting the development of human resources in this field. Therefore, this paper seeks to provide a model of human resources development in the national news media, which can consequently bring in reputation for the media. Our results indicated that a significant relationship does exist between these variables which in itself indicates the validity of the proposed model.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">عصر امروز را عصر اطلاعات می‌نامند. عصری که نفوذ انواع مختلف ابزارهای اطلاع‌رسانی در جامعه موجب شده است تا در کمترین زمان ممکن اطلاعات در سراسر دنیا منتشر گردد. بنابراین، موجب شده است تا رسانه‌ها تلاش نمایند تا در این فضای رقابتی (رقابت رسانه‌ای) سهم مخاطب بیشتری را به خود جلب کنند. این امر ممکن نیست مگر اینکه رسانه در جامعه نقشی فعال و متمایز ایفا نماید. آنچه می تواند رسانه‌ها را در فضای رقابتی متمایز سازد، شهرت آن‌هاست. مهم‌ترین متغیر در این بین که منبع مزیت رقابتی نیز محسوب می‌گردد، منابع انسانی رسانه است. لذا، تحقیق حاضر با هدف مطالعة نقش توسعة منابع انسانی، مهم‌ترین عامل تأثیرگذار بر شهرت رسانه‌ای در واحد مرکزی خبر انجام شده است. روش تحقیق توصیفی- همبستگی و به‌طور مشخص مبتنی بر مدل معادلات ساختاری است. بر این اساس مدل ساختاری از چگونگی روابط میان متغیرهای اصلی پژوهش در نرم‌افزار لیزرل اجراشد. نتایج تحقیق حاضر نشان می‌دهد که بین این متغیرها رابطة معناداری وجود دارد و اعتبار مدل پیشنهادی پژوهش تأیید می‌گردد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">: توسعة منابع انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شهرت رسانه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عوامل مؤثر بر توسعة منابع انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کیفیت خبری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_50395_260f5c24fcfa79717f0623bc0534c21e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
