<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Measuring Efficiency of Sepah Bank Branches and Determining Inefficiency Factors
(Case Study in Tehran Province)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Alvani, Alvani]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Jandaghi, Jandaghi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Raeis Safari, Raeis Safari]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Efficiency]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cost Function]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Bank Branches]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Bank Sepah]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The present research is seeking to assess the technical efficiency of Bank Sepah branches (in Tehran province) and to identify the factors which exert influence on it. Data over the period 2005-2007 relating to 52 different branches of Tehran province sepah Bank. In order to do this, the estimated stochastic cost function with the use of Maximum Likelihood (ML) method has been exercised in this research. The results obtained from the first model, that is the inefficiency of variant with time, indicate that the Bank Sepah branches have not given facilities with the least cost, considering the main thesis of research. The average efficiency of branches has been 77.1 percents in the first model and the efficiency of branches has been decreased throughout the time. The results of the second model have shown structural effects and the average efficiency of branches has been 64.2 percents. The reason for the difference between the first and second models has been the influence of structural variants of the branches (economic size, the ratio of fixed assets to total assets, employees’ education, level of mechanization).]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_35529_237d2cd9dd3e670cb88ca42dd9727306.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2012.35529]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Investigating Lean Production in IRAN KHODRO Company in Accordance with Jackson &amp; amp; Jones Model]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Amirkhani, Amirkhani]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Faghih, Faghih]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Lean Management]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[The Nine Key Elements of Development]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Levels of Organizational Learning]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Lean Production]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[waste]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The present study attempts to investigate lean production in Iran Khodro Company in order to address the importance of renovation and implementation of strategic improvement cycle to achieve competitive advantage through improving product quality as well as correcting consumption pattern for energy in the country along with national strategies. Due to its comprehensiveness, having clear framework of lean tools and methods, and practical methodology, Jackson &amp; Jones Model was used in this research. The method used here is of descriptive - correlative type based on structural equations. In this way, a questionnaire composed of 88 questions was designed for the nine key elements of development. First, Jackson &amp; Jones model was used to evaluate level of organizational learning based on the nine key elements. Then, using factor analysis, the validity of Jackson &amp; Jones model was verified. Findings of data analysis through structural equations show significant mutual relation between the three vertices of development triangle which in turn play significant role in development of Iran Khodro. Finally, Freedman test was used to identify the priority and importance of the nine key elements in development.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_35530_485b7cc7adddff7edf35f2b246d1a134.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2012.35530]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Identification of a New Plot Line in the Public Policy Narratives Using Narrative Policy Framework in order to Predict Public Policy Changes in Iran]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Amiri, Amiri]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Farhangi, Farhangi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Pourezzat, Pourezzat]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Gholampour Rad, Gholampour Rad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Policy Change]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Narrative Framework Policy]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Public Policy Narratives]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Plot]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Plot Line]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Identification of the factors causing change in policy process plays an important role in implementing healthy policy process. Narrative policy framework introduces new concepts and tools to identify the factors causing policy change. One of the important variables in narrative policy framework is narrative structure. Narrative structure has so many elements which the main one is plot. Plot line is a series of coherent plots which allows you to sort and categorize the narratives. A longitude 10 year research (2002-2012) has been conducted on policy narratives with the subject of subsidy purposefulness in order to identify the plots of policy narratives. The analysis of narratives using the content analysis pattern of Howland indicates that research propositions have beenconfirmed. Narrative analysis has revealed some other plots in addition to six above-mentioned plots. This new plot helps policy narrators to form narrative plots with more awareness and based on context.  ]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_35531_7fc862ae420705c1f8fa808cd277efee.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2012.35531]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Examining Current Situation of Specialized English Course Resources and Common Methods of Teaching in Order to Improve Learning Level of English Language of Students]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Tanaomi, Tanaomi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Najafikhah, Najafikhah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Specialized English for Management]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[The Resources of English Language]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Common Teaching Methods]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Improving Learning Level]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The aim of this research is analysis of current situation of specialized language of management, common methods, determining of their lacks and presenting the ways to improve of learning level of the language of the students. The method of research is applying and it's method of data gathering is field-analyzing. In the stage of collecting and assigning of research literature and theoretical fundaments is used library method and in field sector are used observing, interviewing and questionnairing methods for gathering information .In regard to importance of specialized English for management and English main resources of this major, the improvement of learning level of the language of the students leads to successfulness and students careers and scientific advancement. By investigation the most important books and other resources in this field and also the results by asking students and the information gathered from questionnaires and interviews, by observing the research methods of English language, it was obvious that the present resources are not good enough to satisfy the needs of students.  ]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_35532_8c62d95fc1446f254df5284ce2d9f8b9.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2012.35532]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[A Model for Explaining the Role of Participation of Employees in Public Sector Human Productivity Enhancement]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hassani Kakhaki, Hassani Kakhaki]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Zahedi, Zahedi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[participation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[productivity]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Substantive Guarantees]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Procedural Guarantees]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[By reviewing literature of human productivity, it's obvious that participation of employees and partnership environment is one of the main suggestions. But how human productivity is affected by participation of employees? This paper tries to answer this question. In other word, in this paper illustrated that participation of employees initiates two groups of guarantees that improve productivity of employees which we call them substantive and procedural guarantees. For measurement and testing the validity of model in this research as one of applied researches, we used Confirmatory factor analysis by equation modeling. The hypotheses in this research will be tested in C.O of I.R.I as one of the greatest and important economical organization in Islamic Republic of Iran. At the end of this paper by reviewing results that achieved, we explained the results by answering some questions.  ]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_35533_8b45c30558b98bf5f3b6ffe40a3978c4.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2012.35533]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Pathology of Innovation Process in Iranian Firms]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Rastgar, Rastgar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Taleghani, Taleghani]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[esmaeel, eghbali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Tajeddin, Tajeddin]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation Process]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Conceptualization]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Commercialism]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Shannon Entropy]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Content analysis]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In recent years, innovation and its related issues as succeeding factors in business and also a way to enter the international markets are much taken into consideration. How innovation is created in organizations /companies and basically what processes are followed in order to present a new product to the market are significant aspects of innovation which are taken into account. In this paper, the innovation process in 10 active organizations of food industry and IT are investigated. For conducting this research, 10 organizations were selected, 3 chief managers (CEOs), and 30 managers on the whole were interviewed in a semi-structured way. The data of the interviews were analyzed by Shannon Entropy method. The results showed that the investigated companies / organizations suffered some problems in “Conceptualization” and “Commercialism” phases.    ]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_35534_ffeba09539e1849a57ee0bdafb8f6a6e.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2012.35534]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Analysis of Relation between Job Resources and Work Engagement in Educational Institutions (Case Study: University of Tehran)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Roshannejad, Roshannejad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Sherafat, Sherafat]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Gholipour, Gholipour]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Job Characteristics]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Job resources]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[work engagement]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Work engagement is often considered as a critical factor in the organization's success and competitiveness. Some of researchers claim that engagement is an “essential” challenge for contemporary organizations and argue that organizations can gain a competitive advantage through employee engagement. This study investigates the correlation among job resources such as job significant, job control, meaningfulness, and internal reward, and work engagement. Findings indicate that there is significant correlation between job resources and work engagement. This is a survey on a sample of 136 employees who work in University of Tehran. We used questionnaire to gathering data, and correlation test and liner regression to analyzing them. We found that there is a meaningful relationship between job resources and work engagement]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_35535_7b87cc69a02738e50a466adccf7bf1cb.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2012.35535]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Explanation of Policy-making for SMEs Export Promotion with Using Grounded Theory Strategy]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Monavvarian, Monavvarian]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Moghimi, Moghimi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Movahedi, Movahedi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hoseinzadeh, Hoseinzadeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Export]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Small and Medium-Sized Enterprises (SMEs)]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grounded Theory Building]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[A large part of the country's industrial and manufacturing units are small and medium enterprises, but these firms have not been able to play an important contribution to achieving the export development goals. Given the importance of export promotion as the engine of the economy and low export share of SMEs, the purpose of this study is explanation the policy of export promotion for this group of firms and identifying factors and conditions that must be considered in policymaking. The method used in the study is grounded theory. Data collection was done by depth interviews with 23 managers and experts from the Trade Promotion Organization of Iran. Data analysis was performed in three stages: open coding, axial coding and selective coding. The results show that in export promotion policymaking, Empowerment and enhance export capabilities of SMEs (as the main strategy), creation a favorable environment for export promotion (as context conditions), provide incentives and stimulate businesses to start and sustain export promotion and development of export infrastructure (as the intervention conditions), should be considered by policymakers.  ]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_35536_b99668e33ee32d4db5752f82b9bcd587.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2012.35536]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>