<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Influence of Social Rewards on Team Collaborative Culture and Knowledge sharing through the Mediating Role of Team Affective Commitment]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Aghajani, Hasanali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Rezaee, Saeed]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[knowledge sharing]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Team Collaborative Culture]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Team Affective Commitment]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social Reward]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Nowadays, teams play a significant role in organizations' success and competitive advantage. That's why managers and researchers are trying to find antecedences and factors affecting teams' effectiveness. This study aims at evaluating the indirect effect of social rewards on team collaborative culture and knowledge sharing. The research is applied in terms of objective, and is correlational – descriptive in terms of methodology. Social rewards is considered as independent variable, knowledge-sharing and collaborative culture are considered as dependent variables, and team affective commitment is regarded as mediating variable. Quality control teams of companies that are located in Mazandaran province and produce automobile parts constituted the population of the research. Totally, 210 questionnaires were distributed. Validity of the questionnaire was approved by confirmatory factor analysis and its reliability was calculated as 0.83 by Cronbach's alpha coefficient. The results of the study indicate that social reward has a positive effect on team affective commitment. Moreover, team affective commitment has a significant and positive effect on team members' knowledge sharing and collaborative culture.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_51704_7e879e5a9714e6751920f115431746a5.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.51704]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Analyzing Improvement Mechanisms of Human Resource Development
(Case Study: Faculty Members of Agriculture colleges)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Akbari, Morteza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hosseini, Seyed Mahmud]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hejazi, Seyed Yousef]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Rezvanfar, Ahmad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture Higher Education]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Faculty Members]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Individual Development]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[professional development]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This research was conducted with the purpose of analyzing improvement mechanisms of Human Resource Development (HRD) in agriculture faculties. This survey research was descriptive-explanatory. The population of this research consisted of all agricultural faculty members of Iran universities (N=1178). Data was collected using multi-stage random sampling method. Finally, 248 questionnaires were collected. The questionnaire’s validity was confirmed by a group of agriculture faculty members and its reliability was calculated using Cronbach's alpha coefficient (above 0.7). Data was analyzed using SPSSwin18 software. The results showed that 48 improvement mechanisms are effective in developing faculty members. They were classified into four principal components of individual, social-participation, professional and educational factors, using explanatory factor analysis technique, which explained 61 percent of variance.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_51705_8eae12d529114c9658c91ce3d6a873b0.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.51705]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Canonical Analysis of the Relationship between Emotional Intelligence and Academic Performance Evaluation]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Taghizadeh Yazdi, Mohammadreza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Soleimani, Afshar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Rahmat, Naser]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Nargesian, Javad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[academic performance evaluation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Emotional intelligence]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The purpose of this research was to investigate the relationship between emotional intelligence and academic performance evaluation. The population of the study included faculty members of the University of Urmia in 1391. To select a sample, stratified random sampling method was used while considering the proportions. In total, 200 people were selected. The study was of descriptive - correlational type. To collect data, the standardized questionnaire of Syber Yashring and the researcher-made academic performance evaluation questionnaire were used in five-point Likert scale. Data collected based on the research hypotheses was analyzed using canonical correlation analysis. The results of canonical analysis confirmed the 99 percent probability of the correlation between the two sets of variables. The results of multiple regression showed that the components of self-awareness, empathy, social skills, and self-motivation are good predictors of academic disciplines criterion, scientific ability and teaching method.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_51706_7821ea7bf041bfa64a36b8e3e55dce9a.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.51706]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Investigating the Relationship between Social Capital and Organizational Virtuousness
(A Case Study: Rasht Municipality)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hassanzadeh, Toraj]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hemmati, Mahnaz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Nikroo, Hassan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organizational virtuousness]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[participation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[trust]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The purpose of this study is to analyze and explain the relationship between social capital and organizational virtuousness in Rasht municipality. Studying the relationship between social capital and organizational virtuousness and describing its variables are among the theoretical foundations of this research. The main assumption in this study is: ‘Is there a significant and positive relationship between social capital and organizational virtuousness, and are social capital variables able to explain the organizational virtuousness changes?’ For this purpose, from the population of 927 employees in Rasht municipality, a sample of 240 people was selected using stratified random sampling. The assessment instrument was a questionnaire consisted of 36 questions. To test the hypotheses related to the suggested conceptual model, descriptive statistics and inferential statistics methods were used. In descriptive method, statistical tables were applied for demographic analysis. Besides, in inferential statistics method, correlational and regression analyses were used. The results of this study show that there is a significant positive relationship between social capital and organizational virtuousness in Rasht municipality; i.e. with the increase of social capital, organizational virtuousness also improves.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_51707_f2ba3d1aecf77174bf81dc76323611df.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.51707]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Presenting a Model of Technological Entrepreneurship in Knowledge-Based Entreprises in Science and Technology Parks: a Qualitative Approach]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ramezanpour Nargesi, Ghasem]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Taleghani, Gholam Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ramezanpour Nargesi, Somaye]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghafary, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Entrepreneurship]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[knowledge-based entreprise]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[science and technology parks]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Technological Entrepreneurship]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Rapid changes in science and technology have made the uncertainty a distinctive feature of our environment. The main reason for such changes is technology, and entrepreneurs are the technology creators. In our country, technological entrepreneurship, which in most authorities’ opinion is the key to technological and economic development, has not been explored so far. Although nearly a decade has passed since the establishment of science parks, and less than a decade has passed since the establishment of incubators to support technological entrepreneurs in the form of knowledge-based enterprises, little information exists on technological entrepreneurs, technological entrepreneurship, and new technology-based businesses or knowledge-based enterprises in the country. In this study, the model of technological entrepreneurship in knowledge-based firms in science and technology parks at national level has been examined. The research methodology is qualitative, including interviews and focus groups.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_51708_6856f51e7dce311fe5742fcc6c9adf6a.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.51708]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Investigating the Impact of Organizational Identification on Job Satisfaction and Turnover, Given the Mediation Role of Organizational Citizenship Behavior
(Case Study: Region 2 of Tehran Municipality)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Zare Khafri, Shahab Aldin]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hassani, Mohammad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Job satisfaction]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organizational Citizenship Behavior]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organizational identification]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Turnover]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The present study investigated the mediating role of Organizational Citizenship Behavior (OCB) in the relationship between job satisfaction, turnover, and organizational identification. The population of the present study included all employees working at Tehran municipality at district 2 and the sample consisted of 260 employees selected using random sampling and Cochran formula. The research methodology was descriptive-correlational. To test hypotheses, we have used regression test and structural equation modeling to fit the overall model. The results of structural equation model analysis (confirmatory factor analysis) indicated that the model was standard and appropriate. The results of the study model showed that Organizational Citizenship Behavior was a partial mediator in the relationship between job satisfaction, turnover, and organizational identification.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_51709_143664c7875d4c3c4d62740d013c0067.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.51709]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Role of Perceived Justice in the Relationship between Organizational Justice and Staff Performance]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Sepahvand, Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Rahimi Aghdam, Samad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Arefnejhad, Mohsen]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Distributive Justice]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Interactional justice]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[perceived justice]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Procedural Justice]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[performance]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Today, given the pervasive role of organizations in human lives and the status of justice in Islamic culture, the importance of justice in organizations has become more apparent than ever before. The aim of this research is to offer practical solutions to improve staff performance of University of Tabriz based on organizational justice. The research is applied in terms of objective, and its methodology is descriptive -correlational. The data was collected using a questionnaire. The validity of the questionnaire was confirmed by experts and the questions’ factor analysis and the reliability were confirmed by Cronbach’s alpha coefficient. The results of the structural equations modeling on the data collected from 236 questionnaires completed by the employees of University of Tabriz showed that organizational justice has a direct impact (with path coefficient of 0.86) and an indirect impact (with path coefficient of 0.54 and the perceived justice mediating role) on employees performance. It also has a positive impact (with path coefficient of 0.69) on perceived justice. Moreover, perceived justice (with path coefficient of 0.79) has a positive effect on employees’ performance.
perceived justice structure by path coefficient of 0.79 has a positive effect on employees performance.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_51710_681d0ba55a5f42f22b4e5aa4fd939a92.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.51710]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Inquiry about the factors affecting the formation of political behavior in organization]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Fani, Ali Asghar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Sheikhinejad, Fatemeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[danaeefard, Hasan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hasanzadeh, Alireza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organizational politics perception]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[political behavior]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[political skill]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[political will]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[water industry]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The organizational activities are political, because in this context interests, power and conflict of interests exist. Therefore, one of the apparent behaviors of people is political behavior. This study seeks to answer the question that what factors are causing political behavior in organization? Researcher after describing the theoretical foundations, tests the process of inter-organizational variables that indicate the formation of such behavior in the companies of water sector. This research method is survey. This research data was collected by using a sample of 525 people of managers and experts of water industry, with stratified random sampling method. Content validity of the questionnaires was confirmed and its reliability was confirmed with Cronbach,s alpha coefficient for each variable. For data analysis by Structural equation modeling and path analysis were used LISREl and Smart P.L.S. The research results show that identified variables except locus of control and self-monitoring affect the political behavior of employees.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_51711_71c51aed68c8d11e30627f7e6debf8a0.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.51711]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Investigating the Relationship between Organizational Structure and Burnout among High School Teachers in Shahrekord]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Nazari, Seifolahe]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Siadat, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Abedi, Mohammad Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Complexity]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[centralization]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[formalty]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Job Burnout]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organizational structure]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The main purpose of this research was to study the relationship between organizational structure and burnout among high school teachers. Research method was descriptive correlational. To collect data, two questionnaires were used: organizational structure with reliability coefficient of 93 % and job burnout with reliability coefficient of 95 %. The population consisted of all high school teachers of Shahrekord in academic year of 1387-88 (2008-2009). 160 teachers were selected using cluster sampling and the questionnaies were distributed among them. The reaserch findings showed that: 1. There was no significant relationship between complexity of structure at schools and job burnout among teachers. 2. There was no significant relationship between centralization of structure at schools and job burnout among teachers. 3. There was no significant relationship between formality of structure at school and job burnout among teachers. 4. There was no significant difference among teachers with regard to their demographic characteristics.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_51712_a87174da392d564fbce47e6eadec26f7.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.51712]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Explaining the framework of relationships between knowledge sharing and organizational citizenship behavior in the base of positive organizational behavior]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Yazdanshenas, Mehdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[khoshnoud, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Knowledge Sharing Behavior]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Psychological capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Psychological Empowerment]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organizational Citizenship Behavior]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Positive organizational behavior]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Knowledge sharing can be considered as an organizational behavior with a great importance which is affected by the other organizational behavior variables. This paper with a descriptive-survey approach, tries to investigate knowledge sharing behavior as a substantial aspect of knowledge management and to analyze its relationships with psychological empowerment and psychological capital as the main concepts of positive organizational behavior. Furthermore, the mediating role of organizational citizenship behavior has been regarded in the abovementioned relations and finally a framework has been presented which explains the relationships among these variable and concepts. Research questionnaire was distributed among a random sample of the Iranian Airports Holding Company. Collected data have been analyzed through different descriptive and inferential statistical techniques such as regression analysis and path analysis. Findings supported the presented conceptual framework and also verified the mediating role of organizational citizenship behavior in the relationships of psychological capital, psychological empowerment and knowledge sharing behavior. Furthermore, results revealed that the mediating role of the organizational citizenship behavior according to psychological empowerment is slightly greater than psychological capital.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_50768_9578b7a63789152eaffbcc888f053303.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2014.50768]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>