<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An Investigation of the Effect of customer orientation of service and health institutions on strategic innovation (A Case of Nikan Hospital)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر مشتری‌گرایی مؤسسات خدماتی و بهداشتی بر نوآوری راهبردی (مطالعۀ موردی: بیمارستان نیکان)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>803</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>818</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">57356</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2015.57356</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>حقیقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشکدة مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سونیا</FirstName>
					<LastName>عطایی سعیدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه تهران پردیس ارس، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>غفاری</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد MBA، دانشگاه تهران ، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The Aim of This Study is Investigation of the effect of customer orientation on strategic innovation in Nikan Hospital, which considered as an applied research and the research methodology as descriptive and based on Survey. The population consisted of hospital managers and customers of Nikan Hospital; Customers Were Unlimited and Managers Population Consisted of 20 Person and the number of managers with the Morgan Sampling Table Selected as 19 samples for use in inferential statistics, In total, 349 samples Selected So for Decreasing the number of Responses, 350 Correct Questionnaire were analyzed in total. In this study, stratified random sampling method was used, In This Research, Internal Customer Orientation Questionnaire was completed by managers and other sectors of questionnaires completed by customers, results showed significant positive effect of customer orientation on Strategic Orientation.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف پژوهش حاضر، بررسی تأثیر مشتری‌گرایی بر نوآوری راهبردی در بیمارستان نیکان است. این تحقیق، از نظر هدف کاربردی و از نظر روش، توصیفی است که به­روش پیمایش انجام شده است. جامعۀ آماری پژوهش شامل مدیران و مشتریان بیمارستان نیکان است. تعداد مشتریان نامحدود و تعداد مدیران 20 نفر است. با استفاده از جدول مورگان، 19 نمونه برای استفادۀ آمار استنباطی و درمجموع، 349 نفر نمونه انتخاب شدند. با پخش تعداد بیشتری پرسشنامه، درمجموع 350 نمونۀ سالم تحلیل شدند. برای نمونه‌گیری، از روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی طبقه‌ای استفاده شد. پرسشنامۀ مشتری‌گرایی داخلی توسط مدیران و سایر بخش‌ها توسط مشتریان تکمیل شد. نتایج نشان­دهندۀ تأثیر مثبت و معنادار مشتری‌گرایی و انواع آن بر نوآوری راهبردی است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بیمارستان نیکان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشتری‌گرایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشتری‌گرایی داخلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشتری‌گرایی خارجی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوآوری راهبردی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_57356_9402e936566c9fa638c7e0a38e9cc088.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
