<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Study of Effective Factors on The successful implementation of cultural events from the perspective of tourists, Case study SADEH celebration</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر عوامل مؤثر بر اجرای موفق رویدادهای فرهنگی از دیدگاه گردشگران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>699</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>720</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">57352</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2015.57352</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>نظری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشکدة مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زاهد</FirstName>
					<LastName>قادری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد مدعو گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشکدة مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیده فروزنده</FirstName>
					<LastName>فضلوی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، مدیریت بازرگانی گرایش جهانگردی، دانشکدة مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>30</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Today event tourism is an important strategy for distributing tourism accurate and square in different areas and in different times. This research helps to fulfill the research gaps in terms of cultural events and also will try to survey the sensational elements in order to have a successful implement every year in Kerman province for Sadeh celebration. The research in terms of goal is practical and in terms of information is describing. The statistic society research, the tourists will be in the celebration for analyzing the theories and examining the relation between researches variables from approach making model of the structural equivalents for partial least square or PLS to be used. . For analyzing data of the research totally 109 questioners was correctly gathered and also analyzed by Smart-PLS software. The results has shown that from these three important elements, executing quality has got the most effective in terms of satisfaction, destination image and memorable experience to the minds of the tourists. The other variables of the research cannot have a meaningful effect on the 95% confidence of Successful Executing Events Indicators.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">گردشگری رویداد، یکی از راهبرد‌های مهم برای توزیع گردشگری به‌صورت عادلانه و منظم در مناطق و زمان‌های مختلف در کشور محسوب می‌شود. این پژوهش، به پرشدن شکاف پژوهشی در حوزۀ رویدادهای فرهنگی کمک می‌کند و در آن، تأثیر عوامل مؤثر بر اجرای موفق رویداد جشن سده در استان کرمان بررسی می­شود. پژوهش از نظر هدف، کاربردی و از لحاظ جمع‌آوری اطلاعات، توصیفی- پیمایشی است. جامعة آماری، گردشگران حاضر در جشن هستند و برای تحلیل فرضیه­های مدل و نیز آزمون روابط بین متغیرها، از رویکرد مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری مبتنی­بر حداقل مربعات جزئی استفاده شده است. برای تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌های پژوهش، 109 پرسشنامة درست جمع‌آوری و با نرم‌افزار Smart-PLS تحلیل شد. مطابق نتایج، از میان سه عامل مؤثر، کیفیت اجرا بیشترین اثر را بر رضایت، تصویر مقصد و تجربة به‌یادماندنی در ذهن گردشگران دارد و سایر متغیرها، در سطح اطمینان 95 درصد، اثر معناداری بر شاخص‌های اجرای موفق ندارند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تجربة به‌یادماندنی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تصویر مقصد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رضایت گردشگران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رویدادهای فرهنگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شاخص‌های اجرای موفق رویداد</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_57352_e587375054e29d93093afaafe1b6907c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
