<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The study and Comparison of Government Financial Accountability In four presidencies after the Islamic Revolution, using critical discourse analysis</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">moradi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof of Accounting, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">abbas</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">nargesian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof. of Public Administration, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">hanieh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">akhavan</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc. Accounting, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The accountability ensures the health of the governments in countries. This paper is the qualitative analysis of Comments Presidents about macroeconomic issues to explore financial accountability of governments after the Islamic Revolution. Method research is based on the Fairclough&#039;s critical discourse analysis model considering the political and economic conditions and the ruling ideological forces on the community to distinguish positions governments for the economic performance and their reactions to the results obtained. The Statistical population is the president&#039;s comments in four different presidencies which are published in the Etelaat newspaper. 12 texts were selected over the years 1360 to 1392, as samples that based on theoretical saturation method of sampling. The results show according to the discourse types which studied, government&#039;s accountability for economic performance had substantial differences with regard to requirements of the political and social fabric of its time, but they have had steady process in support of conditions and the results obtained from their actions also critical view to the previous governments performance compared their performance with them.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>9</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>193</start>
					<end>212</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_64360_5c83460efdcd65236b0d61efc96dce5b.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2017.234447.2022</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Bureauphobia: the Ambivalentl Look of Citizens on Public Services</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">zeinab</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">molavi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. Candidate in Public Administration, Farabi Campus of Tehran University, Qom, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">tahmaseb</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof. in Public Administration, Farabi Campus of Tehran University, Qom, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">hasan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">danaeefard</namePart>
				<affiliation>Prof. in Public Administration, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">hamidizadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof. in Public Administration, Farabi Campus of Tehran University, Qom, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Several studies have been conducted on the negative image of public administration among citizens. Most of these studies have considered the government&#039;s inefficiency, and rarely has study the ambivalent look of citizens to public services. The purpose of this descriptive-correlational study is to conceptualize and identify it, was conducted in two stages. Initially, bureauphobia was verified by analyzing the information obtained from the evaluation of the performance of governmental organizations. In the next step, by survey the citizens, some of the individual variables that were effective on the bureauphobia were identified. The statistical population of the survey was all citizens 18 to 70. The research instrument was questionnaire and documents. Logistic regression was conducted. The results showed that distrust of the government and public sector&#039;s employees were not necessarily related to the performance of public services. The results showed that 29 percent of respondents were bureauphobia. Also, the results indicated that age, gender, education level, and times of referrals are related to bureauphobia, but income and type of occupation with bureauphobia are not significant.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>9</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>213</start>
					<end>234</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_64362_366064a47c9135e5af884b5272facabe.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2017.240217.2078</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Identify factors to the commercialization of research in Knowledge of public administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Amir Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Narimani</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Candidate of Human Resource Management, Allameh Tabataba`i University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">vaezi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Prof. in Public Administration, Allameh Tabataba`i University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Nowadays universities to commercialize research results, play a new role. Because of the importance of innovation and business development is increasingly becoming; Universities can play a greater role in innovation and commercialization of academic research. In this regard, more activities commercialization conducted with an emphasis on science and engineering, but human sciences research, particularly public administration has not been significant. In this study, the aim is to identify factors to commercialization of public administration research by exploratory analysis of theme-based approach carried out semi-structured interviews. The validity of the interviews was confirmed by the opinion of 14 experts and the retest method was used to confirm the reliability of the interviews. The results indicated that a total of 26 influential factors obtained in the three main themes: individual, organizational and environment were identified. In the end, based on the results, suggestions were presented in this area.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>9</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>235</start>
					<end>262</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_64364_593fab411efc2f96628f4ce7a6689182.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2017.236485.2047</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Implementation of performance-based budgeting system based on the Balanced Scorecard in Science Policy Research Center</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Aboyee Ardakan</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Prof. in Public Administration, University of Teheran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hamid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Kazemi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Prof. in Business Management, Allameh Tabataba&amp;#039;i  University, Teheran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fardin</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hoseini</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc, Student of Public Administration, University of Tehran, Teheran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Science Policy Research Center، As an academic- public organization is subsidiary of the Ministry of Science, Research and Technology; which has attempted to develop a strategic plan. The next step in the operationalization of the strategic plan will be, its relationship with the duty applications, such as financial programming and the budget. Performance based budgeting is the budgeting system used for this purpose. The purpose of the study is how to implement performance based budgeting in order to communicate the annual budget with strategic plan with using the Balanced Scorecard in the Science Policy Research Center of the country. To collect information observation, interviews and review documents and archival library have been used. The research method is action research which two-cycle action have been taken during this study. Statistical Society of research is administrative and financial experts of Secretariat of SRT , managers and experts of STRC and expert of MPO that for sampling we used judgment one. This study is applied one and used a qualitative approach. Results of research will be dimension of Implementation of performance-based budgeting, how to implement and the distribution of the budget during the strategic plan in order to strategic issues.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>9</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>263</start>
					<end>282</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_64365_5507b184fe1216e4170dfd12b1efab8c.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2017.220369.1875</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Prioritize effective measures to deter corruption by relying on Islamic teachings</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">sayedmahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">alvani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Prof, Department of Management, Faculty of Management and Accounting, Allameh Tabatabaei University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">vajhallah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">ghorbanizadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Prof. Public Administration, Faculty of Management and Accounting, Allameh Tabatabaei University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">eslampanah</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD. Candidate in Human Resources Management, Allameh Tabataba&amp;#039;i University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The present study aims to rank the factors affecting the deterrence of corruption by relying on the teachings of Islam. The research method used in mixed (qualitative-quantitative) of exploration. The population consisted of experts of Administrative Offenses Prevention Department Samat to 79 people. The sample consisted of 30 experts and regional experts as well as experts of Administrative Offenses were selected. Method of determining the criteria and sub criteria are qualitative semi-structured interviews with experts as well as the book Nahj al-Balagha, respectively. Criteria and sub criteria using pairwise comparison matrix and hierarchical analysis technique was ranked AHP. Rating factors as levels of excellence, prevention and exposure (treatment), and the moral virtues and intellectual elite (0.365), monitoring and evaluation mechanisms (0.270), people care and social good companionship (0.134), a selective-specialized mechanisms (0.081), particularly avoiding want (0.063), structural mechanics (0.060) and mechanisms solver (0.027), respectively.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>9</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>283</start>
					<end>306</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_63602_7071d26478dafb92db26c9fbabdc68b3.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2017.232761.1997</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Organizational Social Inertia and laziness;
Dysfunctions of the bureaucratic Organizational culture</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Rahman</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghaffari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof. in Management, Faculty of Humanities Sciences, Islamic Azad University, Sari Branch, Sari, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Yahya</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rostamniya</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc. of Business Management, Faculty of Management, Payam Noor University, Shahr Rey Branch, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This study aims to identify the impact of organizational culture of bureaucratic inertia, is an organization with the role of social laziness. The population of this study included 210 people from all employees Ilam Governor Of these, 140 were selected as sample. Three questionnaires were used to collect data from standard bureaucratic culture (Tanya, 2006), organizational inertia (The Hague, 2014) and social laziness (Ground, 1393) was used. Analysis of data from structural equation modeling with partial least square method through software PLS is done, showed that the research proposals approved and in the cultural component of bureaucratic inertia, cognitive, behavioral, cognitive - social, economic and political impact is positive and also features the work of variables, features group and individual perception, the relationship between the culture of bureaucratic and organizational inertia play the role of mediator. It is suggested that the governor of Ilam, corporate culture in order to better participate in the organization and increase employee commitment and their efforts to achieve the goals of the organization, is encouraging. The managers increase employee participation and involvement in important corporate decisions to reduce social laziness and inertia to provide the enterprise.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>9</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>307</start>
					<end>332</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_64368_327100b169ce5a19fe0ab3e2a4f251ae.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2017.234155.2019</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Investigating effects of job security and autonomy on intention to quit through the mediating role of job embeddedness in public organizations</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">fariborz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">rahimnia</namePart>
				<affiliation>Prof. of Management, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Mashhad, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">saeid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">nosrati</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc. Student of Executive Management, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Mashhad, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">ghasem</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">eslami</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. Candidate of Management of Organizational Behavior, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Mashhad, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The purpose of this study was to investigate the mediating role of job embeddedness in relation between perceived job security and autonomy with intention to quit among employees of governmental organizations in Mashhad. The present research is applied in terms of the purpose and in terms of the method of doing the work is a survey type. The statistical population consisted of employees of 10 Public Organizations in Mashhad who were prepared to cooperate. A random stratified sampling method was used to collect data from these organizations. The minimum size of the sample was determined according to the Cochran formula of 433 people. Finally, 450 questionnaires were collected and analyzed. Findings showed that perceived job security and autonomy had a positive effect on job embeddedness. Also, the effect of job embeddedness, perceived job autonomy and security on the intention to quit among employees was also meaningful. In addition, the mediating role of job embeddedness was confirmed.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>9</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>333</start>
					<end>357</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_64371_88e5542e4ea21bb26018d258459afd2c.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2017.242169.2097</identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>