<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2009</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigation of Relation between Authority Language and Government&#039;s Legitimacy: a Critical Discourse Analysis of Imam Khomeini Speech</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی رابطه بین زبان اقتدار با مشروعیت دولت‌ها:
(تحلیل گفتمان انتقادی سخنان امام خمینی(ره))</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">20315</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد صادق</FirstName>
					<LastName>ضیایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>نرگسیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>منیژه</FirstName>
					<LastName>کیامنفرد</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In democratic governments, major basis of political power is people intention, and government is manifestation of national intention, and it&#039;s legitimacy is caused of public intention and will.  In democratic governments, is applied political power through active political participation, that base on various political institutions of society is setting by public opinion and under people supervision applying political power and consistency of legitimacy in applying political power depend on acquisition of public satisfaction. In this article is discused to investigation of Imam Khomeini discourse with use of method of Critical Discourse Analysis (CDA). The results of the research exhibit that Imam Khomeini discourse is pluralism, which that is Reproduce rule base and citizenship law.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در حکومت‏های دموکراتیک، اراده مردم مبنای اصلی قدرت سیاسی است و دولت مظهر اراده ملی است، و مشروعیت آن از خواست و اراده عمومی منبعث می‏شود. در حکومت‏های دموکراتیک  قدرت سیاسی از طریق مشارکت فعال سیاسی اعمال می‏شود که براساس آن نهادهای سیاسی مختلف جامعه، به وسیله آرای عمومی شکل گرفته و تحت نظارت مردم، قدرت سیاسی را اعمال می‏کنند و تداوم مشروعیت این نهادها در اعمال قدرت سیاسی به میزان توانایی آنها در کسب «رضایت عمومی» بستگی دارد. در این مقاله به بررسی گفتمان امام خمینی(ره) با روش تحلیل گفتمان انتقادی پرداخته می‌شود. نتایج تحقیق حاکی از آن است که گفتمان امام خمینی(ره)، گفتمان تکثرگراست؛ گفتمانی که در صدد بازتولید قانون‌مداری و حقوق شهروندی است. در این گفتمان، گذشته برای عبرت و درس‌آموزی قابل نقد است. این گفتمان، که مخالف خشونت و خشونت‌گرایی است، معتقد به حقوق ترمیمی است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل گفتمان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قدرت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گفتمان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشروعیت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_20315_d98dfb79c140b5b6d3902cf3b7b113b6.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
