<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Organizational Citizenship Behavior’s Relationship and Staffs' Psychological Empowerment</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hasanali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Aghajani</namePart>
				<affiliation>associate Professor, Industrial Management, University of Babolsar, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hossein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Samadi Miarkolaei</namePart>
				<affiliation>Master of Public Administration, University of azad, Young Researcher Club, Qaemshahr, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hamzeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Samadi Miarkolaei</namePart>
				<affiliation>PHD student, Lecturer of Payame Noor University, Qaemshahr, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Abstract: Existence of professional and skillful employees in organizations is vital for survival and business success in uncertain environment. Such employees work beyond their official responsibility and help organizations to achieve their goals. There are several factors such as psychological empowerment that play a key role on the forming of this behavior. The main purpose of present research is investigation of relationship between organizational citizenship behavior and psychological empowerment of staffs of Mazandaran Province’s Education and Training Organization. Statistical population of present study includes 387 persons of staffs of Mazandaran Province’s Education and Training Organization, and its equal sample includes 172 staffs, and is collected data by using standard questionnaires. Data analysis was done by SPSS and LISREL software. Results showed that there was a positive and significant relationship between organizational citizenship behavior and psychological empowerment. This positive and significant relationship so found between dimensions of psychological empowerment and organizational citizenship behavior. In order to intensification in practical objectives, organizations and their managers must encourage their employees to participation in organizational citizenship behavior. Employees would show organizational citizenship behavior and the organizational effectiveness would increase when employees perceive high levels of empowerment.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>18</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_36732_753f6a283020d8f9896b4ee904716f95.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2013.36732</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The study of Citizens’ Political Empowerment Under ICT penetration</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Piranjad</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistance Professor Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Aryan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Gholipour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Prof Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Political Participation of citizens is an important political issue which affects the process of political development in each society. In the age of information revolution, information and communication technologies are penetrating all levels of societies and have catalyzed the process of development in every country and encourage many scholars to study how these technologies affect the social, political and economic aspects of each society. This study examines the effect of ICTs penetration on citizens’ political empowerment, as an important component of the process of political development. In this paper, in order to explore the effect comprehensively, the interview method and employs qualitative approaches such as grounded theory are used. Sixteen scholars in the fields of political science, public administration and information and technology were interviewed to investigate how ICT affect the citizens’ political empowerment. The results of the analyses of the interviews were categorized into six categories: digital information, political parties, virtual social networks, digital public control, digital consultant, and digital public decision making. The explanation of each factor regarding the effects of ICT on political empowerment is discussed.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>19</start>
					<end>36</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_36735_41bdb22b4fc5442c2b1775b62e809fc3.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2013.36735</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Provide a model for explaining the factors affecting work – life balance.</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Since early of 1970s, composition of the labor force changed and increased the number of women in work place. Coordinating work and family responsibilities became a problem to employees and even organizations. HR professionals and managers had decided to find a solution to this challenge. Although many studies have been done to identify and solve problems in this area and many concepts created in the work-family literature, but the concept of balance is still unclear. This study identifies the concept of work-family balance and investigates its causes and contributing factors. The data is collected through the questionnaire and from a sample of 330 women who work in four universities in Tehran. The correlation and path analysis were used to analyze the data. The results show that there is a negative relationship between work- family support and work-family conflict. Also is a negative relationship between individual resources and conflict. Work-family support, individual resources, and work flexibility have positive relationship with work-family enrichment and work-family balance. Work-family conflict has negative relationship with work-family balance and work-family enrichment. It is recommended to provide training programs to improve individual resources and work-family supports. Also it is proposed to provide the necessary conditions for the implementation of the work flexibility schedules</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>37</start>
					<end>54</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_36738_8cbd8ab792815d9391858d362bbd0f30.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2013.36738</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Submit of  Knowledge management model in the industry based on contextual factors</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Maryam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Atoufi N.</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.Sc. in Industial Management Islamic Azad university zahedan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyyed Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Banihashemi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Instructor in Industial Management pun. Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Knowledge management, in the wisdom and knowledge-based era, has been in organizations&#039; priority, and knowledge is considered as an organizational capital, and its management enjoys a growing importance. This paper has been written with the aim of reviewing the state of knowledge management underlying factors including organizational culture, information technology and knowledge processes in Khash Cement Company as a way to measure the organization readiness for implementing knowledge management. Then, Was adjusted in a model of KM infrastructure. The model fitness was assessed using factor analysis and LISREL software. As was explained in the preparation of various dimensions using descriptive and analytical software SPSS, and was ranked the factors by Friedman Test. The results of this research show the importance of organizational culture is in first place among 3 factors, and information management has the first rank of importance in all subfactors. Then some suggestions have been presented for its state improvement.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>55</start>
					<end>72</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_36743_6cb22471a7100d76489cb630bb9df46b.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2013.36743</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Explaining the role of job resources and personal resources in employees work engagement</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ahmad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Esakhani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant prof. of Management Department, Qazvin Islamic Azad University, Qazvin, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In a past decade concept of employee enagagement has attracted the attention of human resources and organizational behavior reserachers and practitioners. This research aims to study the role of job resources (autonomy, social support, feedback, supervisory coaching, and opportunities for development) and personal resources (self- efficacy, proactive personality, conscientious trait) on work engagement (vigor, dedication and absorption). Respondents were employee of an industrial group (main company and six affiliated companies). Research data collected via questionnaire. Research model was tested by using path analysis and structural equation modeling techniques. Results showed positive and significant relationship between variables and also job resources and personal resources had positive impact on work engagement. But impact of job resources on work engagement is greater than personal resources.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>73</start>
					<end>96</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_36744_2a9cafe8725d971325c5b740c35530cd.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2013.36744</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Evaluating the effect of the characteristics of the research participants on the relationship between Strain and Organizational Citizenship Behavior</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Jeiran</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof. in management, Shahid Chamran University, Ahvaz, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Aliasghar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Fani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof. in management, tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Adel</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Azar</namePart>
				<affiliation>Prof. in management, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Saeed</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Fathi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof. in Esfahan University, Esfahan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Improvement of human resources performance for achieving goals of the organization, is one of the most important subjects in all organizations. Therefore it&#039;s necessary schematization of plans and solutions for decreasing strain and increasing satisfaction and then Organizational Citizenship Behaviors, One of the most important of the activities is recognition of the effective variables on the OCBs for its preservation, increasing and reinforcement. This meta-analytical study wants to uphold and support the negative relation between strains &amp; OCBs, and it has recognized the moderator variables (the characteristics of the research participants) that have been affected this relationship. Statistic society is the hole of the studies that have investigated the relationship between strains and OCBs, total studies are 169 with 845 effect sizes. Meta-analytic results revealed a negative relationship between strains and OCBs (ρ = -.21). Furthermore, this relationship is moderated by the characteristics of the research participants: the kind of gender, the number of year (tenure), the quantity of the income (or salary), and the kind of religion.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>97</start>
					<end>124</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_36745_d705218cac7a14a6c24d99ba7e880a9a.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2013.36745</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Designing a policy making model to improve the business environment of IRAN , A grounded theory</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abbas</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Monavarrian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Prof. of  Management Faculty , Tehran University Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Aboyee Ardakan</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Prof. of  Management Faculty , Tehran University Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Javad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Iravani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Prof. of  Management Faculty , Tehran University Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">MohammadReza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Zandimanesh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph D student of Management faculty , Tehran University , Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>A varity of policy making models have been put forward in different era. Although in real world each one of these models have a color and crystallized and an effect of each one could be traced in policy making . It is endeavored with the consideration of complexity of business environment and its various performers &amp; players involved to present a conceptual model of policy making in order to improve the business environment of the Islamic Republic of Iran. This approach is based on quality research and grounded theory method . The population is business environment experts who have been interviewed through theoretical sampling by deep interviews. In this method the researcher with a deductive approach and by the use of gathered data is personally to prepare a reliable policy making theory . So after open coding , concepts and categories are extracted &amp; will be put under the core category , causal conditions, context, intervening conditions and action and reaction strategies . Accordingly the main phenomena is the role of chamber of commerce &amp; some actions are interaction between government &amp; private sector, planning for improvement of business environment &amp; real agenda setting . Finally the story line is illustrated and the theory is presented.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>125</start>
					<end>142</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_36746_f7e1aefb54d1a3edd21564b8ce512945.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2013.36746</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Study of its Relationship with public Participation, Public Accountability and Transparency in 3’s region of city of Tehran</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mirhossein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ayatollah Zade Shirazi</namePart>
				<affiliation>مدیرعامل/ شرکت مشاوران نرم افزاری اعوان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abbas</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nargesian</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.sc Student Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Citizen Relationship Management: Study of its Relationship with public Participation, Public Accountability and Transparency in 3’s region of city of Tehran.This research seeks to study the role of citizen relationship management in the promotion of public participation, accountability and transparency of the public.This study aimed to identify the effect of increasing citizen relationship management, public participation, public accountability and transparency of government organizations in Tehran is in District 3 .</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>143</start>
					<end>168</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_36747_0c940b921d628ac15e19943aff981e5b.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2013.36747</identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>