<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>To Determine Organizational Culture of Ministry of Energy Subsidiary Companies of ZahedanTownship and Its Relationship With Dimensions of All-embracing Quality's Management</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Amirhossein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Amirkhani</namePart>
				<affiliation>استادیار مدیریت دانشگاه پیام نور، مرکز گرمسار، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Keikha</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت اجرایی از دانشگاه پیام نور گرمسار، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Javad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Dadras</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی از دانشگاه آزاد کرمان، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ashraf</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mirshekari</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس مهندسی برق از دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Following recent theories and studies on management, organizational spirit has gained a growing significance and has been a central and fundamental topic in management. Anthropologists, sociologists and recently psychologists and even economists, have paid due attention to these new topics and have made lots of research and hypotheses in order to comprehend them and have used their findings in solving management issues. The study aims at perceiving the relation between organizational spirit and aspects of qualitative comprehensive management. The data was celestial through two questioners, the team work spirit question are specially prepared for the staff, consisted of two main sections, the first part included personal credentials asking for the person&#039;s age, education, sex, work experience, employment status, and the second part consisted of 28 questions, administered based on the objectives of the study and the question are to the aspects of comprehensive qualitative management consisting of 49 questions filled out by people in change of different department statistic analysis was carried out using Spearman and freedman’s correlation tests and SPSS software, the findings showed there was a relation between organizational spirit and aspects of qualitative comprehensive management.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>7</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2011</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>22</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_23705_4fac2dae45615b759d857e608a46de58.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Identifying the Factors and Developing the Human Resource Empowerment Conceptual Model in ICT Ministry (Case Study</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Manouchehr</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ansari</namePart>
				<affiliation>- دانشیار دانشکدهمدیریتدانشگاه تهران، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hossein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">rahmany youshanlouei</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد سلماس، باشگاه پژوهشگران جوان، سلماس، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Vahid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Oskuei</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات،دانشکده مدیریت،دانشگاه تهران، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ahad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hosseini</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد،دانشکده مدیریت،دانشگاه تهران، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In recent years empowerment of human resource has become a tool which can be employed to efficiently manage of modern organizations which have features such as variety of diffusion channels, an increased reliance on horizontal and network structures, reduction in communication gap between managers and staff and reduction of organizational bias The ami of This Paper is  to identify and measure factors affecting empowerment of ICT Ministry personnel, and develop a conceptual model for the empowerment of this organization. For introduction the effective factors, we applied Factor Analysis method, and for relationship intensity between those factors and empowerment of human resource, we used Path Analysis method. The results show there is a significant relationship between empowerment of human resource and job enrichment factors, team work, challenging situation, feedback, control locus, organizational commitment and role ambiguity.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>7</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2011</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>23</start>
					<end>40</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_23706_7bf860e3ad7ccfaf1c5cf219c9c6cd51.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Organizational Structure Pathology
 Of Islamic republicOf Iranian central insurance</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hamidreza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hassanzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشیار دانشگاه تهران، پردیس قم، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hossein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khanifar</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشیار دانشگاه تهران، پردیس قم، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hasan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">koolivand</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی دانشگاه تهران، پردیس قم، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Naser</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Asgari</namePart>
				<affiliation>عضوهیات علمی دانشگاه شهید ستاری. تهران، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The basic goal of this research is recognition of losses of organizational structure of Iranian central insurance and secondary importance are recognition of losses of organizationalcomplexity, organizational formalization and organizational centralization. For data collecting is designed aquestionnaire that is measuring organizational structure situation in robin’s structural dimension’s model. After data analysis with spss software, losses is recognized and then with attention to obtained is presented essential proposes for organizational structure reform. Statistical Population of this research is all of Iranian central insurance employee that between of them is selected 75 people for Statistical Sample. find of this research show that with attention of theoretic literature and out put’s research exam’s, Iranian central insurance’s organizational Structure of Islamic republic of Iran must be organic and flexible but it’s mechanical with high degree of organizational complexity, organizational formalization and organizational centralization. Finally, with test in confidence level 0/095 , sig</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>7</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2011</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>41</start>
					<end>69</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_23707_1206bf12891f9331cca185fb47acf0cb.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Transformational leadership and organizational citizenship behavior in school: Retesting and changing a tested model in industry</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hassan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Zeinabadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>- استادیار گروه مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه تربیت معلم تهران، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>One of the high citation researches surrounding model of transformational leadership&#039;s impact on organizational citizenship behavior has been conducted by Podsakoff, MacKenzie, Moorman and Fetter (1990). Using structural equation modeling, current study aims at testing this model and also 4 other models in schools on a sample including 652 teachers and 131 principals. Results showed that Podsakoff and colleagues model doesn’t have good fit with observed data. Results of testing of other models demonstrate that only one model (final model) has best fit with observed data. In this model transformational leadership affected organizational citizenship behavior indirectly through intrinsic job satisfaction and trust in principal. In general, the results indicate that attention to the role of principal&#039;s transformational leadership, teacher trust in principal and intrinsic job satisfaction in organizational citizenship behavior of teachers is crucial. Implications of the study are discussed in relation to principals, as well as to policy makers and further research.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>7</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2011</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>63</start>
					<end>80</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_23708_2cf70bb2899c03ccefde0eb0f7043912.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Structural Model of Developing Workers' Productivity</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Farahollah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rahnavard</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشیار گروه آموزشی مدیریت دولتی، مرکز آموزش مدیریت دولتی، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Majid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khodabaksh</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای، مرکز آموزش مدیریت دولتی، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In general, productivity is gaining maximum profit from manpower, equipments, time, place, and son on in order to enhance social welfare. Without doubt, promoting productivity at individual, group, and organizational levels depends on different factors. This research is about to find a model to recognize influencing factors on workers’ productivity in the MST Group, and to show relationships among relevant variables at individual level. A finding of this research is indicative of following influencing factors on worker’s productivity:
1) perceived organizational justice; 6) individual ability;
2) perceived organizational trust; 7) organizational citizen behavior;
3) Motivation; 8) personality; 
4) Organizational commitment; 9)Maritalstatus
5) perceived organizational support;
support;
The structural model of variables relationships illustrates key for following factors roles in development of human resource productivity: 1) organizational support; 2) individual ability; and 3) organizational trust.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>7</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2011</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>81</start>
					<end>94</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_23709_372736d4ab935668af8d324654c6aa86.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Comprehensive Model for evaluating the knowledge sharing in governmental project-based organizations according to the human, organizational and technical aspects</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Babak</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sohrabi</namePart>
				<affiliation>1-دانشیار دانشکده مدیریت ، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sakineh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Forouzandeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده حسابداری و مدیریت، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Iman</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Raeesi Vanani</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Nowadays, the utilization of organizational knowledge and sharing it with other employees in governmental project-based organizations, have become a strategic source of gaining and preserving competitive advantage. Acquiring competitive advantage requires means and approaches that make the governmental project-based organizations capable of improving their knowledge sharing performance and gaining a better position. The initial goal of this paper is to comprehensively review the international literature on knowledge sharing and to present an applied model for measuring the knowledge sharing capability through the identification of the most approved and practical measurement indicators including human, organizational and technical factors. According to the statistical analysis and subsequent results, these factors are all influential on knowledge sharing in the governmental projects. Afterwards, the final approved model has been evaluated in one of the branches of the ministry of commerce as one of the most project-based governmental organizations. The statistical results have shown some weaknesses in the performance of knowledge sharing for which a comprehensive set of guidelines and recommendations have been provided. Finally, a set of guidelines for improving the knowledge sharing performance in project-based organization have been addressed and some suggestions for the future endeavors have also been provided for the interested audience.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>7</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2011</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>95</start>
					<end>114</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_23710_0e94064626f2407f49d71de413a761e2.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>studying factors affect on increase of productivity (case study:Saman bank).</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Gholam Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Taleghani</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mohammad mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">tanaomi</namePart>
				<affiliation>2استادیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Aliakbar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Farhangi</namePart>
				<affiliation>استاد گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Jafar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Zarrinnegar</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>: Recently, productivity discussion has been considered in social and scientific discussions. In the extreme world  of competition and growth of technology, policy makers and management  consider increase of  productivity as tool or as a goal occasionally (3) in this research  it is intended to recognize effects  factor on increase of productivity  particularly factors such as providing  essential needs of personnel , participation  of personnel in decision making and  leadership style of ,anger  and some guidelines will be presented  to increase productivity. This research studies three effective factors on productivity by correlation analysis. Statistical community  includes staff personnel occupied in central building of Saman bank which have been selected randomly using by  questionnaire based on their opinions.
The results of research proved that considering essential needs of personnel, staff participation  in decision making and leader ship style of  manager can increase productivity of personnel in the workplace.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>7</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2011</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>115</start>
					<end>130</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_23711_ab53f462f5f38c3b32ec878bf7354830.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Mapping “Urban Management Science”
Based on ISI Subject Areas</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hasan Abedi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Jafari</namePart>
				<affiliation>دکترای مدیریت، استادیار دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Abooyee Ardakan</namePart>
				<affiliation>دکترای مدیریت،استادیار دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fattah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Aghazadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت شهری دانشگاه تهران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The goal of this article is mapping urban management Science. The main question of the research is “what are the subject areas of urban management science and how is the relation between these subject areas?” The map of urban management science can help to recognize urban management and its subject areas and can help policy makers to get familiar with the priorities in this subject area. For this purpose the ISI’s data-base was selected as a resource of data extraction. To achieve a science base for urban management five steps were done: 1-designing the search strategy, 2-searching, 3-analyzing search results, and 4-designing matrix of relationships, 5-clustering.
Research results shows that the map of urban management includes 36 subject areas and 18 districts.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>7</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2011</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>131</start>
					<end>138</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_23712_a069f937ddb283a4d9ee2664e7788172.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Explanation of Intra organizational and Extra organizational Construction of Organizational Identity in Public Organizations</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">aryan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">gholipour</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دولتی دانشگاه تهران، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali Asghar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Pourezzat</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دولتی دانشگاه تهران، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">fereshte</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">mohammadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت دولتی دانشگاه تهران، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>One of the most hot topic in recent years in management is Organizational identity and more important than it, is identity Construction which ignored in researches. Nowadays in most of the public organizations, the increase of turnover rate, reducing employees` job satisfaction, increasing the amount of job absent, developing job alienation, and lack of accepting responsibility sense and generally lack of identifying of the members with their organization, are noticed. The need for promoting the awareness of managers and directors of these organizations are among the effective factors on constructing the organizational identity and potential interests resulted from the strong and tenacious organizational identity more than ever. The present research is going to study internal and external factors effective on the constructing the organizational identity and the relationship between each of these factors with the organizational identity and present some guidelines for improving and strengthening it in the organizations. The mutual relationship of each of these factors with the organizational identity has been studied through correlation research method. The results show that there is positive and significant relationship between the positive media attentions to the organizations, external recognition, internal communication, top management team, human resources management and internal communication with organizational identity.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>7</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2011</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>149</start>
					<end>166</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_23713_cafecb61272fb1e21597171f5fc5f942.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The comparison study for customer’s satisfaction in the Iranian banking system by using Mishra model</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mostafavi</namePart>
				<affiliation>استادیار، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصادی، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>مقاله حاضر به‎منظور بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر رضایت‎مندی ودرنتیجه توسعه وتعمق در ابعاد رضایتمندی بانک‎های دولتی و خصوصی تنظیم شده است.تجزیه و تحلیل دو مرحله‎ای عوامل رضایتمندی می‎تواند به مقایسه‎ی سطح رضایتمندی مشتریان منجر شود.این مقاله پنج بعد رضایتمندی را برای مشتریان بانک‎ها با استفاده از مدل میشرابه‎دست آورده است. آن ابعاد عبارتند از:خدمت محوری، سعی و کوشش، هواداری مشتری، تعهد و خوش برخوردی.در شهر مشهد سطح رضایتمندی برای هر دو سیستم بانکی دولتی و خصوصی از متوسط 50% بالاتر است. در میان ابعاد رضایتمندی در بانک‎های خصوصی بالاترین و پایین‎ترین نرخ به‎ترتیب به رفتار کارکنان بانک با مشتریان و توجه بانک‎ها به نیازهای مشتریان (80% و 8/54%) اختصاص دارد. در حالی‎که نرخ‎های مشابه برای بانک‎های دولتی به‎ترتیب 80% و 59% برای رفتار کارکنان بانک‎ها با مشتریان و اطلاع‎رسانی کارکنان به مشتریان است. در مجموع سطوح رضایتمندی مشتریان برای بانک‎های دولتی و خصوصی به‎ترتیب 22/25 و 14/24 محاسبه شده است.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>7</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2011</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>167</start>
					<end>184</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_23714_fd9ca9e8ac669658a53377858f052ac7.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>