<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2008</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Human, Social and Emotional Capital Management with Effective Approach to Career Success an empirical study in mellat bank:</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مدیریت سرمایه انسانی، اجتماعی و عاطفی با رویکردی اثربخش در موفقیت شغلی: مطالعه موردی بانک ملت</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">27939</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباسعلی   حاجی</FirstName>
					<LastName>کریمی</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرجان</FirstName>
					<LastName>فرجیان</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Up to now, most of the discussions about success and progress have been based on this issue that what could organization do for employee improvement. But according to environmental changes, career development literature has changed and the employee’s efforts for improving themselves became important. Indeed, human capital as a major factor for success and career advancement and social and emotional capital as other factors have been recognized lately. So, This paper investigated to identify the effect of human, social and emotional capital on managers’ career success. This study was guided to measure the mentioned variables through survey and correlation research method. For this reason a sample of 219 first-line manager of melat bank was examined. The research is based on structural equation modeling. The findings of this research indicated the effect of two capital(human and social capital) on managers’ career success. The authors interpreted the findings from the viewpoint of improving managers’ career success through increasing competency level of each capital.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">تاکنون اکثر گفتمان‌های تاریخی درباره موفقیت و پیشرفت بر مبنای این موضوع بوده است که سازمان‌ها چه کاری می‌توانند برای پیشرفت کارکنانشان انجام دهند. اما با توجه به تغییر و تحولات عصر حاضر، ادبیات پیشرفت شغلی نیز تغییر نموده و اینکه افراد برای موفقیت شغلی خود چه کاری می‌توانند انجام دهند، مورد توجه قرار گرفته است. در این راستا سالهاست که موضوع سرمایه انسانی به عنوان عاملی مهم و تاثیر گذار برای موفقیت و پیشرفت شغلی  و اخیرا نیز سرمایه اجتماعی و عاطفی نیز به عنوان عوامل دیگر در این زمینه شناسایی شده است. از این رو پژوهش حاضر با هدف شناسایی روابط متقابل بین سرمایه انسانی، اجتماعی و عاطفی و اثرات آنها بر موفقیت شغلی  انجام شده است. روش تحقیق مورد استفاده پیمایشی- همبستگی و بطور مشخص مبتنی بر مدل معادلات ساختاری می‌باشد. نتایج تحقیق حاضر نشان داد که  دو بعد سرمایه انسانی و اجتماعی بر طبق مدل تحلیل مسیر ارائه شده بر موفقیت شغلی مدیران تاثیر می‌گذارد. در پایان پیشنهاداتی برای مدیران سازمان ارائه گردید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل معادلات ساختاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">موفقیت شغلی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_27939_e7951f84d3e8eede63f7c870c902c64c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
