<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Review and Identify Problems of Compiling the Budget Settlement Report</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی و شناسایی مشکلات تدوین لایحۀ تفریغ بودجه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>349</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>372</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">59883</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2016.59883</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>غلام حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>نیکوکار</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشگاه امام حسین ‌(ع)، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرزانه</FirstName>
					<LastName>جلالی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری حسابداری، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>فلاح هروی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی گرایش مالی و اقتصادی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بیتا</FirstName>
					<LastName>مشایخی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه حسابداری، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>11</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>According to Article 55 of Islamic Republic of Iran`s constitution, preparing &quot;the budget settlement report&quot; by the Supreme Audit Court in order to enforce the monitoring and control of the financial activities of the government is essential.. Studies have shown that during the 105 years of legal budgeting in Iran, the executive branch has not been able to prepare the settlement of budget bill on time to offer to the supreme audit court the legislative branch. In this study, we are going to identify the codification problems of the budget settlement report. This study, using semi-structured interviews, contents analysis by specialists and experts in the field of accounting and budgeting in Iran. Many factors, respectively, related to the budget bill and the law of budgeting; executive issues, the concept of settlement funds; regulatory issues; governmental accounting problems; problems in the Court, challenges and behavioral and environmental concepts and issues are research and expertise</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">براساس اصل 55 قانون اساسی جمهوری اسلامی ایران، ضروری است دیوان محاسبات کشور به‌منظور حسن اجرای نظارت و کنترل فعالیت‏های مالی دولت، «گزارش تفریغ بودجه» تهیه کند. بررسی به‌عمل‌آمده نشان می‌دهد طی 105 سال بودجه‏ریزی قانونی در کشور ایران، قوۀ مجریه نتوانسته است لایحۀ تفریغ بودجه را به‌موقع تهیه، تنظیم و تقدیم دیوان محاسبات عمومی و قوۀ مقننه کند. در پژوهش حاضر قصد داریم مشکلات تدوین این لایحه را بررسی کنیم. تحقیق حاضر با استفاده از روش تحلیل محتوای مصاحبه‌های نیمه‌ساختار‌یافته با متخصصان و خبرگان حوزۀ حسابداری و بودجه در ایران صورت گرفته است. عوامل یادشده به‌ترتیب فراوانی از موضوع لایحه و قانون بودجه، مسائل دستگاه‏های اجرایی، مفهوم تفریغ بودجه، مسائل قانونی، مشکلات حسابداری دولتی، مسائل موجود در دیوان محاسبات، چالش‏ها و مفاهیم رفتاری و محیطی و مسئلۀ تحقیق و تخصص، ریشه گرفته‎اند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بودجه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">چالش‌های لایحۀ تفریغ بودجه‌</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">لایحۀ بودجه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">لایحۀ تفریغ بودجه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_59883_93765eed06520fd1e555c759dc472a80.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
