<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1397</YEAR>
<VOL>10</VOL>
<NO>2</NO>
<MOSALSAL>0</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>0</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تحلیل تطبیقی پروژه‌های آینده‌نگاری حکومت الکترونیکی در جهان به منظور الگوبرداری برای ایران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Comparative Study of E-government Foresight Projects in the World in Order to opt as the Benchmark for Iran</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: آینده‎نگاری دولت الکترونیکی در ایران هنوز انجام نشده و در سطح جهان نیز مدل مشخصی برای آن وجود ندارد. هدف محققان از اجرای این پژوهش، ارائه چارچوب آینده‌نگاری دولت الکترونیکی است. روش: پژوهش بر مبنای تحلیل تطبیقی و ترازیابی تجربه‎های جهانی به اجرا درآمد. با مرور مطالعات انجام شده در دهه اخیر، 18 پروژه آینده‎نگاری دولت الکترونیکی شناسایی شد. این پروژه‎ها با هشت شاخص، شامل روش‎ها، سطح پروژه، پشتیبانان، مشارکت‎کنندگان، اهداف پروژه، عوامل تأثیرگذار، عدم قطعیت‎ها و خروجی‎ها و نتایج، استخراج و تحلیل شدند. به کمک روش آنتروپی شانون به بررسی پشتیبانی کمی پژوهش‎ها و پروژه‎های گذشته از مؤلفه‎های هر یک از این شاخص‎ها پرداخته شده است. یافته‎ها: برای پروژه‎های حکومت الکترونیکی، افق زمانی کمتر از 10 سال مناسب است و سطح آینده‎نگاری ملی، بهترین پشتیبان برای اجرای این پروژه‎ دولت محسوب می‎شود. همچنین تعداد مشارکت‎کنندگان مناسب برای این پروژه، بین 51 تا 200 نفر است. روش پانل خبرگان، سناریونگاری و نقشه راه مناسب‎ترین روش‎ها هستند. مهم‎ترین عوامل تأثیرگذار بر اجرای این پروژه، عوامل فرهنگی ـ اجتماعی شناخته شدند و تدوین سناریو و ارائه چشم‌انداز مهم‎ترین خروجی‎ها بودند. نتیجه‎گیری: پیاده‎سازی پروژه‎های دولت الکترونیکی، به طرح آینده‎نگارانه و مبتنی بر اجماع ذی‎نفعان نیاز دارد. برای اجرای این پروژه، تجربه‎های جمع‎بندی شده سایر کشورها در این مقاله، راه‎گشایی برای سیاست‎گذاران و برنامه‎ریزان در ایران است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: In Iran, E-government foresight project hasn’t been done yet, and we couldn’t find a specific model for it in the world. The aim of this research is presenting an e-government foresight framework based on comparative analysis and benchmarkingin the world. Methods: having reviewed the related literature, 18 e-government foresight projects were identified all around the world among which 8 indicators were extracted. They include Methods, Project territory, Sponsors, Participants, Project Objectives, Influential factors, Uncertainties, and Outputs and Outcomes. Shannon entropy was used to determine these indicators among the pervious related literature. Results: The results showed that the best indicators for e-government foresight project are: time horizon for less than 10 years, Project territory: national, and the government as the important sponsor, participants: between 51 to 200 people. To do so, Expert Panel, Scenario Writing and Roadmap are considered as the suitable methods Cultural-Social factors are claimed to be the most important factors, and designing scenarios and providing vision are the most important Outputs. Conclusion: At the end, some suggestions are presented for e-government foresight project that address policy makers and planners in Iran. The implementation of e-government projects requires a futuristic plan based on stakeholder consensus. In order to implement this project, the experiences of other countries are discussed in this paper can be used as guidelines for policymakers and planners in Iran.  </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>187</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>208</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فاطمه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ثقفی</Family>
						<NameE>Fatemeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Saghafi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکده مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>fsaghafi@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نور محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>یعقوبی</Family>
						<NameE>Nour Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Yaghoubi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه مدیریت دولتی و فناوری اطلاعات، دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت، دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان، زاهدان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه مدیریت دولتی و فناوری اطلاعات،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>yaghoobi@hamoon.usb.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سعیده</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>انصاری</Family>
						<NameE>Saeideh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ansari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد گروه مدیریت دولتی و فناوری اطلاعات، دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت، دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان، زاهدان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد گروه مدیریت دولتی و فناوری اطلاعات،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sansari1368@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آینده‌نگاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دولت الکترونیکی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فراترکیب</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تحلیل تطبیقی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آنتروپی شانون</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>آیت‎اله‎زاده شیرازی، میرحسین؛ نرگسیان، عباس (1392). مدیریت ارتباط با شهروند: مطالعه رابطه آن با مشارکت، پاسخگویی عمومی و شفافیت در منطقه 3 شهر تهران. فصلنامه مدیریت دولتی، 5(2)، 143- 168.##ثقفی، فاطمه (1389). تبیین عوامل کلیدی موفقیت دولت الکترونیکی با رویکرد آینده‎شناسی. پایان‎نامه دکتری مهندسی صنایع. تهران: دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران.##ثقفی، فاطمه؛ ناصر اسلامی، فاطمه؛ علیجربان، معصومه (1389). مدل بلوغ دولت سیار، فصلنامه سیاست علم و فناوری، 3(2)، 49-64.##ثقفی، فاطمه؛ زارعی، بهروز؛ دیباج، سید مهدی (1390). مدل ملی توسعه حکومت الکترونیکی ایران. فصلنامه سیاست علم و فناوری، 4(2)، 27-40.##جمالی، قاسمعلی؛ نرگسیان، عباس؛ پیران نژاد، علی (1396). ارزیابی وضعیت شفافیت پورتال سازمان‎های دولتی (مطالعه موردی: وزارتخانه‎های ایران). فصلنامه مدیریت دولتی، 9(1)، 61-84.##خالقی، امیرحسین؛ پورعزت، علی اصغر؛ رهبر، فرهاد؛ قاضی نوری، سید سپهر (1392). تحلیل گفتمانی امر اخلاقی در سیاستگذاری حکومت الکترونیکی ایران. فصلنامه مدیریت دولتی، 5(4)، 79-100.##سرداری، احمد (1388). فرایند شکل‎گیری دولت الکترونیکی و راهبردهای آینده‎نگاری در ایران. فصلنامه چشم‎انداز مدیریت بازرگانی، 8(30)، 181-200.##طباطباییان، سید حبیب‎الله؛ قدیری. روح‎اله (1386). متغیرهای مؤثر بر انتخاب ابعاد در یک پروژه آینده‎نگاری. فصلنامه علوم مدیریت ایران، 2(7)، 55-80. عاملی، سعید رضا (1397). آینده‎پژوهی دولت الکترونیک، تهران: انتشارات امیرکبیر.##عبادی، نغمه (1395). بررسی وضعیت بلوغ حکمرانی الکترونیک در پورتال وزارتخانه‏های کشور. فصلنامه مدیریت دولتی، 8(3)، 487-510.##عبادی، نغمه؛ پیران نژاد، علی (1395). حکمرانی الکترونیک در شهرداری‎ها: مطالعه پورتال شهرداری‎های کشور. فصلنامه مدیریت دولتی، 6(2)، 265-288.##معاونت توسعه و مدیریت دولت الکترونیک. (1392). طرح تجارت الکترونیکی برای جمهوری اسلامی ایران، کمیته توسعه پشتیبانی و مدیریت سرمایه انسانی.##نامداریان، لیلا (1393). طراحی مدل ارزیابی اثرات آینده نگاری علم، فناوری و نوآوری (STI). رساله دکتری سیاست‎گذاری علم و فناوری. تهران: دانشگاه تربیت مدرس.## وزارت ارتباطات و فناوری اطلاعات (1393). ضوابط فنی اجرایی توسعه حکومت الکترونیکی (مصوب شورای عالی فناوری اطلاعات). تهران: انتشارات دبیرخانه شورای عالی فناوری اطلاعات.##References##Aichholzer, G., (2004). Scenarios of e-government in 2010 and implications for strategy design. Electronic Journal of e-Government, 2(1), 1-10.##Al-Jaber, H. (2013). Qatar e-Government 2020 Strategy. Minister of Information and Communications Technology, Qatar.##Amanatidou, E. (2014). Beyond the veil- the real value of Foresight. Technological Forecasting &amp; Social Change, 87, 274–291.##Ameli, S. R. (2018). E-government Futures Studies. Tehran, Amir Kabir Publishing.##(in Persian)##Bharti, A.K., &amp; Dwivedi, S. K. (2011). Design of an Analytical and Foresight Based Strategic Model for e-Governance in Public Transportation, Verlag Berlin Heidelberg, International Conference on Computational Intelligence and Information Technology, 615–620.##Codagnone, C., Wimmer, M.A. (2007). Roadmapping eGovernment Research. Visions and Measures towards Innovative Governments in 2020. Results from the EC-funded Project eGovRTD2020.##Denis, L., Cuhls, K., Keenan, M., &amp; Nedeva M. (2001). The practice of national Foresight programmes- A New Analytical Framework. Policy Research in Engineering Science &amp; Technology (PREST). https://cordis.europa.eu/project/rcn/93842_en.html.##Deputy Director for Electronic Government Development and Administration Development, (2013). Electronic Commerce Plan for the Islamic Republic of Iran, President of the Development Assistance and Human Capital Management Department. (in Persian)##Di Malo, A., Kreizman, G., Harris, R.G., Rust, B., &amp; Sood, R. (2005). Government in 2020: Taking the Long View, Gartner Industry Research.##Ebadi, N. (2016). The Maturity Level of E-Governance in Iran Ministry Portals. Journal of public administration, 8(3), 487-510. (in Persian)##Ebadi, N., &amp; Piranejad, A. (2014). E-Governance in Municipalities: Studying the Iranian Municipalities’ Portals. Journal of Public Administration, 6(2), 265-288. (in Persian)##European Commission, (2004). E-Government in the EU in the next decade. The vision and key challenges, DG JRC, Institute for Prospective Technological Studies, Technical Report EUR 21376 EN.##Gavigan, P. J. &amp; Fabiana Scapolo, (2000). FOREN Workpackage 3, IPTS, Seville, December.##Horton, A. (1999). A simple guide to successful foresight. Foresight, 1(1), 5-9.##Ian, M., &amp; Keenan, M. (2003). Organising a Technology Foresight Exercise. Technology Foresight for Organizers, Ankara, Turkey, 8-12.##Info-communications Development Authority of Singapore (2006). From Integrating Service to integrating Government- Report by the iGov2010 Project Steering Committee. Singapore: Info-communications Development Authority.##Information and Communication Ministry (2014). Technical regulations for the development of egovernment (approved by the Supreme Council of Information Technology), publications of the Secretariat of the Supreme Council of Information Technology. (in Persian)##Information Society and Media Directorate-General eGovernment Unit, (2006). A roadmap for Inclusive eGovernment: towards making all citizens, and especially disadvantaged groups major beneficiaries of eGovernment, European Commission.##Jamali, Gh., Nargesian, A., &amp; Pirannejad, A. (2017). Evaluation of Transparency of Governmental Portals (Ministries of Iran). Journal of public administration, 9(1), 61-84. (in Persian)##Khaleghi, A., Pourezzat, A., Rahbar, F., Ghazinoory, S. (2014). Discourse analysis of the Ethical in IRI policy documents on e-Governance. Journal of Public Administration, 5(4), 79-100. (in Persian)##Martin, B. R. (1995). Foresight in science and technology. Technology analysis &amp; strategic management, 7(2), 139-168.##Miles, I., &amp; Keenan, M. (2003). Organizing a Technology Foresight Exercise.Technology Foresight for Organizers, 8-12 December, Ankara, Turkey.##Ministry of Government Administration and Home Affairs, (2007). Master Plan for the Next Generation e-Governmant in Korea, Korea: Ministry of Government Administration and Home Affairs.##Ministry of Interior and Kingdom Relations (2005). Scenario session Report. E-Government beyond 2005. The Netherlands, Zenc.##Misuraca, G., Broster, D., Centeno, C., Punie, Y., Lampathaki, F., Charalabidis, Y., Askounis, D., Osimo, D., Szkuta, K., &amp; Bicking, M. (2010). Envisioning Digital Europe 2030: Scenarios for ICT in Future Governance and Policy Modelling, Publications Offie of the European Union.##Namdarian, L. (2014). Designing a model to evaluate the impact of science, technology and innovation (STI) foresight. PhD Thesis in Science and Technology Policy making, Faculty of management and economy, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran.##(in Persian)##Nargesian, A., &amp; Shirazi, A. (2013). Citizen Relationship Management: studying the relation with participation, accountability &amp; transparency. Journal of Public Administration, 5(2), 143-168. (in Persian)##National Computer Center &amp; National IT Industry Promotion Agency (2012). Electronic Government Development &amp; Strategy- Assessment, Research, Strategy, Implementation Plan Philippines.##Nordfors, L., Ericson, B., and Lindell, H. (2006). Framtidens e-förvaltning. Scenarier 2016, VINNOVA Rapport VR.##Nordfors, L., Ericson, B., Lindell, H. &amp; Lapidus, J. (2009). E-Government of Tomorrow- Future Scenarios for 2020, VINNOVA Report VR.##Nordfors, L., Ericson, B., Lindell, H., &amp; Lapidus, J. (2009). E-Government of Tomorrow - Future scenarios for 2020, ViNNoVa –Verket för innovationssystem /Swedish Governmental Agency for Innovation System.##Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) Korea Policy Centre, (2012). Advancing Indonesian Local E-governmentChallenges, Opportunities, and Strategic Roadmap, Korea Policy Centre.##Polyzos, Y. N., Zalisova, I., Wimmer, M.A., Osimo D. (2010). CROSSROAD-A Participative Roadmap for ICT Research in Electronic Governance and Policy Modelling, European Commission, https://cordis.europa.eu/project/rcn/93842_en.html.##Popper, R. (2009). Mapping foresight, European foresight monitoring network.##Rowley, J. (2011). E-Government stakeholders-Who are they and what do they want? International Journal of Information Management, (31), 53–62.##Saghafi, F. (2011). Clarification of E-government Critical Success Factors with Future Study Approach. A Thesis Submitted in Partial Fulfillment of the Requirement for the Degree of Doctor of Philosophy in Industrial Engineering, Iran University of Science and Technology, Tehran, Iran. (in Persian)##Saghafi, F., Nasereslami, F, &amp; Alijerban, M. (2010). Mgovernmnet maturity model. Journal of Science and Technology Policy, 3(2), 49-64. (in Persian)##Saghafi, F., Zareri, B., Dibaj, S.M. (2011). National Egovernment development model. Journal of Science and Technology Policy, 4(2), 27-40. (in Persion)##Sardari, A. (2009). The Formation Process of E-Government &amp; Foresight Strategies in Iran. Journal of Business Management, 8(30), 181-200. (in Persian)##Tabatabaeian, S.H., &amp; Ghadiri, R. (2007). Variables affecting dimension selection in a foresight Project. Journal of Management Science of Iran, 2(7), 55-80. (in Persian)##Tejasvee, S., &amp; Sarangdevot, D. (2011). Integration of ICT and E-Governance in Rajasthan. Indian Journal of Computer Science and Engineering, 2(2), 177-183.##UNDESA, (2014). United Nations e-government survey 2014 e-governmen for the future we want, UN Department of Economic and Social Affairs. https://publicadministration. un. org/egovkb/portals/egovkb/documents/un/2014-survey/e-gov_complete_survey-2014.pdf##VERVA, (2007). Ett nationellt informationssystem. Medborgares och företags tillgång till elektronisk samhällsservice, VERVA Report.##Voros, J. (2003). A generic foresight process framework. foresight, 5(3), 10-21.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بازنمایی سیستم تاراج نوین در قالب سوداگری اداری</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Recall of New Spoil System as Administrative Trader</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: پژوهش حاضر با هدف بازشناسی انواع رفتارهای سوداگرانه اداری و ارائه دسته‎بندی دقیق از این نوع رفتارها، اجرا شده است. روش: رهیافت پژوهش کیفی بوده و استراتژی پژوهش مبتنی بر نظریه‎پردازی داده‎بنیاد است. اطلاعات پژوهش حاضر از طریق مصاحبه نیمه ‎ساختاریافته گردآوری شد و تجزیه و تحلیل اطلاعات با استفاده از روش استراوس و کوربین و مدل پارادایمی انجام گرفت. در این پژوهش، نمونه‎گیری به روش نظری و هدفمند بود که بر مبنای آن، 16 مصاحبه با مدیران، اعضای هیئت علمی و خبرگان سازمانی که در زمینه سوداگری دارای تجربه و دانش بودند، برگزار شد. یافته‎ها: تحلیل داده‎های به ‎دست آمده از مصاحبه‎ها طی فرایند کدگذاری باز، محوری و انتخابی، به طراحی مدل نظریه سوداگری سازمانی بر اساس چهار مفهوم علی، سه مفهوم زمینه‎ای، چهار مفهوم مداخله‎گر، سه استراتژی کنش، هفت استراتژی واکنش و سه پیامد منجر شد که با ‎‎استفاده از روش معادلات ساختاری، مدل یاد شده به تأیید رسید. نتیجه‎گیری: نتایج نشان داد سوداگری در سازمان‎ها، سازوکارهای انسانی، اجتماعی و سازمانی را تحت تأثیر خود قرار داده و به توسعه‎نیافتگی آنها منجر می‎شود. هدف: پژوهش حاضر با هدف بازشناسی انواع رفتارهای سوداگرانه اداری و ارائه دسته‎بندی دقیق از این نوع رفتارها، اجرا شده است. روش: رهیافت پژوهش کیفی بوده و استراتژی پژوهش مبتنی بر نظریه‎پردازی داده‎بنیاد است. اطلاعات پژوهش حاضر از طریق مصاحبه نیمه ‎ساختاریافته گردآوری شد و تجزیه و تحلیل اطلاعات با استفاده از روش استراوس و کوربین و مدل پارادایمی انجام گرفت. در این پژوهش، نمونه‎گیری به روش نظری و هدفمند بود که بر مبنای آن، 16 مصاحبه با مدیران، اعضای هیئت علمی و خبرگان سازمانی که در زمینه سوداگری دارای تجربه و دانش بودند، برگزار شد. یافته‎ها: تحلیل داده‎های به ‎دست آمده از مصاحبه‎ها طی فرایند کدگذاری باز، محوری و انتخابی، به طراحی مدل نظریه سوداگری سازمانی بر اساس چهار مفهوم علی، سه مفهوم زمینه‎ای، چهار مفهوم مداخله‎گر، سه استراتژی کنش، هفت استراتژی واکنش و سه پیامد منجر شد که با ‎‎استفاده از روش معادلات ساختاری، مدل یاد شده به تأیید رسید. نتیجه‎گیری: نتایج نشان داد سوداگری در سازمان‎ها، سازوکارهای انسانی، اجتماعی و سازمانی را تحت تأثیر خود قرار داده و به توسعه‎نیافتگی آنها منجر می‎شود.  </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: The purpose of this study is to identify the types of administrative speculative behaviors and provide a precise classification of these behaviors. Methods: The research ‎approach is qualitative and the strategy applied in this research is based on the grounded theory. Semi-structured ‎interviews were used to collect the data and they were then analyzed using Strauss and Corbin ‎methods and the Paradigm model. Based on judgmental and snowball sampling 16 managers, faculty members and organizational experts with expertise in the related field of study were selected Results: Analysis of the data from the interviews resulted in the designing of a model of ‎organizational negotiation through ‎open, axial and selective coding process. The model was developed based on four causality concepts, three ‎conceptual concepts, four meddlesome concepts, three ‎action strategies, seven response strategies and three consequences. Then, using the structural equation method, the model was ‎approved. Conclusion: The results showed that commercialization in the ‎organizations can affect human, social and organizational ‎mechanisms and lead to a self-sustaining and immature organization.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>209</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>226</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی اصغر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>پورعزت</Family>
						<NameE>Ali Asghar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Pourezzat</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>pourezzat@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قربانی</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ghorbani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ghorbani02@pnu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>جهان</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عبدی</Family>
						<NameE>Jahan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Abdi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه مدیریت، پردیس دانشگاهی باختر، ایلام، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه مدیریت، پردیس دانشگاهی باختر،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>j_abdi_p@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فاطمه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نجارشمس</Family>
						<NameE>Fatemeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Najjar Shams</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت، پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت، پیام نور، تهران، ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>&lrm;ghorbanio2@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سوداگری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سیستم تاراج نوین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>منافع ملی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فساد اداری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عملکرد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>الوانی، سیدمهدی؛ قربانی‎زاده، وجه‎الله؛ اسلام‎پناه، مهدی (1396).اولویت‎بندی معیارهای تأثیرگذار بر بازدارندگی فساد اداری با اتکا به رهنمودهای اسلامی.مدیریت دولتی، 9 (2)، 283- 306.##پورعزت، علی‌اصغر (1387). مبانی دانش اداره دولت و حکومت. تهران: انتشارات سمت.##پورعزت، علی‌اصغر (1391). اصول مدیریت دولتی. تهران: انتشارات سمت.##درویش، حسن؛ عظیمی زاچکانی، فاطمه (1395). بررسی تأثیر شفافیت سازمانی بر کاهش فساد اداری با میانجی‌گری اعتماد سازمانی. مجله علمی پژوهشی مدیریت دولتی، 8 (1)، 153- 166.##ربیعی، علی؛ آصف، هاجر (1391). نقش فرهنگ سازمانی در پیشگیری از بروز فساد اداری. فصلنامه مدیریت دولتی، 4(10)، 45- 58.##سعادت، اسفندیار (1390). مدیریت منابع انسانی. تهران: انتشارات سمت.##Alvani, S., Ghorbanizadeh, V., Eslampanah, M. (2017). Prioritizing the Criteria for Enhancing the Corruption of the Office of Corruption, Using the Relativism of Islamic Prophecy. Scientific Journal of Tehran Public Administration, 9(4), 283-306. (in Persian)##Bureau of Surveys (2014). Good governance is the foundation of development. By the efforts of Ahmad Mardi and Jafar Kheirkhahian (editors), the Islamic Consultative Assembly, the Research Center.##Chin, W. W. (1998). The partial least squares approach to structural equation modeling. Modern methods for business research, 295(2), 295-336.##Corbin, J., &amp; Strauss, A. (2008). Basics of Qualitative Research: Techniques and Procedures for Developing Grounded Theory (3rd ed), CA: Sage.## Darvish, H., Azimi, F. (2016). Investigating the Effect of Organizational Transparency on Reducing Corruption by Mediating Organizational Trust. Journal of Public Administration, 8(1), 153-166. (in Persian)##Denhardt, R. B. &amp; Denhardt, J.V. (2000). The New Public Services: Serving Rather than Steering. Public Administation Review, 60(6), 549-559.##Dehkordi, L. F., Sarlak, M. A., Pourezzat, A.A., Ghorbani, A(2012). A Comprehensive Conceptual Framework for the E-Government Realization. Australian Journal of Basic and Applied Sciences, 6(8), 50-64.##Feeley, T. H (2002). Comment on Halo Effects in Rating and Evaluations of Communication Instruction. Communication Education, 5(1), 236-255.##Frederickson, G. H., &amp; Frederickson, G.D (1995). Public perceptions of Ethics in Government: The Problems of Distance and Role Differentiation. The Annals of American Academy of Political and Socail Science, 537, 163-172.##Frederickson, G. H (1999). Ethics and New Managerialism. Public Administration &amp; Management. An Interactive Journal, 4(2), 299-324.##Hallack, J., Poisson, M (2007). Corrupt schools, corrupt university. International institute for educational planing, in UNESCO.##Hughes, O. E (2003). Public Management &amp; Administration: An Introduction. (Second edition), Macmillan Press LTD.##Gefen D., Straub, W (2005). A practical guid to factorial using pls-graph: tototrial and annotated example. Communication of the AIS, 16(5), 91-109.##Kuhalman, T.M. (2008). Understanding corruption in organization development and empirical assessment of and action model. Journal of business ethics, 82, 447-495.##Leary, M. R., &amp; Kowalski, R. M (1990). Impression Management: A Literature Review and Two Component Model. Psychological Bulletin, 107, 34-47.##Mosher, F. C (1974). Watergate, Implications for Responsible Government. In Jay M. Shafritz &amp; Albert C. Hyde (Eds.). 1997. Classics of Public Administration. Fourth Edition. Harcourt, 420-431.##Pourezzat, A.A (2008). Principles of Knowledge Governance and Government.Samt publication. (in Persian)##Pourezzat, A.A(2012). Principles of Governmental management. Principles of Knowledge Governance and Government.Samt publication. (in Persian)##Rabiei, A., &amp; Asef, H. (2012). The role of organizational culture in the prevention of corruption. Journal of Public Administration, 4(10), 45-58. (in Persian)##Rao, A., Schmidt, S. M., &amp; Murray, L. H (1995). Upward Impression Management: Goals, Influence Strategies, and Consequences. Human Relations, 48(2), 67-147.##Seadat, E (2010). Human Resources Management. Tehran. Post Office. (in Persian)##Simeon, H. (2004). Compilation of Lawson graft and corruption. Office of ombudsman. Manila, PhilipPhines.##Turban, E., &amp; Chaffey, D (2002). Electronic commerce, a managerial perspective. 2nd ed Prentice Hall.##Vinzi, V.E., Chin, W.W., Henseler J. W (2010). Handbook of Partial Least Squares. Berlin.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>آسیب‌شناسی نظام مدیریت استراتژیک در یک سازمان عمومی (رویکرد ترکیبی)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Strategic Management Framework Diagnosis in Public Organization (Multi-Method Approach)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: هدف اصلی تحقیق حاضر، ارائه مدل آسیب‎‎شناسی نظام مدیریت استراتژیک بر اساس تحلیل شکاف در سازمان‎های عمومی است. بر خلاف مطالعات پیشین در حوزه آسیب‎‎شناسی سازمانی، در این مطالعه به‎ طور مشخص نظام مدیریت استراتژیک سازمان تحلیل و عارضه‎‎یابی می‎شود.
روش: رویکرد پژوهش ترکیبی است و از هر دو نوع شیوه‎ کمی و کیفی برای جمع‎‎آوری و تحلیل داده‎ها استفاده شده است.
یافته‎ها: نتایج مورد انتظار تحقیق در بخش مفهومی به ارائه مدل آسیب‎‎شناسی نظام مدیریت استراتژیک در سازمان‎های عمومی منجر شد و در بعد عملی، بر اساس نتایج پژوهش مشخص شد که این سازمان در قسمت تدوین در محدوده شکاف کم بوده و در قسمت‌های مدل، اجرا و کنترل، در حوزه شکاف زیاد قرار گرفته است.
نتیجه‎گیری: . نتایج این پژوهش در ارائه هر چه بهتر نظام مدیریت استراتژیک پنج‎ساله دوم این سازمان به‎کار برده شده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: The main concern of this paper is to present a customized method for diagnosing the strategic management status of a given company based on the gap analysis. Unlike the previous studies in organizational diagnosis (OD), current research specifically investigates the strategic management framework (SMF) within the public organizations.
Methods: This study is conducted based on multi-method approach through which both quantitative and qualitative data were gathered and analyzed. The needed data were collected from key managers and executives involved in strategic management of the intended organization and also the related high level documents, open interviews, questionnaire and group discussions. The collected data were primarily analyzed using required calculative techniques and finalized in focus groups including the selected key managers and the consulting team.
Results: The conceptual finding of this study is the exclusive model of SMFD that could be practiced in other similar organizations and the practical findings indicate a small gap in developing strategies and the presence of a significant gap in other phases of strategic management framework (SMF) in the case organization such as model, implementation, and control.
Conclusion: The outcomes of this research served better strategic management formulation to be implemented for the next 5-year plan in the intended organization.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>227</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>250</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>هاشم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>آقازاده</Family>
						<NameE>Hashem</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Aghazade</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشکده مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>haghazade@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ابوالملوکی</Family>
						<NameE>Hassan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Abolmolouki</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری سیاست‎گذاری بازرگانی، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری سیاست‎گذاری بازرگانی، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>abolmolouki@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آسیب‌شناسی سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آسیب‎شناسی نظام مدیریت استراتژیک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تحلیل شکاف</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سازمان عمومی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>ابزری، مهدی؛ شائمی، علی؛ طالبی، هوشنگ؛ عبدالمنافی، سعید (1390). بررسی شکاف بین وضعیت موجود و مطلوب مدیریت دانش در صنعت خودروی ایران. فصلنامه مدیریت دولتی، 3(6)، 19-52.##اعرابی، سید محمد؛ حقیقی، مهدی (1383). الگوی هماهنگی تلاطم محیطی و استراتژی سازمانی، فصلنامه مطالعات مدیریت بهبود و تحول، 11 (41 و 42)، 54-78.##الوانی، سید مهدی؛ شریف‌زاده، فتاح (1390). فرایند خط‎مشی‌گذاری عمومی (چاپ هشتم). تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی.##توکلی، غلامرضا؛ رمضان، مجید؛ معیا، عباس (1394). تحلیل رابطه ظرفیت تغییر سازمانی و تفکر استراتژیک، فصلنامه مطالعات مدیریت بهبود و تحول، 24 (77)، 153-169.##رضائیان، علی؛ اسمعیلی گیوی، حمید رضا؛ ابراهیمی، عباس (1388). ارائه الگوی شکل‌گیری رهبری کاریزماتیک در سازمان از دیدگاه مدیریت برنامه‌ریزی راهبردی، فصلنامه مدیریت دولتی، 1(3)، 35-50.##عباسی، عباس؛ معتضدیان، رسول؛ میرزایی، محمد (1395). بررسی موانع اجرای خط‎مشی‌های عمومی در سازمان‎های دولتی. پژوهش‎های مدیریت منابع سازمانی، 6(2)، 49-69.‎##فرهنگی، علی اکبر؛ سلطانی‎فر، محمد؛ محکی، علی اصغر؛ دانائی، ابوالفضل (1392). معرفی نظام ارزیابی عملکرد مبتنی بر نقشه راهبردی (مطالعه موردی: روزنامه همشهری). فصلنامه مدیریت دولتی، 5(4)، 175-200.##محمودزاده، ابراهیم (1385). طرح‎ریزی استراتژیک ـ فقط یک گام تا اجرا. فصلنامه مطالعات مدیریت بهبود و تحول، 13(49)، 39-55.##منوریان، عباس (1369). فرایند برنامه‎ریزی استراتژیک برای سازمان‎های دولتی و غیرانتفاعی. فصلنامه فرایند مدیریت و توسعه، ۴ (۳)، ۶۰-۸۱.##منوریان، عباس؛ آقازاده، ‎هاشم؛ شهامت‎نژاد، مینا (1391). سنجش تفکر استراتژیک در مدیران شهرداری تهران. فصلنامه مدیریت بازرگانی، 4(12)، 129-146.##نیکوکار، غلامحسین؛ علیدادی، یاسر (1388). آسیب‎شناسی سازمانی و الگوهای آن (جست‎وجویی در الگوهای علی بورک ـ لیتوین)، تحلیلی در کاربرد آسیب‎شناسی در سازمان‎های نظامی. فصلنامه علوم انسانی دانشگاه امام حسین، (75) 139-166.##References##Abassi, A., Motazadyian, R., Mirzaee, M. (2016). Investigation the barriers of Public Policy Implementation in Governmental Organizations. Organizational Resources Management Researchs, 6(2), 49-69. (in Persian)##Abzari, M., Shaemi, A., Talebi, H., Abdolmanafi, S. (2011). A Study of gap between current and ideal State of Knowledge Management in Automobile Industry of Iran. Iranian Public Administration, 3(6), 19-52. (in Persian)##Andrews, R., Boyne, G. A., Law, J., &amp; Walker, R. M. (2009). Strategy, structure and process in the public sector: a test of the Miles and Snow model. Public Administration, 87(4), 732-749.##Alvani, SM., Sharif zadeh, F. (2011). Public Policy making process. 8th edition. Atu Publications. (in Persian)##Arabi, S., Haghighi, M. (2004). The pattern for accordance between environmental turbulence and strategies of organizations. Management Studies in Development and Evolution, 11(41/42), 54-78. (in Persian)##Balm, G.J. (1996). Benchmarking and Gap analysis: what is the next milestone? Benchmarking for Quality Management &amp; Technology, 3(4), 28 – 33.##Balogun, J., Hailey, H. V., &amp; Gustafsson, S. (2015). Exploring strategic change. Pearson Education.##Barney, J. B., &amp; Mackey, A. (2016). Text and metatext in the resource‐based view. Human Resource Management Journal, 26(4), 369-378.##Bloor, M., Frankland, J., Thomas, M., Robson, K. (2001). Focus groups in social research. London: Sage Publications.##Brodeur,M. (2008).The Role of organizational Diagnosis in organizational learning. Antioch New England graduate school, Journal of counseling and development, 71(6), 642-650,200##Bryson, J. M. (1988). A strategic planning process for public and non-profit organizations. Long range planning, 21(1), 73-81.##Bryson, J. M. (2004). What to do when stakeholders matter: stakeholder identification and analysis techniques. Public management review, 6(1), 21-53.##Buchanan, S., &amp; Cousins, F. (2012). Evaluating the strategic plans of public libraries: An inspection-based approach. Library &amp; Information Science Research, 34(2), 125-130.##Burton, R. M., &amp; Obel, B. (2004). Strategic organizational diagnosis and design: The dynamics of fit (Vol. 4). Springer Science &amp; Business Media.##Creswell, J. W., &amp; Clark, V. L. P. (2017). Designing and conducting mixed methods research. Sage publications.##Cummings, T. G., &amp; Worley, C. G. (2014). Organization development and change. Cengage learning.##Dimitriadis, S., &amp; Stevens, E. (2008). Integrated customer relationship management for service activities: an internal/external Gap model. Managing Service Quality: An International Journal, 18(5), 496-511.##Farhangi, A., Soltani Far, M., Mahaki, A., Danaei, A. (2013). The Introduction of an Appraisal System’s Performance based on a Strategic Map (Case Study: Hamshahri newspaper). Iranian Public Administration, 5(4), 175-200. (in Persian)##Fred, R. D., &amp; Forest, R. D. (2016). Strategic Management: A Competitive Advantage Approach. Concepts and Cases.##Grant, R. M. (2016). Contemporary strategy analysis: Text and cases edition. John Wiley &amp; Sons.##Graves, S., &amp; Moran, J. (1994). The pitfalls associated with strategic and operational planning. In the Quality Management Forum, 20(4), 1-4.##Hambrick, D. C., &amp; Fredrickson, J. W. (2001). Are you sure you have a strategy? The Academy of Management Executive, 15(4), 48-59.##Kaufman, R., &amp; Russell, J. D. (2001). Strategic thinking: A guide to identifying and solving problems. Performance Improvement, 40(1), 49-50.##Liamputtong, P. (2011). Focus group methodology: Principle and practice. Sage Publications.##Llewellyn, S., &amp; Tappin, E. (2003). Strategy in the public sector: management in the wilderness. Journal of management studies, 40(4), 955-982.##Mahmoodzadeh, E. (2006). Strategic Planning: An Iterative Model. Management Studies in Development and Evolution, 13(49), 39-55. (in Persian)##Mintzberg, H. (1994). The fall and rise of strategic planning. Harvard Business Review, 72(1), 107-114.##Monavarian, A. (1990). Strategic planning for public organizations. Journal of Management and Development Process, 4 (3), 60-81. (in Persian)##Monavarian, A., Aghazade, H., ShahamatNejad, M. (2012). Measuring the Strategic Thinking of the Managers of Tehran&#039;s Municipality. Iranian Business Management, 4(12), 129-146. (in Persian)##Moore, M., &amp; Khagram, S. (2004). On creating public value: What business might learn from government about strategic management. Corporate Social Responsibility Initiative Working Paper, No. 3.##Moratalla, J., de Castro, V., Sanz, M. L., &amp; Marcos, E. (2012, July). A Gap-Analysis-Based Framework for Evolution and Modernization: Modernization of Domain Management at Red. es. In Srii global conference (srii), 2012 annual (pp. 343-352). IEEE.##Nikoukar, G.H., Alidadi, Y. (2010). Organizational Diagnosis models. Journal of social science 17 (75), 139-166. (in Persian)##Porter, M. E. (2011). Competitive advantage of nations: creating and sustaining superior performance (Vol. 2). Simon and Schuster.##Rezaeyan, A., Esmaely Givi, H., Ebrahimi, A. (2009). Presentation of &quot;Formation of Charismatic Leadership in Organization&quot; Model Based on Strategic Planning Management. Iranian Public Administration, 1(3), 35-50. (in Persian)##Ring, P. S., &amp; Perry, J. L. (1985). Strategic management in public and private organizations: Implications of distinctive contexts and constraints. Academy of management review, 10(2), 276-286.##Rumelt, R. P., Schendel, D. E., &amp; Teece, D. J. (Eds.). (1995). Fundamental issues in strategy: A research agenda. Rutgers University Press.##Tavakoli, G., Ramezan, M., Moayya, A. (2015). The Analysis of Relationship between Organizational Capacity for Change and Strategic Thinking. Management Studies in Development and Evolution, 24(77), 153-169. (in Persian)##Texas, A. (2004). Gap Analysis Overview of identifying Gaps Process. Middle Level School Principal Seminar.##Wheelen, T. L., Hunger, J. D., Hoffman, A. N., &amp; Bamford, C. E. (2017). Strategic management and business policy. Pearson.##Whittemore, R., Chase, S. K., &amp; Mandle, C. L. (2001). Validity in qualitative research. Qualitative health research, 11(4), 522-537.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>آسیب‎شناسی سیاست‎گذاری تولید محتوای فضای مجازی در ایران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigating the laws and Regulations in Monitoring Content Production in Cyberspace in Iran</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: هدف پژوهش حاضر شناخت و بررسی آسیب‌های فرایند سیاست‎گذاری نظارت بر مدیریت تولید محتوا در فضای مجازی ایران است. روش: این پژوهش با استفاده از رویکرد کیفی اجرا شده و داده‎های آن از طریق برگزاری مصاحبه‌های نیمه ‌ساختاریافته با 10 نفر از خبرگان حوزه قوانین و مقررات فضای مجازی که دست کم پنج سال سابقه فعالیت در این حوزه را داشتند، جمع‎آوری شده است. همچنین روش نمونه‌گیری، گلوله برفی بوده است. یافته‎ها: با استفاده از روش تجزیه و تحلیل مضمون متن مصاحبه‌ها، آسیب‌های فرایند سیاست‎گذاری مدیریت و نظارت بر تولید محتوا در فضای مجازی، شناسایی شد و در هفت دسته کلی قرار گرفت. نتیجه‎گیری: آسیب‌های شناسایی شده که به هفت طبقه دسته‎بندی شدند، عبارت‌اند از: آسیب‌های سیستم نظارتی، سیاست‌های تولید محتوا، حمایت از تولید محتوا، امنیت و حریم خصوصی، عوامل و زیرساخت‌های فرهنگی، ضعف در تصمیم‌گیری و زیرساخت‌های فنی.  </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: The purpose of this study was to identify and investigate the problems of the policy-making process of monitoring content production management in cyberspace in Iran. Methods: This research was carried out using a qualitative approach by conducting semi-structured interviews with ten experts in the domain of cyberspace laws and regulations that have had an experience of at least five years of activity in this area. The snowball sampling method was used to decide over the participants of this study. Results: Content analysis was used to identify the problems of the policy-making management process and monitoring the content production in cyberspace. Then, the results were classified into seven general categories. Conclusion: These seven categories include problems of the regulatory system, content production policies, supporting content generation, security and privacy, cultural factors and infrastructures, weaknesses in decision making and technical infrastructure.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>251</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>268</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شریفی</Family>
						<NameE>Seyyed Mahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sharifi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار مدیریت رسانه، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار مدیریت رسانه، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.sharifee58@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>بیتا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مرزبان</Family>
						<NameE>Bita</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Marzban</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد علوم ارتباطات اجتماعی ـ شاخه مدیریت رسانه، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد علوم ارتباطات اجتماعی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>marzbanarta@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سمیه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>لبافی</Family>
						<NameE>Somaye</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Labafi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مدیریت رسانه، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مدیریت رسانه، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>s.labafi@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آسیب‌شناسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سیاست‎گذاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فضای مجازی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قوانین و مقررات</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت تولید محتوا</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>باقری، محمود (۱۳۹۲). چالش‎های اعمال حقوقی فضای مجازی. فصلنامه برنامه‎ریزی و بودجه، 16 (۱)، ۲۷-۴۶.##حاجی علی محمدی، مقصود؛ موذن زادگان، حسن علی؛ رضوی فرد، بهزاد (۱۳۹۴). تولید، ارسال و مورد معامله قرار دادن آثار مستهجن و مبتذل در فضای مجازی. پایان‎نامه کارشناسی ارشد. تهران، دانشکده حقوق و علوم سیاسی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی.##روشندل اربطانی، طاهر؛ کوهی، احمد (۱۳۹۱). هم‎گرایی رسانه‎ای (رابطه تولید محتوای اینترنتی توسط کاربران و نحوه تماشای تلویزیون).مطالعات فرهنگ ـ ارتباطات، 13(20)، ۱۴۳-۱۶۸.##روشندل اربطانی، طاهر؛ رضی، حسین؛ لبافی، سمیه (۱۳۹۱). بررسی آسیب‎شناسانه فرایند سیاست‎گذاری در سازمان صدا و سیمای جمهوری اسلامی ایران. مجله مدیریت دولتی، (۱۰)، ۷۹-۱۰۰.##شورای عالی انقلاب فرهنگی. (۱۳۹۲). مقررات و ضوابط شبکه‌های اطلاع‌رسانی رایانه‌ای. مرکز پژوهش‌های مجلس شورای اسلامی. مشاهده ‌شده در ۳ دی ۱۳۹۲. قابل دسترس به آدرس:                                                                                          www.rc.majlis.ir##قانون جرائم رایانه‌ای. (1392). بازبینی‌شده در ۷ دی ۱۳۹۲. قابل دسترس به آدرس:                    www.cyberpolice.com##هاتف، مهدی (۱۳95). چالش‎ها و چشم‎اندازهای امنیت در فضای مجازی. ماهنامه توسعه انسانی پلیس، ۶(22)، 93- ۱۱۷.##References##Albarran, A. (2008). Hand book of media management and economic, Lawrence Erlbaum Associates. Publishers, London.##Albarran, A. (2014). Assessing the Field of Media Management and Economics Research: Looking Back, Looking Forward. Palabra Clave, 17(4), 1025-1040.##Amstutz, A., Amstutz, M. (2011). Mechanisms of Evolution for a Law of the Future. In: Sam Müller/Stavros Zouridis/Morly Frishman/Laura Kistemaker (eds.). The Law of the Future and the Future of Law, 395–405.##Anderson, C. (2014). Human aggression. Annual Review of Psychology, (53), 27–51.##‌Bagheri, M. (2013). The Challenges of Cyberspace Laws. Quarterly Journal of Planning and Budget, 16 (1), 27-46. (in Persian)##Baldwin, L. (2012). Hydropedological functional units. AGU Annual Fall Conference Proceedings. March 23th, Netherlands.##Bruns, A. (2012). Quantitative Approaches to Comparing Communication Patterns on Twitter,journal of technology in human services, (30),160-185.                               ##Chik, M., Warren, B. (2010). Customary Internet-ional Law”: Creating a Body of Customary Law for Cyberspace. Part I: Developing Rules for Transitioning Custom into Law. Computer Law &amp; Security Review, 26 (1), 3–22.##Cottle, S. (2003). Media organization and production, mapping the field, Sage, CA, 23-25.##Denardis, L. (2014). Global War for Internet Governance. Yale University Press News.##Haji Ali Mohammadi, M., Moazenzadegan, H., Razavifard, B. (2015). Producing, sending and treating pornographic and pornographic works in cyberspace. Master&#039;s Thesis. Tehran, Faculty of Law and Political Science, Allameh Tabataba&#039;i University. (in Persian)##Hatef. M. (2016). Challenges and security perspectives in cyberspace. Human Development Policies Monthly, 6 (22), 93-117. (in Persian)##Kwach, K. &amp; Ronstel, T. (1999). The context of the regulation of TV broadcasting in East Asia. Gazette, 61(3-4), 255–273.##Labafi, S. (2017). Advertising in Social Media: A theme analysis of networking capability, image transferability, and personal extensibility European Media Management Association (EMMA) conference, Ghent University, Belgium.##Lehman, D. (1993). Continuing the traditional of research on war: The Persian Gulf war, journal of social issues, (49), 1-14.##Participative Web And User-Created Content. (2007). Web 2.0 Wikis and Social Networking, Organization for Economic.##Reed, C. (2012). Making Laws for Cyberspace. International Journal of Law and Information Technology, 20(4), 370-382.##Roshandel Arbatani, T. Kuhi, A. (2012). Media convergence (the relationship between the production of content by the user and the way of watching television). Culture Communication Studies, 13 (20), 143-168. (in Persian)##Roshandel Arbatani, T. Razi, H. Labafi. S. (2012). The pathological study of the policy making process at the Islamic Broadcasting Organization of Iran, Journal of Public Administration, (10), 79-100. (in Persian)##Senn, M. (2011). Non-State Regulatory Regimes - Understanding Institutional Transformation. Berlin Heidelberg, Springer Publishers.##Supreme Council for Cultural Revolution. (1392). Terms and Conditions of Computer Information Networks. Islamic Consultative Research Center. Observed on January 3, 2013. (in Persian)##Susskind, R. (1996). The Future of Law: Facing the Challenges of Information Technology, England, Clarendon press.##Sanchez, J. (2015). Media image of seafarers in the Spanish printed press. Journal of Martime Policy and management, (42), 97-110.##Thompson, M. (2013). In Search of Alterity: On Google, Neutrality, and Otherness. Tulane Journal of Technology and Intellectual Property, 14 (2011), 137–190.##Trachtman, J. (2010). The International Law of Financial Crisis: Spillovers, Subsidiarity, Fragmentation and Cooperation. Journal of International Economic Law, (13)719–742##Turow, J. (2009). Media Today, An Introduction To Mass Communication, (3 Ed), Routledge.##Weber, R. (2012). Future Design of Cyberspace Law. Journal of Politics and Law, (5), 1–14.##Weber, R. (2002). Regulatory Models for the Online World, Brill, Zürich.##Weber, R. (2012). Overcoming the Hard Law/Soft Law Dichotomy in Times of (Financial) Crises. Journal of Governance and Regulation 1 (1), 8–14.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>طراحی مدل پذیرش سازمان‎های غیردولتی (مردم‎نهاد) از نگاه شهروندان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Designing a model for Acceptance of Non-governmental Organizations by the Citizens</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: در پژوهش حاضر، تلاش شده است که مدلی برای پذیرش سازمان‎های مردم‎نهاد از نگاه شهروندان طراحی شود. این پژوهش از نظر هدف بنیادین ـ کاربردی به‎شمار می‎رود و از لحاظ ماهیت از دسته پژوهش‎های اکتشافی است.
روش: در این پژوهش با استفاده از روش تحقیق کیفی و استراتژی نظریه‎پردازی داده‎بنیاد، به منظور کشف موضوع، مصاحبه‎‎های عمیقی با 20 نفر از خبرگان و آگاهان کلیدی به روش نمونه‎گیری هدفمند انجام گرفت و از این طریق داده‎های پژوهش گردآوری شدند. در ادامه با استفاده از فرایند کدگذاری باز، محوری و گزینشی، به دسته‎بندی مؤلفه‎ها پرداخته و مدل نهایی پیکربندی شد.
یافته‎ها: یافته‎های پژوهش مبین آن است که «پذیرش» سازمان‎های مردم‎نهاد نتیجه کنش‎ها و تأثیر عوامل مختلف سازمانی، اجتماعی، محیطی و فردی است. در این مدل عوامل سازمانی و عوامل اجتماعی، شرایط علی محسوب می‎شوند؛ سودمندی و نفع عامه، مقوله محوری هستند؛ نگرش شامل احساسات مثبت و منفی، راهبرد مدل مد نظر قرار می‎گیرد و قصد رفتاری، پیامد پذیرش/ عدم پذیرش سازمان شناخته می‎شوند. دو بعد محیط فعالیت و اخلاقیات فردی به عنوان شرایط مداخله‎گر، بر نگرش شهروندان در پذیرش سازمان‎های مردم‎نهاد تأثیرگذار است.
نتیجه‎گیری: پیامد اصلی مدل در حوزه رفتاری پذیرش سازمان‎های مردم‎نهاد توسط شهروندان، نگاه سیستمی به موضوع و در نظر گرفتن عوامل سازمانی، محیطی و فردی است.
 </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: The present study seeks to design a model for Acceptance of Non-Governmental Organizations (NGOs) by the Citizens. This research is fundamental and practical in purpose and is exploratory in nature.
Methods: Qualitative method and Grounded Theory strategy were used to help design the study. 20 key experts were selected sing using judgmental purposive sampling, and then the researchers conducted deep interviews with them. Afterwards, the components were classified using the process of open, axial and selective coding and the final model was configured.
Results: The results of the research showed that the “acceptance” of NGO can be affected by many different factors like organizational, sociological, environmental and personal elements. In the proposedmodel, organizational and social elements are the causal elements; public gain and profitably are the axial categories; the attitudes include positive or negative emotions which are considered as the model Strategy. Eventually, behavioral intent which is the consequence of acceptance or non-acceptance of NGOs were identified. Activity environment and individual morality had significant effects on public attitudes of citizen toward NGOs.
Conclusion: The main outcome of this model in the behavioral field is the acceptanceof NGOs by the Citizens, based onsystematic perspective to the subject and considering organizational, environmental, and individual factors.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>269</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>288</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حمید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شجاعی</Family>
						<NameE>Hamid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Shojaei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>حمید شجاعی دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی ـ رفتار سازمانی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>حمید شجاعی دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی ـ رفتار</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hamidshojaie51@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>موغلی</Family>
						<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mooghali</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mooghali@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد جواد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حضوری</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Javad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hozoori</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hozoori@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رسولی</Family>
						<NameE>Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rasoulei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه پیام نور،تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه پیام نور،تهران،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>karimi@gharb.tpnu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پذیرش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سازمان‎های غیردولتی (مردم‎نهاد)</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شهروندان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت سازمان‎های مردم‎نهاد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بهبود اجتماعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>آیین‎نامه اجرایی تأسیس و فعالیت سازمان‎های مردم‎نهاد (2011). معاونت سازمان‎های مردم‎نهاد، پورتال وزارت کشور##بازرگان، عباس (1391). مقدمه‎ای بر روش‎های تحقیق کیفی و آمیخته. (چاپ سوم)، تهران: نشر دیدار.##بدیع، برتون و بیرون بوم، پی یر (1387). جامعه‎شناسی دولت، ترجمه احمد نقیب‎زاده، تهران: نشر قومس.##پتراس، جیمز (1383). NGOها در خدمت امپریالیسم. ترجمه علیرضا ثقفی، نقد نو، شماره 2، 14-21.##دانایی فرد، حسن؛ امامی، سید مجتبی (1386). استراتژی‎های پژوهش کیفی: تأملی بر نظریه‎پردازی داده‎بنیاد. اندیشه مدیریت، 1(2)، 69- 97.##دماری، بهزاد؛ حیدرنیا، محمدعلی؛ رهبری بناب، مریم (1393). نقش و عملکرد سازمان‎های مردم‎نهاد در حفظ و ارتقای سلامت جامعه. فصلنامه پایش، 13 (5)، 541- 550.##سرلک، محمدعلی و نوریائی، محمدحسین (1395). شناسایی عوامل مؤثر بر جریان‎های شکافنده سازمان‎های دولتی با استفاده از استراتژی نظریه پردازی داده‎بنیاد. فصلنامه مدیریت دولتی، 8 (4)، 553- 570.##سریع القلم، محمود (1389). اقتدارگرایی ایرانی در عهد قاجار، تهران: نشر فرزان.##شعاری نژاد، علی اکبر (1395). فلسفه آموزش و پرورش. تهران: انتشارات امیر کبیر.##صادقی فاطمه (1385). سیاست‎زدایی از جامعه مدنی: تجربه سازمان‎های غیردولتی در دوره اصلاحات، گفت‎وگو، شماره 47.##قانعی راد، محمدامین و حسینی، فاطمه (1384). ارزش‎ها، شبکه روابط و مشارکت در سازمان‎های غیردولتی (مطالعه تجربی در بین جوانان تهران). مجله جامعه شناسی ایران، 6 (2)، 97- 123.##قلی‎پور، آرین (1386). رفتار سازمانی (رفتار فردی). تهران: انتشارات سمت.##قوام، عبدالعلی و مالمیر، مهدی (1393). ارائه یک مدل تحلیلی برای بررسی شکاف دولت ـ ملت (الگویابی روابط بین دولت و جامعه). پژوهشنامه علوم سیاسی، 10(1)، 157- 197.##کاتوزیان، محمدعلی (1380). تضاد دولت و ملت (نظریه تاریخ و سیاست در ایران)، ترجمه علیرضا طیب، تهران: نشر نی.##ملک‎زاده، رضا (1396). گزارش خبری، سلام کشور (خبرنامه داخلی وزارت کشور). شماره 13.##هومن، حیدرعلی (1385). راهنمای عملی پژوهش کیفی. تهران: انتشارات سمت##References##Batel, S., Devine – Wright, P., &amp; Tangeland, T. (2013). Social Acceptance of low Carbon Energy and Associated infrastructures: A critical Discussion. Energy Policy 58, 1-5.##Carle, A., &amp; Chkam, H. (2006). Humanitarian Action in the New Security Environment: Policy and OperationalImplications in Iraq. HPG Background Paper. September. Humanitarian Policy Group, Overseas Development Institute, London. Charmaz, C. (1990). Discovering Chronic Illness: Using Grounded Theory. Social Science &amp; Medicine, 30(11), 1161-1172.##Creswell, J. W. (2005). Educational Research: Planning, Conducting, and Evaluating Quantitative and Qualitative Research (2nd edition).##Diamond, L. (1994). Rethinking civil society. Journal of Democracy, 5, 94-114.##Dreyer, S.J., &amp; Walker, L. (2013). Acceptance and Support of the Australian Carbon Policy. Social Justice Research, 26 (3), 343 -362.##Fast, L., &amp; O’Neill, M. (2010). A closer look at acceptance. Humanitarian Exchange Magazine, 47, 3–6.##Fast, L., Freeman, F., O&#039;Neill, M., &amp; Rowley, E. (2013). In acceptance we trust? Conceptualising acceptance as a viable approach to NGO security management. Social Justice Research, 37(2), 222-243.##Fast, L., Freeman, F., O&#039;Neill, M., &amp; Rowley, E. (2013). The promise of acceptance as an NGO, security management approach. Disasters, 39(2), 208-231.##Fernández, W. D. (2004). Using the Glaserian Approach in Grounded Studies of Emerging Business Practices. Electronic Journal of Business Research Methods, 2(2), 83-94.##Hudock, A. (1999). NGOs and Civil Socity: Democracy by proxy? Cambridge: Polity press. ISBN: 978-0-745-61649-0.##Kaldor, M. (2003). Global civil society: An answer to war. Cambridge: Polity.##Korten, D. (1990). Getting to the 21st century: Voluntary action and the Au5 global agenda. West Hartford, CT: Kumarian.##Lee, J. (2001). A Grounded Theory: Integration and Internalization in ERP Adoption and Use. Unpublished Doctoral Dissertation, University of Nebreska, In Proquest UMI Database.##Lewis, D. (2007). The management of non-governmental development organizations (2nd ed.). London: Routledge.##Paul, J. A. (1996). World Bank and Non-Governmental Organizations. Cornell International Law Journal, 25(3).##Ralph, N., Birks, M., Chapman, Y.E. (2014). Contextual Positioning: Using Documents as Extant Data in Grounded Theory Research. SAGE.## Riddell, R. (2007). Does foreign aid really work? Oxford: Oxford University Press.##Shivani, D. (2001). NGOs As Prime Movers, Sectoral Action for Social Development. Kanishka Publishers and Distributors, New Delhi.##Strauss, A. &amp; Corbin, J. (1990). Basics of qualitative research: Grounded theory procedures and techniques. Newbury Park, CA, Sage publications, Inc.##Tvedt, T. (1998). Angels of mercy or development diplomats? NGOs and foreign aid. Oxford: James Currey.##Willetts, P. (2006). What is a Non-Governmental Organization? UNESCO Encyclopaedia of Life Support Systems Section 1 Institutional and Infrastructure Resource Issuesarticle 1.44.3.7 Non-Governmental Organizations.## Wood, G. D. (1997). States without citizens: The problem of the franchise state, In D. Hulme &amp; M. Edwards (Eds.), Chap. 5 Too close for comfort? NGOs, states and donors. London: Macmillan.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی ارتباط فساد و اعتماد در رابطه بین شفافیت و رضایت شهروندان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigating the Relationship between Corruption and Trust Related to Transparency and Citizen Satisfaction</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: برای دستیابی یه یک جامعه مطلوب و آرمانی، توجه به فساد، شفافیت، اعتماد و رضایت شهروندان در اولویت قرار دارند که هدف اساسی این پژوهش نیز بررسی این عوامل است.
روش: پژوهش حاضر از نظر هدف، کاربردی است، از لحاظ چگونگی گردآوری داده‌ها از نوع پژوهش‌های توصیفی (غیرآزمایشی) و از شاخه مطالعات میدانی محسوب می‎شود و از نظر ارتباط بین متغیرهای پژوهش از نوع علّی است. روش اجرای پژوهش نیز پیمایشی است. جامعه آماری پژوهش حاضر، شامل شهروندان محترم منطقه 8 شهر تهران می‌شود. نمونه‎گیری آن به روش تصادفی خوشه‎ای صورت گرفته است و داده‌ها نیز به کمک ابزار پرسشنامه گردآوری و تجزیه ‌و تحلیل شده‌اند.
یافته‎ها: یافته‎های پژوهش نشان می‎دهد شفافیت بر اعتماد‎ ‎‎و رضایت شهروند و همچنین اعتماد بر رضایت شهروند، تأثیری مثبت و معناداری دارد. در عین ‌حال شفافیت بر بروز فساد و بروز فساد بر اعتماد و رضایت شهروندی، اثر معکوس و معناداری را نشان می‎دهد.
نتیجه‎گیری: دولت‎ ایده‎آل باید با شفافیت بیشتر، مسئله کاهش فساد را در سطح جامعه دنبال کند و با تحقق آن، رضایت و اعتماد شهروندان دست یافتنی خواهد شد.
 </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: Focusing on corruption, transparency, trust, and satisfaction of citizens is a priority in order to achieve a desirable and ideal society. The main objective of this research is to study these factors.
Methods: This study is a practical field study in which the data are collected according to the premises of descriptive studies. This survey research relates the variables based on causal relationships. Research Population consists of Tehran citizens in district #8 where random cluster sampling method has been applied. The data were collected and analyzed in a form of a questionnaire.
Results: The results show that clarity has a significantly positive effect on citizens’ trust and satisfaction; besides,  trust has a significantly positive effect on citizens’ satisfaction. At the same time, transparency has a significantly negaitive effect on corruption and corruption has a significantly negaitive effect on citizens’ trust and satisfaction.
Conclusion: An ideal government should pursue more transparency in the reduction of corruption at the community level and, with this; citizens&#039; satisfaction and trust will be achieved.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>289</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>310</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عباس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نرگسیان</Family>
						<NameE>Abas</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nargesian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>a.nargesian@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>قاسمعلی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>جمالی</Family>
						<NameE>Ghasemali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Jamali</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>gh.jamali@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مسعود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>هراتی</Family>
						<NameE>Masoud</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Harati</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>haratimasoud93@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>آذری</Family>
						<NameE>Hosein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Azari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hossein.azari@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اعتماد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>حکمرانی خوب</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رضایت شهروند</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شفافیت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فساد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>الوانی، سید مهدی (1378). مدیریت عمومی. تهران: نشر نی##جمالی، قاسمعلی؛ نرگسیان، عباس؛ پیران نژاد، علی (1396). ارزیابی وضعیت شفافیت پورتال سازمان‌های دولتی (مطالعۀ موردی: وزارتخانه‌های ایران). فصلنامه مدیریت دولتی، 9(1)، 61- 84##درویش، حسن؛ عظیمی زاچکانی، فاطمه (1395). بررسی تأثیر شفافیت سازمانی بر کاهش فساد اداری با میانجی‌گری اعتماد سازمانی (مطالعۀ موردی: کارکنان بیمارستان پانزده خرداد ورامین). فصلنامه مدیریت دولتی، 8(1)، 153- 166.##زارعی متین، حسن؛ طهماسبی، رضا؛ موسوی، سید محمد مهدی (1388). نقش مؤلفه‎های فرهنگ سازمانی در اعتماد سازی: بررسی روابط بین ابعاد فرهنگی گلوب (GLOBE) و اعتماد. فصلنامه علوم مدیریت ایران، 4(15)، 145-178.##شریفی، حسین؛ مشرف جوادی، محمدحسین؛ حاجی‎پور، مرضیه (1392). بررسی نقش فناوری اطلاعات در کاهش فساد اداری از طریق افزایش شفافیت اطلاعات، بهبود پاسخگویی و ارتقای اعتماد و درستی (مورد مطالعه: شعب بانک صادرات شهر اصفهان). پژوهشنامه پردازش و مدیریت اطلاعات، ۲۸(۳)، 660 – 679.##ضیائی، محمدصادق؛ نرگسیان، عباس؛ آیباغی اصفهانی، سعید (1387). نقش رهبری معنوی در توانمندسازی کارکنان دانشگاه تهران. فصلنامه مدیریت دولتی، 1(1)، 67- 86.##عبادی، نغمه؛ پیران نژاد، علی (1393). حکمرانی الکترونیک در شهرداری ها (مطالعۀ پورتال شهرداری‎های کشور). فصلنامه مدیریت دولتی، 6(2)، 265 – 288.##فرهادی نژاد، محسن (1385). دولت الکترونیک و حکومتداری خوب. تدبیر، (169)، 22- 27.##گر، تدرابرت (1379). چرا انسان‎ها شورش می‎کنند؟ ترجمه علی مرشدی زاد. تهران: پژوهشکده مطالعات راهبردی.##محمدی، جمال؛ زنگنه، مهدی (1392). سنجش عوامل مؤثر بر میزان اعتماد شهروندان به شهرداری (مورد مطالعه: شهروندان شهر نیشابور). جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی محیطی، ۲۴(۱)، 155- 170.##محمدی‌فر، یوسف؛ احمدی، محمد؛ هاشمی، سید دادوش (1389). اعتماد به سازمان‌های دولتی و سطح رضایت‌مندی شهروندان. فصلنامه تحقیقات فرهنگی ایران، 3(11)، 103- 127.##هومن، حیدرعلی (1381). تهیه و استاندارد ساختن مقیاس سنجش رضایت شغلی. تهران: مرکز آموزش مدیریت دولتی.##References##Akgul, D. (2012). Measuring the Satisfaction of Citizens for the Services given by the Municipality: The Case of Kirşehir Municipality. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 62, 555-560.##Almarshad, S. O. (2015). Municipal awareness and citizen satisfaction: The case of the northern borders in saudi arabia. International Review of Management and Marketing, 5(2), 94-101.##Alvani, S. M. (2000). General Management. Tehran: Nashr Ney. (in Persian)##Armstrong, E. (2005). Integrity, transparency and accountability in public administration: Recent trends, regional and international developments and emerging issues. United Nations, Department of Economic and Social Affairs, 1-10.##Asian Development Bank (1995). Governance: Sound Development Management. WP1-95.##Behn, R. D. (1995). The big questions of public management. Public Administration Review, 55(4), 313-324.##Blind, P. K. (2014). Policy-driven democratization: Geometrical perspectives on transparency, accountability, and corruption. Springer.‏##Bouckaert, G., Van de Walle, S., &amp; Kampen, J. K. (2005). Potential for comparative public opinion research in public administration. International Review of Administrative Sciences, 71(2), 229-240.##Darvish, H., &amp; Azimi Zachekani, F. (2016). The effect on reducing corruption organization Transparency mediated by organizational trust studied Khordad hospital staff Varamin. Journal of Public Administration, 8(1), 153-166. (in Persian)##Ebadi, N., &amp; Piranejad, A. (2014). E-Governance in Municipalities: Studying the Iranian Municipalities’ Portals. Journal of Public Administration, 6(2), 265-288. (in Persian)##Farhadi Nejad, M. (2006). Good governance and good governance. Tidbir, (169), 27-22.##(in Persian)##Gattis, B. (2010). The why’s and how’s of citizen satisfaction surveys: An Examination of the Relationships between Data Use and Achieving Desired Outcomes Among National Citizen Survey Participants; capstone conference. (For the degree of master), Faculty of the University of North Carolina.##Gordon, M. T. (2000). Public trust in government: the US media as an agent of accountability? International Review of Administrative Sciences, 66(2), 297-310.##Grimmelikhuijsen, S. (2012). Linking transparency, knowledge and citizen trust in government: an experiment. International Review of Administrative Sciences, 78(1), 50-73.##Grimmelikhuijsen, S. G. (2010). Transparency of Public Decision‐Making: Towards Trust in Local Government? Policy &amp; Internet, 2(1), 5-35.##Grimmelikhuijsen, S., Porumbescu, G., Hong, B., &amp; Im, T. (2013). The effect of transparency on trust in government: A cross‐national comparative experiment. Public Administration Review, 73(4), 575-586.##Gurr, T. R. (2000). Why Men Rebel? (A. Morshedzade, Trans.). Tehran: Research Institute of Strategic Studies. (in Persian)##Heald, D. (2006). Varieties of transparency. In C. Hood &amp; D. Heald (Eds.), Transparency: The Key to Better Governance? (pp. 25-43). New York: Oxford University Press.##Hooman, H. A. (1982). provide and standardization of job satisfaction evaluating’ scale. Tehran: Public Management Training center. (in Persian)##Im, T., Porumbescu, G., &amp; Lee, H. (2013). ICT as a buffer to change: A case study of the Seoul Metropolitan Government&#039;s Dasan Call Center. Public Performance &amp; Management Review, 36(3), 436-455.##Jamali, G., nargesian, a., &amp; Pirannejad, A. (2017). Evaluation of Transparency of Governmental Portals (Ministries of Iran). Journal of Public Administration, 9(1), 61-84. (in Persian)##Kim, S. E. (2005). The role of trust in the modern administrative state: An integrative model. Administration &amp; Society, 37(5), 611-635.‏##Klitgaard, R. (1988). Controlling corruption. Berkeley: Univ of California Press.##Klitgaard, R. (1998). International Cooperation Against Corruption. Finance &amp; Development, 35(1), 3–6.##Kubbe, I. (2013). Corruption and trust: a model designKorruption und Vertrauen–Ein Modellentwurf. Zeitschrift für Vergleichende Politikwissenschaft, 7(1), 117-135.##Lindstedt, C., &amp; Naurin, D. (2010). Transparency is not enough: Making transparency effective in reducing corruption. International political science review, 31(3), 301-322.##Meijer, A. (2013). Understanding the complex dynamics of transparency. Public Administration Review, 73(3), 429-439.‏##Mohammadi, J., Zangeneh, M. (2013). An Investigation of Effective Factors on the Extent of Citizens’ Trust to Municipality Case Study of Neyshabur’s Citizens. Geography and Environmental Planning, 24 (1), 155-170. (in Persian)##Mohammadifar, Y., Ahmadi, M., &amp; Hashemi, S. D. (2010). Impact of Trust in State-run Organizations on Citizen`s Satisfaction. Iranian Journal of Cultural Research, 3(11), 103-127. (in Persian)##Morris, S. D., &amp; Klesner, J. L. (2010). Corruption and trust: Theoretical considerations and evidence from Mexico. Comparative Political Studies, 43(10), 1258-1285.##Nye Jr, J. S. (1997). In government we don&#039;t trust. Foreign Policy, (108), 99-111.‏##Nyhan, R.C. (2000), Changing the paradigm: trust &amp; its role in public sector organizations, American Review of Public Administration, 30 (1), 87-109.##Oliver, R. (2004). What is transparency? New York: McGraw Hill Professional.##Olsen, A. L. (2015). Citizen (dis) satisfaction: An experimental equivalence framing study. Public Administration Review, 75(3), 469-478.##Park, H., &amp; Blenkinsopp, J. (2011). The roles of transparency and trust in the relationship between corruption and citizen satisfaction. International Review of Administrative Sciences, 77(2), 254-274.##Peisakhin, L., &amp; Pinto, P. (2010). Is transparency an effective anti‐corruption strategy? Evidence from a field experiment in India. Regulation &amp; Governance, 4(3), 261-280.##Porumbescu, G. A. (2015 a). Does transparency improve citizens’ perceptions of government performance? Evidence from Seoul, South Korea. Administration &amp; Society.##Porumbescu, G. A. (2015 b). Using transparency to enhance responsiveness and trust in local government: Can it work? State and Local Government Review, 47(3), 205-213.‏##Porumbescu, G. A. (2015 c). Linking transparency to trust in government and voice. The American Review of Public Administration, 47(5), 520-537.‏‏##Rawlins, B. R. (2008). Measuring the relationship between organizational transparency and employee trust. Public Relations Journal, 2(2), 1-21.##Reynaers, A., &amp; Grimmelikhuijsen, S. (2015). Transparency in public–private partnerships: not so bad after all?. Public Administration, 93(3), 609-626.‏##Rousseau, D. M., Sitkin, S. B., Burt, R. S., &amp; Camerer, C. (1998). Not so different after all: A cross-discipline view of trust. Academy of Management Review, 23, 393-404.##Scauer, F. (2011). Transparency in three dimensions. U. Ill. L. Rev., 1339.‏##Sharifi-Renani, H., Moshref-Javadi, M. H., Hajipoor, M. (2014). The Role of Information Technology in Reduction of Administrative Corruption through Increasing of Information transparency, Improvement of Accountability and Promotion of Integrity A Case Study of Saderat Bank Branches in Isfahan. Journal of Information Processing and Management, 28 (3), 660-679.##(in Persian)##Stoica, V., &amp; Ilas, A. (2009). Romanian urban e-government. Digital services and digital democracy in 165 cities. Electronic Journal of E-government, 7(2), 171-182.##Theobald, R. (1990). What is Corruption? In Corruption, development and underdevelopment (pp. 1-18). Palgrave Macmillan, London.‏##UNDP (2004). Anti corruption, final version, and practice note. UNDP press.##United Nations (2011). The Millennium Development Goals Report 2011. New York: United Nations Development Program.##Van Ryzin, G. G. (2004). Expectations, performance, and citizen satisfaction with urban services. Journal of Policy Analysis and Management, 23(3), 433-448.##Welch, E. W., Hinnant, C. C., &amp; Moon, M. J. (2004). Linking citizen satisfaction with e-government and trust in government. Journal of public administration research and theory, 15(3), 371-391.##World Bank. (1997). Helping Countries to Combat Corruption: The Role of World Bank, Washington, DC: The World Bank.##Zarei Matin, H., Tahmasbi, R. &amp; Mosavi, S. M. M. (2009). The role of Organizational Culture in Trust Building; Explanation of the Relationship Between Cultural Dimensions and Trust. Iranian journal of management sciences (IAMS), 4(15), 145-178. (in Persian)##Ziaei, M., Nargesian, A. &amp; Aibaghi, E. S. (2009). The role of spiritual leadership on human resource empowerment in the University of Tehran. Journal of Public Administration, 1(1), 67-86.##(in Persian)##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تأثیر متناقض رضایت شغلی بر آوای مخرب کارکنان با توجه به نقش میانجی‌گری شبکه‌های اجتماعی و تعهد سازمانی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Paradoxical Influence of Job Satisfaction on Destructive Employees’ Voice, Considering the Mediating Role of Social Network Sites and Organizational Commitment</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: هدف از پژوهش حاضر، بررسی نقش متناقض رضایت شغلی در اثرگذاری بر آوای مخرب کارکنان با توجه به نقش میانجی‌گری شبکه‌های اجتماعی و تعهد سازمانی است.
روش: در این پژوهش 240 نفر از کارکنان شرکت آسیاتک پیمایش شده‎اند. برای اعتبارسنجی فرضیه‎ها، روش حداقل مربعات جزئی مد نظر قرار گرفته است.
یافته‎ها: نتایج پژوهش حاکی از آن است که شبکه‌های اجتماعی به تقویت آوای مخرب کارکنان منجر می‎شود. افرادی که رضایت شغلی و تعهد سازمانی بالاتری دارند، از شبکه‌های اجتماعی برای برقراری ارتباط با همکاران خود بیشتر استفاده می‎کنند. تعهد سازمانی به کاهش آوای مخرب منجر شده و رضایت شغلی به طور مستقیم به افزایش آن منجر می‎شود.
نتیجه‎گیری: سهم افزایی نظری در این پژوهش آن است که نشان می‎دهد شبکه‌های اجتماعی علی‌رغم مزایای بسیاری که در محیط کار به ارمغان می‎آورند، با تهدیدهای اجتناب‎ناپذیری مانند تقویت آوای مخرب همراه هستند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: This study aims to investigate the paradoxical influence of job satisfaction on destructive employees’ voice behavior considering the mediating role of using social networking sites (SNSs) and organizational commitment.
Methods: 240 employees of Asia-tech Company have been surveyed in this regard. PLS algorithm has been used to evaluate the validity of the hypothesis. To do so, the WarpPls software has been used.
Results: The results of the study showed that employees&#039; social networking sites utilization can lead to an increase in destructive employees’ voice. The employees with higher level of job satisfaction and organizational commitment take more advantage of SNSs in order to keep in touch with their colleagues. Job satisfaction leads to an increase in level of both employees’ voice and organizational commitment. The employees with higher level of organizational commitment show less destructive voice than others.
Conclusion: The main contribution of this study is to show the fact that in spite of many advantages that can be considered for SNSs in the workplace, they can have some detrimental effects such as increasing destructive voice among employees.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>311</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>332</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>غلامعلی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>طبرسا</Family>
						<NameE>Gholam Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Tabarsa</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت و</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>g_tabarsa@sbu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سجاد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شکوهیار</Family>
						<NameE>Sajjad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Shokouhyar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>s_shokouhyar@sbu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>الفت</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Olfat</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد سیستم‌های اطلاعاتی مدیریت، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد سیستم‌های اطلاعاتی مدیریت، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mohammad.olfat70@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شبکه‌های اجتماعی عمومی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شبکه‌های اجتماعی سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آوای مخرب کارکنان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رضایت شغلی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تعهد سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>جعفری، سید محمدباقر، آرین فر، مسعود، الوانی، سید مهدی. (1395). بررسی تأثیر انگیزه‌های فردی بر رفتار به اشتراک‌گذاری دانش با توجه به نقش تعدیل‎کنندگی ارزش‎ها (مطالعۀ موردی: ایده‎شهر. (فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات، 8(2)، 272-253##طالقانی، غلامرضا، عبدالملکی، جمال، غفاری، علی. (1395). بررسی عوامل فردی مؤثر بر قصد ترک شغلِ کارکنان ادارۀ کل آموزش و پرورش استان کردستان. فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی مدیریت دولتی, 8(1), 219-232.##شاه حسینی، محمدعلی، استیری، مهرداد، کشفی، مریم السادات. (1395). بررسی تأثیر حمایت سازمانی ادراک‎شده و حمایت سرپرست ادراک‎شده بر تعهد سازمانی و عملکرد فردی کارکنان. فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی مدیریت دولتی, 8(2), 373-391.##محمدی، جیران, نداف، مهدی، صفریان، سارا. (1396). تبیین تأثیر اعتماد و سلامت سازمانی بر مقاومت کارکنان در برابر تغییر در سازمان‌های دولتی با توجه به نقش میانجی تعهد سازمانی (مطالعۀ موردی: شهرداری اهواز). فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی مدیریت دولتی, 9(1), 85-106.##References##Aburub, F. (2015). Impact of ERP systems usage on organizational agility: An empirical investigation in the banking sector. Information Technology &amp; People, 28(3), 570-588.##Akbulut, Y., Dönmez, O., &amp; Dursun, Ö. Ö. (2017). Cyberloafing and social desirability bias among students and employees. Computers in Human Behavior, 72, 87-95.##Ali-Hassan, H., Nevo, D., &amp; Wade, M. (2015). Linking dimensions of social media use to job performance: The role of social capital. The Journal of Strategic Information Systems, 24(2), 65-89.##Asrar-ul-Haq, M., Kuchinke, K. P., &amp; Iqbal, A. (2017). The relationship between corporate social responsibility, job satisfaction, and organizational commitment: Case of Pakistani higher education. Journal of Cleaner Production, 142, 2352-2363.##Bharati, P., Zhang, W., &amp; Chaudhury, A. (2015). Better knowledge with social media? Exploring the roles of social capital and organizational knowledge management. Journal of Knowledge Management, 19(3), 456-475.##Boyd, D. M., &amp; Ellison, N. B. (2007). Social network sites: Definition, history, and scholarship. Journal of computer‐mediated Communication, 13(1), 210-230.##Burris, E. R. (2012). The risks and rewards of speaking up: Managerial responses to employee voice. Academy of Management Journal, 55(4), 851-875.##Byrne, B. M. (1994). Structural equation modeling with EQS and EQS/Windows: Basic concepts, applications, and programming. Sage.##Cai, Z., Huang, Q., Liu, H., &amp; Wang, X. (2018). Improving the agility of employees through enterprise social media: The mediating role of psychological conditions. International Journal of Information Management, 38(1), 52-63.##Cao, X., Guo, X., Vogel, D., &amp; Zhang, X. (2016). Exploring the influence of social media on employee work performance. Internet Research, 26(2), 529-545.##Chamberlin, M., Newton, D. W., &amp; Lepine, J. A. (2017). A meta‐analysis of voice and its promotive and prohibitive forms: Identification of key associations, distinctions, and future research directions. Personnel Psychology, 70(1), 11-71.##Cho, V., &amp; Huang, X. (2012). Professional commitment, organizational commitment, and the intention to leave for professional advancement: An empirical study on IT professionals. Information Technology &amp; People, 25(1), 31-54.##Christen, M., Iyer, G., &amp; Soberman, D. (2006). Job satisfaction, job performance, and effort: A reexamination using agency theory. Journal of Marketing, 70(1), 137-150.##Dyne, L. V., Ang, S., &amp; Botero, I. C. (2003). Conceptualizing employee silence and employee voice as multidimensional constructs. Journal of management studies, 40(6), 1359-1392.##Fornell, C., &amp; Larcker, D. F. (1981). Evaluating structural equation models with unobservable variables and measurement error. Journal of marketing research, 39-50.##Fu, W., &amp; Deshpande, S. P. (2014). The impact of caring climate, job satisfaction, and organizational commitment on job performance of employees in a China’s insurance company. Journal of Business Ethics, 124(2), 339-349.##Fulk, J., &amp; Yuan, Y. C. (2013). Location, motivation, and social capitalization via enterprise social networking. Journal of Computer-Mediated Communication, 19(1), 20-37.##Gan, C., &amp; Wang, W. (2017). The influence of perceived value on purchase intention in social commerce context. Internet Research, 27(4), 772-785.##Holland, P., Pyman, A., Cooper, B. K., &amp; Teicher, J. (2011). Employee voice and job satisfaction in Australia: The centrality of direct voice. Human Resource Management, 50(1), 95-111.##Hu, S., Gu, J., Liu, H., &amp; Huang, Q. (2017). The moderating role of social media usage in the relationship among multicultural experiences, cultural intelligence, and individual creativity. Information Technology &amp; People, 30(2), 265-281.##Indarti, S., Fernandes, A. A. R., &amp; Hakim, W. (2017). The effect of OCB in relationship between personality, organizational commitment and job satisfaction on performance. Journal of Management Development, 36(10), 1283-1293.##Jaussi, K. S. (2007). Attitudinal commitment: A three‐dimensional construct. Journal of occupational and organizational Psychology, 80(1), 51-61.##Jin, M. H., McDonald, B., &amp; Park, J. (2018). Person–organization fit and turnover intention: Exploring the mediating role of employee followership and job satisfaction through conservation of resources theory. Review of Public Personnel Administration, 38(2), 167-192.##Kanchana, P. N. (2012). Job Satisfaction as Predictor of Organizational Commitment. In Emerging Trends in Science, Engineering and Technology (pp. 767-773). Springer, India.##Kim, H. W., Chan, H. C., &amp; Gupta, S. (2016). Examining information systems infusion from a user commitment perspective. Information Technology &amp; People, 29(1), 173-199.##Kock, N. (2015). WarpPLS 5.0 User Manual. 2015. Laredo, TX:: ScriptWarp Systems.##Kwahk, K. Y., &amp; Park, D. H. (2016). The effects of network sharing on knowledge-sharing activities and job performance in enterprise social media environments. Computers in Human Behavior, 55, 826-839.##Lam, T., Zhang, H., &amp; Baum, T. (2001). An investigation of employees’ job satisfaction: the case of hotels in Hong Kong. Tourism management, 22(2), 157-165.##Leftheriotis, I., &amp; Giannakos, M. N. (2014). Using social media for work: Losing your time or improving your work? Computers in Human Behavior, 31, 134-142.##Leonardi, P. M., Huysman, M., &amp; Steinfield, C. (2013). Enterprise social media: Definition, history, and prospects for the study of social technologies in organizations. Journal of Computer-Mediated Communication, 19(1), 1-19.##Liu, W., Zhu, R., &amp; Yang, Y. (2010). I warn you because I like you: Voice behavior, employee identifications, and transformational leadership. The Leadership Quarterly, 21(1), 189-202.##Lo, M. C., &amp; Ramayah, T. (2011). Mentoring and job satisfaction in Malaysian SMEs. Journal of management development, 30(4), 427-440.##Martin, G., Parry, E., &amp; Flowers, P. (2015). Do social media enhance constructive employee voice all of the time or just some of the time? Human Resource Management Journal, 25(4), 541-562.##Mauro, T. R. (2016). A Systematic Review of Employee Voice Behavior and its Effect on Managerial Controlled Outcomes. Doctoral dissertation, University of Maryland University College.##Maynes, T. D., &amp; Podsakoff, P. M. (2014). Speaking more broadly: An examination of the nature, antecedents, and consequences of an expanded set of employee voice behaviors. Journal of Applied Psychology, 99(1), 87.##Meyer, J. P., &amp; Allen, N. J. (1991). A three-component conceptualization of organizational commitment. Human resource management review, 1(1), 61-89.##Meyer, J. P., &amp; Allen, N. J. (2004). TCM employee commitment survey academic users guide 2004. London, Ontario, Canada: The University of Western Ontario, Department of Psychology.##Miles, S. J., &amp; Mangold, W. G. (2014). Employee voice: Untapped resource or social media time bomb? Business Horizons, 57(3), 401-411.##Moin, M. F. (2018). The link between perceptions of leader emotion regulation and followers’ organizational commitment. Journal of Management Development, 37(2), 178-187.##Moqbel, M., &amp; Kock, N. (2018). Unveiling the dark side of social networking sites: Personal and work-related consequences of social networking site addiction. Information &amp; Management, 55(1), 109-119.##Moqbel, M., Nevo, S., &amp; Kock, N. (2013). Organizational members’ use of social networking sites and job performance: An exploratory study. Information Technology &amp; People, 26(3), 240-264.##Mowbray, P. K., Wilkinson, A., &amp; Tse, H. H. (2015). An integrative review of employee voice: Identifying a common conceptualization and research agenda. International Journal of Management Reviews, 17(3), 382-400.##Navimipour, N. J., &amp; Zareie, B. (2015). A model for assessing the impact of e-learning systems on employees’ satisfaction. Computers in Human Behavior, 53, 475-485.##Ng, T. W., &amp; Feldman, D. C. (2012). Employee voice behavior: A meta‐analytic test of the conservation of resources framework. Journal of Organizational Behavior, 33(2), 216-234.##Park, J. Y., &amp; Nawakitphaitoon, K. (2018). The cross‐cultural study of LMX and individual employee voice: The moderating role of conflict avoidance. Human Resource Management Journal, 28(1), 14-30.##Peng, J., Li, D., Zhang, Z., Tian, Y., Miao, D., Xiao, W., &amp; Zhang, J. (2016). How can core self-evaluations influence job burnout? The key roles of organizational commitment and job satisfaction. Journal of health psychology, 21(1), 50-59.##Rooksby, J., Baxter, G., Cliff, D., Greenwood, D., Harvey, N., Kahn, A., &amp; Sommerville, I. (2009). Social networking and the workplace. The UK Large Scale Complex IT Systems Initiative, 1-39.##Ruck, K., Welch, M., &amp; Menara, B. (2017). Employee voice: An antecedent to organisational engagement? Public Relations Review, 43(5), 904-914.##Schmidt, G. B., Lelchook, A. M., &amp; Martin, J. E. (2016). The relationship between social media co-worker connections and work-related attitudes. Computers in Human Behavior, 55, 439-445.##Sigala, M., &amp; Chalkiti, K. (2015). Knowledge management, social media and employee creativity. International Journal of Hospitality Management, 45, 44-58.##Spector, P. E. (1985). Measurement of human service staff satisfaction: Development of the Job Satisfaction Survey. American journal of community psychology, 13(6), 693-713.##Steinhardt, M. A., Dolbier, C. L., Gottlieb, N. H., &amp; McCalister, K. T. (2003). The relationship between hardiness, supervisor support, group cohesion, and job stress as predictors of job satisfaction. American Journal of Health Promotion, 17(6), 382-389.##Suifan, T. S., Diab, H., &amp; Abdallah, A. B. (2017). Does organizational justice affect turnover-intention in a developing country? The mediating role of job satisfaction and organizational commitment. Journal of Management Development, 36(9), 1137-1148.##Tabarsa, G., &amp; Nazari, A. J. (2016). Examining the Moderating Role of Mentoring Relationship in between Content Plateauing with Job Satisfaction and Willingness to Leave the Organization (Case Study: Iran Ministry of Industry, Mines and Trade). Indian Journal of Science and Technology, 9(7), 1-8.##Tooksoon, H. M. P. (2011). Conceptual framework on the relationship between human resource management practices, job satisfaction, and turnover. Journal of Economics and Behavioral Studies, 2(2), 41-49.##Van der Voet, J., &amp; Vermeeren, B. (2017). Change management in hard times: can change management mitigate the negative relationship between cutbacks and the organizational commitment and work engagement of public sector employees? The American Review of Public Administration, 47(2), 230-252.##Wakefield, R., &amp; Wakefield, K. (2016). Social media network behavior: A study of user passion and affect. The Journal of Strategic Information Systems, 25(2), 140-156.##Walumbwa, F. O., &amp; Schaubroeck, J. (2009). Leader personality traits and employee voice behavior: mediating roles of ethical leadership and work group psychological safety. Journal of applied psychology, 94(5), 1275.##Wang, J., Keil, M., Oh, L. B., &amp; Shen, Y. (2017). Impacts of organizational commitment, interpersonal closeness, and Confucian ethics on willingness to report bad news in software projects. Journal of Systems and Software, 125, 220-233.##Wombacher, J. C., &amp; Felfe, J. (2017). Dual commitment in the organization: Effects of the interplay of team and organizational commitment on employee citizenship behavior, efficacy beliefs, and turnover intentions. Journal of Vocational Behavior, 102, 1-14.##Wynne, C. W. (1998). Issues and opinion on structural equation modelling. Management Information Systems quarterly, 22(1), 1-8.##Yousef, D. A. (2017). Organizational commitment, job satisfaction and attitudes toward organizational change: a study in the local government. International Journal of Public Administration, 40(1), 77-88.##Zhou, J., &amp; George, J. M. (2001). When job dissatisfaction leads to creativity: Encouraging the expression of voice. Academy of Management journal, 44(4), 682-696.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				