<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Implementation of performance-based budgeting system based on the Balanced Scorecard in Science Policy Research Center</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>پیاده‌سازی سیستم بودجه‌ریزی مبتنی بر عملکرد بر مبنای کارت امتیازی متوازن در مرکز تحقیقات سیاست علمی کشور</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>263</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>282</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">64365</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2017.220369.1875</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>ابویی اردکان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمید</FirstName>
					<LastName>کاظمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار مدیریت بازرگانی، مرکز تحقیقات سیاست های علمی کشور، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فردین</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Science Policy Research Center، As an academic- public organization is subsidiary of the Ministry of Science, Research and Technology; which has attempted to develop a strategic plan. The next step in the operationalization of the strategic plan will be, its relationship with the duty applications, such as financial programming and the budget. Performance based budgeting is the budgeting system used for this purpose. The purpose of the study is how to implement performance based budgeting in order to communicate the annual budget with strategic plan with using the Balanced Scorecard in the Science Policy Research Center of the country. To collect information observation, interviews and review documents and archival library have been used. The research method is action research which two-cycle action have been taken during this study. Statistical Society of research is administrative and financial experts of Secretariat of SRT , managers and experts of STRC and expert of MPO that for sampling we used judgment one. This study is applied one and used a qualitative approach. Results of research will be dimension of Implementation of performance-based budgeting, how to implement and the distribution of the budget during the strategic plan in order to strategic issues.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مرکز تحقیقات سیاست علمی کشور، سازمانی دولتی ـ دانشگاهی و وابسته به وزارت علوم، تحقیقات و فناوری (عتف) بوده که در حال حاضر به‎دنبال عملیاتی کردن استراتژی‌ها و ایجاد ارتباط میان برنامۀ استراتژیک و برنامه‌های وظیفه‌ای سازمان، همچون برنامۀ مالی و بودجه‌ای سازمان است. هدف از تحقیق مطالعۀ چگونگی پیاده‌سازی بودجه‌ریزی بر مبنای عملکرد با استفاده از روش کارت امتیازی متوازن، در این مرکز است. برای جمع‌آوری اطلاعات از روش مشاهده، مصاحبه و بررسی اسناد کتابخانه‌ای و آرشیوی استفاده شده است. استراتژی اصلی پژوهش، اقدام‌پژوهی است که در فرایند تحقیق حاضر با هدف تثبیت یادگیری حاصل از پژوهش، چرخۀ اقدام‌پژوهی دو بار تکرار شده است. جامعۀ آماری تحقیق کارشناسان اداری و مالی دبیرخانۀ شورای عالی علوم، تحقیقات و فناوری، مدیران و کارشناسان مرکز، کارشناسان دفتر مرکزی هیئت امنای وزارت عتف و کارشناسان سازمان مدیریت و برنامه‎ریزی کشور بودند. برای نمونه‌گیری از روش نمونه‌برداری قضاوتی استفاده شده است. این پژوهش کاربردی بوده و در آن از رویکرد کیفی استفاده شده است. در بخش نتایج پژوهش، ابعاد پیاده‌سازی بودجه‌ریزی بر مبنای عملکرد، چگونگی اجرا و در نهایت نحوۀ توزیع بودجۀ مرکز طی برنامۀ استراتژیک و به‌ترتیب موضوعات راهبردی مرکز مشخص شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اقدام‎پژوهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">برنامه‌ریزی استراتژیک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بودجه‌ریزی بر مبنای عملکرد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارت امتیازی متوازن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت عملکرد</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_64365_5507b184fe1216e4170dfd12b1efab8c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
