<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Deadly Sins in Public Budgeting of Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>گناه‎های کشنده در بودجه‎بندی عمومی ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>31</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>58</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">65637</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2018.247589.2143</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>میریعقوب</FirstName>
					<LastName>سیدرضائی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای مدیریت دولتی. دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی اصغر</FirstName>
					<LastName>پورعزت</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجتبی</FirstName>
					<LastName>امیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران - دکترای مدیریت</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عادل</FirstName>
					<LastName>آذر</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Budgeting is a pervasive activity in the governmental system across the world; in a way that “The Budget” as a product of allocation process goes beyond the political rhetoric, representing the real priorities and preferences of each government in the social realm. However, budgeting as a part of political system has a set of recurring issues and problems that reduce the effectiveness of budgeting system in achieving the considered goals; in this study we called those problems, “deadly sins”. To identify these deadly sins in budgeting, the qualitative method of theme analysis has been used and data collection was done through interviews. According to the finding of the study, ten deadly sins in Iran budgeting process are: “Disconnection of budget relations with upstream documents”, “Distortion strategies of the facts”, “Rule of organizational life”, “Lack of theoretical basis”, “Extreme idealism and lack of pragmatism”, “Abundance of budgetary and non-budgetary orders”, “Multiplicity of sundry rows”, “violation of budget principals”, “lack of process transparency” and “lack of accountability”. Obviously, by improving each of these factors, the budget can be set in the right direction and the national goals and objectives mentioned in the upstream documents, in particular the vision document and development plans, can be achieved easier.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &#039;B Mitra&#039;; font-size: 11pt; mso-ansi-font-size: 9.0pt;&quot; lang=&quot;FA&quot;&gt;در سراسر دنیا، بودجه‌‌بندی فعالیت فراگیری در سیستم حکومتی محسوب می‌‌شود؛ به‌طوری‌که محصول فراگرد بودجه‌‌بندی، یعنی سند بودجه، فراتر از لفاظی‌‌های سیاسی، نشان‌‌دهندۀ اولویت‌‌های واقعی و ترجیحات حکومت در عرصۀ اجتماعی است. با وجود این، بودجه‌‌بندی به‌‌منزلۀ بخشی از سیستم سیاسی، دچار مجموعه مسائل و مشکلات تکراری است که از اثربخشی سیستم بودجه‌‌بندی در دستیابی به اهداف مد نظر می‌‌کاهد؛ مشکلاتی که به تعبیری «گناه‌‌های کشنده» نامیده می‌‌شوند. برای شناسایی این گناه‌‌های کشنده در بودجه‌‌بندی، از استراتژی کیفی تحلیل تم استفاده شده و مصاحبه نیز، اصلی‌‌ترین ابزار گردآوری داده‌‌ها مد نظر قرار گرفته است. مطابق با یافته‌‌های پژوهش، «گسستگی روابط میان بودجه‌‌ها با اسناد بالادستی»، «ترفندهای تحریف واقعیت‌‌ها»، «حاکمیت حیات سازمانی»، «فقدان پشتوانۀ نظری»، «آرمان‌‌گرایی افراطی و فقدان عمل‌‌گرایی»، «تعدد تبصره‌‌ها و احکام بودجه‌‌ای و غیربودجه‌ای»، «تعدد ردیف‌های متفرقه»، «نقض اصول بودجه‌‌ای»، «فقدان شفافیت فراگردی» و «فقدان پاسخگویی»، ده گناه کشنده در فراگرد بودجه‌‌بندی ایران هستند. بدیهی است با بهبود هر یک از این موارد، می‌‌توان بودجه را در مسیر درست قرار داد و تحقق اهداف ملی ذکرشده در اسناد بالادستی، به‌‌ویژه سند چشم‌‌انداز و برنامه‌‌های توسعه را سرعت بخشید.&lt;/span&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اولویت‌‌های واقعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بودجه‌‌بندی عمومی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سند بودجه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گناه‌‌های کشنده</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_65637_83fddd3145b8f57fd33b53ca16b5f97f.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
