<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Feminism in organization studies</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>فمینیسم در مطالعات سازمان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>437</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>458</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">53860</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2015.53860</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امیرحسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>خالقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی اصغر</FirstName>
					<LastName>پورعزت</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>11</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Adopting feminist perspectives is, by and large, novel in social science. However, feminism historical background might be followed until 18th century. Through the years, patriarchal epistemology and gendered metaphysics of science have been criticized fundamentally by radical feminist thinkers. Although such criticisms obviously have limitations, their constructive role in addressing original insights is undeniable. Due to Ubiquity of organizations in modern world and significance of power within organization, organizational life has great potential for feminist criticism. Feminist scholars provide creative insights for organization studies and reveal the true nature of organizations. This paper discusses about critical reading of organizational life and aspects of organizations criticized by feminism. In other words, the main question is which characteristics of organizational life make it susceptible to feminist criticism. The current descriptive research is conducted through Theme Analysis (TA) method; a widely used approach to qualitative content. Reviewing 21 texts, it is maintained that objects of feminist criticism in organization studies could be depicted in two-level framework.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA"> از به‎کارگیری دیدگاه‎های فمینیستی در پژوهش‎های اجتماعی زمان زیادی نمی‎گذرد، ولی تبار آنها را می‎توان از قرن هجدهم دنبال کرد. هرچند بر این دست نگرش‎ها نقدهایی هم شده است، نقش سازندۀ آنها در نشان‌دادن سویه‎های تازه را نمی‎توان نادیده گرفت. فراگیر‌شدن سازمان‎ها و نقش بارز قدرت در آنها، سازمان‎ها را از تیغ رویکردهای نقادانه در امان نگذاشته است و اندیشمندان فمینیست هم در آفریدن چشم‎اندازهایی تازه به زندگی سازمانی سهم داشته‎اند. پژوهش پیش رو در پی پاسخ به این پرسش است: رویکرد فمینیستی، به نقد چه جنبه‎هایی از سازمان‎ها و زندگی سازمانی می‎پردازد؟ ‎به بیان دیگر، نقدها بر کدام ابعاد زندگی سازمانی تمرکز دارند؟ پس از مرور پیشینۀ این دیدگاه‎ها و مفاهیم و اندیشه‎های اساسی آنها، پژوهش‎های فمینیستی در مطالعات سازمان بررسی می‎شوند. رویکرد پژوهش‌ توصیفی‌‌ـ تحلیلی است و با روش تحلیل مضمون پیش می‎رود که از روش‎های تحلیل محتوای کیفی به‌شمار می‎آید. پس از بررسی 21 متن، نشان داده می‎شود که می‎توان کانون نقد دیدگاه‎های فمینیستی را در چارچوب دوسطحی جای داد که تصویری از مرزهای این رهیافت نقادانه در مطالعات سازمان فرا رو می‎نهد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جنس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جنسیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فمینیسم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مطالعات سازمان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_53860_9412301dcae2bfe1710fe5122b61287c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
