<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Comparative Study of E-government Foresight Projects in the World in Order to opt as the Benchmark for Iran</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fatemeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Saghafi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Prof. of Industrial Management, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Nour Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Yaghoubi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Prof. of Public Administration and IT, Faculty of Economics and Management, University of Sistan and Baluchestan, Zahedan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Saeideh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ansari</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.Sc. of Management and IT, Faculty of Economics and Management, Sistan and Baluchestan University, Zahedan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Objective: In Iran, E-government foresight project hasn’t been done yet, and we couldn’t find a specific model for it in the world. The aim of this research is presenting an e-government foresight framework based on comparative analysis and benchmarkingin the world. Methods: having reviewed the related literature, 18 e-government foresight projects were identified all around the world among which 8 indicators were extracted. They include Methods, Project territory, Sponsors, Participants, Project Objectives, Influential factors, Uncertainties, and Outputs and Outcomes. Shannon entropy was used to determine these indicators among the pervious related literature. Results: The results showed that the best indicators for e-government foresight project are: time horizon for less than 10 years, Project territory: national, and the government as the important sponsor, participants: between 51 to 200 people. To do so, Expert Panel, Scenario Writing and Roadmap are considered as the suitable methods Cultural-Social factors are claimed to be the most important factors, and designing scenarios and providing vision are the most important Outputs. Conclusion: At the end, some suggestions are presented for e-government foresight project that address policy makers and planners in Iran. The implementation of e-government projects requires a futuristic plan based on stakeholder consensus. In order to implement this project, the experiences of other countries are discussed in this paper can be used as guidelines for policymakers and planners in Iran.  </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>187</start>
					<end>208</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_66384_996528930cf0a95359bc88678db4aa50.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2018.247386.2142</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Recall of New Spoil System as Administrative Trader</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali Asghar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Pourezzat</namePart>
				<affiliation>Prof. in Public Administration, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghorbani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof. in Management, Payamenoor University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Jahan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Abdi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof. of Management, Bakhtar University Campus, Ilam, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fatemeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Najjar Shams</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Student in Management, Payamnoor University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Objective: The purpose of this study is to identify the types of administrative speculative behaviors and provide a precise classification of these behaviors. Methods: The research ‎approach is qualitative and the strategy applied in this research is based on the grounded theory. Semi-structured ‎interviews were used to collect the data and they were then analyzed using Strauss and Corbin ‎methods and the Paradigm model. Based on judgmental and snowball sampling 16 managers, faculty members and organizational experts with expertise in the related field of study were selected Results: Analysis of the data from the interviews resulted in the designing of a model of ‎organizational negotiation through ‎open, axial and selective coding process. The model was developed based on four causality concepts, three ‎conceptual concepts, four meddlesome concepts, three ‎action strategies, seven response strategies and three consequences. Then, using the structural equation method, the model was ‎approved. Conclusion: The results showed that commercialization in the ‎organizations can affect human, social and organizational ‎mechanisms and lead to a self-sustaining and immature organization.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>209</start>
					<end>226</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_65638_a66fd5cf4884afe62057ad1a92cff797.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2018.247808.2150</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Strategic Management Framework Diagnosis in Public Organization (Multi-Method Approach)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hashem</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Aghazade</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Prof. of Business Management, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hassan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Abolmolouki</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. Student in Business Policy, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Objective: The main concern of this paper is to present a customized method for diagnosing the strategic management status of a given company based on the gap analysis. Unlike the previous studies in organizational diagnosis (OD), current research specifically investigates the strategic management framework (SMF) within the public organizations.
Methods: This study is conducted based on multi-method approach through which both quantitative and qualitative data were gathered and analyzed. The needed data were collected from key managers and executives involved in strategic management of the intended organization and also the related high level documents, open interviews, questionnaire and group discussions. The collected data were primarily analyzed using required calculative techniques and finalized in focus groups including the selected key managers and the consulting team.
Results: The conceptual finding of this study is the exclusive model of SMFD that could be practiced in other similar organizations and the practical findings indicate a small gap in developing strategies and the presence of a significant gap in other phases of strategic management framework (SMF) in the case organization such as model, implementation, and control.
Conclusion: The outcomes of this research served better strategic management formulation to be implemented for the next 5-year plan in the intended organization.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>227</start>
					<end>250</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_66080_e34ebdf524ea0d410046fdf8bb8d271d.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2018.256465.2257</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Investigating the laws and Regulations in Monitoring Content Production in Cyberspace in Iran</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyyed Mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sharifi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof. of Media Management, Faculty of Management, Tehran University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Bita</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Marzban</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc Student, Social Communication Sciences, Media Management Branch, Faculty of Management, Tehran University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Somaye</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Labafi</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD. in Media Management, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran.
Email: s.labafi@ut.ac.ir</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Objective: The purpose of this study was to identify and investigate the problems of the policy-making process of monitoring content production management in cyberspace in Iran. Methods: This research was carried out using a qualitative approach by conducting semi-structured interviews with ten experts in the domain of cyberspace laws and regulations that have had an experience of at least five years of activity in this area. The snowball sampling method was used to decide over the participants of this study. Results: Content analysis was used to identify the problems of the policy-making management process and monitoring the content production in cyberspace. Then, the results were classified into seven general categories. Conclusion: These seven categories include problems of the regulatory system, content production policies, supporting content generation, security and privacy, cultural factors and infrastructures, weaknesses in decision making and technical infrastructure.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>251</start>
					<end>268</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_66108_a5fe9813b7acde914f31d043d05f63ab.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2018.254248.2235</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Designing a model for Acceptance of Non-governmental Organizations by the Citizens</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hamid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shojaei</namePart>
				<affiliation>, Ph.D Student of Public Administration - Organizational Behavior Management, Payamenoor University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mooghali</namePart>
				<affiliation>Prof. of Management, Payamenoor University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Javad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hozoori</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Prof. of Management, Payamenoor University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rasoulei</namePart>
				<affiliation>Prof. of Management, Payamenoor University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Objective: The present study seeks to design a model for Acceptance of Non-Governmental Organizations (NGOs) by the Citizens. This research is fundamental and practical in purpose and is exploratory in nature.
Methods: Qualitative method and Grounded Theory strategy were used to help design the study. 20 key experts were selected sing using judgmental purposive sampling, and then the researchers conducted deep interviews with them. Afterwards, the components were classified using the process of open, axial and selective coding and the final model was configured.
Results: The results of the research showed that the “acceptance” of NGO can be affected by many different factors like organizational, sociological, environmental and personal elements. In the proposedmodel, organizational and social elements are the causal elements; public gain and profitably are the axial categories; the attitudes include positive or negative emotions which are considered as the model Strategy. Eventually, behavioral intent which is the consequence of acceptance or non-acceptance of NGOs were identified. Activity environment and individual morality had significant effects on public attitudes of citizen toward NGOs.
Conclusion: The main outcome of this model in the behavioral field is the acceptanceof NGOs by the Citizens, based onsystematic perspective to the subject and considering organizational, environmental, and individual factors.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>269</start>
					<end>288</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_65840_55970774014a0c03648fbd90f97ec76b.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2018.254399.2238</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Investigating the Relationship between Corruption and Trust Related to Transparency and Citizen Satisfaction</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abas</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nargesian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof. of Public Administration, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ghasemali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Jamali</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.Sc. of Public Administration, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Masoud</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Harati</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.Sc of Public Organization Management, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hosein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Azari</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.Sc. of Public Administration, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Objective: Focusing on corruption, transparency, trust, and satisfaction of citizens is a priority in order to achieve a desirable and ideal society. The main objective of this research is to study these factors.
Methods: This study is a practical field study in which the data are collected according to the premises of descriptive studies. This survey research relates the variables based on causal relationships. Research Population consists of Tehran citizens in district #8 where random cluster sampling method has been applied. The data were collected and analyzed in a form of a questionnaire.
Results: The results show that clarity has a significantly positive effect on citizens’ trust and satisfaction; besides,  trust has a significantly positive effect on citizens’ satisfaction. At the same time, transparency has a significantly negaitive effect on corruption and corruption has a significantly negaitive effect on citizens’ trust and satisfaction.
Conclusion: An ideal government should pursue more transparency in the reduction of corruption at the community level and, with this; citizens&#039; satisfaction and trust will be achieved.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>289</start>
					<end>310</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_66385_6e7a20105827947638b1e059943d5430.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2018.255605.2250</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Paradoxical Influence of Job Satisfaction on Destructive Employees’ Voice, Considering the Mediating Role of Social Network Sites and Organizational Commitment</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Gholam Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Tabarsa</namePart>
				<affiliation>Prof. in Public Administration, Faculty of Management, Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sajjad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shokouhyar</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof. in Information Technology Management, Faculty of Management, Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Olfat</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc. in Management Information Systems, Faculty of Management, Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Objective: This study aims to investigate the paradoxical influence of job satisfaction on destructive employees’ voice behavior considering the mediating role of using social networking sites (SNSs) and organizational commitment.
Methods: 240 employees of Asia-tech Company have been surveyed in this regard. PLS algorithm has been used to evaluate the validity of the hypothesis. To do so, the WarpPls software has been used.
Results: The results of the study showed that employees&#039; social networking sites utilization can lead to an increase in destructive employees’ voice. The employees with higher level of job satisfaction and organizational commitment take more advantage of SNSs in order to keep in touch with their colleagues. Job satisfaction leads to an increase in level of both employees’ voice and organizational commitment. The employees with higher level of organizational commitment show less destructive voice than others.
Conclusion: The main contribution of this study is to show the fact that in spite of many advantages that can be considered for SNSs in the workplace, they can have some detrimental effects such as increasing destructive voice among employees.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Journal of Public Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2008-5877</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>311</start>
					<end>332</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_66386_f6051f8181242057f77e2044ac6133ac.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jipa.2018.254720.2240</identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>