<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1394</YEAR>
<VOL>7</VOL>
<NO>3</NO>
<MOSALSAL>3</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>244</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تحلیل نقش حکمرانی خوب در ارتقای توسعۀ انسانی: بررسی بین‌المللی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Role of Good Governance in the Promotion of Human Development: an international Study</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>پژوهش حاضر به بررسی تأثیر شاخص‏های شش‌گانۀ حکمرانی خوب بر شاخص توسعۀ انسانی می‏پردازد. در پژوهش پیش رو شاخص توسعۀ انسانی (HDI)، متغیر وابسته؛ ابعاد حکمرانی خوب، متغیرهای مستقل و توسعۀ فناوری ارتباطات متغیر تعدیل‏کننده در نظر گرفته شده است. رویکرد پژوهش حاضر اقتصادسنجی است و از روش تحلیل داده‏های پانل و تحلیل رگرسیون GLS برای آزمون فرضیه‏های پژوهش استفاده شده است. یافته‏های تخمین مدل برای کشورهای با سرانۀ تولید ناخالص داخلی کمتر از 6800 دلار در سال نشان می‏دهد ضریب متغیرهای کنترل فساد، ثبات سیاسی، اثربخشی حکومت، آزادی بیان و حق اظهارنظر و درصد کاربران اینترنت معنا‏دار است و می‏توان برای تخمین توسعۀ انسانی از آنها استفاده کرد. همچنین معادلۀ پیش‏بینی برای کشورهای با سرانۀ تولید ناخالص داخلی بیشتر از 6800 دلار در سال نشان می‏دهد ضرایب متغیرهای اثربخشی حکومت، مقررات تنظیمی و درصد کاربران اینترنت در مدل معنادار‌‌‌‌ند. درنهایت‌ بر اساس یافته‎ها در کشورهای آسیای جنوب غربی ضریب متغیرهای ثبات سیاسی و اثربخشی حکومت در معادلۀ پیش‏بینی سطح توسعۀ انسانی معنادار‌ند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Recent study examines the impact of good governance on the Human Development Index. In the present study, the Human Development Index (HDI) considered as dependent variable, good governance is independent variables and the development of communication technology has been considered as the moderator variable. The study approach is econometric panel data analysis and GLS regression analysis was used to test the research hypotheses. Findings of model for countries with per capita GDP of less than U.S. $ 6,800 shows that the coefficients of the control of corruption, political stability, government effectiveness and freedom of expression are at significant level and can be used to estimate the level of human development. The prediction equation for countries with GDP higher than $ 6,800 per year shows that the coefficients of the variables of government effectiveness, regulatory quality and internet users are significant. Finally, finding suggests that in the Southeastern countries of Asia the coefficients of the political stability and government effectiveness are significant for predicting levels of human development .</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>413</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>436</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>امیدیان</Family>
						<NameE>mohsen</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Omidian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس‎ارشد مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس‎ارشد مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mohsen_omidian@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>غلامرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>طالقانی</Family>
						<NameE>Gholamreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Taleghani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>gtalaghani@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فرشته</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمدی</Family>
						<NameE>fereshte</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mohammadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی گرایش مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی گرایش مدیریت منابع</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m_6062@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>جمال</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فیروزی</Family>
						<NameE>Jamal</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Firouzi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت منابع انسانی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>jamal_firoozi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حمیدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>یعقوبی</Family>
						<NameE>Hamidreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Yaghobi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس‎ارشد مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس‎ارشد مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hr.yaghubi@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حمزه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خواستار</Family>
						<NameE>Hamza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khastar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه خوارزمی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>khastar@khu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اینترنت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>حکمرانی خوب‌</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>داده‏های پانل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>روش GLS</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شاخص توسعۀ انسانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abbasi Nejad, H. &amp; Rafiee Emam, A.N. (2006).Evaluation of indicators of human development in rural areas. Journal of Economic Research, 72:  31-54.##(in Persian)##Afshani, A., Ebrahimpoor, S. &amp; Askari Nadooshan, A. (2011). Comparison of human based on development indices in the rural areas of the country in 1375 and 1385. Quarterly journal of development and rural, 14(3):1-18.##(in Persian)##Anand, S. &amp; Sen, A. K. (1996). Sustainable human development: concepts and periorities. Office of development studies discussion paper. No 1. New York: UNDP.##Baradaran Shoraka, H. &amp; Malek al-sadati, S. (2008). The impact of good governance on economic growth in selected countries. Journal of Strategy, (49): 27-52. (in Persian)##Bennedsen, M. &amp; Malchow-Moller, N &amp; VintenF. (2005). Institutions and Growth: a Literature Survey. Center for Economic and Business Research (CEBR).##Bridges.org. (2005). E-Ready for What? E-Readiness in Developing Countries: Current Status and Prospects toward the Millennium Development Goals. Cape Town: Bridges.org.##Dabbaq, S. &amp; Nafari, N. (2009). The explanation of Good concept of good governance. Journal of Public Administration, 1(3): 3-18. (in Persian)##Ebrahimpoor, H. &amp; Roshandel Arbatani,T. (2008). Explaining the Role of the National Media(IRIB) in Sustainability Governance Model in Iran. Jouranl of Public Administration, 0(1): 43-62. (in Persian)##Engerman S.L &amp; Sokoloff, K.L.  (2005). Colonialism, Inequality and long-run paths of development. Working Paper 11057. National Bureau of Economic Resesarch. Cambridge, MA.##Feng, Y. (2003). Democracy, Governance and Economic Performance: Theory and Evidence. Cambridge: MA, MIT Press.##Fosu, A.K. (2001). Political Instability and Economic Growth in Developing Economies: Some Specification Empirics. Economics letters, 70(2): 289-294.##GeoSINC. (2002). e-Readiness Guide-How to Develop and Implement a National e-Readiness Action Plan in Developing Countries. Washington, DC: infoDev - The World Bank. GeoSINC International.##Gilbert, N. (2003). Trade  openness  policy,  Quality  of  instituations  and  economic  growth,  University Auvergne Clermont, Frrand, France.##Grindle, S. M. (2007). Good enough governance revisited. Development Policy Review, 25(5): 553-574.##‌Hosseini, M.A. (1994). Human Development Index in rural provinces in the national and global scale. Jihad, 17: 9-17. (in Persian)##Johnson, R. W. &amp; Minis, H. (1990). Toward democratic decentralization. USA ID Washington.##Knack, S. &amp; Keefer, P. (1995). Institutions and Economic Performance: Cross Country Tests Using Alternative Institutional Measures. Economics and Politics, 7: 207-227.##Mahany, A.S., Barouni, M., Mohammadzadeh, A., Mashali, B. &amp; Rezapour, A. (2010). Comparing of townships efficiency of Kerman province in accessing to human development index (HDI) via Data Envelopment Analysis (DEA) - 2001&amp; 2007. Teb va Tazkieh, 76: 46-101.##‌Mahmoodi, M.J. (2008). Measurmenet of human-development index: the country, Tehran province and its sub-cities. Quarterly journal of population, (67-68): 81-118. (in Persian)##Matsuo, H. (2005). The Rule of Law and Economic Development: A Causeor a Result? In The: Role of Law in Development: Past, Present and Future, ed. Y. Matsuura, CALE Books 2. Nagoya: Nagoya University.##Mauro, P. (1995). Corruption and Growth. Quarterly Journal of Economics, 110: 681-712.##Meydari, A. &amp; Kheirkhahan, J. (2004). Good Governance. Majlis Research Center.##Mirshojaeyan Hosseini, H. &amp; Rahbar, F. (2011). Understanding Ali’s relationship among good governance components in the countries which are at the risk of natural resource curse. Nameye Mofid, No 87.##Moghimi, S.M. &amp; Alayee, M. (2011). Assessing the criteria of good governance and the role of government in promoting it. Quarterly Journal ofInformationTechnology Management, 3(8): 171-188. (in Persian)##Noorbakhsh, F. (2002). Human development and regional disparities in Iran: a policy model. Journal of international development, 14 (7): 927-949.##Polat, R.K. (2005). The Internet and Political Participation Exploring the Explanatory Links. European Journal of Communication, 20(4): 435-459.##Qolipoor, R.A. (2004). Feasibility analysis and good governance with emphasis on the role of government in Iran. Management Knowledge, 67: 85-111.##Renani, M. (2003). The government&#039;s role in institutional reforms through legislation. The parliament and research, 10(39): 13-30.  (in Persian)##Rizk, N. (2004). E-Readiness Assessment of Small and Medium Enterprises in Egypt: A Micro Study. Cairo.##Roy, I. (2008). Civil society &amp; good government. Re conceptualizing the interface. World development, 36 (4): 667-705.##Sabaq Kermani, M. &amp; Baskha, M. (2009). The role of good governance in improving the functioning of government expenditure: Case study: Islamic countries health and education sectors. Journal of Economic Research, 4(1): 109-130. (in Persian)  ##Sagar, A. D. &amp; Najam, A. (1997). The human development index: a critical Review. Ecological Economics, 25: 249–264.##Sameti, M., Ranjbar, H. &amp; Mohseni, F. (2011). The analysis of the impact of good governance on the Human Development Index; Case Study; Southeast Asian countries. Quarterly journal ofresearch growth and economic development, 1(4): 183-223. (in Persian) ##Shahabadi, A. &amp; Pourjavan, A. (2010). Rule, competitiveness and economic growth in selected countries. Strategy Development Journal. 22: 129-168.##(in Persian) ##Suryadarma, D. (2008). Corruption, Public Spending and Outcomes: Evidences from Indonesia, Economics and Democracy Conference. The AustralianNational University, Canberra.##Taqvayee, M. (2006). Analysis and classification of rural areas in the provinces on the basis of human development indicators. Geographical Investigation, 82: 28-44. (in Persian) ##Taqvayee, M. &amp; Noroozi Avargani, A. (2010). Determining the level of analysis to rural areas nationwide by using numerical taxonomy and cluster analysis method. Planning Welfareand social development, 5: 91-116. (in Persian) ##The Economist Intelligence Unit (EIU). (2010). Digital economy rankings 2010 beyond e-readiness. London: Economist Intelligence Unit.##UNDP. (2013). Human Development Report 2013: The Rise of the South: Human Progress in a Diverse World. Available online: http: //hdi.undp.org.##WDI. (2007). World Development Indicators. The World Bank, Washington DC. 19. (1): 46-58.##Ziaeipour, E., Taghizade, A., Bazazan, F., Khoshalhan, F. &amp; Mohamadian, A. (2009). Sixth International Conference on Information Technology: New Generations. pp: 993-998. IEEE Computer Society.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>فمینیسم در مطالعات سازمان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Feminism in organization studies</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT> از به‎کارگیری دیدگاه‎های فمینیستی در پژوهش‎های اجتماعی زمان زیادی نمی‎گذرد، ولی تبار آنها را می‎توان از قرن هجدهم دنبال کرد. هرچند بر این دست نگرش‎ها نقدهایی هم شده است، نقش سازندۀ آنها در نشان‌دادن سویه‎های تازه را نمی‎توان نادیده گرفت. فراگیر‌شدن سازمان‎ها و نقش بارز قدرت در آنها، سازمان‎ها را از تیغ رویکردهای نقادانه در امان نگذاشته است و اندیشمندان فمینیست هم در آفریدن چشم‎اندازهایی تازه به زندگی سازمانی سهم داشته‎اند. پژوهش پیش رو در پی پاسخ به این پرسش است: رویکرد فمینیستی، به نقد چه جنبه‎هایی از سازمان‎ها و زندگی سازمانی می‎پردازد؟ ‎به بیان دیگر، نقدها بر کدام ابعاد زندگی سازمانی تمرکز دارند؟ پس از مرور پیشینۀ این دیدگاه‎ها و مفاهیم و اندیشه‎های اساسی آنها، پژوهش‎های فمینیستی در مطالعات سازمان بررسی می‎شوند. رویکرد پژوهش‌ توصیفی‌‌ـ تحلیلی است و با روش تحلیل مضمون پیش می‎رود که از روش‎های تحلیل محتوای کیفی به‌شمار می‎آید. پس از بررسی 21 متن، نشان داده می‎شود که می‎توان کانون نقد دیدگاه‎های فمینیستی را در چارچوب دوسطحی جای داد که تصویری از مرزهای این رهیافت نقادانه در مطالعات سازمان فرا رو می‎نهد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Adopting feminist perspectives is, by and large, novel in social science. However, feminism historical background might be followed until 18th century. Through the years, patriarchal epistemology and gendered metaphysics of science have been criticized fundamentally by radical feminist thinkers. Although such criticisms obviously have limitations, their constructive role in addressing original insights is undeniable. Due to Ubiquity of organizations in modern world and significance of power within organization, organizational life has great potential for feminist criticism. Feminist scholars provide creative insights for organization studies and reveal the true nature of organizations. This paper discusses about critical reading of organizational life and aspects of organizations criticized by feminism. In other words, the main question is which characteristics of organizational life make it susceptible to feminist criticism. The current descriptive research is conducted through Theme Analysis (TA) method; a widely used approach to qualitative content. Reviewing 21 texts, it is maintained that objects of feminist criticism in organization studies could be depicted in two-level framework.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>437</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>458</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>امیرحسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خالقی</Family>
						<NameE>Amir</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khaleghi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>amirkhaleghi@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی اصغر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>پورعزت</Family>
						<NameE>Ali asghar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Pourezzat</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>pourezzat@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جنس</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جنسیت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فمینیسم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مطالعات سازمان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Acker, J. (2009). From glass ceiling to inequality regimes. Sociologie du travail, 51(2): 199–217.##Acker, J. (1992). From Sex Roles to Gendered Institutions. Contemporary Sociology, 21 (5): 565-569.##Acker, J. (2000). Gendered Contradictions in Organizational Equity Projects. Organization, 7 (4): 625-632.##Acker, J. (2006). Inequality Regimes: Gender, Class, and Race in Organizations. Gender and Society, 20 (4), 441-464.##Acker, J. (2011). Theorizing Gender, Race, and Class in Organizations. In E. Jeanes, D. Knights, &amp; P. Y. Martin (Eds.), Handbook of Gender, Work and Organization (1st Edition ed., pp. 65-80). Chichester, West Sussex: Wiley.##Ahanchian, M. R. (2009). End of Management; Collapse of the Management narratives in the Modern age. Tehran, Iran: Nashr-e-Ney. (in Persian)##Alvesson, M. &amp; Billing, Y. D. (1992). Gender and Organization: Toward a Differentiated understanding. Organization Studies, 13 (12): 73-102.##Anderson, E. (1995). Feminist Epistemology: An Interpretation and a Defense. Hypatia, 10 (3): 50-84.##Britton, D. M. (2000). The Epistemology of the gendered organization. Gender &amp; Society, 14 (3): 418-434.##Brooks, A. (2003). PostFeminism, Feminism, Cultural theory and cultural Forms. New York: Routledge.##Butler, J. (1999). Gender Trouble, Feminism and the subversion of identity. New York and London: Routledge.##Calas, M. B. (1993). Deconstructing charismatic leadership: re-Reading weber from the darker side. Leadership Quarterly, 4(3-4): 305-328.##Calas, M. B. &amp; Smircich, L. (1999). From &#039;The Woman &#039;s &#039; Point of View: Feminist Approaches to Organization studies. In S. R. Clegg, &amp; C. Hardy (Eds.), Studying organization, Theory and method (pp. 212-251). London, Thousand Oaks and New Delhi: Sage Publications.##Calás, M. B. &amp; Smircich, L. (1991). Voicing Seduction to Silence Leadership. Organization Studies, 12 (4): 567-602.##Coppock, V., Haydon, D. &amp; Richter, I. (1995). The Illusions of Post-Feminism: New Women, Old Myths. London: Taylor &amp; Francis.##Deetz, S. (1996). Describing differences in approaches to Organization Science: Rethinking Burrell and Morgan and their legacy. Organization Science, 7 (2): 191-207.##Delmar, R. (1986). What is Feminism? New York: Pantheon Books.##Ebrahimpour, H., Mokabberi, A. H., Rivaz, D. &amp; Roshandel, T. (2011). The media and glass ceiling: Explanation of television impact on the women promotion to the managerial levels. Journal of Public Administration, 3 (6):1-18.##(in Persian)##Farmer, D. J. (1997). Derrida, Deconstruction and public administration. American Behavioral Scientists, 41 (1): 12-27.##Fay, B. (2009). Contemporary philosophy of science, A multicultural Approach. Trans by K. Deyhimi. Tehran, Iran: Nashr-e-Ney. (in Persian)##Feldberg, R. L. &amp; Glenn, E. N. (1979). Male and Female: Job versus Gender Models in the Sociology of Work. Social Problems, 26 (5): 524-538.##Gamble, S. (2006). PostFeminism. In S. Gamble (Ed.), The Routledge Companion to Feminism and Postfeminism (pp. 36-45). London: Routledge.##Griffin, G. H. (2000). Editorial. Feminist Theory, 1 (1): 5-9.##Hale, M. M. (1996). Gender Equality in Organizations: Resolving the Dilemmas. Review of Public Personnel Administration, 16(1): 7-18.##Harding, S. &amp; Hintikka, M. B. (1983). Introduction. In S. Harding, &amp; M. B. Hintikka (Eds.), Discovering reality, Feminist Perspectives on Epistemology, Metaphysics, Methodology, and Philosophy of Science (pp. ix-xix). Dordrecht, Holland: Kluwer Academic Publishers.##Hatch, M. J. &amp; Cunliffe, A. L. (2006). Organization Theory;Modern, Symbolic, and postmodern perspectives. 2nd edition ed. New Delhi: Oxford university press.##Hearn, J. &amp; Parkin, P. W. (1983). Gender and Organizations: A Selective Review and a Critique of a Neglected. Organization Studies, 4 (3): 219-242.##Horn, P. (1995). Where Is Feminism Now? Agenda, 26: 71-74.##Humm, M. (1990). The Dictionary of Feminist Theory. Columbus: Ohio State University Press.##Jaggar, A. (2000). Feminism in Ethics: Moral Justification. In M. Fricker, &amp; J. Hornsby (Eds.), The Cambridge Companion to Feminism in Philosophy. Cambridge: Cambridge university Press.##Jardine, A. (1985). Gynesis: Configurations of Woman and Modernity. Ithaca and London: Cornell University Press.##Jones, C. (2004). Jacques Derrida. In S. Linstead (Ed.), Organization theory and Postmodern Thought (pp. 34-63). London, Thousand Oaks, New Delhi: Sage.##Lyotard, J. F. (1984). The postmodern Condition: A report on Knowledge. Trans by G. Bennington &amp; B. Massumi. Minneapolis: University of Minnesota Press.##Martin, J. (1990). Deconstructing Organizational Taboos: The Suppression of Gender Conflict in Organizations. Organization Science, 1 (4): 339-359.##Martin, J. (2000). Hidden Gendered Assumptions in Mainstream Organizational Theory and Research. Journal of Management Inquiry, 9 (2): 207-216.##Martin, J. &amp; Knopoff, K. (1997). The gendered implications of apparently gender-neutral theory: re-reading Max Weber. In E. F. R, &amp; A. Larson (Eds.), Women&#039;s Studies and Business Ethics: Toward a New Conversation. New York: Oxford University Press.##Mills, A. J. (1988). Organization, Gender and Culture. Organization Studies, 9(3): 351-369.##Mills, S. (2003). Foucault. London: Routledge.##Morgan, G. (2005). Images of Organization. Trans by A. M. Moshabaki. Tehran, Iran: University of Tehran Publication. (in Persian)##Morgan, G. &amp; Burrell, G. (2007). Sociological Paradigms and Organizational Analysis. Trans by M. T. Norouzi. Tehran, Iran: SAMT Publishing.##(in Persian)##Mumby, D. K. &amp; Putnam, L. L. (1992). The Politics of Emotion: A Feminist Reading of Bounded Rationality. The Academy of Management Review, 17 (3): 465-486.##Nicolson, P. (2005). Gender, Power and Organisation, a psychological Perspective. London &amp; New York: Routledge.##Offen, K. (1988). Defining Feminism: A Comparative Historical Approach. Signs, 14 (1): 119-157.##Pilcher, J. &amp; Whelehan, I. (2004). Fifty concepts in Gender Studies. London, Thousand Oaks &amp; New Delhi: Sage Publication.##Riley, P. (1983). A structurationist account of political culture. Administrative Science Quarterly, 28 (3): 414-437.##Sanders, V. (2006). First Wave Feminism. In S. Gamble (Ed.), The Routledge Companion to Feminism and Postfeminism (pp. 15-24). London: Routledge.##Scott, R. W. (2006). Organiazations and Organizing, Rational, natural and open system perspectives. New York: Prentice hall.##Taleghani, G. R., Pourezzat, A. A. &amp; Farajji, B. (2009). Survey on the Effect of Glass Ceiling on Decrease of Women Empowerment in Iran Power Development Co. (IPDC). Journal Of Public Administration, University of Tehran, 1 (2): 89-102. (in Persian)##Thompson, D. (2001). Who’s Afraid of Defining Feminism? Australian Women’s Studies Conference, Macquarie University. sydney.##Thornham, S. (2006). Second Wave Feminism. In S. gamble (Ed.), The Routledge Companion to Feminism and Postfeminism (pp. 25-35). London: Routledge.##Tong, R. (2009). Feminist Thought: A Comprehensive Introduction. 3th Edition ed. Colorado: Westview Press.##Tyler, M. (2011). Postmodern Feminism and Organization Studies: A Marriage of Inconvenience? In E. Jeanes, D. Knights, &amp; P. Y. Martin (Eds.), Handbook of Gender, Work and Organization (1st Edition ed., pp. 9-24). Chichester, West Sussex: Wiley.##Walters, M. (2005). Feminism, A very short Introduction. New York: Oxford University Press.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی عوامل رفتاری وساختاری موثر بر خادمیت کمیته امدادامام خمینی(ره)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigating  Structural  and  Behavioral  Factors Affecting Stewardship within the Imam Khomeini Relief Foundation</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT> هدف نهایی سازمان‌های دولتی و عام‌ا‌لمنفعه، عملکردی است که منافع مردم را تأمین کند، از آنجا‌ که نمود این عملکرد در سازمان خادم تجلی می‌یابد، شناسایی عوامل مؤثر بر شکل‌گیری این نوع سازمان اهمیت دارد. این مقاله که مبتنی بر پژوهش کمّی است با استفاده از ‌مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری به مطالعۀ عوامل مؤثر بر خادمیت نهاد کمیتۀ امداد امام‌خمینی(ره) می‌پردازد. جامعۀ آماری این مطالعه را کلیۀ کارکنان نهاد کمیتۀ امداد امام‌خمینی(ره) تشکیل می‌دهد که 257 نفر از آنان به‎کمک روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی طبقه‌بندی و به‌منزلۀ نمونۀ آماری انتخاب شدند. داده‌ها به‎کمک پرسشنامۀ پژوهشگرساخته گردآوری شدند و تجزیه‎وتحلیل آنها با اجرای آزمون معادلات ساختاری و تحلیل عاملی در نرم‌افزار لیزرل صورت گرفت. یافته‎های پژوهش نشان داد آگاهی از عوامل برانگیزانندۀ کارکنان، نگرش و خلق وخوی خادمانه، شکل‎گیری فضای مناسب خدمت در سازمان، تقویت رفتارهای خادمانه با رهبری خادم و مطالبه‌گری محیطی، تأثیر شایان توجهی در خادمیت این نهاد دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>AbstractThe ultimate goal of any state or public organization is to function in such a way that seeks to act in the public interest and, consequently, result in the general public consent. Since this is reflected by the manners of conduct and performance of organizations’ employees towards people and clients under the title of Organizational Stewardship, it is important to identify the factors that affect such a conduct to be realized within organizationsThis paper, which is based on a quantitative research methodology, attempted to study the factors that affected organizational serving to be developed within the Imam Khomeini Relief Foundation using the Structural Equation Modeling (SEM). The statistical population of this study consisted of all the employees working in the Imam Khomeini Relief Foundation, i.e. 780 individuals, 256 of whom were chosen as the participants using the Stratified Random Sampling method and Cochran’s Formula. Data were collected using the designed questionnaire, and were analyzed through conducting the Structural Equation Test and a factor analysis in LISREL software. The results verified the hypotheses, and finally, it was suggested that employee awareness of the motivating factors, the existence of a serving attitude and of an appropriate milieu for organizational serving, and ultimately, reinforcing such conducts with the help of a servant leader and local demanding play an important role towards the development of an organizational serving attitude..</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>459</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>480</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>درویش</Family>
						<NameE>Hassan Darvish</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Darvish</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران‌</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>dr.darvish@hotmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فتحی زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Fathizade</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری رشتۀ مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران‌</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری رشتۀ مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>a_fathii@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>انگیزه‌های خادمیت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سازمان خادم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کنش‌های خادمیت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abakus, E., Yavas, U. &amp; Ashill, N. J. (2011). Service worker burnout and turnover intentions: Roles of person-job fit, servant leadership, and customer orientation. Services Marketing Quarterly, 32(1): 17–31.##Alvani, S. &amp; Danaifard, H. (2001). Public Trust. Journal of Management knowledge, 14(55): 5-28. (in Persian)##Alvani, S. (2002). Stewardship Theory or Agency Theory, Quarterly Journal of Management and Development process, 16 (1): 6-11. (in Persian)##Armstrong, J. (1997). Stewardship and public service, Discussion paper prepared for the Public Service Commission of Canada.##Benoy, J.W. (1996). Internal Marketing Builds Service Quality. Journal of Health Care Marketing, 16(1): 54-59.##Block, P. (1993). Stewardship: Choosing Service over Self Interest, San Francisco: Published by Berrett-Koehler Publishers.##Choi, J. &amp; Wang, H. (2007). The promise of a managerial values approach to corporate philanthropy. Journal of Business Ethics, 75(4): 345–359.##Danaeefard, H., Rajabzadeh, A. &amp; Darvishi, A. )2010(. The role of Islamic-ethical competence in increasing public hospitals accountability. Iranian Journal of Business Medical and History of Medicine, 3 (4): 57-70.##Darvish, H., Hasanzadeh, A., Montazeri, M. &amp; Fathizadeh, A. (2015). Design and Explanation of the Servant Organization Model (Case study: Imam Khomeini Relief Foundation (RA)). Journal of public organizations management, 2(4): 57-74. (in Persian)##Davis, J., Schoorman, D. &amp; Donaldson, L. (1997). Towards a stewardship theory of management. Academy of Management Review, 22(1): 20-47.##Denhardt, R. &amp; Denhardt, J. (2002). The New Public service: An approach to reform. Arizona state university.##Dibrell, C. &amp; Moeller, M. (2011). The impact of a service-dominant focus strategy and stewardship culture on organizational innovativeness in family-owned businesses. Journal of Family Business Strategy, 2(1): 43–51.##Donaldson, L. &amp; Davis, J.H. (1991). Stewardship Theory or Agency Theory. Australian Journal of Management, 16(1): 49-64.##Eddleston, K.A. &amp; Kellermanns, F.W. (2007). Destructive and productive family relationships: A stewardship theory perspective. Journal of Business Venturing, 22 (4): 545-565.##Faghihi, A. &amp; Kelidbari, H. (2007). Studying Iranian Hospitals from the Standpoint of Stewardship Theory. Iranian Journal of management science, 3(89):1-18. (in Persian)##Gholipor, A., Poreza, A. &amp; Hazrati, M. )2008). Survey Impact of Servant Leadership on Organizational Trust and Development of Staff in Government organization. Government Management, 1(2): 103-118.##Hernandez, M. (2008). Promoting stewardship behavior in organizations: A leadership model. Journal of Business Ethics, 80(1): 121–128.##Hernandez, M. )2012(. Toward an understanding of the psychology of stewardship. Academy of Management Review, 37(2): 172-193.##Jeavons, T.H. (1994). Stewardship Revisited: Secular and Sacred Views of Governance and Management. Published by sage, 23(2): 107-122.##Johnson, J.W. (1996). Linking employee perceptions of service climate to customer satisfaction. Personnel Psychology, 49(4): 831-851.##Kim, C. &amp; Mauborgne, R. (2003). Fair process: Managing in the knowledge economy. Harvard Business Review, 81(5): 127–136.##King, Ch. S. (1997). Government is us: public administration in an Anti-Government Era. Sage publication. Thousands Oaks, C.A.##Lange, D. (2008). A multidimensional conceptualization of organizational corruption control. Academy of Management Review, 33(3): 710–729.##Lehto, A. (2013). Exploring Organizational Service Orientation: Preliminary Analysis in the Retail Industry. Master’s Thesis, Aalto-yliopisto, PL 11000, 00076 AALTO.##Leonus Wesley, C. (2010). The impact of stewardship on firm performance, Submitted to the office of Graduate Studies of Texas A&amp;M University in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the degree of Doctor of Philosophy.##Lewis, R. &amp; Noble, J. (2011). Servant leadership. Management Books 2000 Ltd.##Lytle, R. S., Hom, P. W. &amp; Mokwa, M. P. (1998). SERV*OR: managerial measure of organizational service-orientation. Journal of Retailing, 74(4): 455-489.##Marvel, M. &amp; Marvel, H. (2008). Government-to-government contracting: Stewardship, agency, and substi‏tution. International Public Management Journal, 11(2): 171–192.##Mortazevi, S., Rahimnia, F. &amp; Hakimi, H. (2013). Congruence stewardship and agency of manager and effective in the organizational behavior of firm imagery. Management general researches, 6(19): 41-59. (in Persian)##Moseley, D. (1997). Joyful Giving: Sermons on stewardship. St. Louis, Missouri: Chalic press.##Nóbrega, K. (2008). Servant organization: how individual behavior can be expanded to a business approach, Universidade Potiguar.##Nooteboom, B. (2007). Social capital, institutions and trust. Review of Social Economy, 65(1): 29–53.##Ostrom, E. (1990). Governing the commons: The evolution of institutions for collective action. Cambridge University Press.## Parris, D.L. &amp; Peachey, J.W. (2013). A Systematic Literature Review of Servant Leadership Theory in Organizational Contexts. Journal of Business Ethics,113(3): 377–393.##Schein, Edgar H. (2010). Organizational Culture and Leadership. San Francisco: Jossey-Bass Pub- lishers.##Schneider, B. &amp; Bowen, D. E. (1995). Winning the Service Game. Boston, MA: Harvard Business School Press.##Schneider, Benjamin, Arthur P. Brief, and Richard A. Guzzo. (1996). &quot;Creating a Climate and Culture for Sustainable Organizational Change. Organizational Dynamics, 24 (4): 6-19##Segal, L. &amp; Lehrer, M. (2012). The Institutionalization of Stewardship: Theory, Propositions, and Insights from Change in the Edmonton Public Schools. Organization Studies, 33(2): 169-201.##Timney, M. (1999). The Imperative of Theory in public Administration practice. PA Times, Sage, 3)7):18-37.##Vaezi, R. (1992). Political environment and efficiency. Journal of observation management, 3(9): 155-164. (in Persian)##Van Slyke, D. (2007). Agents or stewards: Using theory to understand the government–-nonprofit social service contracting relationship. Journal of Public Administration Research and Theory, 17(2): 157–187.##Vlaar, P., Van den Bosch, F. &amp; Volberda, H. (2007). On the evolution of trust, distrust, and formal coordina­tion and control in interorganizational relationships. Group &amp; Organization Management, 32(4): 407–429.##Walker, J. (2007). Service climate in New Zealand English language centres. Journal of Educational Administration, 45(3(: 315-337.##Washington, R. R., Sutton, C. D. &amp; field, H. S. (2006). Individual Difference in Servant Leadership: The Roles of Values and Personality. The Leadership and Organization Development Journal, 27)8(:700-716.##Wasserman, N. (2006). Stewards, agents, and the founder discount: Executive compensation in new ventures. Academy of Management Journal, 49(5): 960–976.##Winston, B. (2003). Extending Patterson’s servant leadership model: explaining how leaders and flowers interact in a circular model. Paper presented at the Servant Leadership Research Roundtable, Regent University: Virginia Beach, VA; 13(1) 69–72.##Wong, P. (2003). An Opponent-Process Model of Servant Leadership and Typology of Leadership Styles, Trinity western University, 1(2): 22-44.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>پژوهشی بنیادین در حوزۀ مفاهیم نظری سیاستگذاری رسانه ای</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Essential research in the field of theoretical concepts of media policy</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT> سیاستگذاری رسانه‌ای، راهبردهای کلانی است که بر هدایت رسانه‌ها در نیل به اهداف مشخص نظام حاکم دلالت دارد. از‌ آنجا‌که حوزۀ سیاستگذاری رسانه‌ای، حوزه‌ای ناشناخته در داخل کشور است، هدف این پژوهش، اجرای پژوهشی نظری در حوزۀ سیاستگذاری رسانه‌ای و تبیین چارچوبی نظری برای آن است. از بررسی‌های به‎عمل‎آمده مشخص شد که از بعد نظری دو رویکرد در حوزۀ سیاستگذاری رسانه‌ای وجود دارد؛ رویکرد اول که رویکردی سنتی به سیاستگذاری رسانه است، رسانه‌ها را نهادهایی قابل سیاستگذاری می‌داند و در این راستا بیشتر دولت و حاکمیت‌ها را پر‌رنگ می‌کند که چطور دولت‌ها برای حفظ منافع عمومی دست به سیاستگذاری رسانه‌ای می‌زنند. رویکرد دوم ‌از نظر پیشرفت‌های تکنولوژیک حوزۀ ارتباطات، عرصۀ رسانه را عرصه‌ای غیر‌قابل سیاستگذاری می‌داند. در این مقاله تلاش شده است بر‌اساس مدل‌ها و نظریه‌های موجود در حوزۀ سیاستگذاری رسانه‌ای، در قالب این دو رویکرد چارچوب نظری جداگانه‎ای تدوین شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Media policy is the major strategies that guide the media in achieving the specific objectives. Since the field of media policy area in the country is unknown, purpose of this study is carried out theoretical research in the field of media policy and develops a theoretical framework. Theoretically there are two approaches in the field of media policy. The first approach is that the traditional approach to media policy, media and policy institutions can be understood in this context to highlight the role of government and the rule of it that how governments protect the public interest.The second approach is an approach those in terms of technological advances in the field of non-media communication&#039;s policy. In this work, based on models and theories in the field of media policy, theoretical framework in the form of two separate approaches has been developed.Key words: media, media policy, policy</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>481</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>504</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>طاهر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>روشندل اربطانی</Family>
						<NameE>Taher</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Roshandel Arbatani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت رسانه‏، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت رسانه‏، دانشکدۀ</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>arbatani@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رسانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سیاستگذاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سیاستگذاری رسانه‌ای</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Barman, S. (2010). Where has media policy gone? In the communication law and policy, 9(2): 153-182.##Binzerhbolt, S. &amp; Kelemmesen, R. (2005). Responsive government? Public opinion and government policy, political studies, 53(2): 379-402.##Chin, Y.C. (2011). Policy process, policy learning, and the role of the provincial media in China, University of Nottingham. Media, Culture &amp; Society journal, 33(2): 193-210.##Cuilenburg, J.V. &amp; McQuail, D. (2003). Media Policy Paradigm Shifts. European Journal of Communication, 18(2): 181-207.##Do sola pool, I. (1974). Analysis of Political elites = those in power, Harvard university publication.##Dye, T.R. (2007). Understanding public policy, prentice hall policy press.##Freedman, D. (2006). Dynamics of power in contemporary media policy-making, Goldsmiths College. Media Culture Society, 28(6): 907-923.##Freedman, D. (2008). The politics of media policy, Cambridge, UK, Polity Press.##Freedman, D. (2010). Media Policy Silences: The Hidden Face of Communications Decision Makin. International Journal of Press/Politics, 15(3): 344-361.##Garnham, N. (2006). The media; An Introduction. London: longman press.##Halin, D. &amp; Manincy, P. (2006). Camparing media systems: Three models of media and politics, Mc gill university.##Hemerijck, A.C. (2007). Media Policy for the Digital Age, Amsterdam University Press.##Herman, B. D. (2011). New media law and policy, Hunter College. New Media &amp; Society, 13(2): 350-356.##Howard, T. (2009). Media power, professionals and policies, sage publications.##Humphreys, P. (2009). The politics of media policy: how political? Politics, School of Social Sciences, University of Manchester publication.##Hutchin, D. (2010). Media policy, Blackwell press.##Iosifidis, P. (2007). Public television in the digital era: techological challenges and new strategies for Europe, sage press.##Jenkins, H. (2006). Convergence culture: where old and new media collide. USA: New York university press.##Katz, Y. (2000). The diminishing role of governments in cable policy. European Journal of Political Research, 38(2): 285–302.##Kwach, K. &amp; Ronstel, T. (1999). The context of the regulation of TV broadcasting in East Asia, Gazette, 61(3-4): 255–273.##Lasswell, H. (1951). The Policy Sciences, Stanford: Stanford University Press.##Lazarsfeld, P. (1941). Radio and the Printed Page: An Introduction to policy. New York: Duell, Sloan, and Pearce.##Leah, L. &amp; Livingstone, S. (2008). The handbook of new media, sage publications.##McChesney, R. W. (2003). Theses on media deregulation. Media Culture &amp; Society, 25(1): 125-133.##McQuail, D, (2009). Mass communication theory, London: sage.##Miller, D. (2004). Tell me lies: propaganda and media distortion in the attack on Iraq. London: Pluto Press.##Monygomery, K. (2007). Youth and Digital Media: A Policy Research Agenda. journal of adolescent health, 27(2): 61-68.##Napoli, P.M. &amp; Seaton, M. (2007). Necessary Knowledge for Communications Policy: Information Asymmetries and Commercial Data Access and Usage in the Policymaking Process. Federal Communications Law Journal, 59(2): 295-330.##Olmsted, Ch. &amp; Sylvia, M. (2006). Competitive Strategy for Media Firms; Strategic and Brand Management in Changing Media Markets. Lawrence Erlbaum Associates.##Puppis, L. (2010). Exploratory study of how policy research is used in the policy process by policy maker staff and public administrators. Political Communication, 23(4): 407-420.##Rhodes, R. (2010). Policy networks: a British perspective. Journal of theoretical politics, 18(7)##Sarkakiss, J. (2006). An introduction to policy process. Open University Press, McGraw-Hill Education.##Smith, P. (2007). The Politics of Television Policy: the introduction of digital television in Great Britain, Lewiston, USA / Queenston, Canada / Lampeter, UK, The Edwin Mellen Press.##Sorokas, S. (2008). Agenda-setting dynamics in Canada. Vancouver: University of British Columbia Press.##Tamber, H. (2007). Media power, professionals and policies. Sag publications.##Turow, J. (2009). Media Today, An Introduction to Mass Communication, 3rd Edition, Routledge publication.##Van de Donk, P. (2005). Media Policy for the Digital Age, The Netherlands Scientific Council for Government Policy, Amsterdam University Press.##Vivian, J. (2008). The Media of Mass Communication, Person Publications.##Ward, D. (2008). Television and Public Policy: change and continuity in an era of globalization, Lawrence Erlbaum Association press.##Yoo, Y., Lyytinen, K. &amp; Yang, E. (2005). The role of standards in innovation and diffusion of broadband mobile services. Journal of Strategic Information Systems, 14(3): 323–353.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>شناسایی و اولویت بندی معیارهای مدیریت ارتباط با شهروندان در سازمان ‏های دولتی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Identification and Prioritization of Criteria of Citizen Relationship Management in Governmental Organizations</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT> مدیریت ارتباط با شهروند، رویکردی نوین برای بهبود خدمات سازمان‏های دولتی و بخش عمومی و دستیابی به خرسندی شهروندان است. هدف اصلی این پژوهش بررسی و رتبه‏بندی عامل‏های بخش‏بندی مشتریان در سازمان‏های دولتی است. بدین‌منظور با بررسی پژوهش‏های پیشین، چهار دسته عامل روان‏شناختی، جمعیت‌شناختی، رفتاری‌ و موقعیتی شناسایی شد. هر یک از این عامل‏ها نیز شماری زیرعامل دارند. روش پژوهش حاضر، از نظر هدف کاربردی است و از لحاظ روش، توصیفی‌ـ پیمایشی به‎شمار می‎رود و به‌طور مشخص مبتنی بر روش تحلیل سلسله‌مراتبی است. جامعۀ آماری این پژوهش را خبرگان سازمان‏های دولتی شهر بوشهر و دانشگاه خلیج فارس تشکیل می‏دهند. به‌منظور گردآوری داده‏ها از ابزار پرسش‌نامه استفاده شده است. با به‌کارگیری روش تحلیل سلسله‌مراتبی، وزن هر یک از عامل‏ها و‌ زیرعامل‏ها محاسبه شد. یافته‏های پژوهش نشان می‏دهد معیارهای موقعیتی در رتبۀ نخست قرار دارد و رتبه‎های بعدی به‎ترتیب به عامل رفتاری، روان‏شناختی و جمعیت‌شناختی اختصاص یافته است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Citizen Relationship Management is a novel approach for public sector and governmental organization to improve their services and to achieve citizen satisfaction. The main purpose of this study is to identify and prioritize customer segmentation in governmental organizations. For the reason, based on reviewing the literature, four group of psychological, demographic, behavioral, and situation factors were identified. Each of these factors includes some sub-factors. Required data were collected using a questionnaire answered by experts from both academia and organization. Using Analytical Hierarchy Process, the weight for each factor and all the sub-factors were calculated. Research findings show that situation factor is in the first rank. Following that, behavioral, psychological, and demographic factors are in the lower ranks, respectively.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>505</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>524</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>خداکرم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سلیمی فرد</Family>
						<NameE>Khodakaram</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Salimifard</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار تحقیق در عملیات، گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشگاه خلیج فارس، بوشهر، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار تحقیق در عملیات، گروه مدیریت صنعتی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>salimifard@pgu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>بدریه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رضایی</Family>
						<NameE>Badriyeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rezaee</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه خلیج فارس، بوشهر، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی، گروه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ba.rezaee@mehr.pgu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>آزاده</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رجبی</Family>
						<NameE>Azadeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rajabi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه خلیج فارس، بوشهر، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی، گروه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>az.rajabi@mehr.pgu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بخش‌‏بندی ارباب‌رجوع‌</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>روان‏شناختی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رفتاری‌</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت ارتباط با شهروند</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>‌معیار جمعیت‏شناختی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>موقعیتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Aghaie, A. (2009). Measuring and Predicting Customer Lifetime Value in Customer Loyalty Analysis: A Knowledge Management Perspective (A Case Study on an e-Retailer). International Journal of Industrial Engineering &amp; Production Research, 20(1): 21-30.##Andrade, V. &amp; Camacho, P. (2014). Citizen relationship management: What are the determinants that influence the implementation of citizen relationship management in governments? First International Conference on eDemocracy &amp; eGovernment (ICEDEG) (pp. 97-102). Quito: IEEE.##Bahari, M. (2011). Citizen Relationship Management Implementation in Local Government – Towards a Theoretical Research Framework. Journal of Information Systems Research and Innovation, 2(1): 51-61. ##Barnett, C. &amp; Mahony, N. (2011). Segmenting Publics. National Coordinating Center for Public Engagement. E.S.R.C Economic &amp; Social Research Council.##Chatfield, A. (2009). Public Service Reform through e-Government: a Case Study of ‘e-Tax’ in Japan. ElectronicJournal of e-Government, 7(2), 135 - 146.##Cotterill, S. (2008). How Local Partnerships Can Contribute to the Delivery of E-Government. In C. Reddick, Handbook of Research on Strategies for Local E-Government Adoption and Implementation (pp. 105-121). Information Science Reference.##Danaee, H., Aghaee, Z., Haghtalab, H. &amp; Poursalimi, M. (2013). Classifying and Designing Customer&#039;s Strategy Pyramid by Customer Life Time Value (CLV) (Case study: Shargh Cement Company). Journal of Basic and Applied Scientific Research, 3(7): 473-483.##Enayati, S. &amp; Majidi, M. (2008). Implememnting Citizen Relationship Management. Tehran: Center of City Management System. (in Persian)##Eslami, S. (2012). A Study on the Customer Relationship Management Model Adaptability with the Municipality Services and Duties Environment. International Research Journal of Finance and Economics, 82(January): 33-48.##Ghodsi Poor, S. H. (2012). Analytical Hierarchy Process. 10 ed. Tehran: Amirkabir University Publications. (in Persian)##Hakimi, H. (2014). Retail Banking Customer’s Market Segmentation Based on Psychological Factors: Case Study in Islamic Republic of Iran Bank Mellat. Proceedings of 9th International Business and Social Science Research Conference.##King, S. F. (2007). Citizens as Customers: Exploring the Future of CRM in UK Local Government. Government Information Quarterly, 24(1): 47-63.##King, S. F. &amp; Cotterill, S. (2007). Transformational Government? The Role of Information Technology in Delivering Citizen-Centric Local Public Services. Local Government Studies, 33(3): 333-354.##Mirghafuri, S.H, Shafieie Roodposhti, M. &amp; Malekshahi, F. (2014). Analysis of critical success factors (CSF) municipalities in the field of## New Services Development (NSD) with structural equation modeling approach (Case study: the area of beautification of Region 1 Tehran Municipality). Journal of Public Administration, 6(2): 375-400. (in Persian)##Momeni, M. (2014). Advanced Topics in Operations Research. 6 ed. Tehran: University of Tehran press (UTP). (in Persian)##Mostafavi, S.M. (2011). Comparison of customer satisfaction in private and state banks in the Iranian banking system by Mishra model. Journal of Public Administration, 3(7): 167-184.(in Persian)##Nargesian, A. &amp; Ayatollah Zadeh Shirazi, M. H. (2013). Citizen Relationship Management: Study of its Relationship with Public Participation, Public Accountability and Transparency in 3’s Region of City of Tehran. Journal of Public Administration, 5(2): 143-168. (in Persian)##Nigro, H.O &amp; González Císaro, S.E. (2014). Prediction of citizen satisfaction with local government based on perceptions of physical disorder. Journal of Place Management and Development, 7(2): 153 – 175.##Radfar, R., Nezafati, N. &amp; Yusefi Asli, S. (2014). Internet Bank Customer Classification Using Data Mining Algorithm. Journal of Information Technology Management, 6(1): 71-90. (in Persian)##Ramaraju, C. &amp; Savarimuthu, N. (2011). A Classification Model for Customer Segmentation. First International Conference, ACC 2011, Kochi, India,July 22-24, 2011. Proceedings, Part I, 190, pp. 661-670.##Schellong, A. (2007). Citizen Relationship Management. In A. V. Anttiroiko. Electronic Government: Concepts, Methodologies, Tools, and Applications. Hershey Information Science Reference.##Schellong, A. &amp; Langerberg, T. (2007). Managing Citizen Relationships in Disasters: Hurricane Wilma, 311 and Miami-Dade County. 40th Annual Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences (HICSS&#039;07) (p. 96). Waikoloa, HI: IEEE.##Shahin, A., Saleh Zadeh, R. &amp; Ghandhari, M. (2012). A Combination of Clustering Methods, AHP, and Kano to Describe Saman Bank Servises: The Case of Qom County. Managemement Researches in Iran, 16(1): 73-91.(in Persian)##Taleghani, Gh. Farhangi, A.A. &amp; Abedie Jafari, A. (2010). The model designing for factors affecting the trust of citizens towards urban management. Journal of Public Administration, 2(4): 89-106. (in Persian)##Weerakkody, V. &amp; Reddick, C. G. (2012). Public Sector Transformation Through E-government: Experiences from Europe and North America. Taylor &amp; Francis.##Yueh Shih, Y., Ren Liu, D., &amp; Hshiung Tzeng, G. (2002). Combining Clustering and MCDM Approach for Evaluating Customer Lifetime Value Ratings. The Second International Conference on Electronic Business. Taipei, Taiwan.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>شناسایی عوامل تأثیرگذار بر تصمیم ‏گیری اخلاقی مدیران دانشگاه پیام نور</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Identifying Factors Affecting Payame Noor University Managers&#039; Ethical Decisions</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>بسیاری از اندیشمندان معتقدند علم مدیریت اساساً مبتنی بر تصمیم‏گیری است و دست‎کم بخشی از آن به تصمیم‏گیری اخلاقی مربوط می‏شود. گام مهم برای منابع انسانی و به‌خصوص مدیران، درک عواملی است که به تصمیم‏گیری‏ها و رفتارهای اخلاقی/غیر‌اخلاقی منجر می‌شود. هدف این پژوهش که بخشی از رسالۀ دکتری محقق نیز محسوب می‎شود، تعیین عوامل مؤثر بر تصمیم‎گیری اخلاقی مدیران دانشگاه پیام نور است. روش پژوهش پیمایشی است و برای اخذ نظرهای خبرگان از فن دلفی استفاده می‎شود. پژوهشگران با مطالعۀ مبانی نظری و مرور پژوهش‏ها‏ی پیشین، 18 متغیر از 39 متغیر تأثیرگذار شناسایی‌شده را انتخاب کردند و به‎کمک جمعی از نخبگان طی نظرسنجی، متغیرهای منتخب نهایی شدند. نتایج نشان داد متغیرهای «باورهای مذهبی»، «ارزش‏های فردی»، «رهبری اخلاقی»، «قضاوت اخلاقی»، «محیط اخلاقی»، «نظام اخلاقی» و «فرهنگ سازمانی»، بیشترین تأثیر و متغیرهای «سن»، «سابقۀ خدمت»، «سابقۀ مدیریت» و «جنسیت» کمترین تأثیر را بر تصمیم‏‏‏گیری اخلاقی مدیران می‏‏‏‏گذارند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Identifying Factors Affecting Payame Noor University Managers&#039; Ethical DecisionsMany scholars in the field of management science believe that this science is fundamentally predicated on decision-making and, to say the least, part of it delves into the issue of ethical decisions. An important finding in the human resource arena, of particular value to the managers, is to understand the factors that lead onto ethical / unethical decisions or behaviors. This research, as an integral component of the researcher&#039;s PhD thesis, serves to identify the factors that influence the ethical decisions made by managers at Payame Noor University. The research method has been survey-based in this instance whereby the Delphi technique was used in order to obtain the views of the experts. The researcher, reviewing the previous studies and theoretical considerations, has chosen 18 variables out of the 39 identified variables as influential factors in this particular case. The experts thereafter finalized those variables that had been introduced in the related survey questionnaire. &quot;Religious Beliefs&quot;, &quot;Personal Values&quot;, &quot;Ethical Leadership&quot;, &quot;Ethical Judgment&quot;, &quot;Ethical Environment&quot;, &quot;Ethical System&quot; and &quot;Organizational Culture&quot;, were found to have the greatest impact on the managers&#039; ethical decisions, and &quot;Age&quot;, &quot;Work Experience&quot;, &quot;Management Experience&quot; and &quot;Gender&quot; having minimal impacts.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>525</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>546</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مژگان</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سیاهکل رودی</Family>
						<NameE>Mozhgan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Siahkalroudi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، مازندران، رامسر</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، مازندران،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>siahkalroudi_m@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>طاهره</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فیضی</Family>
						<NameE>Tahereh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Feizi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>tahereh_feizi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رسولی</Family>
						<NameE>Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rasoli</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>rasoli@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>جواد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حضوری</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Javad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hozoori</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hozoori@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تصمیم‏‏گیری اخلاقی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دانشگاه پیام نور</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>روش دلفی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Aranya, N. &amp; Ferris, K. R., (1984). A Re-examination of Accountants&#039; Organizational Professional Conflict. Accounting Review, 59(1): 1-15.##Barnett, J.H. &amp; Karson, M.J. (1989). Managers, Values and Executive Decisions: An Exploration of the Role of  Gender, Career Stage, Organizational Level, Function and the Importance of Ethics, Relationships and Results in Managerial Decision-Making. Journal of Business Ethics, 8(10): 747-771.##Beltramini, R., Peterson, R. &amp; Kozmtsky, G. (1984). Concerns of College Students Regarding Business Ethics. Journal of Business Ethics, 3(3): 195-200.##Blasi, A. (1980). Bridging Moral Cognition and Moral Action: A Critical Review of the Literature. Psychological Bulletin, 88(1): 1-45.##Bommer, M., Gratto, C., Gravander, J. &amp; Tuttle, M. (1987). Behavioral Model of Ethical Decision-Making. Journal of Business Ethics, 6(4): 265-280.##Browning, J. &amp; Zabriskie, N. B. (1983). How Ethical are Industrial Buyers?  Industrial Marketing Management, 12(4): 219-224.##Callan, V.J., (1992). Predicting Ethical Values and Training Needs in Ethics. Journal of Business Ethics, 11(10): 761-769.##Chang, Chiu-Cheng, (2000). An Ethical Decision-Making Framework for Appointed Actuaries.##Chonko, L. B. &amp; Hunt, S.D. (1985). Ethics and Marketing Management: An Empirical Examination. Journal of Business Research, 13(4): 339-359.##Comer, D.R. &amp; Vega, G. (2008). Using the PET Assessment Instrument to Help Students Identified Factors that Could Impede Moral Behavior. Journal of Business Ethics, 77(2): 129- 145.##Darley, J. &amp; Batson, C. (1973). From Jerusalem to Jericho: A Study of Situational and Dispositional Variables in Helping Behavior. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 27(1): 100-108.##Deconinck, J. B. (2005). The Influence of Ethical Control Systems and Moral Intensity on Managers&#039; Ethical Perceptions and Behavioral Intentions. Marketing Management Journal, 15(2): 123-131.##Delaney, J. &amp; Sockell, D. (1992). The Value of Company Ethics Programs: An Empirical Study. Journal of Business Ethics, 11: 719-727.##Donald,E. (2006). The Influence of Ethical Control Systems and Moral Intensity on Sales Managers&#039; Ethical Perceptions and Cultures. Marketing Management Journal, 15(2): 123-131.##Dubinskey, A. J. &amp; Loken, B. (1989). Analyzing Ethical Decision Making in Marketing. Journal of Business Research, 19(2): 83-107.##Ferrel, O.C., Gresham, L.G. &amp; Fraedrich, J. (1989). A Synthesis of Ethical Decision Models for Marketing. Journal of Macro-Marketing, 9: 55-63.##Ferrell, O. C., Fraedrich, J. &amp; Ferrell, L. (2002). Business Ethics: Ethical Decision Making and Cases. New York: Houghton Mifflin.##Ferrell, O.C. &amp; Gresham, L.G. (1985). A Contingency Framework for Understanding Ethical Decision Making in Marketing. Journal of marketing 49: 87-96.##Ferrell, O.C. &amp; Skinner, S.J., (1988). Ethical behavior and Bureaucratic Structure in Marketing Research Organizations. Journal of Marketing Research, 25 (February): 103-109.##Ford, R. C. &amp; Richardson, W. D. (1994). Ethical Decision-Making: A Review of the Empirical Literature. Journal of Business Ethics, 13(3): 206-224.##Franke, G.R., Crown, D.F. &amp; Spake, D.F., (1997). Gender Differences in Ethical Perceptions of Business Practices: Asocial Role Theory Perspective. Journal of Applied Psychology, 82(6): 920-935.##Frederickson, H., G. &amp; Ghere, R. K. (2005). Ethics in Public Management, New Delhi: Prentice- Hall.##Fritzsche, D. J. (1988). An Examination of Marketing Ethics: Role and Decision Maker, Consequence of Decision, Management Position and Sex of the Respondent. Journal of Micromarketing, 8(3): 29-39.##Gentle, L.M., (1997). Ethical Decision- making by Federal Managers. Dissertation Abstracts International Section A. Humanities and Social Science, 58, 2-A.##Greenfield, R. R. (2005). Business Ethics Survey: In Michigan Community College, Published Doctoral Students.##Haines, R. &amp; Leonard, L. N.K. (2012). Situational Influences on Ethical Decision- making in an IT Context. Elsevier, Information and Management, 44: 313-320##Harris,J.,(1990). Ethical Values of Individuals at Different Levels in the Organizational Hierarchy of a Singel Firm. Journal of Business Ethics, 9: 741-750.##Hegarty, W. &amp; H. Sims,Jr., (1978). Some Determinants of Unethical Decision Behavior: An Experiment. Journal of applied Psychology, 63(4): 451-457.##Hegarty, W. &amp; H. Sims, Jr. (1979). Organizational Philosophy, Policies and Objectives Related to Unethical Decision Behavior: A Laboratory Experiment.  Journal of Applied Psychology, 64(3): 331-338.##Hull, A. K. (1999). Influence and Change: A Study of the Ethical Decision Making of Trainee Accountants. Thesis submitted to the University of Nottingham for the degree of Doctor of Philosophy.##Hunt, S. &amp; Vitell, S. (1986). A General Theory of Marketing Ethics. Journal of Macromarketing, 6: 5-16.##Jones, T. M., (1991). Ethical decision making by Individuals in Organizations. Academy of Management Review,16(2): 366-395.##Jones, T.M., and Hiltebeitel, L.V., (1995). The Effects of Organizational Forces on Individual Morality, Judgment, Moral Approbation, and Behavior. Business Ethics Quarterly, 8(3): 431-445.##Kelley, E.K., Ferrel, O.C. &amp; Skinner, S.J. (1990). Ethical Behavior among Marketing Researchers: An Assessment of Selected Demographic Characteristics. Journal of Business Ethics, 9(8): 681-688.##Kohlberg, L. (1969). Stage and Sequence: The Cognitive-Developmental Approach to Socialization. In Handbook of socialization Theory and research, ed, D.A. Goslin. Chicago: Rand McNally.##Kohlberg, L. &amp; Candee, D. (1984). The Relationship of Moral Judgment to Moral Action. In Morality, Moral Behavior and Moral Development, ed. W. M. Kurtins and J. L. Gewirtz, New York: Wiley.##Kreitner, R. &amp; Kinicki, A. (2004). Organizational Behavior (6th ed.). New York: The McGraw-Hill Companies.##Laczniak, G. R. &amp; Inderrieden, E. J. (1987). The Influence of Stated Organizational Concern upon Ethical Decision Making. Journal of Business Ethics, 6: 297-307.##Locke, E.A. &amp; Latham, G.P. (1990). A Theory of Goal Setting and Task Performance. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice Hall.##Mashayekhi, A.N., Farhangi, A.A., Alidousti, S. &amp; Momeni, M. (2005). Investigation of Factors Affecting the Use of information Technology in Iran’s Public Organizations: Application of Delphi Method. Human Sciences MODARES, 42(3): 191 – 232. (in Persian)##Mazaheri-Rad, H. (2011). An overview of the Concepts of Ethical Behavior in Organizations. Scientific Management Articles Portal. Available in: http://www.system.parsiblog.com. (in Persian)##Menzel, D. C. (2007). Ethics Management for Public Administrators: Building Organizations of Integrity. Translated by: Ahmadi, A.A., Siahkalroudi, M. and Nikzad. َA., Tehran: Mahkameh.##Mobley, S. E. (2002). The Study of Lawrence Kohlberg&#039;s Stages of Moral Development Theory and ethics: Considerations in Public Administrations. Dissertation Abstracts International, Section A: Humanities and Social Sciences, 63, 5-A.##Mowday,R.,Steers,R. &amp; Porter, L. (1979). The measurement of organizational commitment. Journal of Vocational Behavior, 14(2): 224-247.##Painter- Morland, M. (2008). Business Ethics and Practice: ethics as the everyday business. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.##Patterson, D. (2001). A model of Ethical/Unethical Decision Making by Auditors in the Big-Six Accounting Firm. Journal of Business Ethics, 83-120.##Peek, K.L. (1999). The Good, the Bad, and the &quot;Misunderstood&quot;: A Study of the Cognitive Moral Development Theory and the ethics in the Public Sector. Dissertation Abstracts International Section A: Humanities and Social Sciences, vol. 60, 5-A: 1787.##Piaget, J.(1932). The Moral Judgment of the Child. New York: Free Press.##Pourezzat, A.A. &amp; Rahimian, A. (2012). Characteristics of Public Policy for the Management of Diverse and Complex Cities- The Case Studied: Tehran City. Tehran University. Journal of Public Administration, 10: 25-44. (in Persian)##Radcliffe, D.M. (2011). Training Ethical Decision Makers. Available in: http://cornellhrreview.org.##Rest, J.R. (1986). Moral development: Advances in research and theory. Westport, CT: Praeger.##Rest, J.R., (1984). The Major Components of Morality. In W. Kurtniss &amp; J. Gerwitz (Eds.), Morality, Moral Behavior, and Moral Development. New York: Wiley.##Robertson, D. C., (1993). Empiricism in Business Ethics: Suggested Research Directions. Journal of Business Ethics, 12: 585-599.##Rotter, J. B. (1966). GGeneralized Expectancies for Internal versus External Control of Reinforcement. Psychological Monographs: General and Applied, 80(1): 1-28.##Ruegger, D. &amp; King, E. W. (1992). A Study of the Effect of Age and Gender upon Student Business Ethics. Journal of Business Ethics, 11: 179-186.##Saeedi-Kia, M. (2009). The Basis and Foundations of Entrepreneurship, Fourteenth Edition, Tehran: Kia Publishing. (in Persian)##Schwartz, S.H., (1977). Normative Influences on Altruism. In Advances in Experimental Social Psychology, Berkowitz. New York: Academic Press.##Sepasi, S. (2011). Designing an Ethical Decision-Making Model for Public Accountants. A Doctoral Dissertation, University of Tehran. (in Persian)##Shelileh, M., (2005). Professions and Professionalism. Hesabras Journal, 24 - 25: 63-67. (in Persian)##Stevens, G. E. (1984). Business Ethics and Social Responsibility: The Response of Present and Future Managers. Akron Business and Economic Review, Fall, 6-11.##Sweeney, J.T. (2005). The Moral Expertise of Auditors: An Exploratory Analysis. Research on Accounting Ethics, 1:. 213-234.##Swisher, L.L., (2000). Measuring Moral Development in Public Administration. Dissertation Abstracts International Section A: Humanities and Social Sciences, vol. 60, 8-A.##Thoma, S.J., (1985). On Improving the Relationship between Moral Reasoning and External Criteria: The Utilizer/Nonutilizer Dimention. Ph.D. dissertation, University of Minnesota.##Trevino, L. (1986). Ethical Decision –Making in Organization: A Person Situation Interactions Model. Academy of Management Review, 11: 601-617.##Trevino, L.K. &amp; Youngblood, S., (1990). Bad Apples in Bad Barrels: A Causal Analysis of Ethical Decision Making Behavior. Journal of Applied Psychology, 75(4): 378-85.##Velasquez, M., Moberg, D., Meyer, M.J., Shanks, T., McLean, M.R., DeCosse,D.,… &amp; Hanson, K. O. (2009). A Framework for Thinking Ethically, Markkua Center for Applied Ethics at Santa Clara University.##Victor, B. &amp; Cullen, J.B. (1987). A Theory and Measure of Ethical Climate in Organizations. In Research in Corporate Social Performance and Policy: An Empirical Studies of Business Ethics and Values, ed. W.C. Frederick, pp.51-71. Grwwnwich, CT: JAI Press.## Victor, B. &amp; Cullen, J.B. (1988). The Organizational Bases of Ethical Work Climates.  Administrative Science Quarterly, 33(Mar): 101-125.##White, R.D. (1999). Are Women More Ethical?  Recent Findings on the Effects Gender upon Moral Development. Journal of Public Administration Research and Theory, 9(3): 459-72.##Wittmer, D. P. (2005). Developing a Behavioral Model for Ethical Decision Making in Organizations: Conceptual and Empirical Research. In Frederickson, H., George, Ghere, Richard K. (Ed.), Ethics in Public Management, 149-64.##Wittmer, D. P. (1992). Ethical Sensitivity and Manegerial Decision Making: An Experiment.  Journal of Public Administration Theory and Research, 2: 443-62.##Wittmer, D. P. (2000). Ethical Sensitivity in Management Decisions. Developing and Testing a Perceptual Measure among Management and Professional Students Groups.##Wittmer, D.P. &amp; Coursey, D. (1996). Ethical Work Climates: Comparing Top Managers in Public and Private Organizations. Journal of Public Administration Research and Theory, 6(4): 559-572.##Yeung, F.P.F. &amp; Keup, J. R. (2009). Ethical decision making in College: Choosing Between Right, Wrong, and Space in Between. University of California-Los Angeles.##Zey-Ferell M. &amp; Ferrel, O.C., (1982). Role- Set Configuration and Opportunity as predictors of Unethical Behavior in Organizations. Human Relations, 35: 587- 604.##Zey-Ferell M., Weaver, K.M. &amp; Ferrel, O.C., (1979). Predicting Unethical Behavior among Marketing Practitioners. Human Relations, 32: 557-569.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تأثیرات تنوع تیمی بر تعهد و هویت تیمی و اهمیت تعدیل‏ کنندۀ اندازۀ تیم</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigating effects of team diversity on team commitment and team identity and mediating role of team size</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>امروزه‌ تیم‏ها منبع اصلی یادگیری و کار در سازمان‏ها شده‏اند و این موضوع اهمیت طراحی ساختارهای مبتنی بر تیم را دوچندان کرده است. مدیریت تنوع تیم‏ها موضوعی است که مدیران هنگام تیم‏سازی باید به آن توجه کنند. هنوز در ایران‌ اثر تنوع تیمی بر پیامد‏های تیم و متغیرهای تعدیل‏کنندۀ آن، به‌طور کامل مشخص نشده‏ است. بنابراین، با توجه به اهمیت موضوع، در این پژوهش به بررسی تأثیرات تنوع تیمی (شامل تنوع سنی، جنسیتی، تحصیلاتی، قومیتی و اخلاق کاری اسلامی) بر تعهد و هویت تیمی و نقش تعدیل‏کنندگی اندازۀ تیم در این زمینه پرداخته می‏شود. بدین‌منظور اعضای تیم‏های پروژه‏ای سازمان‏های تولیدی و مشاوره‏ای شهر تهران جامعۀ آماری در نظر گرفته شدند و 202 پرسشنامۀ پژوهشی بین افراد نمونه توزیع شد که این تعداد پس از جمع‏آوری، با بهره‎مندی از روش تجمیع برای تبدیل داده‏های سطح فردی به سطح گروهی به 54 تیم کاهش یافتند. نتایج به‌دست‌آمده نشان می‏دهد اخلاق کاری اسلامی اثر مثبت و معناداری بر انسجام تیمی دارد. همچنین انسجام تیمی به‌منزلۀ متغیر میانجی، اثر مثبت و معناداری بر هویت تیمی می‎گذارد. از سوی دیگر‌ اندازۀ تیم، روابط میان تنوع با تضاد و انسجام تیمی را تعدیل نمی‌کند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Today, teams are a key resource for learning and work in organizations and this has increased the importance of designing team-based structures. Diversity management teams is something that managers should consider when Team building. The effect of team diversity on team outcomes and its moderating variable,hasn’t completely identified yet in Iran. Therefore, given the importance of, this study examined the effects of team diversity (including diversity in age, gender, education, ethnicity and Islamic work ethic) on team commitment and team identity and moderating role of team size in this relationship are paid. for this purpose, members of the project teams productive and advisory organizations Tehran city are selected as the statistical community and then The 202 number of study questionnaires were distributed between samples that after gathering the questionnaires، they were decreased to 54 teams by using of integration method to convert individual level data to group level data. The results of this study showed that Islamic work ethic has a positive and significant effect on team Cohesiveness. also team cohesiveness has a positive and significant effect On team identity. On the other hand, team size doesn’t moderate the relation among team diversity, conflict and team cohesiveness.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>547</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>572</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>آرین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قلی پور</Family>
						<NameE>Arian</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Gholipoor</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد مدیریت منابع انسانی‏، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد مدیریت منابع انسانی‏، دانشکدۀ مدیریت،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>agholipor@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عاطفه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سیف</Family>
						<NameE>Atefe</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Seif</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس‎ارشد مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس‎ارشد مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشکدۀ</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>seif66@live.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مظاهر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>یوسفی امیری</Family>
						<NameE>Mazaher</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Yousefi Amiri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت سازمان‏های دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت سازمان‏های دولتی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.yusefi@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اخلاق کاری اسلامی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تضاد و انسجام تیم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تعهد و هویت تیم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تنوع تیمی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Ansari, M., Rahmani Youshanlouei, H., Oskouyi, V. &amp; Hoseini, A (2012). Identifying the factors and developing the human resource empowerment conceptual model in ICT Ministry (Case Study). Public Administration, 3 (7): 23-40. (in Persian)##Capehart, A. M. (2005). A configurational framework for diversity- socialization &amp; culture. Personnel Review, 34 (4): 488-503.##Chi, N., Huang, Y. &amp; Lin, S. (2009). A Double-Edged Sword: Exploring the Curvilinear Relationship between Organizational Tenure Diversity and Team Innovation: The Moderating Role of Team-Oriented HR Practices. Group &amp; Organization Management, 34 (6): 698- 726.##Chowdhury, S. (2005). Demographic diversity for building an effective entrepreneurial team: is it important? Journal of Business Venturing, 20(6): 727–746.##Cross, G.A. (2000). Collective form: an exploration of large-group writing. The Journal of Business Communication, 37 (1): 77-100.##Dahlin, K. B., Weingart, L.R. &amp; Hinds, P.J. (2005). Team diversity and information use. The Academy of Management Journal, 48 (6): 23-34.##Fooa, M. D., Wong, P. &amp; Ong, A. (2005). Do others think you have a viable business idea? Team diversity and judges’ evaluation of ideas in a business plan competition. Journal of Business Venturing, 20(3): 385-402.##Gammage, K. L., Carron, A.V. &amp; Estabrooks, P.A. (2001). Team Cohesion and Individual Productivity: The Influence of the Norm for Productivity &amp; the Identifiability of Individual Effort. Small Group Research, 32 (3): 3-18.##Gefen, D. &amp; Straub, D. (2005). A practical guide to factorial validity using PLS-Graph: Tutorial and annotated example. Communications of the Association for Information systems, 16(1): 91-109.##Geisser, S. (1975). The predictive sample reuse method with applications. Journal of the American Statistical Association, 70 (350): 320-328.##Gholipour, A. (2009). Sociology of organizations (Sociological approach to organization and management).Tehran: SAMT. (in Persian)##Gholipour, A. (2012). Human resource management (Concepts, theories and applications).Tehran: SAMT. (in Persian)##Green, A. L. &amp; Hill, A. Y. (2005). The use of multiple intelligences to enhance team productivity. Management Decision, 43 (3): 349-359.##Gupta, V. K., Huang, R. &amp; Niranjan, S. (2010). A Longitudinal Examination of the Relationship between Team Leadership and Performance. Journal of Leadership &amp; Organizational Studies, 17 (4): 335–350.##Haas, H. (2010). How can we explain mixed effects of diversity on team performance? A review with emphasis on context. Equality, Diversity and Inclusion: An International Journal, 29 (5): 458-49 0.##Hamilton, B. H., Nickerson, J. &amp; Owan, H. (2003). Diversity and productivity in teams. Working Paper, John M. Olin School of Business, Washington University in St. Louis.##Hanafizadeh, P. &amp; Rahmani, A. (2011). Research methodology of multi-dimensional structures. Tehran: Termeh. (in Persian)##Horwitz, S. K. (2005). The compositional impact of team diversity on performance: theoretical considerations. Human Resource Development Review, 4 (2): 219-245.##Horwitz, S.K. &amp; Horwitz, I.B. (2007). The effects of team diversity on team outcomes: a meta-analytic review of team demography. Journal of Management, 33 (6): 987-1015.##Jackson, S. E., &amp; Joshi, A. (2004). Diversity in social context: a multi-attribute, multilevel analysis of team diversity and sales performance. Journal of Organizational Behavior, 25 (6): 675-702.##Jackson, S. E., Joshi, A. &amp; Erhardt, N. L. (2003). Recent Research on Team and Organizational Diversity: SWOT Analysis and Implications. Journal of Management, 29 (6): 801–830.##Jehn, K. A. (1995). A multimethod examination of the benefits and detriments of intergroup conflict. Administrative Science Quarterly, 40 (2): 256-83.##Jehn, K.A. (1999). Why differences make a difference: a field study of diversity, conflict, and performance in workgroups. Administrative Science Quality, 44 (4): 741-63.##Kayes, A. B., Kayes, D. C. &amp; Kolb, D. A. (2005). Experiential learning in teams. Simulation and Gaming, 36, 330-354.##Kichuk, S. &amp; Weisner, W. H. (1998). Work teams: selecting members for optimal performance. Canadian psychology, 39 (1-2): 23-32.##Konrad, A. M. (2003). Special issue introduction: Defining the domain of workplace diversity scholarship. Group &amp; Organization Management, 28 (1): 4-17.##Liang, T.P. &amp; Liu, Ch. (2007). Effect of team diversity on software project performance. Industrial Management &amp; Data Systems, 107 (5): 636-653.##Maddux, R. (2004). Team building. Translator: Eskandarim M.R. Tehran: Institute of Isiran. (in Persian)##Magoshi, E., &amp; Chang, E. (2009). Diversity management and the effects on employees’ organizational commitment: Evidence from Japan and Korea. Journal of World Business, 44(1): 31–40.##Malaki, A. H., Gholipour, A. &amp; Abedjafari, H. (2010). investigating  the impacts of religious beliefs on the tendency to set up a new business. Entrepreneurship Development, 1 (3): 11-34. (in Persian)##Momeni, M. &amp; Fa&#039;al Ghayyoumi, A. (2008). Statistical Analyses using SPSS. Tehran: Ketabe Now. (in Persian)##Nekouyi Moghaddam, M. &amp; Pirmoradi Bezanjani, N. (2007). Investigating the relationship between personality traits and organizational conflicts (interpersonal) in  public organizations. Public administration, 1(1): 105-122. (in Persian)##Ng, E. S.W. &amp; Wyrick, C. R. (2011). Motivational bases for managing diversity: A model of leadership commitment. Human Resource Management Review, 21(4): 368–376.##Olson, B. J., Bao, Y. &amp; Parayitam, S. (2007). Strategic decision making within Chinese firms: The effects of cognitive diversity and trust on decision outcomes. Journal of World Business, 42(1): 35-46.##Peters, L. &amp; Karren, R. J. (2009). An Examination of the Roles of Trust and Functional Diversity on Virtual Team Performance Ratings, Group &amp; Organization Management, 34 (4): 479-504.##Pitts, D. &amp; Jarry, E. M. (2007). Ethnic diversity and organizational performance: assessing diversity effects at the managerial and street levels. International Public Management Journal, 10 (2):1-17.##Raymond, W. (2005). Building a successful team. The project network Newsletter, Available in: http://www.mympa.org.##Rietzschel,E. F. (2011). Collective regulatory focus predicts specific aspects of team innovation. Group Processes &amp; Intergroup Relations, 14 (3): 337–345.##Ringle, C. M., Wende, S. &amp; Will, A. (2005). Smart PLS – Version 2.0, University at Hamburg, Hamburg. Available at: (Http://www.smartpls.de).##Rink, F. &amp; Ellemers, N. (2007). The Role of Expectancies in Accepting Task-Related Diversity: Do Disappointment and Lack of Commitment Stem from Actual Differences or Violated Expectations. Personality and Social Psychology Bull, 33 (6): 842-854.##Rink, F. &amp; Ellemers, N. (2010). Benefiting from deep- level diversity: How congruence between knowledge and decision rules improves team decision making and team perceptions. Group Processes &amp; Intergroup Relations, 13 (3): 345-359.##Riordan, C. M., &amp; Shore, L. M. (1997). Demographic diversity and employee attitudes: An empirical examination of relational demography within work units. Journal of applied psychology, 82(3): 342-358.##Rovio, E., Eskola, J. A., Kozub, S., Duda, J.L. &amp; Lintunen, T. (2009). Can High Group Cohesion as harmful: A Case Study of a Junior Ice-Hockey Team. Small Group Research, 40 (4): 421-435.##Sarmad, Z., Bazargan, A. &amp; Hejazi, E. (2001). Research methodology in behavioral sciences. 6th ed, Tehran: Agah. (in Persian)##Shaw, J. B. (2004). A Fair Go for All: The Impact of Intragroup Diversity and Diversity-Management Skills on Student Experiences and Outcomes in Team-Based Class Projects. Journal of Management Education, 28 (2): 139- 169.##Shore, L. M., Chung-Herrera, B. G., Dean, M. A., Ehrhart, K. H., Jung, D. I., Randel, A. E. &amp; Singh, G. (2009). Diversity in organizations: Where are we now and where are we going? Human Resource Management Review, 19(2): 117-133.##Solansky, S.T. (2011). Team identification a determining factor of performance. Journal of Managerial Psychology, 26 (3): 247-258.##Stone-Romero, E. F. &amp; Anderson, L. E. (1994). Relative power of moderated multiple regression and the comparison of subgroup correlation coefficients for detecting moderating effects. Journal of applied psychology, 79 (3): 354-359.##Swartz, A.L. &amp; Triscari, J. S. (2011). A Model of Transformative Collaboration. Adult Education Quarterly, 61 (4): 324–340.##Tekleab, A. G., Quigley, N. R. &amp; Tesluk, P. E. (2009). A Longitudinal Study of Team Conflict, Conflict Management, Cohesion, and Team Effectiveness. Group &amp; Organization Management, 34 (2): 170-205.##Tran, V., Garcia-Prieto, P. &amp; Schneider, S. (2011). The role of social identity, appraisal, and emotion in determining responses to diversity management. Human Relations, 64 (2): 161- 176.##Van der Vegt, G.S., &amp; Bunderson, J.S. (2005). Learning and performance in multidisciplinary teams: the importance of collective team identification. Academy of Management Journal, 48 (3): 532-47.##Van Dick, R., Stelimacher, J., Wagner, U., Lemmer, G. &amp; Tissington, P.A. (2009). Group membership salience and task performance. Journal of Managerial Psychology, 24 )7(: 609-626.##Vos, M., &amp; Zee, K. (2011). Prosocial behavior in diverse workgroups: How relational identity orientation shapes cooperation and helping. Group Processes Intergroup Relations, 14 (3): 363- 379.##Whiteoak, J., Crawford, N., &amp; Mapstone, R. (2006). Impact of Gender and Generational Differences in Work Values and Attitudes in an Arab Culture. Thunderbird International Business Review, 48 (1): 77–91.##Yousef, D. A. (2001). Islamic work ethic: A moderator between organizational commitment and job satisfaction in a cross-cultural context. Personnel Review, 30 (2): 152-169.##Zellmer-Bruhn, M., Maloney, M., Bhappu R. S., &amp; Anita, D. (2008). When and how do differences matter? An exploration of perceived similarity in teams. Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes, 107(1): 41-59.##Zhou, W. &amp; Shi, X. (2011). Culture in groups and teams: a review of three decades of research. International Journal of Cross Cultural Management, 11 (1): 5–3.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>پدیدارشناسی تجربۀ اخراج‏ شدن از کار</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Phenomenology of the Experience of Getting Fired</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>با توجه به نقش محوری کار در زندگی افراد، اخراج‌شدن می‏تواند تبعات زیادی برای فرد و اطرافیان وی به دنبال داشته باشد؛ اما در حال حاضر در‌خصوص این تجربه فهم ناچیزی وجود دارد. بنابراین در این پژوهش از روش پدیدارشناسی گیورگی و گیورگی استفاده شد تا معنای این پدیده توصیف شود. بدین‌منظور به‎کمک روش نمونه‏گیری هدفمند، با 8 تن از افرادی که به‏تازگی از کار خود اخراج شده بودند، مصاحبۀ پدیدارشناسی عمیق شد. نتایج تحلیل داده‏ها نشان می‏دهد جوهرۀ تجربۀ اخراج‌شدن از سه تم اصلی و یازده تم فرعی تشکیل شده است که عبارت‏اند از: 1. اخراج به‏مثابۀ محرومیت ناگهانی با تم‏های فرعی اخراج به‏مثابۀ فروپاشی برنامه‏ها، از دست‎دادن امنیت مالی و ‌محیط اجتماعی کار؛ 2. اخراج به‏مثابۀ محرک عواطف با تم‏های فرعی نفرت، شوک، بی‏انصافی و بی‏عدالتی، سردرگمی، غم و اندوه و رهایی و 3. تأثیر اخراج بر خودانگاره با تم‏های فرعی تصور بی‏اهمیتی و تصور بی‏کفایتی. فهم به‏دست‏آمده از تجربۀ اخراج‌شدن، می‏تواند مدیریت این پدیده را هم برای سازمان‏ها و هم برای افراد تسهیل کند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Considering the pivotal role that job plays in people’s lives, it can be argued that getting fired may have many consequences for the individual and his or her family and friends. However, there is little understanding of this experience. Using Giorgi and Giorgi’s phenomenological method, this study aims to describe the meaning of this experience. The sample includes 8 people who have recently been discharged from work. Deep phenomenological interviews were conducted on subjects. The result of analyses shows that this experience consists of three main themes and eleven subthemes which are: 1) Getting fired as a sudden loss; the subthemes of which being: getting fired as perished plans, loosing financial security, and losing social environment of work. 2) Getting fired as instigated emotions; the subthemes of which being: hatred, shock, unfairness, confusion, sorrow, and emancipation and 3) the impact of getting fired on self-concept; the subthemes of which being: the notion of being worthless, and the notion of being incompetent. The understanding of this experience can facilitate the management of this phenomenon for both organizations and individuals dealing with it.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>573</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>594</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>هادی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عارف</Family>
						<NameE>Hadi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Aref</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشکدۀ</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hadiaref@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بودلایی</Family>
						<NameE>Hasan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Boudlaei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hasanboudlaie@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>وحید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بیگی</Family>
						<NameE>Vahid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Beygi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>vahdbeygi@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اخراج به‏ مثابۀ محرک عواطف</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اخراج به‏م ثابۀ محرومیت ناگهانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پدیدارشناسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تأثیر اخراج بر خودانگاره</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تجربۀ اخراج‌شدن از کار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Ahmadi, A. K., Rasuli, R., Ghatari, A. R. &amp; Pooya, P. (2012). Presenting a Crisis Management Model with Emphasis on Human Resources Management System for Hospitals of Tehran.Journal of public administration. 4(10): 1-24. (in Persian)##Armstrong, M. (2010).Armstrong&#039;s Essential Human Resource Management Practice. London: Kogan Page Limited.##Bell, M.P., Berry, D.P., Marquardt, D.J. &amp; Green, T.G. (2013). Introducing discriminatory job loss: antecedents, consequences, and complexities.Journal of Managerial Psychology, 28 (6): 584-605.##Creswell, J. (2008). Research design: Qualitative, quantitative, and mixed methods approaches, 2nd edn. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage.##Danaeefard, H., Khaefollahi. A. &amp; Khodashenas, L. (2012). Understanding essence of retirement exprince in public sector: a phenomenological study. Strategic management thinking, 12(2): 153-176. (in Persian)##Defrank, R. S. &amp; Ivancevich, J. M. (1986). Job loss: an individual-level review and model. Journal of Vocational behavior, 18 (1): 1-20.##Eby, L. T. &amp; Buch, K. (1998). The Impact of Adopting an Ethical Approach to Employee Dismissal during Corporate Restructuring. Journal of Business Ethics, 17(12): 1253–1264.##Englander, M. (2012). The Interview: Data Collection in Descriptive Phenomenological Human Scientific Research. Journal of Phenomenological Psychology, 43(1): 13-35.##Ghodratipoor, M. &amp; Hassanmoradee, N. (2014). Investigating the Effectiveness of Organizational Factors and Management of Deviant Workplace Behavior (A Survey on the Staff of Civil Servant Pension Fund).Journal of public administration, 6(2): 333-354. (in Persian)##Gibson, S. K. &amp; Hanes, L. A. (2003). The contribution of Phenomenology to HRD research.Human resource development review, 2 (2): 181-205.##Gill, M. J. (2014).The possibilities of phenomenology for organizational research.Organizational research methods, 17(2): 1-20.##Giorgi, A. &amp; Giorgi, B. (2008). Phenomenological psychology, in C. Willig and W. Stainton Rogers (eds) The Sage Handbook of Qualitative Research in Psychology. London: Sage.##Gowan, M. A. (2012). Employability, well-being and job satisfaction following a job loss.Journal of Managerial Psychology, 27 (8): 780-798.##Gowan, M. A. (2014). Moving from job loss to career management: The past, present, and future of involuntary job loss research.Human Resource Management Review, 24 (3): 258–270.##Gray, D. E. (2007). Facilitating management learning: developing critical reflection through reflective tools.management learning, 38 (5): 495-517.##Holt, R. &amp; Sandberg, J. (2011).Pheomenology and Organization Theory. In H. Tsoukas, &amp; R. Chia, Philosophy and Organization Theory (pp. 215-249). United Kingdom: Emerald Group Publishing Limited.##Homes, T. H. &amp; Rahe, R. H. (1967). The social readjustment rating scale. Journal of psychosomatic Research, 11 (2): 213-218.##Kalil, A. (2009). Joblessness, famili relations, and children&#039;s development.Family Matters, 83: 15-22.##Karren, R. &amp; Sherman, K. (2012). Layoffs and unemployment discrimination: a new stigma. Journal of Managerial Psychology, 27 (8): 848-863.##Langdrige, D. (2007). phenomenological psychology: Theory, research and method. Edinburgh Gate: Pearson Education.##Latack, J. C., Kinicki, A. &amp; Prussia, G. E. (1995).An integrate process model of coping with job loss.Academy of management review, 20 (2): 311-342.##Leana, C. R. &amp; Feldman, D. C. (1988). Individual responses to job loss: Perceptions, reactions, and coping behaviors. Journal of management, 14 (3): 375-389.##Mahapatro, B. (2010). Human Resource Management. New Delhi: New Age International (P) Ltd.##McKee-Ryan, F.M. &amp; Kinicki, A.J. (2002). Coping with job loss: a life-facet perspective.International review of industrial and organizational psychology, 17: 1-29.##McKee-Ryan, F.M., Song, Z., Wanberg, C.R. &amp; Kinicki, A.J. (2005). Psychological and physical well-being during unemployment: A meta-analytic study. Journal of Applied Psychology, 90 (1): 53-76.##Paul, K. &amp; Moser, K. (2009). Unemployment impairs mental health: meta-analyses. Journal of Vocational Behavior, 74(3): 264–282.##Price, R., Choi, J. &amp;Vinokur, A. (2002). Links in the chain of adversary following job loss: how financial strain and loss of personal control lead to depression, impaired functioning and poor health. Journal of Occupational Health Psychology, 7 (4): 302-312.##Raeisifar, K. &amp; Melati, A. (2015). The role of positive OB in preventing job pathologies: investigating the relationship between Psychological Capital and Job Burnout. Journal of public administration. 6(4): 705-723. (in Persian)##Saunders, M., Lewis, P., and Thornhill, A (2009).Research methods for business students. Milan: Pearson Education.##Scheneer, J. A. (1993). Involuntary turnover and its psychological consequences: a theoretical model. Human resource management review, 3 (1): 29-47.##Seidman, I. (2006). Interviewing as qualitative research: A guide for researchers in education and social sciences. (3rd ed.). New York: Teachers College.##Shahba, S., Alvani, M. &amp; Afsharkazemi, M. A. (2015). Effect of Cognitive Emotion Regulation strategy On The Subjective Well-being and job performance (Study of Customs Administration of Islamic Republic of Iran). Journalof public administration. 6(4): 725-745. (in Persian)##Shin, K., Kim, M., &amp; Kim, Y. (2003). Study on the lived experience of aging. Nurse Health Science, 5 (4): 25-49.##Van Maanen, J. (1979). The self, the situation, and the rules of interpersonal relations. In W. Bennis, J. Van Maanen, E. H. Schein, &amp; F. I. Steele, Essays in interpersonal dynamics (pp. 43-101). Homewood: Dorsey Press.##Wanberg, C. R. (2012). The individual Experience of Unemployment. Annual Review of Psychology, 63: 369-396.##Willig, C. (2008). Introducing Qualitative Method in Psychology, 2nd Edition. New York: Open University Press.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>چالش های بهره‌وری در دولت</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Challenges of Productivity In Government</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>بر‌اساس سند چشم‌انداز کشور، مقرر است که اقتصاد جمهوری اسلامی ایران که در حال حاضر (با استناد به آمارهای رسمی کشور) نهاده‌محور است، به اقتصاد دانش‌محور در سال 1404 تبدیل شود. از‌جمله راهکارهای اصلی رسیدن به این هدف، ارتقای بهره‏وری است. این در حالی است که بهره‏وری دولت طی سال‏های گذشته وضعیت مناسبی نداشته است. با توجه به این مهم و چالش موجود در موضوع بهره‏وری دولت، نویسنده تلاش می‌کند که به بررسی این موضوع بپردازد و بهره‏وری را در چارچوب مفهومی نوین دولت تبیین‎کرده و وضعیت آن در دولت ایران را تحلیل کند. روش به‌کار گرفته‌شده ‌در این پژوهش اسنادی است و نویسنده تلاش می‌کند با تحلیل‏های ثانویه در یافته‏های موجود، ضمن ترسیم و تحلیل وضعیت موجود بهره‌وری دولت در ایران، راه‎حل‏های بهبود آن را ارائه کند. این راه‎حل‏ها به‎طور عمده ساختاری و معطوف به اصلاح ساختار دولت و شیوۀ ادارۀ سازمان‏های دولتی است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>With respect to the vision statement, economy of Iran has to transform to a knowledge-based economy in 1404, which is currently (according to the official statistics) an input-oriented one. Improving productivity is among primary solutions to reach the goal. Nevertheless, productivity of the government has not been in a good condition during past few years.Due to this matter and challenges in productivity of government, the author tries to investigate it and explain productivity in a new conceptual framework of government and analysing its situation in Iranian state, in addition. The technique which has been used in this study is documentary and the author by the help of secondary analysis of the findings, tries to draw and analyse the current productivity situation in Iranian government, as well as suggesting solutions. These solutions are typically structural with consentration on structural revision of government and methods in which public organizations are conducted.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>595</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>618</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رحمت‎الله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قلی پور</Family>
						<NameE>Rahmatollah</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Gholipour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>rgholipor@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بهره ‏وری‌</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>راه حل‏های بهبود بهره ‏وری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت دولتی نوین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abtahi, H. &amp; Kazemi, B. (2003). Productivity. Tehran: Institution of business researches and studies. (in Persian)##Alvani, S.M, Memarzade Tehran, Gh, Alborzi, M. &amp; Kazemi, H. (2013). Proposing of Spiritual Leadership Model in Iranian Bureaucracy. Quarterly Journal of Public Administration, 5(1): 21- 40. (in Persian)##Amid, H. (2010). Amid Persian Dictionary. F. Ghorbanzade (Ed), Dehkhoda Dictionary, Tehran. (in Persian)##Belgheisi, P. (1994). Organization Productivity and Analyzing the Methods. Quarterly Journal of Public Administrational Change, 8(9): 62-78. (in Persian)##Bouckart, G. B. (1992). Public Productivity in Retrospective. Public Productivity Handbook. edited by: Holzer, united state.##Camus, D. (2007). The ONS Productivity Handbook, Chapter 9: Public Service Productivity. Published with the permission of the Controller of Her Majesty’s Stationery Office (HMSO).##Coe, D.T. &amp; Helpman, E. (1995). International R&amp;D spillovers. European Economic Review, 39(5): 859-887.##Coe, D.T. &amp; Helpman, E. (1997). North – South International R &amp; D Spillovers. The Economic Journal, 107(440): 134- 149.##Economic Report and Monitoring of Operation in The Law of the 2nd Economic, Social and Cultural DevelopmentPlan of the Islamic Republic of Iran (Ultra- division contexts). (2001). (in Persian)##Eslami, K. &amp; Shahlou, V. (2009). The Productivity Square and Productivity Improvement Management. Journal of Quality Control, 36: 30-34. (in Persian)##Faghihi, A. &amp; Mousavi Kashi, Z. (2011). The Model of Productivity measuring (effectiveness and efficiency) in Iranian Public Service. Journal of Public Administration. Management faculty of Tehran university, 2(4): 107- 126. (in Persian)##Faghihi, A. &amp; Mousavi Kashi, Z. (2013). Proposing of Spiritual Leadership Model in Iranian Bureaucracy. Quarterly Journal of Public Administration, 5(1): 21- 40. (in Persian)##Gholipour, R. (2008). Good Governance and Appropriate Model of the Government. Center for Strategic Research, Tehran, Iran. (in Persian)##Gholipour, R. (2013). Challenges of Bureaucracy. University of Tehran publications, Tehran, Iran. (in Persian)##Gholipour, R. &amp; Hamidian, M. (2009). Recruitment and Productivity in Iran. Center for Strategic Research, Tehran, Iran. (in Persian)##Jaaskelainen, A. (2009). Identifying a suitable approach for measuring and managing public. Proceedings of the European Conference on Intellectual Capital, P. 271.##Jaaskelainen, A. &amp; Lonnqvist, A. (2009). Designing operative productivity measures in public services, VINE. The journal of information and knowledge management systems, 39(1): 55-67.##Karwan, K.R. &amp; Markland, R. E. (2006). Integrating service design principles and information technology to improve delivery and productivity in public sector operations: The case of the South Carolina DMV. Journal of Operations Management, 24(4): 347–362.##Komijani, A. &amp; Shahabadi, A. (2011). Survey of Internal and External R &amp; D Effects (via Foreign Trade) on Total Factor Productivity. Bulletin of commercial. Iranian Journa of trade studies, (18): 211-230. (in Persian)##Lee, G. &amp; Perry, J.L. )2002(. Are computers boosting productivity? Atest of the paradox in state governments. Journal of PublicAdministration Research and Theory, 12 (1): 77–102.##Linna, P., Pekkola, S., Ukko, J. &amp; Melkas, H. (2010). Defining and measuring productivity in the public sector: managerial perceptions. International Journal of Public Sector Management, 23(3): 300-320.##National Iranian Productivity Organization. (2001). Familiarity with Productivity Concepts. (in Persian)##National Iranian Productivity Organization. (2004). Manual of Determining Strategies and Productivity Improvement Mechanisms for Country’s Economic and Social and Cultural Divisions and Subdivisions (Special Statement of 4th Development Plan Productivity Promotion. (in Persian)##National Iranian Productivity Organization. (2004). Report of Recognition of Productivity Public Situation towards Productivity Promotion Strategies in The Law of the 4th Economic, Social and Cultural DevelopmentPlan of the Islamic Republic of Iran. (in Persian)##Nollet, J. &amp; Haywood-Farme, J. (1991). A Model of Productivity performance migrateon. International Journal of Productivity and Performance Management, 62(6): 83-105##Parker, D., Waller, K. &amp; Xu, H. (2013). Private and public services: productivity. International Journal of Productivity and Performance Management, 62(6): 652 – 664.##Readout of Decreasing Productivity in Iran. (2009). Monthly journal of Khandani. 8(57): 36-37.##Report of Economic Indicators of The Central Bank of the Islamic Republic of Iran, 2011, No. 45- 57. (in Persian)##Saee, M, Allame Haeri, F. &amp; Alavi, S.A. (2009). Effective Factors on Productivity Rate and its Development via dedicated indexes codification and suggesting some solutions for its Improvement. Monthly Journal of Quality Control, (35): 46- 57. (in Persian)##The Law of the 4th Economic, Social and Cultural Development Plan of the Islamic Republic of Iran Ratified in 2004.##Thornhill, D. (2006). Productivity attainment in a diverse public sector. paper presented at Seminar on Promoting Productivity in aDiverse Public Sector, Dublin, 21 April.##Zahedi, Sh. &amp; Kakhaki Ahmad, H. (2012). A Model for Explaining the Role of Participation in Public Sector Employees’ Productivity Promotion. Quarterly Journal of Public Administration, 4(3): 69- 90. (in Persian)##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی عناصر چیره‏ دستی سازمانی در سازمان ‏های علمی و فناورانه (‏مطالعۀ موردی: جهاد دانشگاهی)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Designing Ambidexterity model in scientific and technological organizations Based on Grounded Theory (A Case of ACECR)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف پژوهش حاضر بررسی عناصر چیره‌دستی سازمانی در سازمان‌های علمی و فناورانه است. پژوهش حاضر از دسته پژوهش‌های توصیفی به‌شمار می‌رود که به روش پیمایش اجرا می‌شود. در این پژوهش مدل چیره دستی سازمانی از نظر کمی آزمایش شده است. جامعۀ آماری از میان شرکت‏های فعال علمی و فناورانۀ جهاد دانشگاهی انتخاب شده است، به‌طوری که این شرکت‎ها بیش از 10 نفر کارمند و 5 مدیر دارند و 94 شرکت را دربرمی‎گیرد. با توجه به فرمول کوکران 76 نمونۀ آماری از شرکت‌های فعال به روش تصادفی ساده انتخاب شد. در هر شرکت 3 مدیر به سؤال‎های پرسشنامه پاسخ دادند که میانگین نظر آنها به‎منزلۀ نمایندۀ شرکت تحلیل شد. بازگشت پرسشنامه‎ها از نمونۀ آماری 92 درصد بود که داده‌های جمع‌آوری‎شده به‎کمک روش مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری و تکنیک تحلیل مسیر ‌تحلیل شدند. این پژوهش نُه فرضیه را مطرح کرده است که هشت فرضیۀ آن به تأیید رسید و فقط تأثیر عوامل مداخله‌گر بر استراتژی‌ها و راهبردهای چیره‌دستی به‌دلیل عدد معناداری پایین ‌تأیید نشد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>. By Using Theorical Sampling and using sampling techniques targeted (judgment) Sampling and application of Snowball (chain) and Purposive Sampling was carried out on the basis of 16 interviews with administrators, faculty and Academic Experts of ACECR Which were Experienced in the field of Exploitation and Exploration and are Expert in both Fields. Analysis of Interview Data in The Process of Open Coding, Axial Coding and Selective Coding emerged in a theory in the field of ambidexterity in which architecture of Ambidexterity based on Committed Intelligence, Engineering Exploration and Technology-Based Exploration were Selected as Main Concepts Orienting to Ambidextrous.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>619</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>636</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>پورعابدی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammadreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Pour Abedi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار مدیریت منابع انسانی، جهاد دانشگاهی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار مدیریت منابع انسانی، جهاد دانشگاهی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>pourabedy@acecr.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بهره‌برداری فناورانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پژوهش مهندسی‌شده‌</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>چیره‌دستی سازمانی‌</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سازمان‌های علمی و فناورانۀ جهاد دانشگاهی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Adler, P., Goldoftas, B. &amp; Levine, D. (1999). Flexibility versus efficiency? A case study of model changeovers in the Toyota production system. Organization Science, 10(1): 43-68.##Beckman, C.M. (2006). The influence of founding team company affiliations on firm behavior. Academy of Management Journal, 49(4): 741-758.##Bledow, R., Frese, M., Anderson, N., Erez, M., &amp; Farr, J. (2009). A dialectic perspective on innovation: Conflicting demands, multiple pathways, and ambidexterity. Industrial and Organizational Psychology, 2(3), 305-337.##Cantarello, S., Martini, A., &amp; Nosella, A. (2012). A Multi‐Level Model for Organizational Ambidexterity in the Search Phase of the Innovation Process. Creativity and Innovation Management, 21(1), 28-48.## Cao, Q., Gedajlovic, E. &amp; Zhang, H. (2009). Unpacking organizational ambidexterity: Dimensions, contingencies, and synergistic effects. Organization Science, 20(4): 781-796.##Eisenhardt, K. M. &amp; Brown, S. L. (1998). Patching. Restitching business portfolios in dynamic markets. Harvard business review, 77(3): 72-82.##Ferrary, M. (2011). Specialized organizations and ambidextrous clusters in the open innovation paradigm. European Management Journal, 29(3): 181-192.##Flickinger, M., Gruber-Mücke, T. &amp; Fiedler, M. (2013). The linkage between human resource practices and organizational ambidexterity: An analysis of internal labor market dynamics in a port-of-entry context. Journal of Business Economics, 83(8): 923-946.##Gibson, C. B., &amp; Birkinshaw, J. (2004). The antecedents, consequences and mediating role of organizational ambidexterity. Academy of Management Journal, 47, 209-226.##Glaser, B. G. (1992). Emergence vs forcing: Basics of grounded theory analysis. United States: Sociology Press.##Graetz, F. &amp; Smith, A. (2005). Organizing forms in change management: The role of structures, processes and boundaries in a longitudinal case analysis. Journal of Change Management, 5(3): 311-328.##Grant, R. M. (1996). Toward a knowledge‐based theory of the firm. Strategic management journal, 17(S2), 109-122.##Gupta, A. K., Smith, K. G. &amp; Shalley, C. E. (2006). The interplay between exploration and exploitation. Academy of management journal, 49(4): 693-706.##He, Z. &amp; Wong, P. (2004). Exploration vs. Exploitation: An Empirical Test of the Ambidexterity Hypothesis. Organization Science, 15: 481-494.##Jansen, J. J., Tempelaar, M. P., Van den Bosch, F. A., &amp; Volberda, H. W. (2009). Structural differentiation and ambidexterity: The mediating role of integration mechanisms. Organization Science, 20(4): 797-811.##Jansen, J. J., Volberda, H. W., &amp; Van Den Bosch, F. A. (2005). Exploratory innovation, exploitative innovation, and ambidexterity: The impact of environmental and organizational antecedents. Schmalenbach Business Review, 57: 351-363.##Jansick, V. J. (1994). The dance of qualitative research design. Handbook of qualitative research, 209-219.##Junni, P., Sarala, R. M., Taras, V., &amp; Tarba, S. Y. (2013). Organizational ambidexterity and performance: A meta-analysis. The Academy of Management Perspectives, 27(4), 299-312.##Lee, G., Delone, W. and Espinosa, J. A. (2006), &quot;Ambidextrous Coping Strategies in Globally Distributed Software Development Projects&quot;, Communications of the ACM, vol. 49, no. 10, pp. 35-40.##Lee, J. Y. and MacMillan, I. C. (2008), &quot;Managerial knowledge-sharing in chaebols and its impact on the performance of their foreign subsidiaries&quot;, International Business Review, vol. 17, no. 5, pp. 533-545.##Lin, Z., Yang, H., &amp; Demirkan, I. (2007). The performance consequences of ambidexterity in strategic alliance formations: Empirical investigation and computational theorizing. Management Science, 53(10), 1645-1658.##Lubatkin, M. H., Simsek, Z., Ling, Y., &amp; Veiga, J. F. (2006). Ambidexterity and performance in small-to medium-sized firms: The pivotal role of top management team behavioral integration. Journal of management, 32(5), 646-672.##O’Reilly III, C.A., Tushman, M.L. (2008). Ambidexterity as a dynamic Capability: Resolving the innovator’s Dilemma. Research in organizational behaviour, 28: 185-206.##O’Reilly, C.A. &amp; Tushman, M.L. (2008). Ambidexterity as a dynamic Capability: Resolving the innovator’s Dilemma. Research in organizational behaviour, 28: 185-206.##O&#039;Reilly, C.A. &amp; Tushman, M. (2013). Organizational ambidexterity: Past, present and future. The Academy of Management Perspectives, published online before print. doi:10.5465/amp.2013.0025.##Pellegrinelli, S., Murray-Webster, R., &amp; Turner, N. (2015). Facilitating organizational ambidexterity through the complementary use of projects and programs. International Journal of Project Management, 33(1): 153-164.##Raisch, S. &amp; Birkinshaw, J. (2008). Organizational ambidexterity: Antecedents, outcomes, and moderators. Journal of Management, 34(1): 375-409.##Reilly, C. A. &amp; Tushman, M. L. (2004). The ambidextrous organization. Harvard business review, 82(4): 74-83.##Smith, W. K., &amp; Tushman, M. L. (2005). Managing strategic contradictions: A top management model for managing innovation streams. Organization Science, 16, 522-536.##Smith, W. K., Binns, A., &amp; Tushman, M. L. (2010). Complex business models: Managing strategic paradoxes simultaneously. Long Range Planning, 43(2), 448-461.##Strauss, A. L. &amp; Corbin, J. (1990), Basics of Qualitative Research: Grounded Theory Procedures and Techniques, Los Angeles: Sage.##Taylor, A., &amp; Helfat, C. E. (2009). Organizational linkages for surviving technological change: Complementary assets, middle management, and ambidexterity. Organization Science, 20(4): 718-739.##Venkatraman, N., Lee, C. H., &amp; Iyer, B. (2007). Strategic ambidexterity and sales growth: A longitudinal test in the software sector. In Unpublished Manuscript (earlier version presented at the Academy of Management Meetings, 2005).##Wang, C. L., &amp; Rafiq, M. (2014). Ambidextrous Organizational Culture, Contextual Ambidexterity and New Product Innovation: A Comparative Study of UK and Chinese High‐tech Firms. British Journal of management, 25(1): 58-76.##Wei, Z., Yi, Y. &amp; Guo, H. (2014). Organizational learning ambidexterity, strategic flexibility, and new product development. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 31(4): 832-847.##Wei, Z., Zhao, J. &amp; Zhang, C. (2014). Organizational ambidexterity, market orientation, and firm performance. Journal of Engineering and Technology Management, 33(1): 134-153.##Yang, Z., Zhou, X., &amp; Zhang, P. (2015). Discipline versus passion: Collectivism, centralization, and ambidextrous innovation. Asia Pacific Journal of Management, 32(3): 745-769.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مطالعه تاثیر رسانه‌های اجتماعی آنلاین برشفافیت و اعتماد ‌عمومی با اثر میانجیگیری مشارکت‌ عمومی (مطالعۀ موردی: دانشجویان دانشگاه تهران)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Study effect of social media on transparency &amp; public trust with moderating role of public participation(case study: Tehran university students)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>بین رسانه‏های مدرن، اینترنت به‌دلیل جاذبه‏های متنوع، جایگاه ویژه‏ای دارد. گسترش سریع فناوری‏های ارتباطی در سراسر جهان این پرسش را مطرح می‏کند که این رسانه‏ها و واسطه‏های ارتباطی چه تأثیری در مشارکت عمومی و تحولات اجتماعی و سیاسی جهان دارد. در این پژوهش اهمیت رسانه‏های اجتماعی آنلاین بر شفافیت و اعتماد عمومی با اثر میانجیگری مشارکت عمومی، به‌طور کاربردی سنجیده می‏شود. پژوهش حاضر از نظر هدف، کاربردی، از نظر چگونگی گردآوری داده‏ها از نوع پژوهش‌های توصیفی (غیرآزمایشی) و از شاخۀ مطالعات میدانی و از نظر ارتباط بین متغیرهای پژوهش از نوع علّی است. روش اجرای پژوهش نیز  پیمایشی است. جامعۀ آماری پژوهش حاضر، دانشجویان دانشگاه تهران را شامل می‏شود که نمونه‏گیری آن به روش طبقه‌بندی است و داده‏ها به‎کمک ابزار پرسشنامه گردآوری شده‎اند و در نرم‌افزار لیزرل 54/8 تجزیه‎وتحلیل می‎شوند. نتایج پژوهش نشان می‏دهد اثر رسانه‏های اجتماعی آنلاین بر مشارکت مدنی و سیاسی و همچنین اثر این دو نوع مشارکت بر شفافیت و اعتماد عمومی معنادار است و تأیید می‏شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Among modern media the internet has an outstanding position. Quick prevalent of communication technology provide this question that, what Is the role of these communication tools about public participation, social and political change in around the world? In this study we evaluate effect of social media on transparency and public trust with the moderating role of public participation in practical way. Data gathering of this research is descriptive, in term of purpose is practical,Field studies is the type of this study and on how to collect the data requirements is a description of the survey research type.Research Population consists of Tehran university students where categorized random sampling method has been applied. For data analyzing used LISREL 8.54.the result of this study indicate effect of social media on civil and political participation and also effect of those on transparency and and public trust are meaningful and Be confirmed.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>637</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>656</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عباس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نرگسیان</Family>
						<NameE>Abbas</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nargesian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>anargesian@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>هژبرافکن خلاری</Family>
						<NameE>Hassan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hozhabrafkan Khollari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>h.hozhabrafkan@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>معینی کربکندی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammadreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Moeieni</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mr.moeini@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اعتماد عمومی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رسانه‌های اجتماعی آنلاین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شفافیت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مشارکت سیاسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مشارکت مدنی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Ahmadi, P. &amp; Ahmadi, GH. (2003). Media and thechallenges ofidentitycrisis by futures studies approach. Secondnational conference on ayande pajhohi, yadgar derakhshan aria company. (in Persian)##Alvani, M. &amp; Danaeifard, H. (2001). Public administration and public trust. Quarterly Journal of knowledge management, 55(0): 7-24. (in Persian)##AmAndolina, M. W., Jenkins, K., Zukin, C.  &amp; Keeter, S. (2003). Habits from home, lessons from school: Influences on youth civic engagement. Political Science and Politics, 36(02): 275-280.##Ayatolahzadeh, H &amp; Nargesian, A (2014). Study of its Relationship with public Participation, Public Accountability and Transparency in 3’s region of city of Tehran. Public administration journal, 6(2). (in Persian)##Bhattacharya, R., Devinney, T. M. &amp; Pillutla, M. M. (1998). A formal model of trust based on outcomes. Academy of management review, 23(3): 459-472.##Choudhary, A., Hendrix, W., Lee, K., Palsetia, D. &amp; Liao, W. K. (2012). Social media evolution of the Egyptian revolution. Communications of the ACM, 55(5): 74-80.##Eslami, M. (2012). Socialnetworksand their impact ondifferent aspects of life, FirstNational Congress of cyberspace andsocial damagesnovel. (in Persian)##Flanagan, C. (2011). Civic Engagement and~ sychosocial Well-Bemg in College Students. Liberal Education. Retriered from: https://www.aacu.org/ publications-research/periodicals/civic-engagement-and-psychosocial-well-being-college-students.##Gholipour, A. &amp; Pirannezhad, A. (2007). Explanation of four-dimensional model of justice in development of self-efficacy in educational institutions. (in Persian)##Gil de Zúñiga, H., Jung, N. &amp; Valenzuela, S. (2012). Social media use for news and individuals&#039; social capital, civic engagement and political participation. Journal of Computer‐Mediated Communication, 17(3): 319-336.##Gozzo, S. &amp; D’Agata, R. (2010). Social networks and political participation in a Sicilian community context. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 4: 49-58.##Kaniki, M &amp; Alvandi, P. (2012). Social participating online and development local community in Iran. Social Welfare Quarterly, 41(11): 39-67. (in Persian)##Kavanaugh, A. L., Fox, E. A., Sheetz, S. D., Yang, S., Li, L. T., Shoemaker, D. J &amp; Xie, L. (2012). Social media use by government: From the routine to the critical. Government Information Quarterly, 29(4): 480-491.##Kirkpatrick, D. (2011). Technology social power and the coming corporate revolution why employees and customers will be calling the shots. Forbes, 31(2): 291-301.##Monavarian, A., Nargesian, A., Fatahi, M. &amp; Vasegh, B (2011). The study of realation between  public acountibility, public participation &amp; public trust in public organization. Managment reaserch, 11(3). (in Persian)##Rajapat, V. (2009). Social media: Trends &amp; growth of digital media. Siliconindia, 12(6): 28-30.##Rasouli, M. R. &amp; Moradi, M. (2012). The rate of communication student’s coordination in producing social media content. (in Persian)Ugurlu, H. &amp; Ozutku, F. (2014). An Evaluation on the Use of Social Media in Turkey. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 147: 453-457.##Valenzuela, S., Arriagada, A. &amp; Scherman, A. (2012). The social media basis of youth protest behavior: The case of Chile. Journal of Communication, 62(2): 299-314.##Waite, B. C. (2010). Communicator-in-chief: how Barack Obama used new media technology to win the White House. J. A. Hendricks, &amp; R. E. Denton Jr (Eds.). Lexington Books.##Warren, A. M., Sulaiman, A. &amp; Jaafar, N.I. (2014). Social media effects on fostering online civic engagement and building citizen trust and trust in institutions. Government Information Quarterly, 31(2): 291-301.##Wart, M. W. &amp; Van Wart, M. (2012) When Public Participation in Administration Leads to Trust. An Empirical Assessment of Managers’ Perceptions,32(9): 1433-1449.##Welch, E.W. (2012). The relationship between transparent and participative government: A study of local governments in the United States. International Review of Administrative Sciences, 78(1): 93-115.##Wicks, R. H., Wicks, J. L., Morimoto, S. A., Maxwell, A. &amp;Schulte, S. R. (2014). Correlates of Political and Civic Engagement among Youth during the Presidential Campaign. American Behavioral Scientist, 7: 173-208.##Ziaei, M., Nargesian, A. &amp; Aibaghi, E. S. (2009). The role of spiritual leadership on human resource empowerment in the University of Tehran. (in Persian)##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				