<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Meta-analysis Study of Knowledge Management Researches in Iran&#039;s Public Organizations</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>فراتحلیلی بر پژوهش‎های مدیریت دانش در سازمان‎های دولتی ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>299</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>324</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">59881</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2016.59881</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>پیران نژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4517-7259</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>26</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Current study is a meta-analysis of the conducted knowledge management (KM) researches in Iran`s public organizations during the period of last 10 years. In this research, it is attempted to achieve a comprehensive picture of the studies in this field of research in the national level through investigation of the previous researches and based on that, to attract the attention of the researchers on the neglected fields and eventually help the development of this concept in the country. The statistical population of this study includes 87 scientific research papers which has been published during the period of 2006-2015. Among these studies, a sample of 69 papers were chosen as statistical sample and after thorough investigation of these articles, the findings showed that most of the researches were focused on organizational culture and organizational structure in knowledge management projects in the governmental organizations and the least studies focused on intellectual property and technical infrastructures. Finally, some suggestions were offered for correction for the study process in this field.
 </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مطالعۀ حاضر، فراتحلیلی بر پژوهش‌های اجراشده در حوزۀ مدیریت دانش در سازمان‌های دولتی ایران طی ده سال گذشته است. در این پژوهش تلاش می‎شود با بررسی روند تحقیقات انجام‎شده در این حوزۀ مطالعاتی، تصویر جامعی از مطالعات این حوزه در سطح ملی ارائه شود تا بر اساس آن، توجه پژوهشگران به حوزه‎های مغفول باقی‎مانده جلب شود و در نهایت به توسعه‎یافتگی روزافزون این مفهوم در کشور یاری دهد. جامعۀ آماری پژوهش حاضر شامل 87 مقالۀ علمی پژوهشی است که در سال‎های 1394-1385 در کشور به چاپ رسیده‎اند. از میان این مطالعات، 69 مقاله برای نمونۀ آماری انتخاب شد و بررسی روی این مقاله‎ها انجام گرفت. نتایج این پژوهش نشان داد بیشترین پژوهش‎ها به ابعاد فرهنگ سازمانی و ساختار سازمانی در پروژه‌های مدیریت دانش در سازمان‌های دولتی توجه داشته‎اند و کمترین مطالعات بر ابعادی همچون سرمایۀ فکری و زیرساخت‌های فنی تمرکز کرده‎اند. در انتها نیز پیشنهادهایی برای اصلاح روند مطالعاتی در این حوزه ارائه شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ایران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازمان‌های دولتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فراتحلیل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت دانش</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_59881_444a753e8a86a26c92134758d71f95ee.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
