<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Modeling the Disturbance-Dynamics Model of Human Resources Development in Iran&#039;s Oil Industry</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی مدل آشفتگی ـ پویایی توسعه بهره‌وری منابع انسانی صنعت نفت ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>309</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>338</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">70852</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2019.277895.2514</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>مهرگان</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهناز</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسین زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نیما</FirstName>
					<LastName>ربیعی سروندی</LastName>
<Affiliation>انشجوی دکتری، گروه مدیریت تحقیق در عملیات، گروه مدیریت صنعتی، پردیس کیش، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>12</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt; The oil industry is the most important and strategic industry in Iran and plays a dominant role in the economy of the country. Human capital is the main element in the creation and development of productivity, therefore the development of human capital productivity in this industry can be a major step towards achieving economic growth and long-term goals of the country. In planning the development of human resource efficiency, managers and planners have to cope with the complexity of human resources (systems of multidimensional systems) and, psychological relations and socio-cultural issues (systemic attitudes). Considering the fact that, human resource utilization in the oil industry is a turbulent issue, this research aimed at modeling, simulating and strategizing the human resources system of the oil industry using the formulation of a turbulent order and the dynamics of the system. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt; The research’s methodology is inspired by the critical system thinking of research in multiple operations and methodologies (a system of systematic methodologies). This is primarily done using the barriers to the development of Ackoff / Gharage Daghie, the principled embedding of the structure of the problem turmoil, and then into modeling using the dynamics of the system. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt; The findings of the model show that insufficient attention to the transparency of the structure of the oil industry in terms of power and the use of intellectual and human capital in dimensions of value and motivation of staff in cosmetic aspects have caused damage to the abundance of human resources in the industry. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt; The application of hybrid policies in the three sub-systems of value, strength, and beauty were selected as the best way to improve the productivity of human resources in the petroleum industry. It was shown that plans for increasing intellectual and human capital, structural transparency in the oil industry, and the incentivizing systems of workers have significant effects on increasing the value of human resources and improving its productivity in the oil industry.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;هدف:&lt;/strong&gt; صنعت نفت مهم‌ترین و استراتژیک‌ترین صنعت ایران است و در اقتصاد کشور نقش مسلط را بازی می‌کند. از آنجا ‌که عنصر اصلی ایجاد و توسعه بهره‌وری، سرمایه انسانی است، توسعه بهره‌وری سرمایه انسانی در این صنعت، می‌تواند در راستای رسیدن به رشد اقتصادی و اهداف بلندمدت کشور گام‌های بلندی بردارد. در برنامه‌ریزی توسعه بهره‌وری منابع انسانی، مدیران و برنامه‌ریزان این حوزه از یک ‌طرف با پیچیدگی نیروی انسانی (سیستم‌های چندذهنی) و از طرف دیگر با روابط روان‌شناختی و مسائل اجتماعی ـ فرهنگی (نگرش سیستمی) مواجه‎اند. چنانچه مسئله بهره‌وری منابع انسانی را در صنعت نفت، مسئله‌ای از نوع آشفتگی در نظر بگیریم، این پژوهش به مدل‌سازی، شبیه‌سازی و سیاست‌گذاری سیستم بهره‌وری منابع انسانی صنعت نفت با بهره‌گیری از صورت‌بندی نظم آشفته و پویایی سیستم می‌پردازد.&lt;br /&gt; روش: روش‌شناسی پژوهش با الهام از تفکر سیستمی انتقادی تحقیق در عملیات و روش‌شناسی چندگانه (سیستمی از روش‌شناسی‌های سیستمی)، نخست با بهره‌گیری از موانع توسعه ایکاف/ قراجه داغی، به تعبیه اصولی برای ساختاردهی آشفتگی مسئله و سپس به مدل‌سازی با استفاده از رویکرد پویایی سیستم می‌پردازد.&lt;br /&gt; یافته‌ها: یافته‌های مدل، با توجه به وضعیت موجود نشان می‌دهند توجه ناکافی به شفافیت ساختار صنعت نفت در بعد قدرت و بهره‌گیری از سرمایه‌های فکری و انسانی در بعد ارزش و انگیزش کارکنان در بعد زیبایی سبب شده است که به بهره‌وری منابع انسانی صنعت، آسیب‌های فراوانی وارد شود.&lt;br /&gt; نتیجه‌گیری: اعمال سیاست‌های ترکیبی در سه زیرنظام ارزش، قدرت و زیبایی به‌عنوان بهترین دسته راهکار برای بهبود بهره‌وری منابع انسانی صنعت نفت انتخاب شد و نشان داده شد که برنامه‌ریزی برای افزایش سرمایه‌های فکری و انسانی، شفافیت ساختاری نظام صنعت نفت و نظام انگیزشی کارکنان صنعت نفت، بر افزایش میزان ارزش ‌افزوده منابع انسانی و بهبود بهره‌وری منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت اثرهای شایان‌ توجهی دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آشفتگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بهره‌وری منابع انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نگرش سیستمی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پویایی سیستم</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_70852_fb45f3b609d247e781e18cfe0c4bf893.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
