<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>8</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Knowledge Sharing in Sharif University of Technology: Social Capital Approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تسهیم دانش در دانشگاه صنعتی شریف: رویکرد سرمایه اجتماعی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>18</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">24786</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>سرلک</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشگاه پیام نور، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>طاهره</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسلامی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی دانشگاه پیام نور، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this research is to predict knowledge sharing through dimensions of social capital. Knowledge sharing occurrence depends directly upon tendency of knowledge holder to sharing as well as knowledge receiver to take it from holders. In other side, social capital is defined as linkage among people and their unifying factors such as trust. In this research, social capital is conceptualized into three dimensions and six elements as following: structural (organizational caring and rewards); agency or cognitive (pro-social behavior and impression management); and relational (competency and open-mindedness). Main question is: Can social capital elements predict and explain variances of knowledge sharing? 
This research is conducted on 179 randomly employees from Iranian leading university, Sharif University of technology. Employees are asked to express their attitudes toward questionnaire items in form of self-report. Using Structural equation modeling as an analysis strategy, results showed that tow elements of structural (organizational caring and rewards); one element of relational (competency); and one element of agency (impression management) dimensions have significant impacts on knowledge sharing behavior. Those elements of social capital can predict 27 percent of knowledge sharing variances in Sharif University of technology. Also, Open-mindedness and pro-social behavior have no significant effect on knowledge sharing. Practical and theoretical implications of current research are discussed at the end of report.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از پژوهش حاضر، پیش‌بینی رفتار تسهیم دانش از روی عناصر سرمایه اجتماعی است. از یک‌سو، تسهیم دانش به معنای میل افراد به تبادل دانش با دیگران بوده و از سوی دیگر، سرمایه اجتماعی بیانگر شاکله، محتوا و مضامین روابط متقابل میان عناصر شبکه اجتماعی است. مسأله به این شرح است: آیا می‌توان انتظار داشت که کارکنان بنا به دلایل اجتماعی (نه برحسب دستور و جبر)، دانش خود را در اختیار همکارانشان قرار دهند؟ 
با انتخاب نمونه تصادفی 179 نفری از کارکنان دانشگاه صنعتی شریف، توزیع پرسشنامه در میان آن‌ها جهت دریافت داده‌های نگرشی و استفاده از روش مدلسازی معادله ساختاری، نتایج پژوهش نشان داد که دو عنصر از وجه ساختاری (اهمیت به سازمان و پاداش)، یک عنصر از وجه فاعلیت (تسخیر احساس‌ها)، و یک عنصر از وجه رابطه‌ای (ابراز شایستگی) تأثیر معناداری را بر تسهیم دانش کارکنان دارند؛ اما تأثیر نوع دوستی و بلندنظری معنادار نیست. ابعاد سرمایه اجتماعی در این پژوهش توانستند 27 درصد از تغییرهای مربوط به رفتار تسهیم دانش را پیش‌بینی کنند. طبق نتایج برآمده، پیشنهادهایی نیز در قالب اجرایی و نظری در انتهای پژوهش آورده شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اعتماد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تسهیم دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دانشگاه صنعتی شریف</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_24786_e67055d0352e49fde075febad1f8be85.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
