<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Black Hole of Budgeting in Public Budgeting System of Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>سیاه‌چاله‌های بودجه در نظام بودجه‌ریزی ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>571</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>590</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">62177</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2017.62177</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عادل</FirstName>
					<LastName>آذر</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکدة مدیریت دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>طیبه</FirstName>
					<LastName>امیرخانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Abstract: Budgeting black hole as a new concept in literature of budgeting is introduced in this article. Black hole concept comes from the Astronomy science and describes the area in atmosphere that nothing can exit from it. The budgetary black holes are the expenditures in public budgeting to which government assigns a large amount of money every years but don’t have any outcomes for society. For explaining this concept, at first budgeting and the most important roles of it are described and then based on the analysis of documents, the black hole of budgeting is introduced. The society of this research is all of articles and essays about the budgeting of Iran being published in reliable books, magazines or journals and sites. The analysis show that cultural budgeting, current expenditures and construction expenditures are some examples of black hole of budgeting.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این مقاله مفهوم جدیدی به نام سیاه­چاله­های بودجه را در مبانی نظری بودجه­ریزی معرفی می‌کند. سیاه­چاله مفهومی است که از علم نجوم گرفته شده و به ناحیه‎ای از فضا گفته می‌شود که هیچ شیئی نمی‌تواند از میدان جاذبة آن خارج شود. منظور از سیاه­چاله­های بودجه، موارد هزینه­ای در بودجه­ریزی است که هر ساله بودجة شایان توجهی به آن اختصاص می­یابد، اما دستاوردهای آن با منابع اختصاص‌یافته به آن تناسبی ندارد. در این رابطه، ابتدا دربارة بودجه و مهم­ترین نقش­ها و وظایف آن توضیح داده شده است، سپس با روش تحلیل اسناد و مدارک، مفهوم سیاه‌چاله‌های بودجه­ریزی معرفی می­شود. جامعة آماری این پژوهش تمام مطالبی است که در خصوص بودجه­ریزی در ایران در کتاب­ها، نشریه­ها و سایت­های معتبر به چاپ رسیده است. نتایج حاکی از این است که بودجة فرهنگی، اعتبارات هزینه­ای و اعتبارات عمرانی، سه مورد از مهم­ترین سیاه­چاله­های بودجه در ایران هستند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اعتبارات هزینه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بودجه‌ریزی دولتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بودجة عمرانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بودجة فرهنگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیاه‌چاله‌ها</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_62177_8cab419a72a46e57e3e25c406ff9cc4e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
