<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>7</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Explanation of Intra organizational and Extra organizational Construction of Organizational Identity in Public Organizations</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تبیین عوامل درون سازمانی و برون سازمانی مؤثر بر ساخت سازمانی هویت در سازمان‎های دولتی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>149</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>166</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">23713</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ارین</FirstName>
					<LastName>قلی پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دولتی دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی اصغر</FirstName>
					<LastName>پورعزت</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دولتی دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرشته</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت دولتی دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>One of the most hot topic in recent years in management is Organizational identity and more important than it, is identity Construction which ignored in researches. Nowadays in most of the public organizations, the increase of turnover rate, reducing employees` job satisfaction, increasing the amount of job absent, developing job alienation, and lack of accepting responsibility sense and generally lack of identifying of the members with their organization, are noticed. The need for promoting the awareness of managers and directors of these organizations are among the effective factors on constructing the organizational identity and potential interests resulted from the strong and tenacious organizational identity more than ever. The present research is going to study internal and external factors effective on the constructing the organizational identity and the relationship between each of these factors with the organizational identity and present some guidelines for improving and strengthening it in the organizations. The mutual relationship of each of these factors with the organizational identity has been studied through correlation research method. The results show that there is positive and significant relationship between the positive media attentions to the organizations, external recognition, internal communication, top management team, human resources management and internal communication with organizational identity.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">یکی از داغ‎ترین موضوعات در سال‎های اخیر در مدیریت، بحث هویت سازمانی و مهم‎تر از آن شکل‎دهی هویت است که پژوهش‎های بسیار نادری در این زمینه انجام شده است. امروزه در بسیاری از سازمان‎های دولتی، نوعی تمایل به افزایش نرخ جابه‎جایی، کاهش رضایت شغلی، افزایش میزان غیبت از کار، گسترش بیگانگی از کار و فقدان احساس مسئولیت‎پذیری کارکنان و به‎طورکلی عدم هویت‎یابی اعضا با سازمان خود، مشاهده می‎شود. لزوم افزایش آگاهی مدیران و اداره کنندگان این سازمان‎ها از عوامل مؤثر بر شکل‎گیری هویت سازمانی و منافع بالقوه حاصل از وجود هویت سازمانی قوی و مستحکم، بیش از پیش آشکار می‎شود. پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی عوامل درون سازمانی و برون سازمانی مؤثر بر شکل‎گیری هویت سازمانی و ارایه راهکارهایی جهت بهبود و تقویت آن انجام شد. رابطه متقابل هریک از این عوامل با هویت سازمانی از طریق روش همبستگی مورد بررسی قرار گرفت و نتایج حاصل بیانگر وجود رابطه‎ای مثبت و معنادار میان توجه رسانه‎ها به سازمان، وجهه خارجی سازمان، ارتباطات خارجی، تیم مدیران عالی، مدیریت منابع انسانی و ارتباطات درون سازمانی با هویت سازمانی بودند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازمان‎های دولتی.</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شکل‎دهی هویت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هویت اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هویت سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هویت شرکتی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_23713_cafecb61272fb1e21597171f5fc5f942.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
