<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Perceived Organizational Support and Perceived Supervisor Support on Organizational Commitment and 
Individual Performance</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر حمایت سازمانی ادراک‎شده و حمایت سرپرست ادراک‎شده بر تعهد سازمانی و عملکرد فردی کارکنان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>373</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>391</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">59886</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2016.59886</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدعلی</FirstName>
					<LastName>شاه حسینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه MBA، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهرداد</FirstName>
					<LastName>استیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم السادات</FirstName>
					<LastName>کشفی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‎ارشد مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Keeping and retaining of professional staff in organizations and increase their performance have always been the concern of many organizations and companies in competitive situation.  Achievement of these objectives, depends on many factors such as perceiving organization and supervisor supports by the staff. In this research, the effect of perceived organizational and supervisor support on organizational commitment and individual performance will be investigated. For this purpose, a sample gathered through statistical census of Itrac Company with 260 employees, were studies. The method of analysis of the collected data was correlation and regression (step by step) with SPSS software, the results showed that the perceived organizational and supervisor support have positive and significant impact on affective and normative dimensions of organizational commitments and has positive impact on both the task and contextual performance, and there’s not a meaningful positive relationship only between perceived organizational and supervisor support with continued commitment.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">نگه‎داری و حفظ کارکنان متخصص در سازمان‌ها و افزایش عملکرد ایشان، دغدغۀ همیشگی بسیاری از سازمان‌ها و شرکت‌ها در عرصۀ رقابت بوده است. میزان رسیدن به این اهداف، به مؤلفه‌های بسیاری از جمله درک حمایت‌های سازمان و سرپرست از سوی کارکنان بستگی دارد. در پژوهش پیش ‌رو به بررسی تأثیر درک حمایت‌های سازمان و سرپرست بر تعهد سازمانی و عملکرد فردی کارکنان پرداخته می‌شود. به این منظور، نمونه‌ای از طریق تمام‌شماری آماری از شرکت ایتراک با 260 نفر از کارکنان مطالعه شده است. تحلیل نتایج به‌دست‎آمده از داده‌های گردآوری‎شده به‎کمک روش همبستگی و رگرسیون چندگانه (گام‎به‎گام) در نرم‌افزار SPSS نشان داد، حمایت سازمانی و سرپرست ادراک‎شده بر ابعاد عاطفی و هنجاری تعهد سازمانی و بر هر دو بعد وظیفه‌ای و زمینه‌ای عملکرد فردی تأثیر مثبت و معناداری می‎گذارد و تنها میان حمایت‌های سازمانی و سرپرست ادراک‎شده با تعهد مستمر رابطۀ معناداری وجود ندارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تعهد سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حمایت سازمانی ادراک شده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حمایت سرپرست ادراک شده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد فردی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_59886_52933641e2478c7ba56414d79e02ff88.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
