<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Presenting a Crisis Management Model with Emphasis on Human Resources Management System for Hospitals of Tehran]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Akbar Ahmadi, Seyed Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Rasuli, Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[rajabzadeh ghatari, ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[pooya, parisa]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Crisis Management]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cultural factors]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Hospital.]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Human Resources Management]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Crisis Management, as one of the key activities in strategic management has significant importance. One of the major requirements of crisis management is the high level of readiness and qualification of human resources responsible for crisis management. The focus of this paper is on presenting a crisis management model with human resources approach. First, we reviewed the literature and extracted the components related to human resources management in crisis management context. Then, we sought the opinions of 71 experts in this field in order to test the validity of the artifacts of the proposed model such as the role of human resources in different stages of crisis, different dimensions of human resources management in crisis management teams and finally, the effective cultural factors in this process. The results showed that the human resources play a vital role in the stages of prevention, shock, aggravation, chronic, control and learning from the crisis management. In addition, cultural factors such as team work spirit, conquering fear, expertism, self-devotion, ignoring rumors, desire for adopting new information technologies and pioneering culture have high influence in crisis management process.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_29128_cc16f72fa4082aa2411b2ff91d160940.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2012.29128]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Title: Public Policy necessities for administration of complex and different cities
(Case study: Tehran)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Pourezzat, ali Asghar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Raheimian, Ashraf]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[decision support system]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Mixed Model of Policy Making]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Riquisit Variety and Complexity]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Urban Management Dashboard]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Due to complexity and huge varieties in mega cities, their administration need suitable policy making that is designed specifically for each city. So, in the light of contingency approach and collage metaphor, in each city, designing of a mixed policy making system is necessary; a system that is able to use collection of current policy making models, and support urban management system for adopting better decisions. There for it's characteristic and necessities should be designed to be able to answer the continuous changes in complex and variety of cities problem in the future.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_29129_1a85c7e36160b8fee91f55a3cc996e2a.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2012.29129]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Role of Organizational Culture in Preventing from Administrative Corruption]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[rabiee, ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Assef, hajar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Administrative Corruption.]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[corruption]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Culture]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organizational Culture]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Administrative corruption is one of the problems with which most societies are tackling with. Nowadays, the approaches are emphasized most that try to prevent such phenomenon rather those exerting punishment to offenders. Current research investigates the role of organizational culture as one of preventing factors in decreasing administrative corruption. Current research is a practical research from goal perspective and according to its nature is a descriptive survey. First, the most important cultural factors were extracted with the help of 30 of Tehran’s administrative experts. Since the statistical population was unlimited, 373 administrative experts were chosen as a sample and the most important normal and behavioral patterns were extracted from cultural factors using closed questionnaires. The most important cultural factors affecting administrative corruption are as follow respectively: organizational values, sociability and individuation, behavior control, personal values, fundamental values and motivational methods. This research suggests prioritizing cultural approach beside structural and disciplinary approaches.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_29130_f1c3bf623f5480e5209cb0f0510516e5.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2012.29130]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Analyzing Entrepreneurship Obstacles in Agricultural Faculties of Iran
(Students' viewpoints)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[razavi, Seyyed Mostafa]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Fallah Haghighi, Negin]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Rezvanfar, Ahmad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Kalantari, Khalil]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agricultural Faculties]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Communicational Obstacles]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Educational Obstacles]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Entrepreneurship]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Students.]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[: The purpose of this study was analyzing entrepreneurship obstacles in agricultural faculties of Iran. Statistical population consisted of 61418 students that by stratified random sampling method, 403 individuals of them were selected from agricultural faculties of Iran. The instrument of data gathering was questionnaire and analyzing the data was done by using of SPSS software. The findings of research showed that only 6 percent of students had a job that was in relating with their field of study. The results of FA showed that, 5 infrastructural factors were known as the most important obstacles of entrepreneurship in agricultural faculties that were: "educational obstacles", "individual – characteristic obstacles", "law – support obstacles", "facilities obstacles" and" communication obstacles", these factors could totally explained 64.88 percent of variance of variables. Finally on the basis of findings, some suggestions were delivered.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_29131_2d882cd455162dd30b00f34f37d2294e.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2012.29131]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Pathological Study of the Policy Making Process in the Islamic Republic of Iran Broadcasting (IRIB)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Roshandel Arbatani, Taher]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[razi, Hoseini]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[labafi, somayeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Media]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[media policy]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[pathology]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Because of the complex and variable environment of media organization, its need a road map to help them to manage this environment and Respond effectively to sudden changes in front of that. Policy making in media organization can play an important role in this regard. In this study has been studied the policy-making process in the Islamic Republic of Iran Broadcasting (IRIB) and damages of this process has been analysis by the method of theme analysis. Twelve senior executives of Islamic Republic of Iran Broadcasting (IRIB) and academics and media elites, who were randomly selected as sample of research, were chosen. Results shows, Formation of macro policies on a tiny range of executives, Lack of transparency rules on the Policy Council, dominated management thinking are some of important problem in media policy process.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_29132_0bbe24a65b7842c5d67e88edb551579c.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2012.29132]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Study of Comparative and Analytical Characteristics of Employee Training System Characteristics of Employee Training System]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Abbaspour, Abbas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[dehghani, ali reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Employee Training]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Human resource management]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Training and Development (T&D) System]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Training needs]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In order to study the characteristics of employee training system in two large media organizations, namely IRIB and BBC and identification and comparison of common and different aspects between them, in the direction of appropriate understanding of existing dysfunctions and bottlenecks in IRIB employee training system, a research was conducted by utilizing descriptive-survey method with comparative approach. The conceptual framework of this research was based on four environmental characteristics impacting employee training system and Bernardin’s systemic model of employee training. The results obtained indicates that the common aspects between the two training and development systems is mostly related with internal characteristics and the differing aspects frequently arise from environmental factors which impact employee training and development mechanism.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_29133_7892b3270a92119de04e343d810c7091.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2012.29133]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[A Comparative Study on Importance of Public Relations for Foreign Household Appliances in Iran]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Farhangi, Ali Akbar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Irani, Alireza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Irani, Sepideh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Brand]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Marketing Communications]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[promotion]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Publicity]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Public relations]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Public relations has always been considered an important tool in human communications. Paying too much attention to advertising by sellers over time has distracted attention from public relations. In the case of the sellers of household appliances, they have come to a better understanding of the characteristics of public relations, and they have consequently found out that it in fact establishes a mutual communication with the customers, but not a one-way communication, and hence provides the sellers with information about customers’ needs. In addition, public relation as a sort of public relation–oriented marketing could be a substitute for advertising–oriented marketing. It is more cost effective, and it provides the sellers with direct feedback through mutual communications. The present study, adopting a descriptive–applied research, which attempts to study the significance of public relations for the foreign producers of household appliances working in Iran. Administering in present and desirable situation, the required data was collected from the senior managers of major producers, which are in Europe and Eastern Asia and work in Iran. Results indicated a significant difference between importance of public relations in European companies compared to that of the Eastern Asian’s.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_29134_f265e1c4d5bccdfe0f618b4ca7475b0f.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2012.29134]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Human Resources Strategy Formulation by Strategic Reference Points Theory (Case Study: RPK Company)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Golamzadeh, Daryoosh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[jalali, sonya]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Human Resources Strategy]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[strategic human resource management]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Strategic Reference Points.]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Strategy]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[HR strategy is the pattern of HR-related decisions. That is, the gestalt of negotiated people related policies and practices in use indeed the formulation and enactment of an HR strategy designed to link HR policies and practices with the strategic goals and objective of the firm. The purpose of this research is Human resources Strategy formulation for PRK Company. Integrative Model (Bamberger &amp; Meshoulam) used in this research. Population universe of the study includes directors of the company. Which measure each determining variables of strategic reference points for every strategic occupations of the company Data gathering instruments include questionnaire and interviewing? After processing of the data, strategic coordinates of the occupations were determined and appropriate strategic pattern of each occupation was identified. The results demonstrate that the appropriate strategy for the main occupations in competition strategy of the organization is the commitment Strategy. Appropriate strategy for the other occupation is the secondary strategy. Commitment attitude will result in better understanding of intents and objectives of the organization, and in fact it is a framework for management and training of the staffs for reliance on the company’s success in achieving its objectives.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_29135_3fb8270a1370105f5c4ee56b103ccd30.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2012.29135]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[A Theorical Model: Exploring Administrative and Political Domain]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[nafari, neda]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Administrative Field]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Authority]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Influential Variables]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Politic- Administration Dichotomy]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Political Field]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[An essential issue from the very outset of the field of public administration was to find proper limits of bureaucrats authorities in a democratic state .Contemporary research on the issue lead to emergent of two set of theories. The first is theories of political control of bureaucracy and the second is theories of bureaucratic politics. The research is against theoretical efforts and is considered as research and development on theoretical foundations of the political - administrational relationships. The aim of this article was to design a flexible model of political - administrational and the findings suggest the new classification of content and context characteristics public problem (independent variable) that affects the manner of choosing the field of administration- politic (dependent variable that involves actor, political-administrative action, and action mechanism). Characteristics of political - administrative action is classified under three categories: valuable, behavioral and structural components. And finally we try to explain the extent of authorities and field of politic - administration relationships in the form of influential variables in each field. The important issue in this article is to suggest that although the absence of accurate and predetermined boundaries between administration and politic makes the analysis easier, but two basic problem arise. First, theoretically the complexities and covert relations of them are ignored. Second, in the real world, politicians and bureaucrats are encountered with huge and complex variable circumstances that challenge the type of behavior to be selected and to determine the amount of their authorities.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_29136_2f74dd0ac8b8707fde282351a0d3739f.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jipa.2012.29136]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Journal of Public Administration]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>