<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identify factors to the commercialization of research in Knowledge of public administration</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی عوامل تسهیلﮔﺮ تجاری‌سازی پژوهش‌های دانش مدیریت دولتی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>235</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>262</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">64364</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2017.236485.2047</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امیر رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نریمانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>واعظی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>25</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Nowadays universities to commercialize research results, play a new role. Because of the importance of innovation and business development is increasingly becoming; Universities can play a greater role in innovation and commercialization of academic research. In this regard, more activities commercialization conducted with an emphasis on science and engineering, but human sciences research, particularly public administration has not been significant. In this study, the aim is to identify factors to commercialization of public administration research by exploratory analysis of theme-based approach carried out semi-structured interviews. The validity of the interviews was confirmed by the opinion of 14 experts and the retest method was used to confirm the reliability of the interviews. The results indicated that a total of 26 influential factors obtained in the three main themes: individual, organizational and environment were identified. In the end, based on the results, suggestions were presented in this area.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;br /&gt; امروزه دانشگاه‌ها در راستای تجاری‌سازی نتایج تحقیقات، نقشی نوینی بر عهده‌ دارند و از آنجا که اهمیت نوآوری و توسعۀ کسب‌وکار روز به‌ روز بیشتر می‌شود، می‌توانند در نوآوری و تجاری‌سازی پژوهش‌های دانشگاهی نقش بیشتری ایفا کنند. در همین رابطه فعالیت‌های تجاری‌سازی بیشتر با محور علوم و مهندسی انجام‌ شده و به تحقیقات علوم انسانی و به‌خصوص مدیریت دولتی توجهی نشده است. هدف این مطالعه، شناسایی عوامل تسهیلﮔﺮ تجاری‌سازی پژوهش‌های مدیریت دولتی است. برای تحقق این هدف، از روش تحقیق کیفی تحلیل مضمون بهره برده‌‌ایم. در این پژوهش برای انتخاب نمونه‌ها، از رویکرد گلولۀ ‌برفی و به‌عنوان استانداردی برای پایان نمونه‌گیری، از روش اشباع مضامین استفاده ‌شده است که مضامین با استفاده از دو منبع ادبیات نظری و مصاحبۀ نیمه‌ساختاریافته، احصا شد. روایی مصاحبه‌ها با نظر 14 خبره به تأیید رسید و برای تأیید پایایی مصاحبه‌ها، از روش باز‌آزمایی استفاده شد که در نهایت عوامل مؤثر بر تجاری‌سازی پژوهش‌های مدیریت دولتی در قالب 26 مضمون فراگیر و 3 مقولۀ فردی، سازمانی، محیطی، شناسایی و تحلیل شدند. در پایان بر مبنای نتایج، پیشنهادهایی در این حوزه ارائه شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پژوهش دانشگاهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پژوهش مدیریت دولتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تجاری‌سازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تجاری‌سازی مدیریت دولتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل مضمون</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_64364_593fab411efc2f96628f4ce7a6689182.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
