<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Organizational Social Inertia and laziness;
Dysfunctions of the bureaucratic Organizational culture</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اینرسی سازمانی و تنبلی اجتماعی؛ کژکارکرد‌های فرهنگ سازمانی بوروکراتیک</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>307</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>332</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">64368</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2017.234155.2019</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رحمان</FirstName>
					<LastName>غفاری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت، دانشکدۀ علوم انسانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد ساری، ساری، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>یحیی</FirstName>
					<LastName>رستم نیا</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشکدۀ علوم انسانی دانشگاه پیام‌ نور شهرری، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>27</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study aims to identify the impact of organizational culture of bureaucratic inertia, is an organization with the role of social laziness. The population of this study included 210 people from all employees Ilam Governor Of these, 140 were selected as sample. Three questionnaires were used to collect data from standard bureaucratic culture (Tanya, 2006), organizational inertia (The Hague, 2014) and social laziness (Ground, 1393) was used. Analysis of data from structural equation modeling with partial least square method through software PLS is done, showed that the research proposals approved and in the cultural component of bureaucratic inertia, cognitive, behavioral, cognitive - social, economic and political impact is positive and also features the work of variables, features group and individual perception, the relationship between the culture of bureaucratic and organizational inertia play the role of mediator. It is suggested that the governor of Ilam, corporate culture in order to better participate in the organization and increase employee commitment and their efforts to achieve the goals of the organization, is encouraging. The managers increase employee participation and involvement in important corporate decisions to reduce social laziness and inertia to provide the enterprise.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر با استفاده از الگویابی معادلات ساختاری، به­دنبال بررسی تأثیر فرهنگ ‌سازمانی بوروکراتیک بر اینرسی‌ سازمانی با توجه به نقش میانجی تنبلی ‌اجتماعی است. جامعۀ ­آماری این پژوهش شامل 210 نفر از کارکنان استانداری ایلام است که 140 نفر برای نمونۀ ‌آماری انتخاب شدند. به‎منظور گردآوری داده‌‌های پژوهش، از سه پرسشنامۀ استاندارد فرهنگ‌ بوروکراتیک، اینرسی ‌سازمانی و تنبلی ‌اجتماعی استفاده شده است. تحلیل داده‌­ها به‎کمک مدل‎‌سازی معادلات‌ ساختاری با روش حداقل مربعات جزئی و از طریق نرم‌افزار PLS انجام شد. نتایج نشان داد علاوه‎بر تأیید مدل پیشنهاد شده، مؤلفۀ فرهنگ‌ بوروکراتیک بر اینرسی‌ شناختی، رفتاری، شناختی ـ اجتماعی، اقتصادی و سیاسی تأثیر مثبت و معناداری دارد و متغیرهای ویژگی‌های کار، ویژگی‌های گروه و ادراک فرد نیز در رابطۀ بین فرهنگ‌ بوروکراتیک و اینرسی ‌سازمانی نقش میانجی را ایفا می‌کنند. پیشنهاد می‌شود به‌منظور مشارکت بهتر کارکنان در امور سازمان و افزایش تعهد و تلاش آنها برای دستیابی به اهداف سازمان، فرهنگ‌ مشارکتی در استانداری ایلام تشویق و ترغیب شود. همچنین مدیران با افزایش مشارکت کارکنان و دخالت آنها در تصمیم‌گیری‌های مهم سازمانی زمینۀ کاهش تنبلی ‌اجتماعی و اینرسی ‌سازمانی را فراهم کنند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اینرسی اقتصادی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اینرسی سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اینرسی سیاسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تنبلی اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرهنگ بوروکراتیک</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_64368_327100b169ce5a19fe0ab3e2a4f251ae.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
