<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Application of canonical correlation techniques to investigate the relationship between emotional intelligence, organizational citizenship behavior and organizational commitment</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>کاربرد روش همبستگی متعارف برای بررسی رابطه بین هوش عاطفی با رفتارمدنی سازمانی و تعهد سازمانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>211</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>228</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">50759</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2015.50759</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>تقی زاده یزدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>افشار</FirstName>
					<LastName>سلیمانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‎ارشد مدیریت آموزشی، دانشگاه ارومیه، ارومیه، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Today, one of the most important features of any organization is a committed workforce with high emotional intelligence who want to be involved in the successful change. In other words, they should show the same organizational citizenship behaviors and organizational commitment.  The current study aims to investigate the impact of emotional intelligence on organizational citizenship behavior and organizational commitment. The study sample included Shahindezh city school teachers in the West Azerbaijan. 298 statistical samples were chosen using a randomized stratification sampling and Morgan table. Data collection methods include organizational commitment questionnaire (Muday, 1979), organizational citizenship behavior (Orgon, 1998), and emotional intelligence (Shriyng Sieber, 1998), respectively. The results of canonical correlation analysis with 99% certitude show a strong relationship between emotional intelligence and organizational citizenship behavior thereby organizational commitment was confirmed. Multiple regression results showed that the dimensions of emotional intelligence (self-awareness, self-control and motivation) are a good predictor of organizational citizenship behavior and organizational commitment.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">یکی از مهم‎ترین خصیصه‎های هر سازمانی در عصر حاضر، بهره‎مندی از نیروی انسانی متعهد و با هوش عاطفی زیاد است؛ نیروهایی که به مشارکت در تغییرات موفق سازمان علاقه دارند و می‎خواهند همان رفتارهای شهروندی سازمانی و تعهد سازمانی را از خود بروز دهند. هدف این پژوهش، بررسی تأثیر هوش عاطفی بر رفتار شهروندی سازمانی و تعهد سازمانی است. جامعۀ آماری پژوهش حاضر را معلمان مقطع راهنمایی شهرستان شاهین‎دژ در آذربایجان غربی شکل داده‎اند. حجم نمونۀ آماری با استفاده از جدول مورگان به روش نمونه‎گیری تصادفی طبقه‎ای 298 نفر انتخاب شد. ابزار گردآوری داده، پرسشنامه‎های تعهد سازمانی (مودای، استیرز و پورتر، 1979)، رفتار شهروندی سازمانی (اورگان، 1997) و هوش عاطفی (مایر، سالوی و کاروس، 1999) بوده است. نتایج تحلیل همبستگی متعارف با 99 درصد اطمینان، از رابطۀ قوی بین هوش عاطفی با رفتار شهروندی سازمانی و تعهد سازمانی حکایت می‎کند. نتایج رگرسیون چندگانه نشان داد از میان ابعاد هوش عاطفی (خودآگاهی، خودکنترلی و بعد انگیزشی)، پیش‎بینی‎کننده‎های خوبی برای رفتار شهروندی سازمانی و تعهد سازمانی هستند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تعهد سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفتار سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفتار شهروندی سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هوش عاطفی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_50759_22a71097a60925001180e631abca7e13.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>‎‏The‏ impact of perceived organizational support on reducing social loafing</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل نقش و اثر حمایت سازمانی ادراک‎شده بر کاهش ‏بطالت اجتماعی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>229</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>244</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">54672</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2015.54672</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>دامغانیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکدۀ اقتصاد، مدیریت و علوم اداری دانشگاه سمنان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>لاله</FirstName>
					<LastName>جمشیدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکدۀ روان‎شناسی و علوم تربیتی دانشگاه سمنان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرشته</FirstName>
					<LastName>قلعه آقابابایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشدMBA ، دانشگاه سمنان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Nowadays, organizations are trying to maximize productivity by groups, but the results are not always completely satisfactory thereby causing some problems for organizations such as social loafing. Social loafing reduces motivation and effort in team work compared to individual work. This study intends to achieve the necessary mechanisms to reduce social loafing, and reviews the effect of perceived organizational support on social loafing. The population of this study includes all 220 employees working in offices in Tehran&#039;s Alborz Insurance Company. According to Krejcie &lt;em&gt;and Morgan&lt;/em&gt; Table (1970), the sample size for this study is 140. Sampling for this study has been done by stratified random sampling method. The study is descriptive and correlational, and also questionnaires were used to collect data. Data analysis was conducted using structural equation modeling. The results show negative effect of perceived organizational support on social loafing, and it can adjust social loafing.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه سازمان‌ها به‎دنبال حداکثرشدن بهره‌وری گروه‌ها هستند، اما کارهای گروهی همیشه به‎طور کامل به نتایج مطلوبی ختم نمی‎شود و گاهی با مشکلاتی همراه می‎شود که از آن جمله می‌توان به بطالت اجتماعی اشاره کرد. بطالت اجتماعی انگیزه و تلاش افراد را در کار گروهی در مقایسه با کار فردی کاهش می‎دهد. در این پژوهش با هدف دستیابی به سازوکارهای کاهش بطالت اجتماعی، اثر حمایت سازمانی ادراک‎شده بر بطالت اجتماعی بررسی شده است. جامعۀ آماری این پژوهش را تمام کارکنان شاغل در شعبه‎های بیمۀ البرز شهر تهران (220 نفر) تشکیل می‌دهد. بر اساس جدول کرجسی و مورگان، حجم نمونه 140 نفر تعیین شد و نمونه‌گیری نیز به روش تصادفی طبقه‌ای انجام گرفت. این پژوهش به روش توصیفی از نوع همبستگی اجرا شد و جمع‎‌آوری داده‌ها به‎کمک پرسشنامه انجام گرفت. داده‌ها نیز با بهره‎مندی از مدل معادلات ساختاری تحلیل شدند. نتایج نشان داد حمایت سازمانی ادراک‎شده تأثیر منفی و معناداری بر بطالت اجتماعی دارد و می‌تواند موجب تعدیل آن شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بطالت اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حمایت سازمانی ادراک شده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کار گروهی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_54672_c1ee55b5aee6e308bc9c70ddd5bd9abb.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Achieving national wellbeing through promoting national competitiveness capacity</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحقق رفاه ملی از رهگذر ارتقای ظرفیت رقابت پذیری ملی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>245</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>258</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">53639</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2015.53639</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>دانایی فرد</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جبار</FirstName>
					<LastName>باباشاهی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عادل</FirstName>
					<LastName>آذر</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اسدالله</FirstName>
					<LastName>کردنائیج</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>One of the constant concerns of economists and public administration scientists has been the transition from different stages of development accompanied by justice and social welfare.  Success of governments in achieving this goal is interpreted as one of their power elements. In the present research, promoting national wellbeing is considered from the perspective of improvement of national competitiveness capacity attributes. Research methodology includes both descriptive and correlation analysis based on Structural Equation Modeling. Data was collected by means of documents and library studies from international sources. Research results indicated that providing national competitiveness capacity results in national wellbeing promotion. Meanwhile, promoting national competitiveness capacity with attributes such as &quot;basic requirements&quot;, &quot;efficiency enhancer&quot; and &quot;innovation and sophistication factors&quot; paves the way for improvement of wellbeing in qualitative dimensions such as happiness, gender equality, etc. as well as quantitative dimensions such as health, education and research.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">گذر از مراحل گوناگون پیشرفت و توسعه همراه با عدالت و رفاه اجتماعی، یکی از دغدغه‎های همیشگی اقتصاددانان و اندیشمندان مدیریت دولتی بوده است. میزان توفیق دولت‎ها در دستیابی به این هدف، یکی از مؤلفه‎های قدرت آنها تلقی می‎شود. در پژوهش پیش رو بهبود سطح رفاه ملی از دریچۀ ارتقای ظرفیت رقابت‎پذیری ملی بررسی می‎شود. روش‎شناسی پژوهش از نوع توصیفی ـ همبستگی، مبتنی بر مدل‎سازی معادلات ساختاری است. ابزار اصلی گردآوری داده‎ها، اسناد و اطلاعات کتابخانه‎ای از مراجع بین‎المللی است. نتایج پژوهش نشان می‎دهد فراهم‎کردن ارکان رقابت‎پذیری ملی، به ارتقای رفاه ملی می‎انجامد؛ ضمن آنکه تقویت ظرفیت رقابت‎پذیری ملی با مؤلفه‎هایی همچون «الزامات بنیادین»، «تقویت‎کننده‎های کارایی» و «عوامل مؤثر بر نوآوری»، سبب بهبود وضعیت رفاه ملی از ابعاد کیفی (مانند خوشبختی، برابری جنسیتی و...) و ابعاد کمی (مانند بهداشت، آموزش و پژوهش) می‎شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفاه ذهنی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفاه ملی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رقابت‎پذیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ظرفیت رقابت‎پذیری ملی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_53639_fe5939dbd5b14a6b60ab779b01f40ab4.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The impact of employees&#039; judgments of corporate social responsibilities programs on extra-role behaviors and in-role job performance: with an emphasis on the mediating role of affective commitment</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر قضاوت‎های کارکنان دربارۀ برنامه های مرتبط با مسئولیت‎پذیری اجتماعی سازمان، بر نگرش و رفتارهای آنها</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>259</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>276</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">54673</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2015.54673</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>داود</FirstName>
					<LastName>سلمانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعید</FirstName>
					<LastName>مدرسی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت، پردیس فارابی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کیمیا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نوریان</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‎ارشد MBA، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آرزو</FirstName>
					<LastName>سلمانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‎ارشد EMBA، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>15</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The increasing importance of corporate social responsibility programs and initiatives has led to both a micro- and macro-level consideration of the impacts of these programs and initiatives on organizations. Does employees judgment of corporate social responsibility programs have any relationship with corporate social responsibility specific performance and their in/role job performance? Our attempt in this study is to answer this question. For that purpose, a sample including 237 employees of Yazd’s manufacturing-industrial units was chosen. The results of the data analysis using structural equation modeling and AMOS software indicated that employees’ judgment of corporate social responsibility has a relationship with affective commitment and extra/role performance. Results didn’t show any significant relation between extra-role performance and in-role job performance&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">اهمیت روزافزون برنامه­ها و اقدامات مختص به مسئولیت‎پذیری اجتماعی سازمان، موجب شده است که علاوه‎بر توجه به نتایج کلان سازمانی آنها، به تأثیر این برنامه­ها و اقدامات در سطح خُرد سازمانی نیز توجه شود. در این پژوهش تلاش می‎شود به این پرسش پاسخ داده شود: آیا قضاوت­های کارکنان دربارة برنامه­های مسئولیت‎پذیری اجتماعی سازمانی که در آن مشغول به‎کارند با عملکرد مختص به مسئولیت‎پذیری اجتماعی و عملکرد درون‎نقشی آنها ارتباط دارد؟ به این منظور نمونه­ای شامل 237 نفر از کارکنان واحدهای تولیدی ـ صنعتی استان یزد به روش تصادفی ساده انتخاب شد. تحلیل نتایج به‎دست‎آمده از داده­های گردآوری‎شده به روش مدل­یابی معادلات ساختاری به‎کمک نرم‎افزار AMOS، نشان داد قضاوت کارکنان دربارة مسئولیت‎پذیری اجتماعی سازمانشان، بر تعهد عاطفی و عملکرد رفتارهای فرانقشی مختص به مسئولیت‎پذیری اجتماعی آنها تأثیر دارد؛ هرچند نتایج تحلیل، ارتباط معناداری را میان عملکرد فرانقشی مختص به مسئولیت‎پذیری اجتماعی کارکنان با عملکرد درون‎نقشی آنها نشان نداد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تعهد عاطفی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفتارهای فرانقشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد درون‎نقشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکردِ مختص به مسئولیت‎پذیری اجتماعی سازمان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مسئولیت‎پذیری اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_54673_34e632299647311d6c249354419bbd42.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The effect of psychological capital on the quality of the offered services to the clients by the counter staffs with organizational commitment meditation</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر سرمایۀ روان‌شناختی بر کیفیت خدمات ارائه شده به مشتریان توسط کارکنان باجه با میانجی‌گری تعهد سازمانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>277</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>302</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">52326</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2015.52326</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>سید جوادین</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه بازرگانی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرجان</FirstName>
					<LastName>فیاضی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه منابع انسانی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>بلوچی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت بازاریابی بین الملل، دانشگاه سمنان، سمنان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The current study aims to examine the impact of psychological capital and organizational commitment on the quality of the offered services to the clients by the counter staffs of Ansar bank. In this research, the theoretical model and the theories between the variables were first developed and  structural equation was used to examine research theories. Ansar bank counter staffs of Tehran city are the statistical population. Therefore, for this research, 320 persons are picked based on the Morgan table using random sampling. A questionnaire was used to collect the data, the reliability and validity of which are assessed by Cronbach&#039;s alpha and confirmatory factor analysis.  This conceptual model was examined using structural part called path analysis and structural equation modeling. The results showed the positive influence of psychological capital on the quality of offered services to the clients.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA"> هدف پژوهش حاضر ارائۀ راهکارهای کاربردی به‎منظور بهبود کیفیت خدمات به مشتریانِ کارکنان باجه، بر اساس سرمایۀ روان‎شناختی و تعهد سازمانی است. پژوهش پیش رو از لحاظ هدف کاربردی است و از نظر روش، توصیفی ـ همبستگی شمرده می‎شود. در این پژوهش ابتدا مدل نظری و فرضیه‎های بین متغیرها توسعه داده شد. سپس به‎کمک مدل معادلات ساختاری، فرضیه‎های پژوهش بررسی شدند. جامعۀ آماری، کارکنان باجۀ بانک انصار شهر تهران است. بدین منظور نمونه‌ای برابر با 320 نفر بر اساس جدول مورگان و با بهره‎مندی از روش نمونه‎گیری تصادفی به‎دست آمد. داده‎ها از طریق پرسشنامه جمع‎آوری شد و پس از آن به سنجش پایایی و روایی ابزار پژوهش به‌کمک آلفای کرونباخ و روایی همگرا و واگرا پرداخته شد. نتایج به‎دست‎آمده از این پژوهش نشان داد، سرمایۀ روان‎شناختی بر کیفیت خدمات ارائه‎شده به مشتریان تأثیر مثبت دارد. همچنین نقش میانجی‌گری تعهد سازمانی در تأثیر سرمایۀ روان‎شناختی بر کیفیت خدمات ارائه‎شده به مشتریان، به تأیید رسید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تعهد سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایۀ روان‎شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کیفیت خدمات</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معادلات ساختاری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_52326_7059b6a180740af675a2f7a98a1425e9.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The impact of trade openness and business environment on foreign direct investment: A panel data of world countries from 2004 to 2012</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر آزادسازی تجاری و وضعیت فضای کسب‌و‌کار بر سرمایه‌گذاری مستقیم خارجی بین کشورهای منطقه آسیای جنوب غربی در بازۀ زمانی 2004 تا 2012</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>303</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>328</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">51600</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2015.51600</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهسا</FirstName>
					<LastName>قندهاری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکدۀ اقتصاد و علوم اداری دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعید</FirstName>
					<LastName>اکبریانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری منابع انسانی، پردیس دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سونیا</FirstName>
					<LastName>حبیبی راد</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‎ارشد MBA گرایش مدیریت تکنولوژی، پردیس کیش دانشگاه تهران، کیش، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>عباچیان قاسمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت منابع انسانی، پردیس دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی سفلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‎ارشد مدیریت صنعتی، مؤسسۀ عالی آموزش و پژوهش مدیریت و برنامه‎ریزی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The current study examines the impact of trade openness and business environment on foreign direct investment among 23 countries in Southwest Asia over the period 2004 to 2012. The research approach is econometric and the generalized regression of panel data was used to test the effect of the variables of interest. The results show that trade openness directly (coefficient of 0.002, p-value = 0.031) determines foreign direct investment. Among the business indices, the cost of construction permits (-0.012), enforcement of contracts (-0.002), received electricity (coefficient of 0.002), the cost of starting a new business (-0.051), the time required to export (-0.154), the time required to import (-0.112) and the costs of preparing and paying taxes (0.008) showed sufficient statistical significance. The time required to import and export has the highest share for anticipation of the foreign direct investment. These results suggest that developing an appropriate model in which a convergence is found between policy institutions is a necessary issue to promote trade liberalization and improve the business environment.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مقالۀ حاضر به بررسی تأثیر آزادسازی تجاری و وضعیت فضای کسب‌وکار بر سرمایه‎گذاری مستقیم خارجی بین 23 کشور منطقۀ آسیای جنوب غربی در بازۀ زمانی 2004 تا 2012 می‌پردازد. رویکرد پژوهش اقتصادسنجی است و از تحلیل رگرسیون تعمیم‌یافتۀ داده‌های پانل آزمون تأثیر متغیرهای مد نظر بهره برده است. یافته‌های پژوهش نشان می‌دهد آزادسازی تجاری به‎صورت مستقیم بر سرمایه‎گذاری خارجی تأثیر می‌گذارد. در بین شاخص‌های فضای کسب‌وکار نیز هزینه‌های دریافت مجوز ساخت‌وساز، اجرایی‎شدن قراردادها، دریافت نیروی برق، هزینه‌های شروع کسب‌وکار جدید، زمان لازم برای صادرات، زمان لازم برای واردات و هزینه‎های آماده‌سازی و پرداخت مالیات، از معناداری کافی برخوردارند. متغیرهای زمان لازم برای واردات و زمان لازم برای صادرات، بیشترین سهم را در پیش‌بینی سرمایه‎گذاری مستقیم خارجی به خود اختصاص داده‎اند. با توجه به یافته‌های پژوهش حاضر، ارائۀ مدل مناسب خط‎مشی‎گذاری ملی که در آن نهادهای متولی دارای همگرایی باشند، برای پیشبرد سیاست‎های آزادسازی تجاری و بهبود فضای کسب‎وکار، موضوعی ضروری به‎شمار می‌رود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آزادسازی تجاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">داده‎های پانل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه‎گذاری مستقیم خارجی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فضای کسب‎وکار</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_51600_acc4a2da1a660f1ebceec304c142292a.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Evaluation of civil order phenomenon management based on designing variables measuring level of system effectiveness and its application in modern approach to crisis management</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی مدیریت پدیدۀ نظم در سیستم‌های شهری بر اساس طراحی متغیرهای اندازه‌گیرندۀ سطح اثر بخشی در سیستم‌ها و کاربرد عملیاتی آن در نگرش نوین به مدیریت بحران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>239</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>352</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">54674</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2015.54674</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید جلیل</FirstName>
					<LastName>لاجوردی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار مدیریت دولتی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>ملاجان</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‎ارشد مهندسی سیستم‎های اقتصادی ـ اجتماعی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه صنعتی شریف، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>12</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Today, “Civil Order” may be regarded as one of the most important “Functional Requirements” (FR) of any city, as a real, complex, large-scale system. In this regard, learning about dynamic behavior of the civil order phenomenon and analysis of all information obtained from “Operational Environment” associated with the system of interest may be considered an essential step in the process of “Crisis Management” for mega-cities. For this reason, the present study aims to develop a way for evaluating the effectiveness level of civil order management system by establishing a set of quantitative variables, based on which we can eventually obtain the probability of successfully meeting each of the root-FRs, which is basically required to manage the civil order phenomenon behavior in the system (city) of interest. To verify the practical capability of the presented method, this study, as an analytical-descriptive research, focuses on a population, which consists of “Tehran’s Police Chief Dep.”, “Tehran’s Municipality Org.”, “Tehran’s Emergency Medical Services Org.”, and “Public Media (TV, Radio, and Presses)”, from which, finally,  140 participants are randomly drawn using “Stratified Sampling Method” to be inquired. Library Studies, Face-to-Face/Telephone Interviews, and Researcher–made Questionnaires are all three ways specifically used for gathering all required data and information. This study considers learning of changes in probability of successfully fulfilling each of the system root-FRs to be a sound basis for effective management of civil order phenomenon.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">اطلاع از وضعیت دینامیکی پدیدۀ نظم در سیستم‎های شهری همراه با تجزیه‎وتحلیل اطلاعات دریافت‎شده از رفتار تصادفی آن، گامی اساسی در فرایند مدیریت بحران‌های شهری معرفی شده است. در این زمینه، مطالعۀ حاضر متناظر با هر یک از «الزام‌های کارکردی پایه‌ای در سیستم مدیریت نظم شهری»، متغیر تصادفی ویژه‌ای را طراحی کرده است و پس از آن، به توسعۀ روشی برای اندازه‌گیری سطح اثربخشی سیستم مدیریت دینامیک پدیدۀ نظم در سیستم‌های شهری پرداخته است. پژوهش پیش رو با روش توصیفی ـ تحلیلی، در جامعۀ آماری متشکل از فرماندهی انتظامی و راهنمایی ـ رانندگی شهر تهران، سازمان شهرداری تهران، اورژانس تهران و رسانه‌های جمعی، بر اساس نمونۀ تصادفی با حجم نهایی 140 واحد آزمایشی، بر مبنای رویکرد نمونه‌گیری طبقه‌ای، اجرا شده است. این مطالعه، بازبینی نحوۀ تغییرات احتمال برآورده‌سازی هریک از «الزام‌های کارکردی ریشه‌ای» را پایه‌ای مناسب برای مدیریت اثربخش پدیدۀ نظم در سیستم‌های شهری معرفی می‌کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الزام‌های کارکردی ریشه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تئوری سیستم‎ها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دینامیک پدیدۀ نظم در سیستم‎های شهری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گسترش تابع کیفیت (QFD)</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت بحران</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_54674_ab6506958625eabe764705ffd19eab2d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Benchmarking and its applications in organizations (Case study: Designing the characteristics of organized inner- city area in Tehran city)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بنچ مارکینگ و کاربردهای آن در سازمان (مطالعۀ موردی: طراحی و تدوین مختصات محلۀ سامان‌یافته در شهر تهران)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>353</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>372</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">54675</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2015.54675</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهزاد</FirstName>
					<LastName>مشعلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت، دانشکدۀ علوم انسانی، دانشگاه علم و فرهنگ، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>05</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Tehran municipality, at the lowest level, has been divided to many inner- city areas. If the municipality is going to provide desired services to citizens, it is necessary to design the characteristics of organized inner-city areas. This research is designed to identify the characteristics of organized inner-city areas in Tehran city- based on the benchmarking mechanism. Required data was gathered by interview and data has been analyzed by using Delphi Technique and Content Analysis. The results suggest that 1) to formulate the characteristics of organized inner-city area in city of Tehran, we can use the benchmarking mechanism; 2) to formulate the characteristics of organized inner-city area, the focus must be on both functions and the work processes; 3) the necessity to focus on within industry benchmarking; that is, we must focus on municipalities by using the mechanism of “sister city”; especially, sister city to large municipalities (such as New York, London, Tokyo, etc.).</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">شهرداری تهران در پایین‎ترین سطح خود به چندین محله تقسیم می‌شود. برای اینکه شهرداری تهران بتواند خدمات مطلوبی به شهروندان ارائه کند، باید مختصات محلۀ سامان‎یافته‎ را طراحی کند. هدف این پژوهش ارائۀ راهکاری برای طراحی و تدوین مختصات محلۀ سامان‌یافته در کلان‎شهر تهران با استفاده از سازوکار بنچ‎‌مارکینگ است. در پژوهش پیش رو، داده‎ها با اجرای مصاحبه‎هایی گردآوری شدند و به‎کمک روش دلفی و تحلیل محتوا به تجزیه‎وتحلیل داده‎های یادشده پرداخته شد. با بررسی یافته‎ها این نتایج به‎دست آمد: 1. برای طراحی و تدوین مختصات محلۀ سامان‌یافته در شهر تهران، می‎توان از سازوکار بنچ‌مارکینگ استفاده کرد؛ 2. در طراحی محلۀ سامان‌یافته باید ضمن تمرکز بر وظایف، بر فرایندهای انجام کار نیز توجه شود؛ 3. باید به شرکت‎هایی که این صنعت را پوشش می‎دهند، یعنی به شهرداری‌ها، توجه کرد و سازوکاری با عنوان «خواهرخواندگی» را، به‎بویژه خواهرخواندگی با شهرداری‌های بزرگ دنیا، مانند نیویورک، لندن، توکیو و... را در دستور کار قرار داد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بنچ‎مارکینگ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شهرداری تهران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">محله</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">محلۀ سامان‌یافته</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_54675_7e81761f9d23c399ff19a4d166f00929.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigating the relationship between organizational intelligence and human resource flexibility in knowledge based organizations</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی رابطۀ بین هوش سازمانی و انعطاف پذیری منابع انسانی در سازمان های دانش بنیان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>373</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>392</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">50760</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2015.50760</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امیرهوشنگ</FirstName>
					<LastName>نظرپوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشکدۀ علوم اقتصادی و اداری دانشگاه لرستان، خرم‎آباد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>صمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>رحیمی اقدم</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیئت علمی گروه مدیریت، دانشکده اقتصاد، مدیریت و بازرگانی، دانشگاه تبریز، تبریز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The current study aims to explain the scientific foundation of and offer practical solutions to University of Tabriz human resources flexibility based on organizational intelligence. The research is applied in terms of purpose and descriptive in terms of data collection and it is casual according to relationship among variables .The data were collected by Albrecht organizational questionnaire and human resources flexibility questionnaire based on the Batachariya, Snell and Wright studies. The statistical population consists of scientific members of University of Tabriz in four knowledge groups; where 235 individuals were selected as statistical sample by Cochran formula in confidence level of %95 and finally 210 questionnaires were analyzed using simple random and cluster sampling method. The results of structural equations modeling showed that organizational intelligence by recognition coefficient of %79 is the strong predictor of human resources flexibility. Also, the results of Pearson correlation showed that all organizational intelligence variable dimensions have a positive and significant relationship with human resources flexibility.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف این پژوهش، تبیین چارچوب علمی و ارائۀ راهکارهای کاربردی انعطاف‌پذیری منابع انسانی دانشگاه تبریز، مبتنی بر هوش سازمانی است. پژوهش پیش رو از لحاظ هدف، کاربردی است و از حیث نحوۀ گردآوری داده­ها، از نوع پژوهش­های توصیفی به‎شمار می‎رود و از لحاظ ارتباط بین متغیرهای پژوهش، از نوع علی است. برای جمع‌آوری اطلاعات از پرسشنامۀ­ هوش سازمانی آلبرشت و پرسشنامۀ­ انعطاف­پذیری منابع انسانی بر اساس مطالعات باتاچاریا، اسنل و رایت استفاده شده است. جامعۀ آماری شامل اعضای هیئت‌ علمی دانشگاه تبریز از چهار گروه عمدۀ دانشی است که به‎کمک فرمول کوکران، در سطح اطمینان 95 درصد، حجم نمونۀ آماری 235 نفر مشخص شد و در نهایت 210 پرسشنامه به روش نمونه­گیری طبقه­ای ـ تصادفی ساده به‎دست آمد و به تجزیه‎وتحلیل آنها پرداخته شد. نتایج تجزیه‎وتحلیل داده­ها با بهره‎مندی از روش مدل­سازی معادلات ساختاری نشان داد هوش سازمانی با ضریب تشخیص 79 درصد، تبیین‌کنندۀ قویِ انعطاف­پذیریِ منابع انسانی است. همچنین نتایج ضریب همبستگی پیرسون نشان داد همۀ ابعاد متغیر هوش سازمانی ارتباط مثبت و معنا­داری با انعطاف­پذیری منابع انسانی دارند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انعطاف پذیری منابع انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازمان دانش‎بنیان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هوش سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_50760_399acd62294369c3d74930a20252dd3d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Hypocritical behaviors in interpersonal communications in organization: organizational antecedents and consequences</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رفتارهای منافقانه در ارتباطات بین فردی در سازمان: پیشایندها و پیامدهای سازمانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>393</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>412</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">51984</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2015.51984</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName>
					<LastName>هادوی نژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت، دانشکدۀ علوم اداری و اقتصاد، دانشگاه ولی‌عصر (عج)، رفسنجان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>الهه</FirstName>
					<LastName>بهارلویی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‎ارشد مدیریت، دانشکدۀ علوم اداری و اقتصاد، دانشگاه ولی‌عصر (عج)، رفسنجان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>17</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study has examined the organizational antecedents and consequences of hypocritical behaviors in interpersonal communication in Najafabad public organizations. To this end, proportional questionnaires were distributed among 280 employees of organizations as a sample. To test the hypothesis, the data were fitted to structural equation models based on chi-square, normed chi-square, incremental fit indices, comparative fit index, Tucker- Lewis, and root mean squared error of approximation. In order to adjust the results, the dynamic model of relationships between antecedents and consequences of hypocritical behaviors in interpersonal communication in organization was developed and tested. The results showed that at 95 percent confidence level, climate of silent, political interpersonal communication and legal-supervisory weakness are antecedents of research&#039;s dependent variable and organizational silence and interpersonal trust are its consequences. It was indicated that legal-supervisory weakness will raise climate of silence through affecting  political interpersonal communication. Also the legal-supervisory weakness will decline interpersonal trust through directly and indirectly affecting climate of silence and hypocritical behaviors in interpersonal communication in organization.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش پیش رو، به بررسی پیشایندها و پیامدهای سازمانی رفتارهای منافقانه در ارتباطات بین­فردی می‎پردازد. قلمرو مکانی پژوهش، سازمان­های اجرایی نجف­آباد در نظر گرفته شده است. به این منظور، پرسش­نامه‌های پژوهش میان نمونۀ 280 نفری کارکنان سازمان­های اجرایی نجف­آباد توزیع شد. برای تحلیل داده­ها، مدل­یابی معادلات ساختاری به اجرا درآمد و برای تعدیل نتایج، مدل پویایی­های روابط بین پیشایندها و پیامدهای رفتارهای منافقانه در ارتباطات بین­فردی در سازمان تدوین و آزمون شد. نتایج نشان داد در سطح اطمینان 95 درصد، سه متغیر جو سکوت، ارتباطات بین­فردی سیاسی و ضعف قانونی ـ نظارتی، پیشایندهای رفتارهای منافقانه در ارتباطات بین­فردی در سازمان‎اند و دو متغیر سکوت سازمانی و زوال ­اعتماد بین­فردی، پیامدهای آن محسوب می­شوند. همچنین مشخص شد ضعف قانونی ـ نظارتی از طریق اثرگذاری در ارتباطات بین­فردی سیاسی، به جو سکوت دامن می­زند و به‎تبع آن در سکوت سازمانی اثر می­گذارد؛ ضمن اینکه خود نیز به‎طور مستقیم و غیرمستقیم، از طریق اثرگذاری در جو سکوت و رفتارهای منافقانه در ارتباطات بین­فردی در سازمان، سبب کاهش اعتماد بین‎فردی در سازمان می­شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارتباطات بین فردی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیامدهای سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیشایندهای سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفتارهای منافقانه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_51984_0b8e5f9e6885e80dd1e00c682eed5a06.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
