<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identification of the Methods, Resources and Barriers of Achieving Sustainable Urban Income (Case Study: Urmia Municipality)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی روش‌ها، منبع‎ها و مانع‎های دستیابی به درآمد پایدار شهری (مطالعه موردی: شهرداری ارومیه)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>151</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>178</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">69808</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jipa.2019.272409.2463</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رحمت اله</FirstName>
					<LastName>قلی پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>درویش زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>پیران نژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4517-7259</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt;The management of city affairs is done through sustainable and unsustainable incomes, and in Iran, the highest rate of sustainable incomes make up about 30% of the total incomes. Therefore, in Iran, the challenge of achieving sustainable incomes for local government is of great importance. The present study aimed to identify methods, resources and barriers to achieving sustainable urban income in Urmia municipality.
&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt; According to the subject, the method of qualitative research was carried out through completing a checklist on the agenda with 12 scientific and executive experts who had been selected through the snowball sampling method. They had sufficient control over the concept of sustainable urban income and relied on this type of income in their responsibilities while they are familiar with different dimensions. Open and deep interviews were conducted and the results of the interviews were analyzed based on the theme analysis technique.
&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt; Based on the results of the study, the following 10 themes were identified as methods: “investment”, “outsourcing”, “financial management”, “information technology”, “organizational assessment”, “research”, “delegating governmental authority”, “human resources”, “communications” and “miscellaneous”. There were also 6 themes identified for resources: “tolls”, “Land and buildings”, “cost management”, “bonds”, “advertising” and “miscellaneous” and finally the following 8 themes were identified as barriers to sustainable urban incomes: “manpower”, ”injustice”, “transparency”, “performance weakness”, “corruption”, “law”, “people” and “miscellaneous” were identified.
&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt; In this research, the methods, resources and barriers to achieving sustainable incomes in Urmia municipality were presented as well as suggestions for increasing this type of income. In short, it should be stated that the Urmia municipality will attain a decent level of sustainable incomes, if it will be able to consider the proposed ideas in this study.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;هدف:&lt;/strong&gt; مدیریت امور شهرها با درآمدهای پایدار و ناپایدار رقم می‎خورد و در ایران، بالاترین آمار درآمدهای پایدار، به حدود 30 درصد کل درآمدها می‎رسد. از این رو در ایران، دغدغه دستیابی به درآمدهای پایدار برای حکمرانی‎های محلی اهمیت بسزایی دارد. پژوهش حاضر با هدف شناسایی روش‌ها، منبع‎ها و مانع‎های دستیابی به درآمد پایدار شهری در شهرداری ارومیه اجرا شده است.
روش: با توجه به موضوع، روش تحقیق کیفی از طریق خبره‎سنجی در دستور کار قرار گرفت. با 12 نفر از خبرگان علمی و اجرایی که به روش گلوله برفی انتخاب شدند، مصاحبه‌های باز و عمیقی صورت گرفت و نتایج مصاحبه بر اساس تکنیک تحلیل تم تجزیه ‌و تحلیل شد. شایان ذکر است که خبرگان پژوهش ضمن تسلط کافی به مفهوم درآمد پایدار شهری، در مسئولیت‌های خود با ابعاد مختلف اتکا به این نوع درآمد آشنا بودند.
یافته‎ها: 10 تمِ سرمایه‌گذاری، برون‌سپاری، مدیریت مالی، فناوری اطلاعات، ارزیابی سازمان، پژوهش، واگذاری اختیارات دولتی، نیروی انسانی، ارتباطات و متفرقه برای روش‎ها؛ 6 تمِ عوارض، زمین و ساختمان، مدیریت هزینه، اوراق، تبلیغات و متفرقه برای منابع و 8 تمِ نیروی انسانی، حق‎خوری، شفافیت، ضعف عملکرد، فساد، قانون، مردم و متفرقه برای موانع دستیابی به درآمد پایدار شهری، به‎دست آمد.
نتیجه‎گیری: در این پژوهش روش‎ها، منبع‎ها و مانع‎های دستیابی به درآمدهای پایدار در شهرداری ارومیه شناسایی شدند و پیشنهادهایی برای افزایش این نوع درآمدها ارائه شد. به‎طور خلاصه باید گفت که شهرداری ارومیه زمانی به سطح مناسبی از درآمدهای پایدار دست می‎یابد که بتواند بسته پیشنهادی ارائه شده در این پژوهش را در کانون توجه قرار دهد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارومیه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">درآمد پایدار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">درآمد ناپایدار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شهر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شهرداری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_69808_95b660962689718f9203e48aa07b1d32.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
