<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت دولتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5877</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>6</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The media and glass ceiling: Explanation of television impact on the women promotion to the managerial levels</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رسانه و سقف شیشه‎ای: تبیین نقش تلویزیون در ارتقاء زنان به سطوح مدیریتی جامعه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>18</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">22426</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حبیب</FirstName>
					<LastName>ابراهیم پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی، اردبیل، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امیر حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>مکبری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای مدیریت رسانه دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>داوود</FirstName>
					<LastName>ریواز</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای مدیریت رسانه دانشگاه آزاد، واحد علوم و تحقیقات</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>طاهر</FirstName>
					<LastName>روشندل اربطانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Despite the remarkable growth of women in the work environment, improvement of their managerial positions aren&#039;t suitable with their number in organizations, while there is no reasonable evidences about lack of managerial ability of women but it seems issues like discrimination and job attitudes, limiting mistakes and face the rush toward the occupations and encounter with many problems to catch managerial positions in society. This paper aims to clarify the role of mass media in promoting women to managerial levels is the purpose to investigate the relationship between adaptation Television aspects of cognitive, normative, regulatory and development form the subject of women and their promotion to managerial levels of the other has been discussed. This questionnaire which confirmed its validity and reliability has been estimated that 84 percent was in the form of survey research in fields of management and communication professors of the University of Tehran state level was conducted. According to the research findings and in 95 percent of TV programs have significant effects on promoting women in the community was 42 percent, it indicates that about 42 percent in variations of promotion in society related to TV and 58 Percent of the rest is related to other factors.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">با وجود رشد چشمگیر حضور زنان در محیط‎های کار، میزان پیشرفت آن‎ها در مشاغل مدیریتی متناسب با تعداد آن‎ها در سازمان‎ها نیست و این در حالی است که هیچ‎گونه شواهد منطقی در خصوص عدم توانایی مدیریتی زنان به چشم نمی‎خورد، بلکه آنان با مسایلی نظیر تبعیض شغلی و نگرش‎های غلط و محدود کننده در جامعه مواجهند که حرکتشان را به سمت مشاغل مدیریتی با مشکلات فراوانی مواجه می‎سازد. هدف این مقاله تبیین نقش رسانه‎های جمعی در ارتقاء زنان به سطوح مدیریتی است که بدین منظور به بررسی ارتباط میان سازگاری برنامه‎های تلویزیون از ابعاد شناختی، هنجاری، تنظیمی و شکلی با موضوع رشد زنان از یکسو و ارتقاء آنان به سطوح مدیریتی از سوی دیگر پرداخته شده است.این کار از طریق پرسشنامه‎ای که روایی آن مورد تأیید قرار گرفنه و پایایی آن 84 درصد برآورد شده بود، در قالب یک پژوهش پیمایشی در سطح استادان رشته‎های مدیریت و ارتباطات دانشگاه‎های دولتی سطح تهران انجام گرفت. بر اساس یافته‎های پژوهش و در سطح اطمینان 95 درصد میزان اثر معناداری برنامه‎های تلویزیونی بر ارتقاء زنان در جامعه 42 درصد به‎دست آمد که بیانگر این است که حدود 42 درصد تغییرات در ارتقاء زنان در جامعه مربوط به تلویزیون بوده و 58 درصد بقیه به عوامل دیگری مربوط می‎شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارتقاء زنـان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تلویزیون</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رسانه‎های جمعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سقف شیشه‎ای</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jipa.ut.ac.ir/article_22426_e53cbd0a78618ada7a51f8cd720206b5.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
