﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2009</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biostratigraphy, microfacies and sedimentary environment of the Asmari Formation at Somghan area and correlation with other sections in the Zagros basin</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>زيست چينه نگاري، ريز رخساره ها و محيط رسوبي سازند آسماري در ناحيه سمغان، شمال کازرون و تطابق با برش¬هاي ديگر در حوضه زاگرس</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مهرناز</FirstName><LastName>رحیم زاده </LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>صیرفیان</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی </FirstName><LastName>رحمانی</LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی نفت ایران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></History><Abstract>The difference in the depositional setting of the Zagros, causes multiple carbonate facies.The Asmari Formation deposited in the foreland basin during Oligo-Miocene time. In this study, biostratiography and microfacies of the Asmari Formation at Nowdan anticline next to Somghan village (39 Km north of Kazerun) are studied. The thickness of the Asmari Formation is 302 meters and its upper and lower boundries are coverd. Field work studies resulted to recognize 4 lithostratigraphic units (unit 1: thin to medium bedded limestone, unit 2: thick and some thin and medium bedded limestone, unit 3: thin and thick bedded nudular limestone, unit 4: thin bedded nudular limestone). Based on microscopic studies, 20 genera and 19 species of benthic foraminifera were identified and two biozones related to the Oligocene were identified. Based on textural and faunal studies, nine microfacies related lagoon and open marine were differentiated. Also in this study, to reconstract geometry and to analyze the role of Qatar-Kazerun fault during Oligocene, 11 sections of the Asmari Formation were examined.

</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">هندسه ي متفاوت بستر رسوبي ، بيوزون ها و رخساره هاي کربناته متعدد را سبب مي شود. سازند آسماري، در بازه ي زماني اليگو-ميوسن در حوضه ي فورلند نهشته شده است. در اين تحقيق، زيست چينه نگاري و ريز رخساره هاي سازند آسماري در يال شمال غربي تاقديس نودان (شمال کازرون)، مورد بررسي قرار گرفته است. سازند آسماري در اين برش داراي ستبراي 302 متر مي باشد و مرزهاي بالا و پايين آن پوشيده است. بر اساس مطالعات صحرايي و خصوصيات لايه ها، 4 واحد سنگي (واحد1: آهک هاي نازک و متوسط لايه ، واحد 2: آهک هاي ضخيم لايه و ماسيو با ميان لايه-هاي نازک و گاهاً متوسط، واحد 3: تناوبي از آهک هاي ضخيم، متوسط و نازک لايه ي نودولار، واحد 4: آهک هاي نازک لايه ي نودولار) تشخيص داده شد. بر اساس مطالعات ميکروسکوپي، 20 جنس و 19 گونه تشخيص داده شد و دو بيوزون، در ارتباط با زمان اليگوسن معرفي گرديد. بر اساس نوع بافت و فون هاي تشکيل دهنده در برش مورد مطالعه، 9 ريز رخساره در دو محيط لاگوني و درياي باز شناسايي شد. همچنين در اين تحقيق، 11 برش از سازند آسماري در نواحي فارس، ايذه و زاگرس مرتفع از ديدگاه تطابق بيوزوني مورد مقايسه قرار گرفته اند.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سازند آسماري</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 زيست چينه نگاري</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 ريزرخساره</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 حوضه ي فورلند</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/139507131147573551-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>