﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>34</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2008</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Oligocene microfacies and sedimentary environment of the Asmari Formation at northwest of Deris village, west of Fars province: correlation with three other sections in Zagros Basin</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ريز رخساره ها و مدل رسوبی سازند آسماری (اليگوسن) در شمال غرب روستای دريس (غرب استان فارس) و مقايسه ضخامت، سن و محيط رسوبی با سه برش ديگر در حوضه زاگرس</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>سمیر</FirstName><LastName>اخزری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>صیرفیان</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day></History><Abstract>
In this disquisition, Oligocene (Rupelian-Chattian) microfacies and sedimentary environment of the Asmari Formation at the northwest of Deris village, located in interior Fars zone of the Zagros Basin have been interpreted. The coordinates of such section are N: 29o 41' 59'', E: 51 o 32' 26''. The Asmari Formation deposits in this section are divided into 5 lithological units and consist of 460 m thin, medium, thick and massive bedded, gray and cream to gray limestone, slightly dolomitic with nodular and marly interbedded. By study of hyaline benthic foraminifera genera and non-foraminifera, and also recognition of some properties such as skeletal ingredient associations and sedimentary textures of thin sections, 14 microfacies have been introduced for the Asmari Formation. Gradual perpendicular changes of these microfacies represent that settling the Asmari Formation deposits took place in a homoclinal rapm. This homoclinal ramp consists of middle ramp and inner ramp, that are separated by shoal environment. Middle ramp is recognized by presence and dominition hyaline benthic foraminifera, coralline red algae and echinoids. The most significant skeletal debris of inner ramp are porcelainous foraminifera. To compare the thickness, age and sedimentary environment, zonal correlation of the Asmari Formation done in Deris section with three other sections (Naura anticline, Dill anticline and Dehloran) in the Zagros Basin. This correlation represent that the age of the Asmari Formation gets younger to the deeper parts of the foreland basin of the Zagros.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این تحقیق ریز رخساره ها و مدل رسوبی سازند آسماری به سن الیگوسن (روپلین-شاتین) در شمال غرب روستای دریس، واقع در زون فارس داخلی حوضه زاگرس، بررسی و تفسیر گردیده است. مختصات جغرافیایی این برش "26 '32 °51 شرقی و "59 '41 °29 شمالی می باشد. نهشته های سازند آسماری در برش دریس به 5 واحد سنگ چینه نگاری تقسیم می شوند که شامل 460 متر آهک خاکستری و کرم متمایل به خاکستری نازک، متوسط، ضخیم و توده ای و بعضاً دولومیتی با میان لایه های مارنی می باشد. با مطالعه گونه-های فرامینیفرهای کف زی و غیر فرامینیفرها، و بررسی ویژگی هایی از قبیل اجتماع عناصر اسکلتی و بافت رسوبی مقاطع میکروسکوپی، 14 ریز رخساره برای سازند آسماری معرفی شده است. تغییرات تدریجی عمودی این ریز رخساره ها حاکی از ته نشست رسوبات سازند آسماری در یک رمپ هموکلینال می باشد. این رمپ هموکلینال شامل رمپ میانی و رمپ درونی بوده که این دو بخش توسط محیط سد از هم جدا می شوند. رمپ میانی با حضور و فراوانی فرامینیفرهای هیالین کف زی، جلبک قرمز کورالیناسه آ و اکینوئید معرفی می گردد. همچنین مهم ترین خرده های اسکلتی رمپ درونی فرامینیفرهای پرسلانوز می باشند. به منظور مقایسه ضخامت، سن و محیط های رسوبی، تطابق ناحیه ای سازند آسماری در برش دریس با سه برش دیگر (برش تاقدیس نااورا، برش تاقدیس دیل و برش دهلران)، در حوضه زاگرس انجام شده است. این تطابق بیان کننده جوان تر شدن سن سازند آسماری به سمت بخش های عمیق تر حوضه فورلند زاگرس می باشد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">حوضه زاگرس</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
فارس داخلی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
سازند آسماری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 الیگوسن، ریز رخساره</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
رمپ هموکلینال</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13950310931302428-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>