﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2009</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biostratigraphy, microfacies and sequence stratigraphy of the Asmari Formation (based on Cyclolog) in the Qaleh Nar Oli field, Zagros Basin</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>زیست چینه نگاری، بررسی ریزرخساره¬ها و چینه نگاری سکانسی سازند آسماری (به کمک نرم افزار سیکلولاگ) در میدان نفتی قلعه نار، حوضه زاگرس </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>عباس </FirstName><LastName>قادری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>عادل</FirstName><LastName>نیسی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>غبیشاوی</LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی نفت ایران </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد</FirstName><LastName>اله کرم پوردیل</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان - شرکت ملی مناطق نفت خیز جنوب</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></History><Abstract>In this research, biostratigraphy, microfacies, sedimentary environments and sequence stratigraphy (using by Cyclolog software) of the Asmari Formation are carried out. These studies are done on the basis of 580 samples (core and cutting) from 430 meters thickness of the formation from the well #2 of the Qaleh-Nar oilfield. Paleontological studies are led to identification of 23 genera and 28 species of the benthic and planktonic foraminifera. According to these microfossils, four assemblage zones have been recognized which confirm the age of Oligocene (Rupelian – Chattian) and Early Miocene (Aquitanian – Burdigalian) for the whole formation. Paleoenvironmental studies demonstrate 9 different microfacies that were deposited in the outer ramp (open marine) in the lower Asmari part, middle ramp (open marine to shoal) in the middle Asmari part and the inner ramp environment (tidal flat to lagoon) in the upper Asmari part. The sequence stratigraphy on the well #2 and the auxiliary well numbers 1, 3, 5, 6 and 7 of the Qaleh-Nar oilfield using by Cyclolog software reveals 7 positive breaks and 9 negative break levels alternatively. Some of the positive breaks define sequence boundaries and some of the negative breaks present the maximum flooding surfaces. In addition, a number of positive levels specify the major chronozone (stage boundaries). Comparison of the quintuple reservoir zones of the Asmari Formation in the Qaleh-Nar oilfield with the mentioned break levels suggests a fine correlation with these levels; however this correlation is invalid for other levels.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این پژوهش، زیست چینه نگاری، ریزرخساره¬ها، محیط رسوبی و چینه نگاری سکانسی سازند آسماری (با استفاده از نرم¬افزار سیکلولاگ) با تکیه بر مطالعه 580 مقطع نازک (شامل مغزه و خرده¬های حفاری) تهیه شده از 430 متر توالیهای برش تحت الارضی چاه شماره 2 میدان نفتی قلعه نار انجام شده است. مطالعات فسیل¬شناسی انجام شده به شناسایی 23 جنس و 28 گونه از روزن¬داران کف¬زی و پلانکتون منجر گردید.
بر این اساس، چهار بایوزون تجمعی شناسایی و سن سازند آسماری الیگوسن (روپلین ـ شاتین) و میوسن پیشین (آکیتانین ـ بوردیگالین) در نظر گرفته شد. مطالعه ریز¬رخساره¬های رسوبی به شناسایی 9 ریزرخسـاره انجامیده است که بیانــگر رسوب¬گذاری در سه محیط رمپ خارجی (دریای باز) در بخش آسماری زیرین و رمپ میانی (شول و دریای باز) اغلب در آسماری میانی و رمپ داخلی (بالای پهنه جزر و مدی، پهنه جزر و مدی و لاگون) بیشتر در بخش آسماری بالایی هستند. مطالعات چینه¬نگاری سکانسی در چاه شماره 2 و چاه¬های کمکی 1، 3، 5، 6 و 7 میدان نفتـی قلعه نار با استفاده از نرم افزار سیکلولاگ انجام شده و به شناسایی 7 سطح مرزی مثبت و 9 سطح مرزی منفی منجر شده است. برخی از سطوح مرزی مثبت معرف مرزهای سکانسی و برخی از سطوح مرزی منفی نیز معرف مرزهای حداکثر پیش¬روی سطح آب دریا هستند. علاوه بر این، برخی از سطوح مرزی مثبت مرزهای زمانی اصلی (مرز آشکوبها) را مشخص می¬کنند. مقایسه زونهای پنج گانه مخزنی سازند آسماری در میدان قلعه نار با سطوح مرزی شناسایی شده حاکی از تطابق خوب برخی از زونهای مخزنی (به ویژه زونهای مخزنی 4 و 5 آسماری) با این سطوح است؛ اگرچه برخی دیگر انطباقی با سطوح مرزی نشان نمی¬دهند.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سازند آسماری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 زیست چینه نگاری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
ریزرخساره</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
چینه&amp;#172;نگاری سکانسی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 میدان نفتی قلعه نار</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 نرم افزار سیکلولاگ.</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13951111185514812-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>