﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2005</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative study between Rock-Eval pyrolysis and biomarkers parameters: A case study of Horn Valley  Siltstone source rock in central- Australia </ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>مقایسه ی پارامتر های پیرولیز راک –اول وبایو مارکر ها: مطالعه موردی سنگ منشا هورن والی سیلتستون، مرکز استرالیا </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مهدی</FirstName><LastName>شیری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سید رضا</FirstName><LastName>موسوی حرمی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد رضا</FirstName><LastName>رضائی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه کرتین استرالیا</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day></History><Abstract>In this study 44 Sedimentary rock samples from the Amadeus Basin, in southern portion of the Northern Territory, Australia, were analyzed by two well-proven organic geochemical methods: Rock-Eval (RE) pyrolysis and gas chromatography–mass spectrometry (GC–MS) analysis. These techniques were used to obtain independent parameters on organic matter composition, its thermal maturity, and environment of deposition. This study reveals a close concordance between Rock-Eval pyrolysis data and polycyclic biomarkers parameters such as steranes. 
RE pyrolysis in conjunction with GC–MS analysis show that the Amadeus Basin sediments contain a variable but notable organic-rich facies in the Horn Valley siltstone and prove an unequivocal evidence for Type-II organic matter, which lies dominantly to the peak stage of the conventional oil window (end of diagenesis-middle of catagenesis). The case study from the Amadeus Basin shows that these methods remain undoubtedly suitable for a good assessment of the petroleum potential of source rocks and rapid geochemical characterization of sedimentary organic matter, and can be used in other similar basins. 
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این مطالعه تعداد 44 نمونه از سنگ های رسوبی سازند هورن والی سیلتستون(Horn Valley Siltstone) از حوضه آمادئوس (Amadeus Basin) در مرکز استرالیا ،به وسیله ی دوروش شیمیائی ،پیرولیز راک-اول (R-E) وکروماتوگرافی گازی-اسپکترومتری جرمی (GC-MS) مورد تجزیه وتحلیل قرار گرفته اند .این روش ها برای بدست آوردن پارامتر های مستقل از ترکیبات مواد آلی مانند بلوغ حرار تی ومحیط رسوب گذاری استفاده می شوند.این مطالعه انطباق نزدیکی بین اطلاعات بدست آمده از پیرولیز راک –اول وبایو مارکر های (biomarkers) چند حلقه ای مانند هپان ها (hopanes) واسترن ها(steranes)را نشان می دهد .پیرولیزRE و GC-MS نشان می دهد که رسوبات حوضه آمادئوس حاوی رخساره های غنی از مواد آلی در تمام سازند هورن والی سیلتستون می باشد وگواه روشنی بر کروژن II است که در مرحله پنجره تولید نفت قرار گرفته است (اواخر دیاژنز-اواسط کاتاژنز). این پژوهش در حوضه آمادئوس ،نشان می دهد که این روش ها بدون شک جهت ارزیابی صحیح پتانسیل نفت زائی سنگهای منشا وتوصیف سریع ویزگی های ژئو شیمیائی رسوبات حاوی مواد آلی مناسب هستند ومی تواند در حوضه های مشابه نیز مورد استفاده قرار گیرد </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مواد آلی </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 پیرولیزRock-Eval</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 گاز کروماتو گرافی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
بایو مارکر</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
هورن والی سیلتستون</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
استرالیا </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13950129104811976-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>