﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>16</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biostratigraphy and microfacies of the Asmari Formation in north flank of Khami anticline (north of Gachsaran)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>زیست چینه‌نگاری و ریزرخساره‌های سازند آسماری در یال شمالی تاقدیس خامی (شمال گچساران)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>25</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>منا</FirstName><LastName>رحیم‌آبادی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>صیرفیان</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>حسین</FirstName><LastName>وزیری مقدم</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>فرزاد</FirstName><LastName>ستوهیان</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></History><Abstract>In the present study, biostratigraphy, microfacies and sedimentary environment of the Asmari Formation in north flank of the Khami anticline in the north of the Gachsaran province is investigated. The Asmari Formation at the study section with a thickness of 276 meters is a thin, medium and thick to massive limestone, nodular limestone, marl, marly limestone, dolomite and dolomitic limestone. In this study 166 thin sections are studied and 23 genera and 24 species of foraminifera have been identified and 3 biozones are introduced. 
1-	Archaias 	asmaricus-Archaias 	hensoni-Miogypsinoides 	complanatus 
Assemblage zone. (Chattian) 
2-	Indeterminate zone (Aqutanian) 
3-	Borelis melo curdica-Borelis melo melo Assemblage zone. (Burdigalian) 
Thus, the age of the Asmari Formation at the study area is Chattian to Burdigalian (Oligo-Miocene).
Based on study of thin sections and by considering the sediment texture, distribution of skeletal and non-skeletal grains, 12 microfacies are recognized which were deposited in open marine, bar, semi-restricted and restricted lagoon. Four platform types for the Asmari Formation at the study area in comparison with the recent studies on Asmari Formation including: 1-Rupelian-lower Chattian: Distally steepend ramp, 2-middle Chattian-upper Chattian: open shelf, 3-Aqiutanian: homoclinal ramp, 4-lower Burdigalian: carbonate platform.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این مطالعه زیست چینه‌نگاری، ریزرخساره‌ها و محیط رسوبی سازند آسماری در برش یال شمالی تاقدیس خامی در شمال شهرستان گچساران مورد مطالعه قرار گرفته‌است. سازند آسماری در این برش با 276 متر ضخامت دارای سنگ‌شناسی آهک نازک لایه، متوسط و ضخیم تا توده‌ای، آهک ندولار، مارن، آهک مارنی، دولومیت و آهک دولومیتی می‌باشد. با مطالعه 166 مقطع نازک میکروسکوپی، تعداد 23 جنس و 24 گونه شناسایی و براساس آن 3 زون زیستی برای سازند آسماری در این برش تعیین گردید که شامل زون‌های Archaias asmaricus-Archaias hensoni-Miogypsinoides complanatus Assemblage zone. Indeterminate zone. Borelis melo curdica-Borelis melo melo Assemblage zone.  می‌باشد. با توجه به زون‌های زیستی موجود سن سازند آسماری در این برش از شاتین تا بوردیگالین تعیین شده‌است. همچنین بر اساس مطالعات ریزرخساره‌ها 12 ریزرخساره شناسایی شد که در دریای باز، سد بیوکلاستی و لاگون نیمه محصور تا محصور ته نشست شده اند. چهار نوع پلاتفرم در این ناحیه در مقایسه  با سایر مطالعات اخیر صورت گرفته بر روی سازند آسماری شناسایی شد شامل: رمپ با انتهای شیب‌دار در زمان روپلین- شاتین زیرین، شلف باز در زمان شاتین میانی-بالایی، رمپ هموکلینال در زمان آکی‌تانین، پلتفرم کربناته در زمان بوردیگالین زیرین.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سازند آسماری تاقدیس خامی الیگوسن-میوسن ریزرخساره‌ها فرامینیفرهای کف‌زی بزرگ</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13970820165509-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>16</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evidence of transpressional tectonics in NW of central Iran sedimentary basins based on reflective data and geomorphic indices</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>شواهد زمین¬ساخت ترافشاری در حوضه¬های رسوبی شمال باختر ایران مرکزی بر اساس داده¬های لرزه¬نگاری بازتابی و شاخص¬های ژئومورفیک</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>26</FirstPage><LastPage>45</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محمد </FirstName><LastName>مختاری</LastName><Affiliation>مرکز پیش بینی زلزله</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سید احمد</FirstName><LastName>علوی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>لیلا</FirstName><LastName>مهشادنیا</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></History><Abstract>The depressed basins of northwest central Iran are located in the structural Step and between Soltanieh-Ipac-Koshk-e-Nosrat and Qom –Zefreh system (the Indes - Qom –Khurabad faults). The main process of deformation within the basin with extension and compression of specific structures are comparable and verifiable using experimental models. The extensional structures include roll-over folds and normal faults, resulting in deep sedimentary basins during deposition of the lower and upper red formations. The younger structures, includes back-thrusts and for-thrusts, shortcut, and pop up structures represents the reversal of tectonic of primary extensional basin. These sedimentary basins have been created in relation to the growth faults and hanging wall blocks So In the presence of roll-over fold and antithetic and synthetic faults therefore are suitable for entrapment of hydrocarbons during migration. The active structural features have been identified using combination of geomorphic characteristic and seismic reflection data. Accordingly, none of the old normal faults in the Saveh- Qom and Aran basin show at the present any extensional movement and the fault activity of boundary faults and extensional folding are compressional. The active parts are: hanging wall of Saveh, restraining bending at the end of Indes fault that has stream Length-Gradient (SL) index and high value hypsometric index (Hi). The central part of Saveh-Qom and Aran basin, although show high Hi but the SL is low. This situation is due to the moderating effects of the thick lower and upper red formations and evaporative layer within the basin. In the Aran basin due to incomplete coverage of seismic lines the absence of normal faults cannot be definitively confirmed. However, the center of Aran basin as of Qom-Saveh formed push up which marks the compression of this basin and also activity of reverse and thrust faults.  Based on the existing surface and subsurface data set, active deformation in this area now is transpression basin and the interior domains are in the uplift.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">حوضه¬های فروافتاده آران-سراجه بین گسل¬های کوشک نصرت و سامانه ایندس - قم –خورآباد- کاشان (گسل قم-زفره) قرار گرفته است. وجود ضخامت بالای رسوبات، شناسایی ساختارهای درون حوضه¬ای را دشوار ساخته است. برای شناسایی عناصر ساختاری فعال و سازوکار تشکیل این حوضه¬¬ها از تلفیق شاخص های ژئومورفیک و تفسیر خطوط لرزه ای بازتابی استفاده شد. شواهد موجود در خطوط لرزه ای مراحل اصلی دگرریختی درون حوضه ای، نشانگر حضور میدان تنش کششی محلی است. ساختارهای این مرحله شامل چین های کششی-چرخشی و گسلش نرمال است که در نتیجه آن حوضه های رسوبی عمیق و نهشته شدن سازندهای سرخ زیرین و بالایی است. با ادامه دگرریختی، وارونگی مثبت و فشاری جایگزین شده است. در این مطالعه فعالیت برخی از گسل های نرمال و مرزی و چین های کششی به صورت فشاری تایید گردید. ساختارهای جوانتر این مرحله شامل پس¬راندگی¬ها، پیش¬راندگی¬ها، ساختارهای میانبر  و ساختارهای بالاآمدگی  است که همگی نشان دهنده معکوس شدگی زمین ساختی حوضه ها¬ی کششی اولیه است. بخش های فعال فشاری حوضه بر اساس شاخص¬های ژئومورفیک، شامل فرادیواره راندگی ساوه و خم فشاری واقع در پایانه جنوب خاوری گسل ایندس است. همچنین فشردگی حوضه¬ها و فعالیت گسل¬های راندگی رشدی کف حوضه¬، سبب تشکیل ساختار¬های بالا رانشی  در مرکز هر سه حوضه شده است. دگرریختی در این حوضه¬ها در حال حاضر به صورت ترافشاری است.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">تکتونیک فعال</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 وارونگی مثبت</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 حوضه های کششی </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 شمال باختر ایران مرکزی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13971121177493-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>16</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biostratigraphy and microfacies of the Dariyan Formation in east of Gachsaran (Anneh anticline)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>زیست چینه‌نگاری و ریزرخساره‌های سازند‌ داریان در برش شرق گچساران (تاقدیس آنه)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>46</FirstPage><LastPage>65</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>سمانه </FirstName><LastName>سلیمانی احمدی </LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>حسین </FirstName><LastName>وزیری مقدم</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاهاصفهان </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>صیرفیان</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>طاهری </LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شاهرود </Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></History><Abstract>In this study, biostratigraphy, micofacies and sedimentary environment of Dariyan Formation in Anneh Anticline, near Hosein-Abad village (east of Gachsaran city) were investigated. 
Dariyan Formation at this study were consisted of 196 meters of thick, medium and thin layers of limestone, with orbitolinids, marl and marly limestone. The Daryian Formation is divided into the upper and lower parts, based on the existence of tongue with thin layer of limestone and laminated shale along with interlayer chert, with a large amount of radiolarids and planktonic foraminifera. In study area, Dariyan Formation conformably overlies the Gadvan Formation and is overlain by Kazhdumi Formation.
A total of 114 thin sections were extracted from the study area and 22 benthonic foraminifera and 3 planktonic foraminifera have been identified in 4 biozones and 1 subzone: Praeorbitolina cormyi zone, Palorbitolinoides cf. orbiculata subzone, Hedbergella spp. Assemblage zone, Mesorbitolina texana zone, Mesorbitolina gr. subconcava zone.
Based on identified zones in the study section, the age of Dariyan Formation is designated between Early Aptian to Albian.
Sedimentary environment study of Dariyan Formation in Anneh Anticline led to identification of 9 microfacies related to open marine and lagoon. Due to the lack of a barrier facies, slumping and storm deposits, lump and grapston, an open shelf sedimentary environment was suggested for deposition of the Dariyan Formation in Anneh anticline.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این پژوهش به مطالعه زیست چینه‌نگاری، محیط رسوبی و بررسی ریزرخساره‌های سازند داریان واقع در استان فارس (شرق شهرستان گچساران) در تاقدیس آنه پرداخته شده است. سازند داریان در ناحیه‌ی مورد مطالعه دارای 196 متر ضخامت و متشکل از سنگ ‌آهک‌های توده¬ای تا ضخیم لایه، گاها متوسط و نازک لایه با میان لایه‌های مارن و آهک مارنی و اربیتولین‌دار است. حضور زبانه‌ای متشکل از آهک‌های نازک لایه و شیلی متورق همراه با افق‌های چرت بین لایه‌ای و حاوی مقادیر زیادی رادیولر و فرامینیفر‌های پلانکتون، سبب تقسیم سازند داریان به دو بخش داریان پایینی  و بالایی در این برش شده است. در این منطقه سازند داریان به صورت تدریجی بر روی سازند گدوان و در زیر سازند کژدمی قرار گرفته است. پس از انجام مطالعات صحرایی تعداد 114 مقطع نازک میکروسکوپی از این توالی تهیه شد و تعداد 22 جنس از فرامینیفر‌های بنتیک و 3 جنس از فرامینیفر‌های پلانکتون در قالب 4 زون زیستی و یک زیر زون شامل Praeorbitolina cormyi zone -  Palorbitolinoides cf. orbiculata subzone - Hedbergella spp. assemblage zone - Mesorbitolina texana zone - Mesorbitolina gr. subconcava zone  می¬باشد. بر اساس زون‌های زیستی شناسایی شده در برش مورد مطالعه، سن سازند داریان در فاصله زمانی آپتین پیشین-آلبین تعیین شده است. بررسی محیط رسوبی سازند داریان در برش تاقدیس آنه، منجر به شناسایی تعداد 9 ریزرخساره مربوط به محیط دریای باز و لاگون شد. به علت عدم مشاهده‌ی رخساره¬های سدی، نبود رسوبات ریزشی و طوفانی، لومپ و گریپستون، محیط رسوبی شلف باز برای سازند داریان در برش تاقدیس آنه پیشنهاد شده است.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سازند داریان</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 تاقدیس آنه</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
زیست چینه‌نگاری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
آپتین</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 اربیتولین</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13981123215384-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>16</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Occurrence  of  heavy   crude  oil  in the  Persian  Gulf</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>علل پیدایش  نفت سنگین در خلیج فارس</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>66</FirstPage><LastPage>77</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>علیرضا </FirstName><LastName>بشری</LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی نفت ایران </Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></History><Abstract>Some of the most  prolific  petroleum  reservoirs with  high  gravities  of  oil  in the world  occured  in the Upper Jurassic  and Cretaceous  carbonate  formations  in the Persian Gulf area .Most  of the reservoirs are composed of pelletal,oolitic ,or bioclastic  grainstones and reefal  limestone that  have high primary  porosity and permeability .These reservoirs  are sealed  either  by tight limestone ,massive anhydrite, or  by impermeable rocks. The seals  are effective throughout  most of the Persian Gulf  and surrounding  areas, Accumulations of heavy oil  and natural  asphalts on the Iranian  side  of the Persian  Gulf extend NE to SW along  the Qatar  arch. some of the geological structures  which  are located  along this  trend contain  heavy oil  and natural  asphalts   within  post- Jurassic  formations. The major  geologic  factor  which  caused accumulations  of heavy  oil within  some geological  structures  is the Qatar  arch. As a result ,some differences  appear   in lithologic    units  in two sub-basins  northwest   and southeast of the Qatar  Arch. In  general , the  occurrence  of heavy  oil  in this  trend  can be  explained  as follows;

•	Fracturing  and  joints  within  formation ;
•	Reduction  of  thickness  of  post- Jurassic  sediments;
•	Facies change  of Arab  reservoirs, cap rock (Hith anhydrite), in some  structures  from anhydrite  to  dolomite  and also pinchout;

The absence of proper  environment  for the generation of high  gravity oil may also  be of importance .It should  be mentioned that "F" structure (Ferdows), with  huge  amount of oil in Ratawi  and Sulaiy  carbonate reservoirs(Lower Cretaceous), is one of the  largest heavy  oil fields along  this trend .The Farsi "B" structure, ( Farzad),  with  a thick Jahrum formation (Eocene) which  has excellent  reservoir  properties, is filled with  natural  asphalts. 
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">تعدادی از غنی ترین مخازن نفت سنگين و آسفالت طبيعي در بخش ايراني خليج فارس در جهت NW-SE  شبه جزيره قطر و حواشی ان  رخداده است. اغلب ساختمانهاي زمين شناسي كه در مسير کمان قطر قرار گرفته‌اند دارای  نفت سنگين و آسفالت طبيعي در طبقات پسا ژوراسيك ان است . يكي از فاكتورهاي اصلي زمين شناسي كه باعث تجمع نفت سنگين در ميان تعدادی  از ساختمانهاي زمين شناسي اين منطقه تاثیر گذار بوده عامل بالا زدگی کمان قطر را میتوان نام برد. این رخداد،باعث ايجاد تفاوتهائي بنیادی  در واحدهاي زمين شناسي در بخش  شمال شرق و جنوب غرب کمان قطر ( بالا زدگی قطر)  گرديده است.
بالازدگي باعث تقسيم ژئوسنكلينال خليج فارس بر دو بخش گرديده است. ليكن اين دو بخش همواره از دیدگاه رسوب گذاري يك حوضه مرتبط بحساب مي آيد. فعاليت كوهزائي هيماليا " آلپ " در پايان ميوسن ـ پليوسن  تداوم بخش این رخداده است. در اين زمان چين خوردگي زاگرس بدون شك در شتاب بخشيدن به رشد بعضي از ساختمانهاي زمين شناسي اين ناحيه  بسیار موثر بوده است. از طرفي ساختمانهاي زمين شناسي واقع در شبه جزيره عربستان و بخش عربي خليج فارس ظاهرا" كمتر دستخوش اين حركات كوهزائي قرار گرفته است.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">خلیج فارس</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
نفت سنگین</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
کمان قطر</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
درز وشکاف</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
شکشتگی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
میادین فرزاد </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
فردوس وهامون </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13980903193615-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>16</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Estimation of oil production, restoration of burial history and thermal maturity using Pyrolysis Rock-Eval data and Arrhenius model in one of the wells of Parsi oilfield</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ارزیابی زایش نفت، بازسازي تاریخچه تدفین و بلوغ حرارتی  با استفاده از داده هاي پیرولیز راك ایول و مدل آرنیوس در یکی از چاههای میدان نفتی پارسی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>104</FirstPage><LastPage>115</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>بیژن</FirstName><LastName>ملکی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام خمینی(ه)</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>ابوذر</FirstName><LastName>بازوندی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام خمینی(ه)</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سعیده</FirstName><LastName>سنماری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام خمینی(ه)</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>پرویز</FirstName><LastName>آرمانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام خمینی(ه)</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day></History><Abstract>Investigating potential source rocks in oilfields is important. In this study, in addition to evaluating the hydrocarbon potential, the Arrhenius kinetic model was used to more accurately assess the source rock maturity status as well as the percentage of oil generation in the Parsi oilfield. In the Arrhenius model, the rate of kerogen decomposition is very important. In this research, some source rocks that have been tested by thermal pyrolysis were kinetically analyzed and the source rock conversion ratio (TR) was determined. Based on the results of burial history and thermal modeling, it was found that Kazhdumi and Pabdeh formations were in the oil window well while Gurpi formation did not enter the oil window due to poor organic matter content (TR = 0). Therefore, among the Kazhdomi, Gurpi and Pabdeh formations in the Parsi oilfield, Kazhdumi formation is considered as the main and most effective source rock of this oilfield with high TTI and TR = 100.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">بررسی سنگ‌های منشا احتمالی در میدان های نفتی اهمیت زیادی دارد. در این تحقیق، علاوه بر ارزیابي پتانسیل هیدروکربني، از مدل سینتیکی آرنیوس، برای ارزیابی دقیق تر وضعیت بلوغ سنگ منشاء و همچنین درصد زایش نفت در میدان نفتی پارسی استفاده شد. در مدل آرنیوس، دمای آهنگ تجزیه‌ کروژن از اهمیت زیادی برخوردار است. در این تحقیق برخی از سنگ های منشاء¬ که آزمایش پیرولیز حرارتی بر روی آن‌ها صورت گرفته است از جنبه سینتیکی مورد تجزیه ‌و تحلیل قرار گرفته و نسبت تبدیل سنگ منشاء (TR) تعیین گردید. بر اساس نتایج بدست آمده از بازسازی تاریخچه تدفین و مدل‌سازی حرارتی، مشخص شد که سازندهای کژدمی و پابده در چاه موردنظروارد پنجره نفتی گردیده در حالیکه سازند گورپی بعلت مواد آلی ناچیز وارد پنجره نفت زایی نشده است (TR =0). بنابراین از ميان سازندهاي کژدمی، گورپی و پابده در ميدان نفتی پارسی، سازند کژدمی به عنوان اصلی ترين و موثرترين سنگ منشأ اين ميدان نفتی معرفی می شود که دارای   TR =100و  TTI بالایی میباشد. 
 
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">ارزیابی سینتیکی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
سنگ منشاء</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدل آرنیوس</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تاریخچه تدفین</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
میدان نفتی پارسی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13980327190181-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>