﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2009</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biostratigraphy and sedimentary environment of Asmari Formation in Davan section, North of Kazerun</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>زیست¬چینه¬نگاری و  محیط رسوبی سازند آسماری در برش روستای دوان، شمال کازرون</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مسعود</FirstName><LastName>خوشنود</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>حسین </FirstName><LastName>وزیری مقدم</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاهاصفهان </Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day></History><Abstract>This research concentrates on biostratigraphy, microfasies and Sedimentary environment of the Asmari Formation at Davan village in 10 Km north of Kazerun. Micropalaeontological study led to recognition of 25 genera and 15 species of foraminifera. Based on biostratigraphic study 3 biozones (1-Nummulites vascus – Nummulites fichteli assemblage zone, 2 -Lepdocyclina-Operculina- Ditrupa Assemblage Zone, 3- Archaias asmaricus- Archaias hensoni- Miogypsinoides complanatus Assemblage Zone) are determined. As a result, the age of the Asmari Formation is Oligocene (Rupelian – Chattian) at the study area. Depositional texture, petrographic analyses and fauna led to identification of 9 carbonate microfacies related to open marine, slope, bar and lagoon. These depositional environments correspond to inner, middle, and outer ramp.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این پژوهش زیست چینه نگاری،  ریزرخساره ها و محیط رسوبی سازند آسماری در برش روستای دوان در 10 کیلومتری شمال کازرون مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. بر اساس مطالعات انجام شده 25 جنس و 15 گونه از روزن‌داران در سازند آسماری شناسایی شده و بر اساس آن¬ها 3 زون زیستی تجمعی برای این سازند (Nummulites vascus – Nummulites fichteli assemblage zone)، (Lepdocyclina-Operculina- Ditrupa Assemblage Zone) و (Archaias asmaricus- Archaias hensoni- Miogypsinoides complanatus Assemblage Zone) معرفی گردید. بر این اساس سن سازند آسماری در برش مورد مطالعه الیگوسن (روپلین-شاتین) تعیین شد. مطالعات پتروگرافی و آنالیز رخساره¬ای حاکی از آن است که کربنات¬های سازند آسماری متشکل از 9 ریزرخساره در قالب چهار کمربند رخساره¬ای دریای باز، سد، تالاب و پهنه¬جزرومدی است. با توجه به پخش و پراکندگی روزنداران، تغییرات تدریجی ریزرخساره ها و عدم حضور سد محصور کننده گسترش یافته محیط رسوبی این سازند رمپ هموکلینال تشخیص داده شد که شامل سه قسمت رمپ درونی، رمپ میانی و رمپ بیرونی می باشد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سازند آسماری،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 ریز رخساره ها،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 رمپ هموکلینال،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 پالئو اکولوژی ،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 روزنداران بنتیک</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/139601142242595488-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>