﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>34</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2009</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Modeling Mud Loss in Asmari Formation Using Geostatistics in RMS Software Environment in an Oil Field in Southwestern Iran</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>مدلسازی هرزروی گل حفاری در سازند آسماری با استفاده از روش زمين آمار در محيط نرم افزار RMS در يکی از ميادين نفتی جنوب غربی ايران</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>کیومرث</FirstName><LastName>طاهری</LastName><Affiliation>مهندسی معدن و متالورژی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>فرهاد</FirstName><LastName>محمد تراب</LastName><Affiliation>دانشکده مهندسی معدن و متالورژی</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></History><Abstract>Studying lost circulation in Asmari formation is very important because about 25% to 40% of drilling costs is allocated to drilling mud expenses. Considering that Studied oil field encounters severe mud loss in Asmari formation, therefore the purpose of this study is recognition of the lost circulation zones and illustrating the mud loss distribution in Asmari formation. The mud loss maps in Asmari field were plotted in RMS software using moving average algorithm method. For this purpose, the data of 363 wells in this oil field was processed after data preparation, for mapping and 3D modeling of 11 different zones in Asmari formation. The data processing includes different stages such as elimination of outliers, normal transformation, drawing the histogram, variography and estimation and modeling. In this research, the geostatistical kriging method was also used for estimation and 3D modeling of mud loss in Asmari formation so that the output of geostatistical modeling method shows the localized and better results. Consequently, by applying and analysis of results, the 2D and 3D models of mud loss in Asmari formation were demonstrated. By simulation and modeling of mud loss and its comparison with reservoir fault modeling and production indexes plots, it was identified that the dominant mud losses are related to fault zone fractures and in minor cases the increasing of mud weight is the reason of mud loss. Applying appropriate operations such as under balance drilling (UBD) and suitable well placement, use of drilling mud with proper mud weight in severe mud loss points, use of NIF and MMH especial drilling muds with lowest formation damage, or a combination of these methods are suggested for mud loss control in critical points of the oil field.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">مطالعه هرزروی در سازند آسماری از اهمیت ویژه ای برخوردار است زیرا حدود 25 ٪ تا 40٪ از هزينه هاي حفاري را هزينه سيال حفاري به خود اختصاص می دهد. با توجه به اینکه میدان مورد مطالعه با مشکل هرزروی های شدید در سازند آسماری مواجه است لذا هدف از انجام این مطالعه شناسایی مناطق دارای هرزروی و نمایش توزیع هرزروی در مخزن آسماری می باشد. ابتدا با مدلسازی مخزن در نرم افزار RMS  و بکارگیری الگوریتم میانگین متحرک اقدام به رسم نقشه های هرزروی در مخزن آسماری شد. بدین منظور داده های مربوط به 363 حلقه چاه در این میدان پس از آماده سازی بصورت رقومی در آمده و جهت آماده سازي داده ها براي تهيه نقشه ها و مدل های سه بعدی یازده زون مختلف در مخزن آسماری، مراحل مختلفي همچون حذف داده هاي پرت، نرمال سازی داده ها، رسم هیستوگرام و واریوگرافی داده ها و عملیات تخمین و مدلسازی انجام شده است. در اين مطالعه همچنین از روش  زمین آماری تخمین کریجینگ برای مدلسازی سه بعدی هرزروی مخزن آسماری در میدان نفتی مورد مطالعه، استفاده شده است که خروجی مدلسازی های انجام شده در روش زمین آماری تخمین کریجینگ متمرکزتر و نتایج بهتری بدست داده است. سپس با تجزیه و تحلیل اطلاعات، نقشه مدل های دو بعدی و سه بعدی هرزروی گل حفاری در سازند آسماری ارائه شده است. با شبیه سازی و مدلسازی هرزروی و تطبیق آن با مدل های گسلی مخزن و نمودارهای شاخص تولید مشخص شد که عمده هرزروی های موجود ناشی از شکستگی های گسلی بوده و تنها در موارد اندکی بالا بودن وزن گل موجب هرزروی شده است. بکارگیری روش های عملیاتی مناسب مانند مکان یابی مناسب چاه های جدید با بهره گیری از نقشه های هرزروی ارائه شده و به کارگیری روش های حفاری فروتعادلی و استفاده از سیال حفاری با وزن مخصوص و ترکیب مناسب مانند سیالات حفاریNIF  و MMH در نقاط با هرزروی شدید و یا ترکیبی از این روش ها جهت کنترل هرزروی در نقاط بحرانی مخزن پیشنهاد می گردد. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">هرزروي سيال حفاري</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
پيش بينی هرزروی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدلسازی زمين آماری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
نرم افزارRMS </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/139508011610453694-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>