﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2010</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reconstruction of sedimentary environment, and depositional sequences based on Microfacies of the Qom Formation in the Kahak area (Southwest of Qom city)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بازسازی شرایط محیط رسوبی دیرینه و شناسایی سکانس های رسوبی موجود در سازند قم براساس میکروفاسیس¬ها در ناحیه کهک (جنوب غرب قم)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>32</FirstPage><LastPage>48</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مهدیه </FirstName><LastName>مهیاد</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>حسین </FirstName><LastName>وزیری مقدم</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاهاصفهان </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی </FirstName><LastName>صیرفیان</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day></History><Abstract>In this study, sedimentary environment and depositional sequences were reconstructed based on distribution of microfacies in the sequence belong to the Qom Formation in the Kahak area. The formation was formed alternation of shale and limestone. The boundary between the Qom Formation and the volcanic rocks is unconformable. In addition, the Upper Red Formation in the Kahak area unconformably overlies the Qom Formation. In the study area, 6 microfacies, and 1 terrigenous facies (shale) for the Qom Formation were identified by study of these rock samples. The Qom Formation was deposited in an open-shelf carbonate platform in the study area. This platform can be divided into two environments that the environments consist of the inner shelf (restricted lagoon and semi-restricted lagoon) and middle shelf. Finally, two third-order sequences were identified based on distribution of microfacies in the Kahak area.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این تحقیق، یک توالی از سازند قم در ناحیه کهک به منظور بازسازی محیط رسوبی و سکانس¬های رسوبی براساس توزیع میکروفاسیسس¬ها انتخاب گردید. این سازند به طور کلی از تناوب شیل و آهک تشکیل شده و با ناپیوستگی بر روی سنگهای آتشفشانی ائوسن قرار گرفته و مرز بالایی آن با سازند سرخ بالایی به صورت ناپیوسته است. مطالعه نمونه¬های برداشت شده از ناحیه کهک منجر به شناسایی 6 میکروفاسیس کربناته و یک فاسیس آواری (شیل) برای سازند قم شد. در این ناحیه سازند قم در یک پلت فرم کربناته از نوع شلف باز نهشته شده¬است. این پلت فرم کربناته را می¬توان به دو محیط شلف داخلی (لاگون محصور و نیمه محصور) و شلف میانی تقسیم کرد. در نهایت براساس توزیع میکروفاسیس¬ها دو سکانس رسوبی در ناحیه مورد مطالعه تشخیص داده شد. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">میکروفاسیس</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 سکانس های رسوبی </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 سازند قم</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 ناحیه کهک</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13980215179111-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>