﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Structural Modeling and Estimation of Tectonic Stresses at Lali Oilfield in Dezful Embayment</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>مدل سازی ساختاری و برآورد تنش‎های تکتونیکی میدان نفتی لالی در فروافتادگی دزفول </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>نسرین</FirstName><LastName>کیانی زاده</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تبریز</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>بهزاد </FirstName><LastName>زمانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تبریز</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>رحیم </FirstName><LastName>کدخدائی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تبریز</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>حسین </FirstName><LastName>طالبی</LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی نفت ایران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day></History><Abstract>
 Structural geological study is one of the most important stages of an oilfield exploration and production (E&amp;P) program, since a knowledge of existing structures can play a fundamental role in the oilfield development plan. The main purpose of this study is to create three-dimensional (3D) structural models to determine direction of tectonic stresses at Lali oilfield using subsurface geophysical data. The study area is located within the so-called Dezful Embayment (northern Khuzestan Province, Iran). Accordingly, in order to provide a 3D model of the reservoir, geostatistical tools in Petrel Software were utilized. Incorporating density log data into several coded formulations in MS Excel Software, the reservoir had its modulus of elasticity calculated. Subsequently, maximum and minimum horizontal stresses were calculated using poroelastic equations. 
Fault modeling results showed that, fault dip increases with increasing the depth towards the center of the field. Obtained values of stress using the poroelastic equations show that σ_H&gt;σ_h&gt;σ_v, confirming a regional reverse stress regime, which is consistent with previous studies in this area. Also, the formal stress ratios (Φ = (σ2-σ3) / (σ1-σ3)) obtained from poroelastic equations and inverse analysis method were found to be well-correlated across the area. Finally, average azimuth of the reverse faults on the southern limb (as calculated by Petrel) and the fractures on the limb (as obtained from FMI images and core samples) were found to be N305 and N315, respectively (average = N310). Thus, N040E was inferred to be the average direction of principal stress, i.e. principal stress is mostly directed along a NE-SW axis (perpendicular to the general trend of Zagros Orogeny); this is probably a result of the activities of youngest Zagros orogeny phase. The agreement between the obtained principal stress directions by fractures, faults, and focal mechanism of earthquakes across the World Stress Map (WSM) confirms the validity of this study.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">مطالعات زمین¬شناسی ساختاری از مهمترین مراحل اکتشاف و بهره¬برداری از میادین نفتی می¬باشد چرا که آشنایی با ساختارهای موجود می¬تواند نقش اساسی در توسعه¬ی میدان نفتی داشته باشد. هدف اصلی این مطالعه ایجاد یک مدل سه  بعدی ساختاری و آگاهی از جهت تنش‎های تکتونیکی با استفاده ازداده¬های ژئوفیزیکی زیرسطحی میدان نفتی لالی است. منطقه مورد مطالعه در جنوب غرب ایران و در استان خوزستان واقع شده است. جهت تهیه مدل سه بعدی مخزن، روش زمین‎آمار در قالب نرم‎افزار پترل به کار گرفته شده است. از طریق داده های لاگ چگالی و با استفاده از فرمول‎نویسی در نرم افزار اکسل، ضرایب الاستیک مخزن محاسبه و سپس با استفاده از روابط پروالاستیک، حداکثر و حداقل تنش افقی محاسبه شدند.  
نتایج مدل‎سازی گسل‎ها نشان می‎دهد که با افزایش عمق و به سمت مرکز میدان مقدار شیب گسل افزایش می‎یابد. مقدار تنش‎هایی بدست آمده با روابط پروالاستیک نشان می‎دهد &gt;σ_h&gt;σ_v  σ_Hکه تایید کننده سیستم تنش معکوس در منطقه است و با مطالعات قبلی در این منطقه همخوانی دارد. همچنین مقدار نسبت شکلی تنش Φ=(σ2-σ3) / (σ1-σ3)، که از روابط پرو الاستیک به‎دست آمده و مقدار نسبت شکلی تنش که با روش تحلیل وارون بدست آمده، انطباق خوبی در این ناحیه با هم نشان می‎دهد. نهایتا میانگین آزیموت گسل‎های معکوس یال جنوبی مدل شده با نرم افزار پترل و شکستگی‎های بدست آمده از تصاویر FMI و مغزه ها، N305 و N315(میانگین N310) می‎باشد بنابراین میانگین جهت حداکثر تنش، N40E استنباط شده و در نتیجه حداکثر تنش عمدتا در جهت NE-SW یعنی عمود بر امتداد عمومی کوهزاد زاگرس بوده که احتمالا حاصل عملکرد جوان‎ترین فاز کوهزایی زاگرس می‎باشد. تطابق بین جهت حداکثر تنش بدست آمده از شکستگی‎ها و گسل ها و مکانیزم کانونی زمین‎لرزه در پایگاه نقشه جهانی تنش(WSM)، اعتبار این تحقیق را تایید می‎کند.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مدل‎سازی گسل</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 پترل</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
جهت یابی تنش</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 شکستگی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
  لاگ چگالی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 میدان نفتی لالی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 روابط پروالاستیک‎</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/139601301116295697-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biostratigraphy, microfacies and sequence stratigraphy of the Asmari Formation (based on Cyclolog) in the Qaleh Nar Oli field, Zagros Basin</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>زیست چینه نگاری، بررسی ریزرخساره¬ها و چینه نگاری سکانسی سازند آسماری (به کمک نرم افزار سیکلولاگ) در میدان نفتی قلعه نار، حوضه زاگرس </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>عباس </FirstName><LastName>قادری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>عادل</FirstName><LastName>نیسی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>غبیشاوی</LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی نفت ایران </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد</FirstName><LastName>اله کرم پوردیل</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان - شرکت ملی مناطق نفت خیز جنوب</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></History><Abstract>In this research, biostratigraphy, microfacies, sedimentary environments and sequence stratigraphy (using by Cyclolog software) of the Asmari Formation are carried out. These studies are done on the basis of 580 samples (core and cutting) from 430 meters thickness of the formation from the well #2 of the Qaleh-Nar oilfield. Paleontological studies are led to identification of 23 genera and 28 species of the benthic and planktonic foraminifera. According to these microfossils, four assemblage zones have been recognized which confirm the age of Oligocene (Rupelian – Chattian) and Early Miocene (Aquitanian – Burdigalian) for the whole formation. Paleoenvironmental studies demonstrate 9 different microfacies that were deposited in the outer ramp (open marine) in the lower Asmari part, middle ramp (open marine to shoal) in the middle Asmari part and the inner ramp environment (tidal flat to lagoon) in the upper Asmari part. The sequence stratigraphy on the well #2 and the auxiliary well numbers 1, 3, 5, 6 and 7 of the Qaleh-Nar oilfield using by Cyclolog software reveals 7 positive breaks and 9 negative break levels alternatively. Some of the positive breaks define sequence boundaries and some of the negative breaks present the maximum flooding surfaces. In addition, a number of positive levels specify the major chronozone (stage boundaries). Comparison of the quintuple reservoir zones of the Asmari Formation in the Qaleh-Nar oilfield with the mentioned break levels suggests a fine correlation with these levels; however this correlation is invalid for other levels.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این پژوهش، زیست چینه نگاری، ریزرخساره¬ها، محیط رسوبی و چینه نگاری سکانسی سازند آسماری (با استفاده از نرم¬افزار سیکلولاگ) با تکیه بر مطالعه 580 مقطع نازک (شامل مغزه و خرده¬های حفاری) تهیه شده از 430 متر توالیهای برش تحت الارضی چاه شماره 2 میدان نفتی قلعه نار انجام شده است. مطالعات فسیل¬شناسی انجام شده به شناسایی 23 جنس و 28 گونه از روزن¬داران کف¬زی و پلانکتون منجر گردید.
بر این اساس، چهار بایوزون تجمعی شناسایی و سن سازند آسماری الیگوسن (روپلین ـ شاتین) و میوسن پیشین (آکیتانین ـ بوردیگالین) در نظر گرفته شد. مطالعه ریز¬رخساره¬های رسوبی به شناسایی 9 ریزرخسـاره انجامیده است که بیانــگر رسوب¬گذاری در سه محیط رمپ خارجی (دریای باز) در بخش آسماری زیرین و رمپ میانی (شول و دریای باز) اغلب در آسماری میانی و رمپ داخلی (بالای پهنه جزر و مدی، پهنه جزر و مدی و لاگون) بیشتر در بخش آسماری بالایی هستند. مطالعات چینه¬نگاری سکانسی در چاه شماره 2 و چاه¬های کمکی 1، 3، 5، 6 و 7 میدان نفتـی قلعه نار با استفاده از نرم افزار سیکلولاگ انجام شده و به شناسایی 7 سطح مرزی مثبت و 9 سطح مرزی منفی منجر شده است. برخی از سطوح مرزی مثبت معرف مرزهای سکانسی و برخی از سطوح مرزی منفی نیز معرف مرزهای حداکثر پیش¬روی سطح آب دریا هستند. علاوه بر این، برخی از سطوح مرزی مثبت مرزهای زمانی اصلی (مرز آشکوبها) را مشخص می¬کنند. مقایسه زونهای پنج گانه مخزنی سازند آسماری در میدان قلعه نار با سطوح مرزی شناسایی شده حاکی از تطابق خوب برخی از زونهای مخزنی (به ویژه زونهای مخزنی 4 و 5 آسماری) با این سطوح است؛ اگرچه برخی دیگر انطباقی با سطوح مرزی نشان نمی¬دهند.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سازند آسماری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 زیست چینه نگاری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
ریزرخساره</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
چینه&amp;#172;نگاری سکانسی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 میدان نفتی قلعه نار</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 نرم افزار سیکلولاگ.</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13951111185514812-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Analysis of Electrical Rock Type Bangestan Reservoir in Marun Oil Field</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تجزیه و تحلیل گونه های سنگی الکتریکی مخزن بنگستان در میدان نفتی مارون</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>ابوذر</FirstName><LastName>محسنی پور</LastName><Affiliation>علوم زمین</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>بهمن </FirstName><LastName>سلیمانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شهیدچمران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>احسان</FirstName><LastName>ابهرک پور</LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی حفاری</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>قدرت الله </FirstName><LastName>نیکخواه</LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی حفاری</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></History><Abstract>Studies of the electrical Rock Type a very important role in the development process plays a field.In these studies, theporo-perm  Cores data and well log data used for reservoir simulations. In the present research, the flow of four flow units was determined in the reservoir using porosity and permeability data from well logging core by regional index method. In some wells, using well logging the basic model of electrical rocktype was determined with three methods of MRGC, SOM, and DYNAMIC. The determined facies by different methods were correlated with the flow unit. Finally, SOM method was selected, which has the best concordance. The initially created electrofacieswere reduced to 4 electrofacies due to the similarity of some parameters such as effective porosity and gamma logging. To ensure the accuracy of the electrical rock type by neural networks, these electrofacies were correlated with capillary pressure data. After confirming the determined electrofacies by capillary pressure, these facies were propagated in other wells in this field. This created a model, which was able to separate different parts of the reservoir. In this model, different parts of the reservoir were determined in terms of reservoir quality.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">مطالعات مربوط به گونه¬های سنگی الکتریکی نقش بسیار مهمی را در فرایند توسعه یک میدان ایفا می¬کند. در این مطالعات از داده های  تخلخل-تراوایی مغزه و لاگ های چاهپیمایی جهت شبیه سازی مخزن استفاده می شود. در پژوهش حاضر در ابتدا با استفاده از داده های تخلخل و تراوایی حاصل از مغزه چاه پیمایی به روش شاخص منطقه ای جریان چهار واحد جریانی برای این مخزن تعیین گردید. در تعدادی از چاههای میدان با استفاده از لاگ¬های چاهپیمایی مدل اولیه گونه سنگی الکتریکی به سه روش SOM ، MRGC و  DYNAMICتعیین گردید، رخساره های تعیین شده با روشهای مختلف با واحد جریانی تعیین شده تطابق داده و از بین آنها روش SOM که دارای بیشترین تطابق بود انتخاب گردید،از بین 9 الکتروفاسیس اولیه ایجاد شده با توجه به شباهت برخی از پارامترها مانند  تخلخل موثر و لاگ گاما به 4 الکتروفاسیس تقلیل داده شد، جهت اطمینان از دقت تعئین گونه سنگی الکتریکی توسط شبکه های عصبی، این الکتروفاسیس ها با داده های فشار موئینه تطابق داده و پس از تائید الکتروفاسیس¬های تعیین شده با فشار موئینه این رخساره ها در سایر چاههای میدان انتشار داده شد که منجر به ایجاد مدلی گردید که توانایی جدایش بخش های مختلف مخزنی را از همدیگر دارا بود. در این مدل قسمت های مختلف مخزن از نظرکیفیت مخزنی تعیین گردید.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">گونه&amp;#172;سنگی الکتریکی، واحد&amp;#172;جریانی، مخزن بنگستان، کیفیت مخزنی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13951016205254492-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Genetic classification of the Persian Gulf Eastern part oil fields by infrared spectroscopy of asphaltene samples</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>طبقه بندی ژنتیکی نفت‌های میادین شرق خلیج فارس با استفاده از طیف سنجی مادون قرمز نمونه‌های آسفالتین</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مرتضی</FirstName><LastName>طاهری نژاد</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مرتضی</FirstName><LastName>آسمانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>احمدرضا</FirstName><LastName>ربانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day></History><Abstract>Asphaltene is always considered as a problem in oil industry. But, asphaltenes are desirable compounds in geochemical studies specially in oil-oil correlation. Oil-oil correlation is one of the most important issues in geochemical studies that enables to classify oils genetically. Asphaltenes due to their structural similarity with kerogen and unaffected and/or little affected from secondary processes are known as valuable compounds in geochemical studies. So, in this paper the structural characteristics of asphaltenes were considered as a correlation parameter. For this study 5 oil samples were collected from the Persian Gulf eastern part oil fields. Structural characteristics of these asphaltenes were investigated by Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy. 2D and 3D graphs based on aliphatic and aromatic compounds (predominant compounds in asphaltenes structure) and sulfoxide and carbonyl functional groups (which are represent of sulfur and oxygen abundance in asphaltenes) were used for comparison of asphaltenes structure in different samples. According to the results of these defined graphs, the studied oil samples comprise two oil families with distinct genetic characteristics. The first oil family consists of the Salman and Reshadat oil samples, and the second oil family consists of the Resalat, Siri E and Siri D oil samples. To validation and complement the obtained results, the other common geochemical techniques such as stable carbon isotope and biomarkers parameters, were employed and these techniques completely confirmed previous results. According to biomarker parameters, the first oil family originated from marl source rock and the second oil family was sourced from carbonate source rock.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">آسفالتین موجود در نفت خام همواره به عنوان یک مشکل در صنعت نفت مطرح است، اما آسفالتین¬ها از ترکیبات مطلوب در مطالعات ژئوشیمیایی خصوصا تطابق نفت- نفت هستند. یکی از موضوعات مهم در مطالعات ژئوشیمیایی، تطابق نفت- نفت می¬باشد که این امکان را فراهم می‌آورد که نفت¬ها از نظر ژنتیکی طبقه بندی شوند. آسفالتین¬ها بدلیل شباهت ساختاری به کروژن و همچنین عدم تاثیر یا تاثیر کم از فرآیندهای ثانویه به عنوان ترکیبی ارزشمند در مباحث ژئوشیمیایی مطرح می‌باشند. لذا در این مقاله از ویژگی¬های ساختاری آسفالتین به عنوان پارامتر تطابق بهره گرفته شد. در این مقاله ویژگی‌های ساختاری آسفالتین 5 نمونه نفت از میادین شرقی خلیج فارس با استفاده از روش طیف سنجی مادون قرمز مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. از نمودارهای دوبعدی و سه بعدی تعریف شده براساس ترکیبات آلیفاتیک و آروماتیک (ترکیبات غالب در ساختار آسفالتین¬ها) و گروه¬های سولفوکسید و کربونیل (بیانگر فراوانی عناصر گوگرد و اکسیژن در آسفالتین¬ها) به منظور مقایسه ساختار آسفالتین¬ها در نمونه¬های مختلف مورد استفاده قرار گرفت. براساس نتایج حاصله از نمودارهای تعریف شده، نمونه¬های نفتی مورد مطالعه دو خانواده با خصوصیات ژنتیکی متفاوت را تشکیل می‌دهند. خانواده اول شامل نفت‌ میدان‌های سلمان و رشادت و خانواده دوم شامل نفت‌ میدان‌های رسالت، سیری E و سیری D می‌باشد. به منظور تایید نتایج حاصل از روش طیف سنجی مادون قرمز، از سایر روش-های متداول ژئوشیمیایی مانند پارامترهای بایومارکری و داده¬های ایزوتوپ استفاده گردید که این روش¬ها نتایج بدست آمده را کاملا تایید نمودند. براساس پارامترهای بایومارکری خانواده اول دارای سنگ منشا مارنی بوده و خانواده دوم از سنگ منشا کربناته تولید شده¬ است. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">آسفالتین</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
طیف سنجی مادون قرمز</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تطابق نفت- نفت</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
خلیج فارس</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
ایران</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/139603051212406136-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Origin of seeping hydrocarbon gases from onshore mud volcanoes in Makran coast of Iran</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>منشا گازهای هیدروکربوری گل¬فشان¬های خشکی سواحل مکران ایران</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مهین</FirstName><LastName>فرهادیان بابادی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه خوارزمی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>بهزاد </FirstName><LastName>مهرابی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه خوارزمی</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>آدریانو </FirstName><LastName>مازینی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه  نروژ</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>الینا</FirstName><LastName>پلودتکینا</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه ایالتی مسکو</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>عطا</FirstName><LastName>شاکری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه خوارزمی</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day></History><Abstract>Mud volcanoes are geological structures formed as a result of gas emission, mud-fluid mixing and variably sized rock fragments in onshore and offshore settings. These structures are different morphologically which considered as significant marker of modern crustal movement and neotectonic activity. Occurrence of numerous mud volcanoes on the Makran accretionary prisms in Iran and Pakistan are reported which caused by the convergence of the Arabian and the Eurasian plates.
In this study, origin of discharged hydrocarbon gases from three active onshore mud volcanoes; Ain, Borborok and Sand Mirsuban in Makran coasts of Iran were examined. The released gases of all these mud volcanoes are dominantly methane with concentration between 97.24-99.18 vol. % and minor amount of ethane (0.04-1.2 vol.%), propane (0.001-0.194 vol.%), n-butane (226 ppmvol.%), iso-butane (5-363 ppmvol.%), n-pentane (37ppmvol.%), iso-pentane (1-66 ppmvol.%), hexane (1-78 ppmvol.%) and CO2 (0.07-0.4 vol.%). Carbon and hydrogen isotope ratio of methane and its heavier derivatives indicate thermogenic source for emitted gases of all investigated mud volcanoes and evidences of the absence of biodegradation. CO2 with carbon isotope ratio of -11.1 to -14.3‰ is organic in origin. Our research suggests the presence of hydrocarbon system and active source rock in Makran active tectonic area. Although the occurrence of an exploitable gas reservoir in this area has to be confirmed by geophysical measurements, geological survey and structural settings.   
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">گل¬فشان¬ها، ساختارهای زمین¬شناسی ناشی از خروج گاز، گلآب و خرده¬های سنگی با ابعاد مختلف در مناطق خشکی و ساحلی با مرفولوژی¬های متفاوت و نشانگر حرکت پوسته¬ای و فعالیت تکتونیکی امروزی هستند. گل¬فشان¬های زیادی در منشورهای برافزایشی مکران ایران و پاکستان گزارش شده¬است که به دلیل برخورد صفحات هند و اوراسیا تشکیل می¬شوند. در این مطالعه، منشا گازهای هیدروکربوری گسیل¬شده از سه گل¬فشان فعال عین، بربروک و سندمیرسوبان در سواحل خشکی مکران ایران بررسی شده¬است. گازهای خارج شده از این گل¬فشان¬ها عمدتا متان با غلظت بین vol.% ۱۸/۹۹-۲۴/۹۷ و مقدار کمی اتان (vol.% ۲/۱-۰۴۸/۰)، پروپان (vol.% ۱۹۴/۰-۰۰۱/۰)، ان-بوتان (ppmvol.% ۲۲-)، ایزوبوتان(ppmvol.% ۳۶۳-۵)، ان-پنتان (ppmvol.% ۳۷)، ایزوپنتان (ppmvol.% ۶۶-۱)، هگزان (ppmvol.% ۷۸-۱) و دی اکسیدکربن (vol.% ۴/۰-۰۷/۰) هستند. مقادیر نسبت ایزوتوپی کربن و هیدروژن متان و دیگر گازهای هیدروکربوری نشاندهنده¬ی منشا ترموژنیک گازهای خروجی از گل¬فشان¬های مورد مطالعه است و شواهدی از عدم تجزیه زیستی را نشان می¬دهند. دی اکسیدکربن نیز با نسبت ایزوتوپی کربن ۱/۱۱-  تا ‰ ۳/۱۴- دارای منشا آلی است. نتایج این مطالعه، حضور سیستم¬های هیدروکربوری و سنگ منشا فعال را در این ناحیه تکتونیکی فعال نشان می¬دهد. اگرچه حضور مخزن گازی در این منطقه بایستی توسط مطالعات ژئوفیزیکی، زمین¬شناسی و محیط¬های ساختاری تایید شود. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">گل&amp;#172;فشان</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
ترکیب شیمیایی گاز</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
ایزوتوپ کربن و هیدروژن</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
منشا گازها</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
منشورهای برافزایشی مکران ایران</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
بربروک</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
عین</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
سندمیرسوبان</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/139603061344266148-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biostratigraphy and sedimentary environment of Asmari Formation in Davan section, North of Kazerun</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>زیست¬چینه¬نگاری و  محیط رسوبی سازند آسماری در برش روستای دوان، شمال کازرون</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مسعود</FirstName><LastName>خوشنود</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>حسین </FirstName><LastName>وزیری مقدم</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاهاصفهان </Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day></History><Abstract>This research concentrates on biostratigraphy, microfasies and Sedimentary environment of the Asmari Formation at Davan village in 10 Km north of Kazerun. Micropalaeontological study led to recognition of 25 genera and 15 species of foraminifera. Based on biostratigraphic study 3 biozones (1-Nummulites vascus – Nummulites fichteli assemblage zone, 2 -Lepdocyclina-Operculina- Ditrupa Assemblage Zone, 3- Archaias asmaricus- Archaias hensoni- Miogypsinoides complanatus Assemblage Zone) are determined. As a result, the age of the Asmari Formation is Oligocene (Rupelian – Chattian) at the study area. Depositional texture, petrographic analyses and fauna led to identification of 9 carbonate microfacies related to open marine, slope, bar and lagoon. These depositional environments correspond to inner, middle, and outer ramp.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این پژوهش زیست چینه نگاری،  ریزرخساره ها و محیط رسوبی سازند آسماری در برش روستای دوان در 10 کیلومتری شمال کازرون مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. بر اساس مطالعات انجام شده 25 جنس و 15 گونه از روزن‌داران در سازند آسماری شناسایی شده و بر اساس آن¬ها 3 زون زیستی تجمعی برای این سازند (Nummulites vascus – Nummulites fichteli assemblage zone)، (Lepdocyclina-Operculina- Ditrupa Assemblage Zone) و (Archaias asmaricus- Archaias hensoni- Miogypsinoides complanatus Assemblage Zone) معرفی گردید. بر این اساس سن سازند آسماری در برش مورد مطالعه الیگوسن (روپلین-شاتین) تعیین شد. مطالعات پتروگرافی و آنالیز رخساره¬ای حاکی از آن است که کربنات¬های سازند آسماری متشکل از 9 ریزرخساره در قالب چهار کمربند رخساره¬ای دریای باز، سد، تالاب و پهنه¬جزرومدی است. با توجه به پخش و پراکندگی روزنداران، تغییرات تدریجی ریزرخساره ها و عدم حضور سد محصور کننده گسترش یافته محیط رسوبی این سازند رمپ هموکلینال تشخیص داده شد که شامل سه قسمت رمپ درونی، رمپ میانی و رمپ بیرونی می باشد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سازند آسماری،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 ریز رخساره ها،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 رمپ هموکلینال،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 پالئو اکولوژی ،</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 روزنداران بنتیک</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/139601142242595488-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>