﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>13</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Fracture analysis of the Asmari Formation of Dara anticline, as analog model for other Asmari subsurface hydrocarbon reservoirs </ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تحليل شکستگي‌هاي سازند آسماري تاقديس دارا، به عنوان مدل آنالوگ مخازن هيدروکربني زير سطحي آسماري</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>19</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>فرضی پور صائین </LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سعید</FirstName><LastName>محمدی اصل</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>قدرت الله </FirstName><LastName>شفیعی</LastName><Affiliation>شرکت نفت</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day></History><Abstract>The quality of the Asmari Formation, as the reservoir rock of almost three-quarters of the explored oil In Southwest Iran, is often affected by the fractures system. In this paper, in order to study fracture patterns in the Asmari Formation, as well as to present an analog model for other Asmari reservoirs, the Dara anticline in South Dezful depression, which has extensive outcrops of the Asmari Formation, has been studied. During field studies, eleven stations on the anticline, in its different structural positions, have been investigated. In the southwestern limb, four fracture sets trending AZ40-50,AZ130-140,AZ10-20,AZ80-90, in the northeastern limb four fracture sets trending AZ130-140,AZ50-60,AZ170-180,AZ110-120, and in its hinge area, three fracture sets with AZ50-60,AZ130-140,AZ0-10 trends have been identified. From the structural perspective, all the identified fracture sets are associated with folding. In this study, the relative formation time of the identified fractures relative to folding, has been diagnosed as before or simultaneously with folding. Based on field studies, fractures density in the Dara anticline, the Asmari outcrop, ranges from 11.75 to 2 fractures per meter. Indeed, variation range of the fracture length is 1 to 25 m and most fractures have a length of lower than 5 meters. Also, in this study it was found that there is a negative logarithmic relationship between fracture density and sedimentary layers thickness. </Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">کيفيت مخازن آسماري، به عنوان سنگ مخزن تقريباً سه چهارم نفت اکتشاف شده در جنوب غرب ايران، غالباً تحت تاثير سيستم شکستگي‌ها مي‌باشد. در اين مطالعه به منظور بررسي الگوي شکستگي‌ها در مخازن آسماري و همچنين ارائه مدل آنالوگ براي ساير مخازن آسماري، تاقديس دارا در فرو افتادگي دزفول جنوبي که داراي رخنمون وسيعي از سازند آسماري مي‌باشد، مورد بررسي قرار گرفته است. در طي مطالعات صحرايي يازده ايستگاه بر روي سازند آسماري تاقديس دارا در موقعيت‌هاي مختلف ساختاري، بررسي شده است. در يال جنوب غربي چهار دسته شکستگي با وضعيت  AZ40-50,AZ130-140,AZ10-20,AZ80-90 ، در يال شمال شرقي چهار دسته شکستگي با وضعيت AZ130-140,AZ50-60,AZ170-180,AZ110-120 و در ناحيه لولايي سه دسته شکستگي با وضعيت  AZ50-60,AZ130-140, AZ0-10 شناسايي گرديدند. تمام دسته شکستگي‌هاي شناسايي شده از لحاظ ساختاري مرتبط با چين خوردگي هستند. زمان نسبي تشکيل شکستگي‌هاي شناسايي شده نسبت به چين خوردگي در طي اين مطالعه، قبل و يا همزمان با چين خوردگي تشخيص داده شدند.  دامنه تعييرات تراکم شکستگي در رخنمون آسماري تاقديس دارا بر اساس مطالعات صحرايي 2 تا  11.75 شکستگي، در متر متغير است. دامنه تغييرات طول شکستگي‌ها بر اساس مطالعات صحرايي از 1 متر تا 25 متر مي‌باشد و بيشتر شکستگي‌ها داراي طولي کمتر از 5 متر مي‌باشند. همچنين در اين مطالعه مشخص گرديد بين تراکم شکستگي و ضخامت لايه بندي، رابطه لگاريتمي منفي برقرار است. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مخزن آسماري، شکستگي، تاقديس دارا، فرو افتادگي دزفول جنوبي</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13960127951165660-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>13</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle> Biostratigraphy and microfacies analysis of the Shahbazan and Asmari formations (through Eocene to Oligocene) in the carbonate deposits of northwest Dezful Embayment, Zagros Sedimentary Basin</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بررسي زيست چينه¬نگاري و ريز رخساره¬هاي سازندهاي شهبازان و آسماري (گذر از ائوسن به اليگوسن) در نهشته¬هاي کربناته شمال فروافتادگي دزفول، حوضه رسوبي زاگرس</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>20</FirstPage><LastPage>42</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>سپیده </FirstName><LastName>غلام پور موگهی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>حسین </FirstName><LastName>وزیری مقدم</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاهاصفهان </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>ناصر</FirstName><LastName>ارزانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفها ن</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>افشین </FirstName><LastName>ارمون</LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی نفت ایران </Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></History><Abstract>Abstract
In this research based on petrography study of 320 thin sections (cutting samples), biostratigraphy, microfacies and depositional environment analysis has been done to determine the boundary between the Shahbazan and Asmari formations in well No. 1 of the Balarud Oil Field, located in the north of Dezful embayment. The Shahbazan Formation with 460 meters thick with mainly composed of dolomite along with interlayers of limestone, shale and anhydrite in the studied well. The lower boundary of this formation with the Pabdeh Formation is conformable and its upper boundary with the Asmari Formation is marked by an unconformity. The Asmari Formation with thickness of 140 meters mainly consists of limestone and shale with the interlayers of dolomite; its upper boundary to the Gachsaran Formation is conformable. Biostratigraphy studies documented a high diversity of shallow-water benthic and rare planktonic foraminiferas and led to the determining of one assemblage zone in the Shahbazan Formation (15 genera and 8 species) that indicates age of the Priabonain. Three assemblage zones also were recognized in the Asmari Formation (12 genera and 8 species) that, shows the age of the Asmari Formation from Mid-Rupelian to the Chattian, Aquitanian and Burdigalin. Based on biostratigraphy studies, the boundary between Shahbazan and Asmari formations and the position of an unconformity between them were determined. The facies analysis led to recognition of eight microfacies for the Shahbazan Formation which belong to three facies belts of inner (tidal flat and lagoon), middle and outer ramp, deposited on a ramp-type carbonate platform. Also four microfacies were recognized in the Asmari Formation which are related to the inner carbonate platform. 
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">با تکيه بر 330 مقطع نازک (شامل خرده حفاري) مطالعات زيست چينه¬نگاري، ريز رخساره و تفسير محيط رسوبي جهت تعيين مرز بين دو سازند شهبازان و آسماري در چاه شماره يک ميدان نفتي بالارود واقع در شمال فروافتادگي دزفول انجام شده است. سازند شهبازان با ليتولوژي عمدتاً دولوميتي همراه با ميان لايه¬هايي از سنگ آهک، شيل و انيدريت در چاه مورد نظر داراي ضخامت 460 متر مي¬باشد، در توالي مورد نظر اين سازند در مرز پاييني خود عموماً شيل¬هاي سازند پابده را به طور هم¬شيب پوشانده و مرز بالايي آن با سازند آسماري به صورت ناپيوسته در نظر گرفته شده است. سازند آسماري داراي ضخامت 140 متر، ليتولوژي آن عمدتاً از سنگ¬هاي آهکي و آهک شيلي همراه با ميان لايه¬هاي دولوميت مي¬باشد و مرز بالايي آن با سازند گچساران به صورت پيوسته است. مطالعات زيست چينه¬نگاري منجر به شناسايي روزن¬داران کف¬زي متنوع و تعداد اندکي روزن¬داران پلانکتون گرديده است و براساس زون تجمعي شناسايي شده سن ائوس پسين (پريابونين) براي سازند شهبازان (15 جنس و 8 گونه) در نظر گرفته شد. در سازند آسماري نيز سه زون تجمعي (12 جنس و 8 گونه) به سن¬هاي اواسط روپلين-شاتين، آکي¬تانين و بورديگالين معرفي شده است. بر اساس مطالعات زيست چينه نگاري مرز بين دو سازند شهبازان و آسماري و موقعيت ناپيوستگي بين آنها مشخص گرديد. آناليز رخساره¬ها، در اين برش سبب تشخيص هشت ريز رخساره وابسته به سه کمربند رخساره¬اي رمپ داخلي (پهنه جزر و مدي و لاگون)، رمپ مياني و رمپ بيروني براي سازند شهبازان شده است که در يک سکوي کربناته از نوع رمپ نهشته شده است. همچنين چهار ريزرخساره (کربناته) در سازند آسماري شناسايي شده است که به بخش داخلي پلتفرم کربناته تعلق دارند.   </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سازند شهبازان</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 سازند آسماري</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 زيست چينه&amp;#172;نگاري</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 محيط رسوبي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 ميدان نفتي بالارود.   </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13970210101652101893-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>13</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of shale oil revolution on falling of Oil and Gas prices Technical report</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>انقلاب نفتي شيل و تأثير آن بر کاهش قيمت نفت وگاز گزارش تحلیلی </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>96</FirstPage><LastPage>105</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>علیرضا </FirstName><LastName>بشری</LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی نفت ایران </Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></History><Abstract>The rapid development of shale gas resources in the US has transformed the world gas-market outlook. Despite this, the consensus was for a long time that shale gas would not be a ‘game changer’ in the world as it has been in the US. Shale gas is extracted from solid rock using a process called hydraulic fracturing, or ‘fracking’. Static shows, in USA, production rates decline, for the most of well on average, 80 0r 85 percent over the three years. In order to maintain current level of shale gas production, Hughes estimates that the high rates of deterioration of such wells across the US will require the drilling of 7,000 new wells a year at cost of $42 billion annually. For the maintenance   of overall production of shale oil, some 6,000 new wells would need to be drilled every year, an endeavor that would cost $ 35 billion. A number of environmental concerns have been raised about fracking, including the potential for seismic events, air pollution, surface and groundwater contamination, and greenhouse gas emissions. There is no doubt that shale revolution has been a game-changer in short term, but the implication shows that it is not sustainable in long-term.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">توسعه سريع منابع نفت و گاز  شيلي، در ايالات متحده آمريکا، بازار جهاني نفت وگاز را در چند سال گذشته دستخوش دگرگوني نمود. عليرغم اين توسعه ، اتفاق نظر صاحبنظران جهاني بر اين امر استوار  بود که، اين پديده گذرا و تغيير عمده اي به نحوي که در ايالت متحده  آمريکا پديدار شد در ديگر نقاط جهان عملي نخواهد بود . هيدرو کربورهاي گازي توسط فرآيندي بنام شکافتن لايه هاي شيلي استخراج مي گردد که اصطلاحاًFracking   ناميده ميشود. آمارها علمي و مطالعات دقيق ديويد هيوث زمين شناس نامدار کانادايي  نشان مي دهد که در آمريکا اين منابع،  بطور متوسط 80 تا 85 درصد از توليد گاز آن در سه سال اوليه  افت نموده است. از سويي ديگر  نامبرده با مطالعات دقيق خود بروي اين منابع، اعلام ميدارد که به منظور حفظ سطح توليد گاز از اين منابع شيلي، حفاري 7000 حلقه چاه جديد را که هزينه اي بالغ بر 42 ميليارد دلار دارد را مي طلبد، همچنين براي حفظ ميزان توليد نفت، از لايه هاي شيلي آغشته به نفت همچنين نياز به  حفاري  6000 حلقه چاه و تحمل هزينه 35 ميليارد دلار را دارد. از طرفي همواره نگراني هاي فراواني از ديدگاههاي آلودگي هاي محيط زيست درباره عمليات Fracking  مد نظر کارشناسان مربوطه ميباشد. شکي نيست که انقلاب شيل يک ترفند سياسي  بمنظور  افت قيمت جهاني نفت وگاز در کوتاه مدت بوده، ليکن به هيچ وجه تداوم دراز مدت نخواهد داشت .</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">انقلاب شيل</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 شيل گازي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
شيل نفتي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 تزريق هيدروليکي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13970210114829101895-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>13</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Geochemical characterization and evaluation of the hydrocarbon potential of Gurpi in a number of fields Located in North West of Persian Gulf</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بررسی خصوصیات ژئوشیمیایی و ارزیابی پتانسیل هیدروکربن زایی سازند گورپی درتعدادی  از میادین واقع در شمال غرب خلیج فارس</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>63</FirstPage><LastPage>77</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>آرزو</FirstName><LastName>کرمی</LastName><Affiliation>علوم پایه</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد رضا </FirstName><LastName>کمالی </LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی نفت ایران </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمود </FirstName><LastName>معماریانی </LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی نفت</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>احسان </FirstName><LastName>حسینی </LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی نفت ایران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day></History><Abstract>The results obtained from Rock-Eval pyrolysis and measurement of TOC showe that Gourpi and Pabdeh formations in Binak well show that Source rock does not have the sufficient  organic material to produce hydrocarbons. However,Gourpi and Pabdeh in formations Hendijan and Doroud wells support the organic material to produce hydrocarbons and are placed in a more appropriate stage in terms of production. Samply from Binak Lack Contamiaton and or staining Lokite Source rock Samples from Hendigan and Doroud wells show contamination and Staining to migration from other interuals. Source rock show type II taype II-III in Binak and which the samples are n ot fully matured (the end of diagenesis) and the Kerogen for Source rock type of in Hendijan and Doroud wells is II and II-III respectively traversing maturing pathway by reaching catagenesis stage and reaching at the beginning of oil generation window. In terms of the type of organic matter, most in studay wells are located in oil zone and the maximum production potential is associated with Doroud well Location so that it could serves as a production source rock. Although, the Hendijan well have high yield potential, due to failure to reach to oil generation window it fails in producing oil. Sedimentation in the Binak well is done quickly and in oxidized condition and OM preserved partially. The Hendijan and Doroud wells show medium sedimentation in restricted condition and quick sedimentation in oxidizing environment respectively indicating Marine depositinal environment </Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">نتایج حاصل از پیرولیز راک - ایول شامل اندازه گیری مقادیر TOC و بررسی سنگ منشاء گورپی و پابده در چاه بینک نشان میدهد که این سنگ منشاء از نظر ماده آلی فقیر است و نمونه های سنگ منشاء گورپی از چاه درود و سنگ منشاء پابده از چاه هندیجان حاوی ماده آلی کافی بوده و از میزان بلوغ مناسبتری برخوردار است. شاخص مهاجرت و میزان آلودگی نمونه ها قسمت اعظم نمونه ها در ناحیه زایش درجازا بوده و نشان می دهد که اختلاط مواد آلی با کروژن نمونه ها رخ نداده است، هرچند تعدادی از نمونه های این سازند در میدان درود علائم جزئی از اختلاط مواد آلی و هیدروکربنهای نابرجا مهاجرتی را به نمایش می گذارد. نوع کروژن در سنگ منشأ گورپی و پابده در چاه بینک از نوع II و II-III  که نمونه ها به طور کامل بالغ نشده (انتهای مرحله دیاژنز) و در سازند پابده در هندیجان از نوع II-III و در سازند گورپی در درود II میباشد که بارسیدن به مرحله کاتاژنز و قرار گرفتن در ابتدای پنجره نفت زایی مسیر بلوغ را طی نمودهاند.آنالیز سنگ منشاء گورپی و پابده در اکثر نمونه ها محدوده زون نفتی را نشان می دهد و بیشترین پتانسیل تولید مربوط به سازند گورپی در چاه درود می باشد که می تواند به عنوان سنگ منشاء تولید ایفای نقش کند، اگرچه نمونه های پابده در چاه هندیجان پتانسیل تولید بالایی دارد اما به دلیل عدم رسیدن به پنجره نفت زایی نفتی را تولید نمی کند. رسوبگذاری درسازند های گورپی و پابده در چاه بینک و گورپی در درود سریع و در شرایط اکسیدان و نیمه احیایی بوده است و سازند پابده درچاه هندیجان رسوبگذاری متوسط در شرایط احیایی را نشان می دهد که نماینگر محیط دریایی و حدواسط است.

</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">گورپی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 پابده</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 راک- ایول</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 TOC </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 کروژن</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/139604141029336794-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>13</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Simulation of porosity and permeability reservoir parameters by using Co-Sequential Gaussian Simulation method in one of the oil field in the South West of Iran</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>شبیه سازی پارامترهای مخزنی تخلخل و تراوایی با استفاده از روش شبیه سازی گوسی متوالی توأم در یکی از میادین نفتی جنوب غرب ایران</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>78</FirstPage><LastPage>94</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>بهاره</FirstName><LastName>فریدونی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد </FirstName><LastName>مختاری</LastName><Affiliation>مرکز پیش بینی زلزله</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></History><Abstract>Three-dimensional study of petrophysical parameters of hydrocarbon reservoirs such as porosity and permeability is considered as an efficient and effective tool for comprehensive study of reservoirs as well as reservoir management. In this study, which was carried out on one of the oil fields in the southwest of Iran, the aim is to simulate the petrophysical parameters of effective porosity and permeability by using Co-Sequential Gaussian Simulation in part of Khatiyah reservoir. With this simulation, a three-dimensional model of petrophysical reservoir parameters can be presented which is important for simulating fluid flow and identifying areas that are prone with higher reservoir quality. For this purpose, effective porosity and permeability logs of seven wells with 3D seismic data and seismic inversion results have been used. After reservoir gridding and creating a structural model, up scaled petrophysical data has entered to model and its own cell. For three-dimensional distribution of effective porosity parameter, due to the correlation of effective porosity and acoustic impedance attribute of seismic inversion, 3D seismic data and up scaled effective porosity logs as the initial data and acoustic impedance attribute of seismic inversion as secondary data have entered in Sequential Gaussian Simulation. In order to simulate permeability, due to the good correlation between effective porosity simulation model and permeability log, simulated porosity as a secondary data and up scaled permeability and 3D seismic data as secondary data have been used. The results of validation indicate the accuracy of the present study and the efficiency of Sequential Gaussian Simulation method in effective porosity and permeability modeling in this reservoir.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">بررسی سه بعدی پارامترهای پتروفیزیکی مخازن هیدروکربوری مانند تخلخل و تراوایی به عنوان ابزاری کارآمد و مؤثر جهت مطالعه جامع مخازن و همچنین مدیریت مخزن قلمداد میشود. در این مطالعه که بر روی یکی از میادین نفتی جنوب غربی ایران صورت گرفته است، هدف شبیهسازی پارامترهای پتروفیزیکی تخلخل مؤثر و تراوایی با روش شبیه¬سازی گوسی متوالی توأم در بخش مخزنی خطیا می باشد. با این شبیه سازی می توان یک مدل سه بعدی از تغییر پارامترهای پتروفیزیکی مخزن ارائه کرد که برای شبیه سازی جریان سیال و شناسایی مناطق مستعد با کیفیت مخزنی بالاتر حائز اهمیت می باشد. برای این منظور از نگارهای تخلخل مؤثر و تراوایی هفت حلقه چاه به همراه داده لرزه ای سه بعدی و نتایج وارون سازی لرزه ای صورت گرفته، استفاده شده است. پس از شبکه بندی مخزن و ایجاد مدل ساختمانی، داده های پتروفیزیکی بزرگ مقیاس شده وارد مدل و سلول مربوط به خود شده است. برای توزیع سه بعدی پارامتر تخلخل مؤثر، با توجه به ارتباط تخلخل مؤثر و نشانگر مقاومت صوتی حاصل از وارون سازی لرزه ای، داده لرزه ای سه بعدی و نگار تخلخل مؤثر بزرگ مقیاس شده در حکم داده اولیه و نشانگر مقاومت صوتی حاصل از وارون سازی لرزه ای به عنوان داده ثانویه در شبیه سازی گوسی متوالی توأم وارد شده اند. برای شبیه سازی تراوایی نیز با توجه به ارتباط خوب مدل تخلخل مؤثر حاصل از شبیه سازی با نگار تراوایی، از تخلخل مؤثر شبیه سازی شده به عنوان داده ثانویه و از نگار تروایی بزرگ مقیاس شده و داده لرزه ای به عنوان داده اولیه استفاده شده است. نتایج حاصل از اعتبارسنجی حاکی از صحت مطالعه حاضر و کارآمد بودن روش شبیه سازی گوسی متوالی توأم در مدل سازی تخلخل مؤثر و تراوایی در این مخزن می باشد.     </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">تخلخل مژثر</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تراوایی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 شبیه سازی گوسی متوالی توأم</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 اعتبارسنجی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/139606182151277984-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>13</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>A case study of carbonate reservoir permeability determination using NMR log in one of the southwestern fields of Iran</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>مطالعه موردی تعیین تراوایی مخازن کربناته با استفاده از لاگ NMR در یکی از میادین جنوب غربی ایران</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>43</FirstPage><LastPage>62</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>هدایت اله</FirstName><LastName>طیبی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه ازاد</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>بهرام</FirstName><LastName>حبیب نیا</LastName><Affiliation> Kamataka univercity of India</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day></History><Abstract>Permeability is one of the most important parameters for characterization of hydrocarbon reservoirs that has a basic role in almost all of the petroleum engineering problems. Determination of reservoir permeability is usually done in core laboratories in a time consuming process. In the well test, the obtained average permeability is related to the drainage area. Due to cost, these two methods are not performed in the all wells, whereas well logging tools are generally performed in all wells.
With progress of well logging tools, some researchers tried to estimate permeability from special well logs such as NMR  directly. The data obtained from NMR was used as lithology independent data to estimate the water saturation and porosity, and also for analysis of pore space. One of the important parameters obtained from NMR is the transversal relaxation time (T2).
In this work, NMR log measurement in a carbonate field was used to estimate the permeability using Timur, SDR  and regression models. The results of the methods were compared against core permeability. The results show that SDR method is more accurate with the accuracy of 44.1% and the error of 23.12%. 
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">تراوايی يكی از پارامترهاي بسیار پراهمیت در تعیین مشخصه‏هاي مخازن هیدروكربنی محسوب می‏شود كه تقريباً در تمامی مسائل مهندسی نفت نقش اساسی ايفا می‏نمايد. تعیین دقیق تراوایی مخزن اغلب در آزمایشگاه مغزه طی فرایندی زمانبر صورت می‏گیرد. در چاه‏آزمایی نیز مقادیر تراوایی محاسبه شده به صورت میانگین به ناحیه‏ای که تولید آن صورت گرفته است تخصیص می‏یابد. به علت هزینه‏بر بودن دو روش مذکور، عموماً در تمام چاه‏ها صورت نمی‏پذیرند، در حالی که ابزار نمودارگیری در تمامی چاه‏ها به دلیل صرفه اقتصادی و زمانی اغلب انجام می‏شود.
با پیشرفت‏های صورت گرفته در ابزارهای نمودارگیری تلاش‏هایی برای تخمین تراوایی به صورت مستقیم از نمودارهای ویژه  مانند نمودار NMR  انجام شد. داده‏های حاصل از نمودار NMR به عنوان یک منبع پر استفاده‌ی مستقل از لیتولوژی برای تخمین درجه اشباع آب، تخلخل و آنالیز سیستم‏های فضای متخلخل مورد استفاده قرار گرفته است. یکی از پارامترهای مهمی که در NMR اندازه‏گیری می‏شود مقدار زمان آرامیدگی عرضی ( ) می‏باشد.
در این مقاله از اندازه‏گیری‏های صورت گرفته مربوط به نمودارهای NMR یکی از میادین کربناته جنوب غربی ایران برای تخمین مقدار تراوایی با استفاده از مدل‏های Timur،  SDR و مدل رگرسیونی استفاده شده است. همچنین در ادامه، نتایج حاصل از این سه روش با مقادیر محاسبه شده تراوایی از مغزه مقایسه گردید و روش SDR به عنوان مناسب‏ترین روش با میزان دقت 1/44 وخطای 12/23 برای اندازه‏گیری تراوایی در این مخزن معرفی شد.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">تراوایی مخزن</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
لاگ NMR</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 روش SDR</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 روش Timur</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
توزیع زمان آرامیدگی ( )</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13960621721488019-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>