﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>2</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2004</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>  Geochemical analysis &amp;petrophysical studies: An approach to clay minerals investigation of E member of Qom Formation,  Sarajeh gas field </ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>مطالعه ژئوشیمیائی وپترو فیزیکی بر روی کانی های رسی بخش Eسازند قم،میدان گازی سراجه قم </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>عباس</FirstName><LastName>دهکار</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سهیلا</FirstName><LastName>اصلانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></History><Abstract> 
Geochemical and petrophysical studies on E member of Sarajeh Gas field shows presence of different type of clay minerals. Petrography studies along with XRD , SEM and EDX  analysis on the present samples, indicate presence of Illite, Chlorite and expandable clay minerals. Expandable clays comprise, smectite and mixed layer or interstratified Illite/Smectite (I/S) minerals. Petrophsical studies show Th/K on NGS log in Sarajeh, well 12, composed mainly, Illite, chlorite with minor amount of interstratified Illite/Smectite (I/S). Geochemical studies confirm validity of petrophysical results. The presence of different clay minerals of Qom formation in E member, Sarajeh Gas field, may have significant impact on petrophysical properties of reservoir, and hence affect reservoir productivity as well as cause problem during drilling operations. 
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">مطالعات ژئو شیمیایی  وپترو فیزیکی بخشE  سازند قم (الیگوسن –میوسن زیرین )میدان گازی سراجه حضور بخشی از کانی های رسی را نمایان می سازد .نتایج آزمایش پراش اشعه ایکس(XRD) وتصاویر میکروسکوپ الکترون (SEM)همراه با (EDX)نشان دادند که نمونه های مربوط به مارن های رسی بوده وگویای حضور کانی های ایلیت ،کلریت وس های متورم شونده از نوع مخلوط لایه می باشند (I/S).بررسی میدان توریم وپتاسیم وهمچنین نسبت این دو ،در لاگ NGS مربوط به چاه شماره 12میدان گازی سراجه بیانگر حضور کانی های رسی ازنوع ایلیت ،کلریت میزان جزئی کانی های رسی مخلوط لایه متورم شونده وجزئی کائولینیت در این چاه است .ضمناً مطالعات پترو فیزیکی تائید کننده مطالعات ژئوشیمیایی مبتنی بر وجود کانی های رسی می باشد .حضور کانی های  مشکل ساز رسی در بخش هایی از میدان گازی سراجه امکان تاثیر گذاری بر روی ویژگی های مخزنی ودر نتیجه تولید از مخزن شدت می بخشد .حضور کانی های رسی متورم شونده می توانند در حین عملیات حفاری مشکل ساز گردند. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">کانی های رسی سازند قم</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
بخش E</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
میدان گازی سراجه</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 پترو فیزیک   </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13950219954512205-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>