﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2009</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle> Biostratigraphy and microfacies analysis of the Shahbazan and Asmari formations (through Eocene to Oligocene) in the carbonate deposits of northwest Dezful Embayment, Zagros Sedimentary Basin</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بررسي زيست چينه¬نگاري و ريز رخساره¬هاي سازندهاي شهبازان و آسماري (گذر از ائوسن به اليگوسن) در نهشته¬هاي کربناته شمال فروافتادگي دزفول، حوضه رسوبي زاگرس</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>20</FirstPage><LastPage>42</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>سپیده </FirstName><LastName>غلام پور موگهی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>حسین </FirstName><LastName>وزیری مقدم</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاهاصفهان </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>ناصر</FirstName><LastName>ارزانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفها ن</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>افشین </FirstName><LastName>ارمون</LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی نفت ایران </Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></History><Abstract>Abstract
In this research based on petrography study of 320 thin sections (cutting samples), biostratigraphy, microfacies and depositional environment analysis has been done to determine the boundary between the Shahbazan and Asmari formations in well No. 1 of the Balarud Oil Field, located in the north of Dezful embayment. The Shahbazan Formation with 460 meters thick with mainly composed of dolomite along with interlayers of limestone, shale and anhydrite in the studied well. The lower boundary of this formation with the Pabdeh Formation is conformable and its upper boundary with the Asmari Formation is marked by an unconformity. The Asmari Formation with thickness of 140 meters mainly consists of limestone and shale with the interlayers of dolomite; its upper boundary to the Gachsaran Formation is conformable. Biostratigraphy studies documented a high diversity of shallow-water benthic and rare planktonic foraminiferas and led to the determining of one assemblage zone in the Shahbazan Formation (15 genera and 8 species) that indicates age of the Priabonain. Three assemblage zones also were recognized in the Asmari Formation (12 genera and 8 species) that, shows the age of the Asmari Formation from Mid-Rupelian to the Chattian, Aquitanian and Burdigalin. Based on biostratigraphy studies, the boundary between Shahbazan and Asmari formations and the position of an unconformity between them were determined. The facies analysis led to recognition of eight microfacies for the Shahbazan Formation which belong to three facies belts of inner (tidal flat and lagoon), middle and outer ramp, deposited on a ramp-type carbonate platform. Also four microfacies were recognized in the Asmari Formation which are related to the inner carbonate platform. 
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">با تکيه بر 330 مقطع نازک (شامل خرده حفاري) مطالعات زيست چينه¬نگاري، ريز رخساره و تفسير محيط رسوبي جهت تعيين مرز بين دو سازند شهبازان و آسماري در چاه شماره يک ميدان نفتي بالارود واقع در شمال فروافتادگي دزفول انجام شده است. سازند شهبازان با ليتولوژي عمدتاً دولوميتي همراه با ميان لايه¬هايي از سنگ آهک، شيل و انيدريت در چاه مورد نظر داراي ضخامت 460 متر مي¬باشد، در توالي مورد نظر اين سازند در مرز پاييني خود عموماً شيل¬هاي سازند پابده را به طور هم¬شيب پوشانده و مرز بالايي آن با سازند آسماري به صورت ناپيوسته در نظر گرفته شده است. سازند آسماري داراي ضخامت 140 متر، ليتولوژي آن عمدتاً از سنگ¬هاي آهکي و آهک شيلي همراه با ميان لايه¬هاي دولوميت مي¬باشد و مرز بالايي آن با سازند گچساران به صورت پيوسته است. مطالعات زيست چينه¬نگاري منجر به شناسايي روزن¬داران کف¬زي متنوع و تعداد اندکي روزن¬داران پلانکتون گرديده است و براساس زون تجمعي شناسايي شده سن ائوس پسين (پريابونين) براي سازند شهبازان (15 جنس و 8 گونه) در نظر گرفته شد. در سازند آسماري نيز سه زون تجمعي (12 جنس و 8 گونه) به سن¬هاي اواسط روپلين-شاتين، آکي¬تانين و بورديگالين معرفي شده است. بر اساس مطالعات زيست چينه نگاري مرز بين دو سازند شهبازان و آسماري و موقعيت ناپيوستگي بين آنها مشخص گرديد. آناليز رخساره¬ها، در اين برش سبب تشخيص هشت ريز رخساره وابسته به سه کمربند رخساره¬اي رمپ داخلي (پهنه جزر و مدي و لاگون)، رمپ مياني و رمپ بيروني براي سازند شهبازان شده است که در يک سکوي کربناته از نوع رمپ نهشته شده است. همچنين چهار ريزرخساره (کربناته) در سازند آسماري شناسايي شده است که به بخش داخلي پلتفرم کربناته تعلق دارند.   </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سازند شهبازان</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 سازند آسماري</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 زيست چينه&amp;#172;نگاري</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 محيط رسوبي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 ميدان نفتي بالارود.   </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13970210101652101893-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>