﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2010</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>  Enhancing volume and salinity of production water in oil and gas wells, Case study: Mozduran gas reservoir</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle> افزايش حجم و شوري آبهاي توليدي چاههاي نفت و گاز، مطالعه موردي: مخزن گازي مزدوران</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>18</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>رحیم</FirstName><LastName>باقری</LastName><Affiliation>صنعتی شاهرود</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مهدی</FirstName><LastName>میری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شاهرود </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>فرشید </FirstName><LastName>خبیری </LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شاهرود </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمدرضا </FirstName><LastName>اخلاقی</LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی نفت </Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day></History><Abstract>The production of oil and gas in oil and gas fields is accompanied by production of water (Produced Water). Most of the reservoirs at the beginning of production have fresh water; but with passing time due to the increase in productions and decrease in pressure of reservoir, the produced water gradually becomes saline. The saline Production water causes severe corrosion in pipelines and well head facilitis leading to reduction in gas production. Determining the origin of salinity for reducing the salinity is most important. Khangiran gas field is located in the northeast of Iran which composed of two separate gas formations, Mozduran at lower and Shurijeh at the upper part. The produced water samples were collected from fresh and salty wells in the Mozduran reservoir as well as two deep samples from brine below the gas reservoir (at depth of 3 km) for comparison and different analyzes. The Mozduran reservoir has two major problems, high salinity of the produced water, as well as the volume of water produced, rendering some wells unexploitable. The results revealed that two deep water samples have different behaviors. The deep sample No. 17, taken at a higher elevation than sample No. 13, showed the signs of salt dissolution; whereas the brine from sample no.13 had the origin of the evaporated old sea water. Therefore, any of these brines in the Khangiran reservoir can be the possible source of salinity in produced waters. The saline produced water samples showed a similar behavior to brine sample no.13. The source of fresh produced water is also the condensation of water vapor in the reservoir during production.

</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">توليد نفت و گاز در ميادين نفتي و گازي همراه با توليد آب ((Produced Water مي¬باشد. اکثر مخازن در ابتداي توليد، حاوي آب توليدي شيرين بوده که با گذر زمان و افزايش برداشت و افت فشار، شوري آب توليدي افزايش يافته است. توليد آب شور باعث ايجاد خوردگي و گرفتگي در تاسيسات سرچاهي و در نتيجه کاهش توليد گاز مي‌گردد. منشايابي اين پديده به منظور ارائه راهکار مناسب جهت کم کردن شوري امري ضروري است. ميدان گازي خانگيران واقع در شمال شرق ايران داراي دو سازند گازي مجزاي مزدوران در پايين و شوريجه در قسمت بالاتر مي¬باشد. نمونه آب توليدي سرچاهي از چاههاي شور و شيرين در مخزن مزدوران و 2 نمونه درون چاهي از آبران زير مخزن (عمق حدود 3 کيلومتري) جهت مقايسه و آناليزهاي مختلف گرفته شد. مخزن مزدوران داراي دو مشکل عمده شوري بالاي آب توليدي و همچنين حجم آب توليدي زياد بوده که در برخي از چاهها باعث مرگ آنها شده است. نتايج نشان داد که دو نمونه عمقي آبران رفتار متفاوتي نشان مي¬دهند. بطوريکه نمونه عمقي شماره  17 که در ارتفاع بالاتري از نمونه شماره 13 گرفته شده است، منشا انحلال نمک را نشان داده است، در حاليکه نمونه 13، منشا آب درياي قديمي تبخير شده را نشان مي¬دهد. بنابراين در مخزن خانگيران، آبرانهاي مختلفي وجود دارد که مي¬توانند هر کدام منشا احتمالي آبهاي توليدي سرچاهي باشند. نمونه¬هاي آب توليدي سرچاهي شور رفتاري مشابه با آبران شماره 13 را نشان دادند. منشا آب توليدي شيرين نيز حاصل ميعان بخارات آب موجود در مخزن در طي توليد است. بنابراين آبهاي توليدي شور سرچاهي حاصل اختلاط آب شورابه با ترکيب مشابه آبران شماره 13 با آب شيرين مانند بخار آب مايع شده موجود در مخزن مي¬باشند. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">آب توليدي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 شورابه</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 منشا شوري</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 مخزن گاز مزدور</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13980208178976-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>