﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>34</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2008</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle> The Study of Overburden Pressure Effect on Cementation Factor in Hydraulic Flow Units of Carbonate Rocks</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle> مطالعه تاثير فشار بر روي ضريب سيمان شدگي سنگ هاي كربناته در  واحدهاي جريان هيدروليكي</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>حبیب اله </FirstName><LastName>صدیقی</LastName><Affiliation>پژوهشگاه صنعت نفت </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>کاظم</FirstName><LastName>سعادت</LastName><Affiliation>پژوهشگاه صنعت نفت</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد رضا </FirstName><LastName>اصفهانی</LastName><Affiliation>پژوهشگاه صنعت نفت</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>عزت اله </FirstName><LastName>کاظم زاده</LastName><Affiliation></Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></History><Abstract>
Abstract
Analyze of parameters which influence the petrophysical Properties of reservoir rocks is necessary in dynamic model simulation of reservoirs. According to the relation of cementation factor and reservoir pressure changes, cementation factor is the most effective parameter in water saturation determination in the mentioned model, so the study of the effect of pressure on cementation factor is necessary. In this study, firstly carbonate core samples of a gas reservoir, in the south of Iran was classified by hydraulic flow unit delineation method. Then their cementation factors were determined by Archie equation and best fit curve method at ambient, 800, 2000, 3500, and 5000 psi pressures. The changes in cementation factor values due to increasing overburden pressure were evaluated in each hydraulic flow unit and their relationship with flow zone indicator (FZI) were studied by experimental equations (for 4 flow units 0.95&lt;R2&lt;0.99). In this study a relation between flow zone indicator for each hydraulic flow unit and cementation factor changes, due to the different pressures, were also obtained. The experimental results of studied reservoir cores shows that with increasing flow zone indicator the changes in cementation factors decreases. 
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">چکيده
بررسي عوامل موثر بر خواص پتروفيزيكي سنگ مخزن جهت شبيه سازي مدل ديناميكي مخازن هيدروكربوري امري ضروري مي باشد. اهميت اين مطالعه به اين علت است كه ضريب سيمان شدگي وابسته به تغييرات فشار مخزن است و موثرترين پارامتر در ميزان اشباع شدگي آب در مدل هاي مذكور مي باشد. در اين راستا ابتدا نمونه هاي يکي از مخازن هيدروکربوري واقع در جنوب غرب ايران به روش  واحدهاي جريان هيدروليكي طبقه بندي و سپس براي هر واحد جرياني، ضريب سيمان شدگي در مدل هاي آرچي و بهترين برآزش در فشارهاي محيط ، 800، 2000،3500 و 5000 پام تعيين و تغييرات آن در برابر فشارهاي مختلف به صورت روابط تجربي ارائه گرديد.( محدوده ضريب همبستگي R2 در اين ارتباط بين 96/0 و 99/0 مي باشد). همچنين در اين مطالعه ارتباطي بين شاخص منطقه اي جريان در هر واحد جرياني و بازه تغييرات ضريب سيمان شدگي حاصل از فشارهاي مختلف ارائه شد. نتايج حاصل از اين ارتباط نشان داد كه با افزايش شاخص منطقه اي جريان، بازه تغييرات ضريب سيمان شدگي كاهش يافته است.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">ضريب سيمان شدگي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
واحدهاي جريان هيدروليكي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
اشباع شدگي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
فشار همه جانبه</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/139411141131241009-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>