﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>2</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2004</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>  Effect of multi-walled carbon nanotubes to improve  hydrocarbon wells annular clearance space  </ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>بررسی اثر نانو لوله های کربنی چند دیواره بر بهبود پاکسازی فضای حلقوی چاه های هیدرو کربنی </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>محمد</FirstName><LastName>سلیمانی</LastName><Affiliation>مرکز مطالعات تکنولوزی حفاری</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سعیده</FirstName><LastName>رعیت دوست</LastName><Affiliation>مرکز مطالعات تکنولوزی حفاری</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></History><Abstract>Proper drilling fluids has vital role for achieving to hydrocarbon reservoirs by using Drilling operation. Some important problems such as friction, stuck pipe, slow drilling rate, high torque and drag, lost of materials, density variation of mud can be happened due of poor hole annulus and cuttings down falling that induce expensive drilling. Various drilling fluids have been widely used in the wells drilling to improve lifting capacity of drilled cuttings. In this paper, the experimental results have been studied that conducted on effect of Multiwall Carbon Nano tubes (MWNTs) as additives for lifting capacity of water based mud.  
The effect of Useful parameters such as amount of MWNTs used, cutting size and mud annular velocity  on the drilling fluid cleaning capacity have been  studied.  The results show that lifted cuttings increase as the amount of MWNTs added increases. MWNTs associated with water based mud displays the stability against base mud since surface forces easily balance the gravity force and attached to drilled cuttings, resulting in increase of drag force acts to drilled cuttings and easily lifted cuttings to the surface. The MWNTs also will improve viscosity which will significantly increase carrying capacity of the mud. For small and medium cuttings, the improvement relatively simplified compare to the big cuttings. The impact will significantly 
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">سیالات حفاری نقش مهمی در دستیابی به مخازن هیدرومربنی با استفاده از عملیات حفاری دارند .در عملیات حفاری پاک سازی ضعیف فضای حلقوی چاه یکی از نگرانی های اصلی صنعت نفت وگاز می باشد .این امر می تواند موجب مشکلات پر هزینه ای مانند گیر کردن لوله ها ورشته های حفاری ،کاهش سرعت حفاری ،افزایش گشتاوری ونیروی کششی،کاهش کنترل دانسیته وتضعیف عملیات سیمان کاری شود .
در این مطالعه ، توان پاکسازی وظرفیت بالا بری سیالات حفاری پایه آبی همراه با افزودنی نانو لوله های کربنی چند دیواره بررسی شده است .پارامتر های میزان مصرف  نانو لوله کربنی چند دیواره ،اندازه کنده ها وتاثیر سرعت گل در چاه بر روی ظرفیت انتقال کنده ها بررسی شده است .نتایج نشان می دهدکه حمل کنده ها با افزایش میزان نانو لوله کربنی چند دیواره در سیال حفاری افزایش می یابد .نانو لوله کربنی چند دیواره همراه با گل پایه آبی به عنوان عامل پایه گذاری گل،زمانیکه نیرو های سطحی با نیروی جاذبه به تعادل می رسند وباعث انتقال کنده های حفاری می شوند ،عمل می کند وبا افزایش نیروی کششی ،انتقال کنده های حفاری به سطح نیز سریعتر وآسانتر می گردد .هم چنین با افزایش گرانروی سیال حفاری با افزایه نانو لوله کربنی چند دیواره ،ظرفیت حمل سیال حفاری افزایش می یابد .برای کنده ها با سایز کوچک ومتوسط ،بهبود نسبی در مقایسه با کنده ها با سایز بزرگ مشاهده می گردد .این اثر با افزایش سرعت در فضای حلقوی چاه افزایش می یابد .
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">نانو سیالات حفاری  </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 نانو لوله های کربنی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
ظرفیت حمل ذرات  </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
گرانروی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
کنده های حفاری  </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13950219106382206-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>