﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>2</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2004</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>  Geochemical evaluation of source rocks in the Kilur  Karim oilfield, Southwest of Iran</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ارزیابی ژئو شیمیائی سازند های سنگ منشاء در میدان نفتی کیلور کریم ،جنوب غرب ایران </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>هاشم</FirstName><LastName>صراف دخت</LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی نفت -مناطق نفت خیز جنوب</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></History><Abstract>Kilorkarim oilfield is located in 40 Km North of the Persian Gulf and in the vicinity of Siah Makan, Golkhari, Bibi Hakeemeh oilfields. The present study focuses on geochemical evaluation of probable source rocks in this oilfield. For this purpose, source rock samples that selected from three wells were evaluated using Rock-Eval pyrolysis and reconstruction of burial history modeling. 
The results show that organic matter of these source rocks are mostly a mixture of Kerogen types II and III. Also organic petrography study showed that Vitrinite, Detrovitrinite, Hominite and Fuzinite macerals in Pabdeh, Gurpi and Kazhdomi Formations, and reworked Bitumen in some sections of the Pabdeh Formation. 
Based on Vitrinite Reflectance measurments in well#1, Pabdeh and Gurpi Formations aren’t interred in oil window and Kazhdumi Formation interred in oil window. In well#2 Pabdeh and Gurpi Formations are in the beginning and in oil window, respectively. In well#4 Vitrinite Reflectance is emphasized the entrance of Kazhdumi Formation into oil window. 
Reconstruction of Burial history and thermal modeling was performed by PBM 1D software. Modeling showed that Pabdeh Formation in well #1 and 4a interred in oil window but the opposite is true for middle section of well #2. 
Because of more deposition of Aghajari Formation in the south part, oil window occurs in shallower depth and therefore the maturity is higher in the south toward north of the oilfield. 
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">میدان نفتی کیلور کریم در فاصله 40کیلو متری شمال خلیج فارس ودر مجاورت میادین نفتی سیاه مکان ،شور ،گلخاری وبی بی حکیمه واقع شده است .هدف از این مطالعه ،ارزیابی ژئوشیمیائی  سازند های سنگ منشاءاحتمالی در این میدان می باشد .برای این منظور با استفاده از روش راک ایول ومدل سازی تاریخچه تدفین سه چاه 2،1وA4 مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفت .کروژن موجود در سنگ منشاء های احتمالی این میدان بیشتر مخلوطی از نوع II وIII می باشد .مطالعات پترو گرافی آلی در این میدان نشان داد که در سازند های این میدان ماسرال های ویترینایت ،دتروویترینایت ،هومینایت وفوزینایت  وجود دارد ؛همچنین در برخی از مقاطع از سازند پابده بیتومن های نابرجا مشاهده گردید .بر اساس اندازه گیری میزان انعکاس ویترینایت مشخص شد که سازندهای  پابده وگورپی در چاه شماره 1 به پنجره نفتی وارد نشده ولی سازند کزدمی وارد پنجره نفتی گردیده است .در چاه شماره 2 ،سازند پابده در ابتدای پنجره نفتی وسازند گورپی وارد پنجره نفتی شده است .در چاه شماره A 4 میزان در صد انعکاس ویترینایت مبین ورود سازند کژدمی به پنجره نفتی می باشد .
بازسازی تاریخچه تدفین ومدل سازی حرارتی در این میدان توسط نرم افزار مدل سازی PBM  ID به انجام رسید. بر اساس نتایج مدل سازی در این میدان ،مشخص شد که سازند کژدمی در هر سه چاه وارد پنجره نفت زائی گردیده است .در حالی که سازند پابده در چاه های 1وA4 وارد پنجره نفت زائی نشده ولی در چاه شماره 2 بخش میانی این سازند وارد پنجره نفت زائی شده است .بطور کلی می توان گفت به دلیل رسوب بیشتر سازند آغا جاری در بخش جنوبی این میدان ، از سمت شمال به جنوب پنجره نفت زائی در عمق کمتری قرار می گیرد وبلوغ افزایش می یابد .
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value"></Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 ارزیابی ژئو شیمیائی </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 ماسرال </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
انعکاس ویترینایت </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تاریخچه تدفین</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
میدان نفتی کیلور کریم</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/139502191136282212-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>