﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>34</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2009</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Relation between microfacies, depositional environment and diagenesis with reservoir quality the Jahrum Formation in well no. 11, Golkhary oil field, Zagros basin</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ارتباط ریز رخساره ها، محیط رسوبی و دیاژنز با کیفیت مخزنی سازند جهرم در چاه شماره 11، میدان نفتی گلخاری، حوضه ی زاگرس</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مریم </FirstName><LastName>سیناپور</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>ناصر</FirstName><LastName>ارزانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>صیرفیان</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان </Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></History><Abstract>
In this study the relationship between petrographic studies (microfacies, environment of deposition and diagenesis) and petrophysical data of core analysis in order to identify reservoir quality of  the Jahrum Formation in well no. 11 at the Golkhary oil field. The Golkhary oil field is located at the west of Qatar-Kazerun fault, in between Binak and Nargesi oil fields. The Jahrum Formation consists of limestone, dolomite limestone and dolomite. Petrographical studies accomplish in two parts microfacies studies led to the recognition of 9 microfacies that were deposited in 3 facies belt tidal flat, lagoon and open marine environment. In diagenesis studies the most important factors included bioturbation, micritization, mechanical compaction, secondary porosity, secondary anhydrite cement, calcite burial cement, stylolites and solution seams, replacement dolomite, dolomite cement and hydrocarbon shows. Porosities identified are intercrystalline, intergrain, intrafossil and intragrain, moldic, fracture, solution along stylolite, solution enlarge and shelter. The results of this study shows that Grain supported MF3 (Bioclast  Nummulitidae  Rotalia  wackestone/ packstone/ grainstone) and MF4 (Bioclast  Nummulitidae  Orbitolites  packstone/ grainstone/ floatstone) due to the presence in the environment energetic, micrite absence, lack of widespread cement, presence of effective porosities includes intergrain porosity and intercrystalline porosity identified are reservoir microfacies. Petrophysical data with high levels of permeability and effective porosity between these two microfacies is the confirmation of the results of petrographic studies.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این پژوهش رابطه ی بین مطالعات پتروگرافی (ریز رخساره ها، محیط رسوبی و دیاژنز) و داده های پتروفیزیکی حاصل از آنالیز مغزه در جهت شناسایی خصوصیات مخزنی سازند جهرم در چاه شماره 11 واقع در میدان نفتی گلخاری بررسی شده است. میدان نفتی گلخاری در غرب گسل قطر-کازرون، مابین میادین نفتی بینک و نرگسی قرار دارد. سنگ شناسی این توالی عمدتاً آهک، آهک دولومیتی و دولومیت 
می باشد. مطالعات پتروگرافی در دو بخش صورت گرفته است، مطالعه ریز رخساره ها منجر به شناسایی 9 ریز رخساره در سه کمربند رخساره ای دریای باز، لاگون و پهنه ی جذر و مدی شده است. در مطالعات دیاژنز، مهمترین فرآیندها شامل زیست آشفتگی، میکرایتی شدن، تراکم مکانیکی، تخلخل ثانویه، شکستگی، سیمان انیدریتی ثانویه، سیمان دفنی کلسیتی، استیلولیت و رگچه های انحلالی، دولومیت های جانشینی، سیمان دولومیتی، جای گیری هیدروکربن می باشد و انواع تخلخل عبارت است از بین بلوری، بین دانه ای، درون فسیلی و درون دانه ای، قالبی، شکستگی، انحلال در راستای استیلولیت، چتری و انحلال زیاد. نتایج حاصل از این مطالعه نشان می دهد که ریز رخساره ی دانه پشتیبان MF3 (وکستون/ پکستون/ گرینستون روتالیا و نومولیتیده بایوکلاست دار) و MF4 (پکستون/ گرینستون/ فلوتستون اوربیتولیتس و نومولیتیده بایوکلاست دار) به دلیل حضور در محیط پرانرژی، نبود میکرایت، عدم سیمانی شدن گسترده و حضور تخلخل های مفید از جمله تخلخل
 بین دانه ای و تخلخل بین بلوری جزء رخساره های مخزنی معرفی شده اند. داده های پتروفیزیکی نیز با بالا بودن میزان تراوایی و تخلخل مفید در حد فاصل این دو ریز رخساره تاییدی بر نتایج حاصل از مطالعات پتروگرافی می باشد.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">ریز رخساره</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
دیاژنز</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
کیفیت مخزنی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 سازند جهرم</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
چاه شماره 11</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 میدان نفتی گلخاری.</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/139511241211104979-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>