﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2010</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of sequential pressure on petrophysical properties of carbonate reservoir rocks</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>مطالعه اثرات تغييرات فشار متوالي بر خواص پتروفيزيکي سنگ مخازن کربناته</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>19</FirstPage><LastPage>31</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>علی </FirstName><LastName>مرادزاده</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>یاسر</FirstName><LastName>سلیمی دلشاد </LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>عزت اله</FirstName><LastName>کاظم زاده</LastName><Affiliation>پژوهشگاه صنعت نفت</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>عباس </FirstName><LastName>مجدی </LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران </Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day></History><Abstract>Today, oil industry significantly relies on the precise determination of rock reservoir properties, which reduces the costs and risks of production planning. The reservoir rock always is compacted by pressure drop of the reservoir, which rises effective stress, reservoir compaction and alterations of reservoir properties. As these pressure variations can considerably affect petrophysical properties, in this study, several carbonate reservoir rock samples with different fabric and porosity type (according to CT scan and Archie classification analysis) subjected to cyclic and short-term loading from 600 to 6000 psi. Their petrophysical and compressive properties including pore volume, permeability and compressibility were measured using CMS-300 apparatus. Moreover, structural analysis and heterogeneity of core samples were analyzed by CT scan images. By performing this study, it will be possible to identify the value of the hysteresis effect on the reservoir rock samples as a result of increasing and decreasing of the pressure during cyclic loading. The obtained results show that, pore volume and permeability are both decreased due to loading, whereas reduction of the permeability is several times than the pore volume ones. Moreover, this reduction of pore volume is less severe in vuggy porous samples that shows the effect of heterogeneity and porosity type on hysteresis. Also, the results obtained from the behavior of the reservoir rock under various pressure conditions can provide a suitable design for gas injection studies to enhance oil recovery and also natural gas storage.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه صنعت نفت بسيار متكي به تعيين دقيق خصوصيات سنگ مخزن است كه اين مهم مي¬تواند سبب كاهش هزينه¬ها و ريسك برنامه¬ ريزي توليد شود. سنگ مخزن همواره با افت فشار منفذي ناشي از توليد متراكم‏ مي‏شود که اين امر سبب افزايش تنش مؤثر، فشردگي مخزن و تغييرات در خواص مخزني مي‏گردد. از آنجاييکه اين تغييرات فشار مي¬تواند بر خواص پتروفيزيکي اثرگذار باشد، در اين مطالعه، چندين نمونه سنگ مخزن کربناته با بافت و نوع تخلخل متفاوت براساس تصاوير سي‌تي اسکن و طبقه بندي آرچي تحت بارهاي متوالي و کوتاه مدت، از 600 تا 6000 پوند بر اينچ مربع قرارگرفته¬اند و خصوصيات پتروفيزيکي و تراکمي آنها شامل حجم فضاي منفذي، نفوذپذيري و تراکم‌پذيري توسط دستگاه CMS-300 مورد مطالعه قرار گرفته است. همچنين بررسي ساختاري و ناهمگني نمونه مغزه¬ها توسط تصاوير سي‌تي اسکن مورد آناليز قرار گرفته¬اند. در واقع به کمک اين پژوهش شناسايي اندازه اثر پسماند بر روي نمونه سنگ مخزن در اثر افزايش و کاهش فشار، طي اعمال بار سيکليک مقدور خواهد بود. نتايج حاصل نشان دادند که در اثر بارگذاري تغييرات حجم فضاي منفذي و نفوذپذيري روند کاهشي از خود نشان مي¬دهند، بطوريکه کاهش نفوذپذيري چندين برابر کاهش حجم منفذي است. همچنين اين کاهش حجم فضاي منفذي در نمونه¬هاي داراي تخلخل حفره¬اي با شدت کمتري است که اثر همگني و نوع تخلخل بر ميزان پديده پسماند را نشان مي¬دهد. همچنين نتايج به‌دست آمده از چگونگي رفتار سنگ مخزن تحت تنش-هاي مختلف در اين مطالعه، مي¬تواند الگوي مناسب براي مطالعات مربوط به تزريق گاز به منظور ازدياد برداشت و همچنين متناسب با اهداف مرتبط ديگر نظير ذخيره‌سازي گاز طبيعي را فراهم آورد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value"> سنگ مخزن کربناته</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 طبقه بندي آرچي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
بارگذاري سيکليک</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 تخلخل، تراوايي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 تصاوير سي‌تي اسکن.</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13980214179088-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>