﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>1</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2002</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle> Geochemical characterization and oil family definition  for the Azadegan reservoir in the Azadegan oil field</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle> بررسی ژئوشیمیایی و تعیین خانواده¬های نفتی مخزن آزادگان در میدان نفتی آزادگان</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>سید حسین</FirstName><LastName>حسینی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه چمران اهواز</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></History><Abstract>Abstract
This study aims at geochemical investigation of the hydrocarbons contained within the Azadegan sandstone reservoir by using the GC and GC-MS techniques. The Azadegan reservoir contains paraffinic and paraffinic – naphthenic oils with an API of 30. The gas chromatograms reveal that the source rocks responsible for these oils contains mainly type II kerogen deposited in a reducing environment. According to these data the studied oils have a relatively high level of thermal maturity. Ratios of C35S/C34S, C29/C30, C31R/C30 Hopane and Pr/Ph, Ph/nC18 show that the studied oil derived from carbonate source rock; which is also evident form Pr/Ph Vs. DBT/Phen diagrams. Diagrams of (20R) C29/C27 vs. Pr/Ph as well as the ratios of C21+/C21-, Pr/P, TAR are consistent with abundance of algal organic matter. Presence of Tricyclic terpanes, higher ETR ratios and diagrams of δ13C vs. Pr/P introduce a Jurassic aged source rock for the studied oils. Based on biomarker and isotopic data it could be concluded that oils within the Azadegan reservoir are mainly derived from carbonate source rocks of Mid-Upper Jurassic which are deposited in paralic/open marine environment with a predominance of algal organic matter. 
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">چکیده
هدف از این مطالعه ارزیابی ژئوشیمیایی نفت مخزن آزادگان در میدان نفتی آزادگان با استفاده از روش¬های  GCو  GC- MS می¬باشد. بخش ماسه¬سنگ آزادگان حاوی نفت پارافینی و پارافینی- نفتنی با درجه API 30 می¬باشد. بر اساس نتایج حاصل از داده¬های کروماتوگرافی گازی (GC ) این نفت¬ها از سنگ¬های منشأ با کروژن نوع II در یک محیط دریایی احیایی حاصل شده¬اند و دارای بلوغ حراتی بالا می¬باشند. نسبت هوپان C35S/C34S، C29/C30، C31R/C30Hopane و همچنین نسبت Pr/Ph ، Ph/nC18 و نسبت Pr/Ph در برابر DBT/Phen نشان دهنده سنگ منشأ کربناتی برای نفت¬های مورد مطالعه می¬باشد. نسبت C21+/C21-، Pr/Ph، TAR و نسبت استران¬هاي (20R) C29/C27 در برابر نسبت Pr/Ph مبین شرایط احيايي دریایی و فراوانی مواد آلي جلبكي در محیط رسوبگذاری سنگ¬های منشأ می¬باشد. حضور ترپان¬هاي سه-حلقه‌اي، نسبت ETR و نمودار تغييرات مقادير ايزوتوپ كربن (δ13C) در برابر نسبت Pr/Ph مشخص¬كننده سنگ منشائي دريايي و قديمي¬تر از كرتاسه مي‌باشد. نهایتاً بررسی داده¬های بیومارکری و ایزوتوپی نشان دادند که نفت مخزن آزادگان در میدان نفتی آزادگان از سنگ¬های منشأ کربناته با سن ژوراسیک میانی تا بالایی در یک محیط دریایی تا پارالیک با فراوانی بالایی از مواد جلبکی بوجود آمده¬اند و از نظر بلوغ در اواسط پنجره نفتی قرار دارند.
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">بیومارکر</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مخزن آزادگان</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 سازند کژدمی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 میدان نفتی آزادگان.</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/139411271221261113-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>