﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2009</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Fracture analysis of the Asmari Formation of Dara anticline, as analog model for other Asmari subsurface hydrocarbon reservoirs </ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تحليل شکستگي‌هاي سازند آسماري تاقديس دارا، به عنوان مدل آنالوگ مخازن هيدروکربني زير سطحي آسماري</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>19</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>فرضی پور صائین </LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سعید</FirstName><LastName>محمدی اصل</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>قدرت الله </FirstName><LastName>شفیعی</LastName><Affiliation>شرکت نفت</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day></History><Abstract>The quality of the Asmari Formation, as the reservoir rock of almost three-quarters of the explored oil In Southwest Iran, is often affected by the fractures system. In this paper, in order to study fracture patterns in the Asmari Formation, as well as to present an analog model for other Asmari reservoirs, the Dara anticline in South Dezful depression, which has extensive outcrops of the Asmari Formation, has been studied. During field studies, eleven stations on the anticline, in its different structural positions, have been investigated. In the southwestern limb, four fracture sets trending AZ40-50,AZ130-140,AZ10-20,AZ80-90, in the northeastern limb four fracture sets trending AZ130-140,AZ50-60,AZ170-180,AZ110-120, and in its hinge area, three fracture sets with AZ50-60,AZ130-140,AZ0-10 trends have been identified. From the structural perspective, all the identified fracture sets are associated with folding. In this study, the relative formation time of the identified fractures relative to folding, has been diagnosed as before or simultaneously with folding. Based on field studies, fractures density in the Dara anticline, the Asmari outcrop, ranges from 11.75 to 2 fractures per meter. Indeed, variation range of the fracture length is 1 to 25 m and most fractures have a length of lower than 5 meters. Also, in this study it was found that there is a negative logarithmic relationship between fracture density and sedimentary layers thickness. </Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">کيفيت مخازن آسماري، به عنوان سنگ مخزن تقريباً سه چهارم نفت اکتشاف شده در جنوب غرب ايران، غالباً تحت تاثير سيستم شکستگي‌ها مي‌باشد. در اين مطالعه به منظور بررسي الگوي شکستگي‌ها در مخازن آسماري و همچنين ارائه مدل آنالوگ براي ساير مخازن آسماري، تاقديس دارا در فرو افتادگي دزفول جنوبي که داراي رخنمون وسيعي از سازند آسماري مي‌باشد، مورد بررسي قرار گرفته است. در طي مطالعات صحرايي يازده ايستگاه بر روي سازند آسماري تاقديس دارا در موقعيت‌هاي مختلف ساختاري، بررسي شده است. در يال جنوب غربي چهار دسته شکستگي با وضعيت  AZ40-50,AZ130-140,AZ10-20,AZ80-90 ، در يال شمال شرقي چهار دسته شکستگي با وضعيت AZ130-140,AZ50-60,AZ170-180,AZ110-120 و در ناحيه لولايي سه دسته شکستگي با وضعيت  AZ50-60,AZ130-140, AZ0-10 شناسايي گرديدند. تمام دسته شکستگي‌هاي شناسايي شده از لحاظ ساختاري مرتبط با چين خوردگي هستند. زمان نسبي تشکيل شکستگي‌هاي شناسايي شده نسبت به چين خوردگي در طي اين مطالعه، قبل و يا همزمان با چين خوردگي تشخيص داده شدند.  دامنه تعييرات تراکم شکستگي در رخنمون آسماري تاقديس دارا بر اساس مطالعات صحرايي 2 تا  11.75 شکستگي، در متر متغير است. دامنه تغييرات طول شکستگي‌ها بر اساس مطالعات صحرايي از 1 متر تا 25 متر مي‌باشد و بيشتر شکستگي‌ها داراي طولي کمتر از 5 متر مي‌باشند. همچنين در اين مطالعه مشخص گرديد بين تراکم شکستگي و ضخامت لايه بندي، رابطه لگاريتمي منفي برقرار است. </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مخزن آسماري، شکستگي، تاقديس دارا، فرو افتادگي دزفول جنوبي</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13960127951165660-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>