﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2009</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of shale oil revolution on falling of Oil and Gas prices Technical report</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>انقلاب نفتي شيل و تأثير آن بر کاهش قيمت نفت وگاز گزارش تحلیلی </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>96</FirstPage><LastPage>105</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>علیرضا </FirstName><LastName>بشری</LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی نفت ایران </Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></History><Abstract>The rapid development of shale gas resources in the US has transformed the world gas-market outlook. Despite this, the consensus was for a long time that shale gas would not be a ‘game changer’ in the world as it has been in the US. Shale gas is extracted from solid rock using a process called hydraulic fracturing, or ‘fracking’. Static shows, in USA, production rates decline, for the most of well on average, 80 0r 85 percent over the three years. In order to maintain current level of shale gas production, Hughes estimates that the high rates of deterioration of such wells across the US will require the drilling of 7,000 new wells a year at cost of $42 billion annually. For the maintenance   of overall production of shale oil, some 6,000 new wells would need to be drilled every year, an endeavor that would cost $ 35 billion. A number of environmental concerns have been raised about fracking, including the potential for seismic events, air pollution, surface and groundwater contamination, and greenhouse gas emissions. There is no doubt that shale revolution has been a game-changer in short term, but the implication shows that it is not sustainable in long-term.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">توسعه سريع منابع نفت و گاز  شيلي، در ايالات متحده آمريکا، بازار جهاني نفت وگاز را در چند سال گذشته دستخوش دگرگوني نمود. عليرغم اين توسعه ، اتفاق نظر صاحبنظران جهاني بر اين امر استوار  بود که، اين پديده گذرا و تغيير عمده اي به نحوي که در ايالت متحده  آمريکا پديدار شد در ديگر نقاط جهان عملي نخواهد بود . هيدرو کربورهاي گازي توسط فرآيندي بنام شکافتن لايه هاي شيلي استخراج مي گردد که اصطلاحاًFracking   ناميده ميشود. آمارها علمي و مطالعات دقيق ديويد هيوث زمين شناس نامدار کانادايي  نشان مي دهد که در آمريکا اين منابع،  بطور متوسط 80 تا 85 درصد از توليد گاز آن در سه سال اوليه  افت نموده است. از سويي ديگر  نامبرده با مطالعات دقيق خود بروي اين منابع، اعلام ميدارد که به منظور حفظ سطح توليد گاز از اين منابع شيلي، حفاري 7000 حلقه چاه جديد را که هزينه اي بالغ بر 42 ميليارد دلار دارد را مي طلبد، همچنين براي حفظ ميزان توليد نفت، از لايه هاي شيلي آغشته به نفت همچنين نياز به  حفاري  6000 حلقه چاه و تحمل هزينه 35 ميليارد دلار را دارد. از طرفي همواره نگراني هاي فراواني از ديدگاههاي آلودگي هاي محيط زيست درباره عمليات Fracking  مد نظر کارشناسان مربوطه ميباشد. شکي نيست که انقلاب شيل يک ترفند سياسي  بمنظور  افت قيمت جهاني نفت وگاز در کوتاه مدت بوده، ليکن به هيچ وجه تداوم دراز مدت نخواهد داشت .</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">انقلاب شيل</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 شيل گازي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
شيل نفتي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 تزريق هيدروليکي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13970210114829101895-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>