﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>34</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2008</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparison of image log interpretation and core analysis advantages for study of fractures in hydrocarbon reservoir rocks: a case study in the Asmari reservoir Aghajari oil field</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle> مقايسه تفسير لاگ‌های تصويرگر با مطالعه مغزه‌ها در آشکارسازی شکستگی‌های مخازن نفتی (مطالعه موردی مخزن آسماری ميدان آغاجاری)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>معصومه</FirstName><LastName>وطن دوست</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>فرضی پور صائین </LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>اسماعیل</FirstName><LastName>سالاروند</LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی نفت ایران</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day></History><Abstract>
The Oligo-Miocene Asmari Formation is one of the main reservoir rocks of SW Iran with several decades of production history from different oil fields in the Zagros fold- thrust belt. One of the main reasons for the high quality of the Asmari reservoir is well developed fracture system in this formation. Characteristics of fractures such as type, opening and orientation can be determined by the core analysis and also interpreting the image logs. This paper attempts to compare the advantages of the image log and core analysis in detecting fractures and other geological feathers in different zones of the Asmari Formation. To achieve this goal, we have compared the image log and core of well no. 89 of the Aghajari oil field. Comparison of the core well no. 89 of the Aghajari oil field with its image log revealed distinguish of the bedding planes in the core easier and more reliable than the image log. This study demonstrates the image log is more capable than core to detect the open fractures, while it is not suitable for detecting filled fractures. Indeed, image log rarely can detect shear fractures, but if it is calibrated with core, it can detect shear fractures with reasonable accuracy.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">سازند آسماری (الیگومیوسن) یکی از سنگ مخزن های اصلی جنوب غرب ایران با چندین دهه تاریخ تولید از میادین مختلف در کمربند چین و رانده زاگرس است. یکی از مهمترین دلایل کیفیت مخازن سازند آسماری وجود سیستم شکستگی‌های توسعه یافته در آن است. خصوصیاتی از شکستگی از قبیل نوع، باز شدگی و جهت، با تحلیل مغزه و تحلیل لاگ های تصویری قابل تعیین است. هدف این مطالعه بررسی توانایی لاگ‌های تصویرگر الکتریکی در آشکارسازی شکستگی و دیگر خصوصیات زمین‌شناسی در لایه های مخزنی مختلف سازند آسماری است. در این راستا، شکستگی‌ها و دیگر خصوصیات زمین شناختی در مغزه و لاگ تصویری چاه شماره 89 میدان آغاجاری تشخیص داده شده و سپس اقدام به مقایسه آن ها به منظور تعیین توانایی لاگ تصویری در مطالعه شکستگی شد. مقایسه مغزه‌های بدست آمده از چاه 89 میدان آغاجاری با لاگ تصویری این چاه نشان داد که آشکارسازی سطوح لایه بندی در مغزه نسبت به لاگ تصویری آسانتر و واقعی‌تر است. همچنین این مطالعه نشان داد که لاگ تصویری نسبت به مغزه در شناسایی شکستگی‌های باز تواناتر بوده در حالیکه برای شناسایی شکستگی‌های بسته (پرشده) مناسب نیست. لاگ تصویری ندرتا قادر به آشکارسازی شکستگی‌های برشی بوده ولی در صورتیکه با مغزه تطابق داده شود قادر به شناسایی شکستگی برشی با دقت مناسب خواهد بود.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">زاگرس</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 مخزن آسماری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 میدان آغاجاری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 لاگ تصویرگر</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تحلیل مغزه.</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/139503101032552430-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>