﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>5</Volume><Issue>34</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2005</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Making  the  lithology  log  by Clustering-Estimation approach  in the  wells of an oil field  in south  of Iran </ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ساخت نگار لیتو لوژی با رویکرد خوشه بندی-تخمین در چاه های یک میدان نفتی جنوب ایران </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>ساره</FirstName><LastName>صدیق </LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مهرنوش </FirstName><LastName>علی پور شهسواری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>حسین</FirstName><LastName>معماریان</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>بهزاد</FirstName><LastName>تخم چی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه شاهرود</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day></History><Abstract>Abstruct
Reservoir  lithology  determination  is one  of the main studies  used  for  well correlation  and  analyzing  productive  zones  of the  reservoir. The best  way  foer lithology  determination  is  using  core  and cutting  information . Nevertheless,in  most  wells   these data  is not  complete  and continual, so  in these  cases  usually  use  well  logging  for lithology estimation of  petrophysical  well   data   with  Clustering- Estimation   approach . This  method  has  been  generalized  according  to  one  well from  one  of  the  oil  fields  in  South  of  Iran  that  contains  core  data . Then  this  method  is  generalized  in un cored wells. Clustering  is used  as  a way  for grouping  well data  in  homogenous lithology  clusters After ward, percentage  of mineral  is  estimated  in each  of  these  clusters. The  regression coefficients are  calculated  92.93% and  74.99%  between  real  and  estimated  data  respectively  for  calcite  and  dolomite  in  one  of  the  wells. The  results  with  high  accuracy  show  the  generalization  of  this   method.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">تعیین لیتو لوژی مخزن از مهم ترین بررسی های مخزنی است که جهت تطابق چاه ها وتشخیص قسمت های تولیدی مخزن به کار می رود بهترین روش در تعیین لیتولوژی استفاده از اطلاعات مغزه وخرده های حفاری است .اما در بسیاری از چاه ها این اطلاعات به صورت کامل وپیوسته موجود نیست .به طور معمول در موارد نبود مغزه نسبت به تخمین لیتو لوژی از داده های پترو فیزیکی با رویکرد خوشه بندی –تخمین است .این روش بر اساس داده های یک چاه اکتشافی از یکی از میادین نفتی جنوب ایران که دارای نتایج آنالیز مغزه بوده توسعه داده شده ونسبت به بهینه سازی پارامتر های مدل اقدام شده است .سپس این مدل بر روی چاه های فاقد فاقد مغزه تعمیم داده شده است .خوشه بندی به عنوان عاملی برای تفکیک داده های چاه به جوامع همگن لیتو لوژیکی مورد استفاده قرار می گیرد ،سپس تخمین در صد کانی ها در هر کدام از این جوامع غالب لیتو لوزیکی صورت گرفته است وبه ترتیب ضرایب همبستگی 93/92%و99/74 %بین داده های وافعی وتخمینی دولومیت وکلسیت در یکی از چاه ها بدست آمده است .نتایج معرف دقت مناسب وقابلیت تعمیم قابل توجه رویکرد است </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">مخزن آسماری</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
خوشه بندی </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
لیتو لوژی </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تخمین گر MLP</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
خوشه بندی میانگین K داده </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
خوشه بندی گوستاو سون کسل </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
ایران </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13950107104141485-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>