﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2010</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Estimation of oil production, restoration of burial history and thermal maturity using Pyrolysis Rock-Eval data and Arrhenius model in one of the wells of Parsi oilfield</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ارزیابی زایش نفت، بازسازي تاریخچه تدفین و بلوغ حرارتی  با استفاده از داده هاي پیرولیز راك ایول و مدل آرنیوس در یکی از چاههای میدان نفتی پارسی</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>104</FirstPage><LastPage>115</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>بیژن</FirstName><LastName>ملکی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام خمینی(ه)</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>ابوذر</FirstName><LastName>بازوندی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام خمینی(ه)</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سعیده</FirstName><LastName>سنماری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام خمینی(ه)</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>پرویز</FirstName><LastName>آرمانی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بین المللی امام خمینی(ه)</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day></History><Abstract>Investigating potential source rocks in oilfields is important. In this study, in addition to evaluating the hydrocarbon potential, the Arrhenius kinetic model was used to more accurately assess the source rock maturity status as well as the percentage of oil generation in the Parsi oilfield. In the Arrhenius model, the rate of kerogen decomposition is very important. In this research, some source rocks that have been tested by thermal pyrolysis were kinetically analyzed and the source rock conversion ratio (TR) was determined. Based on the results of burial history and thermal modeling, it was found that Kazhdumi and Pabdeh formations were in the oil window well while Gurpi formation did not enter the oil window due to poor organic matter content (TR = 0). Therefore, among the Kazhdomi, Gurpi and Pabdeh formations in the Parsi oilfield, Kazhdumi formation is considered as the main and most effective source rock of this oilfield with high TTI and TR = 100.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">بررسی سنگ‌های منشا احتمالی در میدان های نفتی اهمیت زیادی دارد. در این تحقیق، علاوه بر ارزیابي پتانسیل هیدروکربني، از مدل سینتیکی آرنیوس، برای ارزیابی دقیق تر وضعیت بلوغ سنگ منشاء و همچنین درصد زایش نفت در میدان نفتی پارسی استفاده شد. در مدل آرنیوس، دمای آهنگ تجزیه‌ کروژن از اهمیت زیادی برخوردار است. در این تحقیق برخی از سنگ های منشاء¬ که آزمایش پیرولیز حرارتی بر روی آن‌ها صورت گرفته است از جنبه سینتیکی مورد تجزیه ‌و تحلیل قرار گرفته و نسبت تبدیل سنگ منشاء (TR) تعیین گردید. بر اساس نتایج بدست آمده از بازسازی تاریخچه تدفین و مدل‌سازی حرارتی، مشخص شد که سازندهای کژدمی و پابده در چاه موردنظروارد پنجره نفتی گردیده در حالیکه سازند گورپی بعلت مواد آلی ناچیز وارد پنجره نفت زایی نشده است (TR =0). بنابراین از ميان سازندهاي کژدمی، گورپی و پابده در ميدان نفتی پارسی، سازند کژدمی به عنوان اصلی ترين و موثرترين سنگ منشأ اين ميدان نفتی معرفی می شود که دارای   TR =100و  TTI بالایی میباشد. 
 
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">ارزیابی سینتیکی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
سنگ منشاء</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
مدل آرنیوس</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تاریخچه تدفین</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
میدان نفتی پارسی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13980327190181-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>