﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2009</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle> Microfacies and depositional environment of the Asmari Formation in the Izeh zone</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>ريزرخساره ها و محيط رسوبي سازند آسماري در زون ايذه (منطقه ايذه)،  حوضه رسوبي زاگرس</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>مجمد رضا </FirstName><LastName>طاهری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی اضغر</FirstName><LastName>غبیشاوی</LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی نفت </Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></History><Abstract>In this study, microfacies features of the Asmari Formation have been studied. The study area is located in the Izeh zone, in the vicinity of Izeh city. Accordingly four outcrop sections (Halayjan, Kuh Shur, Kuh-e Bad and Gharibi Ha) have been sampled and investigated. Due to unique tectonical characteristic and lateral as well as spatial variations of the outcrops, different facies have been deposited across the Asmari Formation platform in the study area. Based on the sedimentary structures, texture, skeletal and non-skeletal grains, 11 microfacies have been recognized which have been deposited in three different sub environments including open marine, shoal and lagoon. Based on this reaserch, for the Asmari Formation, three independent depositional models have been considered during the Chattian, Aquitanian and Burdigalian. On the basis of the results of this study, during the Chattian, Aquitanian and Burdigalian the Asmari Formation has been deposited in a homoclinal ramp system. During the Burdigalian toward the NE of study area (Gharibi Ha section), the shallow water deposits are abruptly overlain by pelagic limestone. Therefore, during the Burdigalian toward the NE of study area, probably, the carbonate ramp has been changed to drowned carbonate platform. It is interpreted as the result of a regional tilting that started in the late of the Burdigalian. During the Chattian in the Gharibi Ha area, the base of the carbonate Asmari Formation transits into the marl-dominated Pabdeh Formation towards the Halayjan area which could be concerned as an analogue to investigate about the stratigraphic oil traps potential in the Izeh zone. 

</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در اين مطالعه ويژگي هاي ريزرخساره اي و شرايط حاکم بر محيط رسوبگذاري سازند آسماري مورد مطالعه قرارگرفته است. منطقه مورد مطالعه در زون ايذه و در اطراف شهرستان ايذه قرار دارد. براين اساس، چهار برش سطحي در اطراف شهرستان ايذه (هلايجان، کوه شور، کوه باد و غريبي ها) مورد برداشت و بررسي قرار گرفتند. با توجه به موقعيت مکاني و زماني برش ها و همچنين ويژگي هاي تکتونيکي منحصر بفرد ناحيه مورد بررسي، ريزرخساره هاي متفاوتي در امتداد حوضه رسوبي تشکيل شده است. با بررسي خصوصياتي نظير بافت و عناصر اسکلتي وغير اسکلتي، تعداد 11 ريزرخساره رسوبي تشخيص داده شده است که در قسمت¬هاي دامنه سراشيب قاره، سد و لاگون رسوبگذاري کرده اند. براساس اين تحقيق، سه مدل مستقل رسوبي براي سازند آسماري در طي زمان هاي شاتين، آکي تانين و بورديگالين در نظر گرفته شده است. با توجه به نتايج حاصل از اين پژوهش، سازند آسماري طي زمان هاي شاتين، آکي تانين و بورديگالين در يک محيط رمپ هم شيب نهشته شده است. طي زمان بورديگالين، به سمت جنوب شرق ناحيه، رسوبات آب هاي کم عمق، بطور ناگهاني توسط آهک هاي عميق پوشيده مي شوند. بنابراين احتمالاٌ در جنوب شرق محدوده مطالعاتي در انتهاي بورديگالين، رمپ کربناته به يک پلاتفرم غرق شده تبديل شده است. اين شرايط متاثر از کج شدگي تکتونيکي ناحيه اي است که در اواخر بورديگالين اتفاق افتاده است. در بازه زماني شاتين، کربنات هاي قاعده آسماري در منطقه غريبي ها تبديل به رسوبات مارني سازند پابده در ناحيه هلايجان مي شود که ميتواند به عنوان الگوي سطحي براي بررسي نفتگيرهاي چينه اي در منطقه مورد مطالعه، مورد استفاده قرار گيرد.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سازند آسماري</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 ريزرخساره</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
حوضه رسوبي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 زون ايذه.</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/139507101025313481-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>