﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2009</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Simulation of porosity and permeability reservoir parameters by using Co-Sequential Gaussian Simulation method in one of the oil field in the South West of Iran</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>شبیه سازی پارامترهای مخزنی تخلخل و تراوایی با استفاده از روش شبیه سازی گوسی متوالی توأم در یکی از میادین نفتی جنوب غرب ایران</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>78</FirstPage><LastPage>94</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>بهاره</FirstName><LastName>فریدونی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمد </FirstName><LastName>مختاری</LastName><Affiliation>مرکز پیش بینی زلزله</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></History><Abstract>Three-dimensional study of petrophysical parameters of hydrocarbon reservoirs such as porosity and permeability is considered as an efficient and effective tool for comprehensive study of reservoirs as well as reservoir management. In this study, which was carried out on one of the oil fields in the southwest of Iran, the aim is to simulate the petrophysical parameters of effective porosity and permeability by using Co-Sequential Gaussian Simulation in part of Khatiyah reservoir. With this simulation, a three-dimensional model of petrophysical reservoir parameters can be presented which is important for simulating fluid flow and identifying areas that are prone with higher reservoir quality. For this purpose, effective porosity and permeability logs of seven wells with 3D seismic data and seismic inversion results have been used. After reservoir gridding and creating a structural model, up scaled petrophysical data has entered to model and its own cell. For three-dimensional distribution of effective porosity parameter, due to the correlation of effective porosity and acoustic impedance attribute of seismic inversion, 3D seismic data and up scaled effective porosity logs as the initial data and acoustic impedance attribute of seismic inversion as secondary data have entered in Sequential Gaussian Simulation. In order to simulate permeability, due to the good correlation between effective porosity simulation model and permeability log, simulated porosity as a secondary data and up scaled permeability and 3D seismic data as secondary data have been used. The results of validation indicate the accuracy of the present study and the efficiency of Sequential Gaussian Simulation method in effective porosity and permeability modeling in this reservoir.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">بررسی سه بعدی پارامترهای پتروفیزیکی مخازن هیدروکربوری مانند تخلخل و تراوایی به عنوان ابزاری کارآمد و مؤثر جهت مطالعه جامع مخازن و همچنین مدیریت مخزن قلمداد میشود. در این مطالعه که بر روی یکی از میادین نفتی جنوب غربی ایران صورت گرفته است، هدف شبیهسازی پارامترهای پتروفیزیکی تخلخل مؤثر و تراوایی با روش شبیه¬سازی گوسی متوالی توأم در بخش مخزنی خطیا می باشد. با این شبیه سازی می توان یک مدل سه بعدی از تغییر پارامترهای پتروفیزیکی مخزن ارائه کرد که برای شبیه سازی جریان سیال و شناسایی مناطق مستعد با کیفیت مخزنی بالاتر حائز اهمیت می باشد. برای این منظور از نگارهای تخلخل مؤثر و تراوایی هفت حلقه چاه به همراه داده لرزه ای سه بعدی و نتایج وارون سازی لرزه ای صورت گرفته، استفاده شده است. پس از شبکه بندی مخزن و ایجاد مدل ساختمانی، داده های پتروفیزیکی بزرگ مقیاس شده وارد مدل و سلول مربوط به خود شده است. برای توزیع سه بعدی پارامتر تخلخل مؤثر، با توجه به ارتباط تخلخل مؤثر و نشانگر مقاومت صوتی حاصل از وارون سازی لرزه ای، داده لرزه ای سه بعدی و نگار تخلخل مؤثر بزرگ مقیاس شده در حکم داده اولیه و نشانگر مقاومت صوتی حاصل از وارون سازی لرزه ای به عنوان داده ثانویه در شبیه سازی گوسی متوالی توأم وارد شده اند. برای شبیه سازی تراوایی نیز با توجه به ارتباط خوب مدل تخلخل مؤثر حاصل از شبیه سازی با نگار تراوایی، از تخلخل مؤثر شبیه سازی شده به عنوان داده ثانویه و از نگار تروایی بزرگ مقیاس شده و داده لرزه ای به عنوان داده اولیه استفاده شده است. نتایج حاصل از اعتبارسنجی حاکی از صحت مطالعه حاضر و کارآمد بودن روش شبیه سازی گوسی متوالی توأم در مدل سازی تخلخل مؤثر و تراوایی در این مخزن می باشد.     </OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">تخلخل مژثر</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
تراوایی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 شبیه سازی گوسی متوالی توأم</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 اعتبارسنجی</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/139606182151277984-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>