﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>34</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2009</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Estimation of formation water saturation using cluster analysis, piecewise nonlinear regression and Monte Carlo simulation in a carbonate reservoir, south-west Iran </ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>تخمين اشباع آب سازندي با استفاده از رگرسيون قطعه‌اي غيرخطي، آناليز خوشه‌اي و روش شبيه سازي مونت کارلو در يکي از مخازن هيدروکربوري جنوب غربي ايران</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>هادی</FirstName><LastName>فتاحی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی اراک</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>زهر</FirstName><LastName>ورمزیاری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی اراک</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>مصطفی </FirstName><LastName>یوسفی راد</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی اراک </Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></History><Abstract>Estimation of formation water saturation (Sw) using log data is an important approach in the oil exploration and characterization of a hydrocarbon reservoir. Therefore, it seems that the proper prediction/simulation of Sw is essential. The first objective of this study was to develop a predictive model for Sw estimation based on hybrid cluster analysis with piecewise nonlinear regression, and after that, using the developed model, Sw was simulated by the Monte Carlo simulation (MCS). In order to achieve objectives of this study, a group of 909 data points was used for model construction and 302 data points were employed for assessment of model. The obtained results of MCS modeling indicated that this approach is capable of simulating Sw ranges with a good level of accuracy. The mean of simulated Sw by MCS was obtained as 0.28 m, while this value was achieved as 0.29 m for the measured one. Furthermore, a sensitivity analysis was also conducted to investigate the effects of model inputs on the output of the system. The analysis demonstrated that RHOB is the most influential parameter on Sw among all model inputs. It is noticeable that the proposed hybrid cluster analysis with piecewise nonlinear regression and MCS models should be utilized only in the studied area and the direct use of them in the other conditions is not recommended.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">     تخمين اشباع آب سازندي با استفاده از داده‌هاي چاه‌نگاري، يک روش‌ مهم برای اکتشاف نفت و تعيين ويژگي‌هاي مخزن به حساب مي‌آيد که شبيه‌سازي و تخمين اين پارامتر را امري اجتناب ناپذير مي‌کند. در اين پژوهش در گام نخست براي ايجاد يک مدل و تخمين اشباع آب سازندي از ترکيب آناليز خوشه‌اي با رگرسيون قطعهاي غيرخطي بهره گرفته شده است. در مرحله‌ي بعد به کمک مدل ايجاد شده و روش شبيه سازي مونت کارلو، مقادير اشباع آب سازندي شبيه‌سازي شده است. براي اين کار از بانک اطلاعاتي مجموعه داده‌هاي تصحيح شده در ميدان نفتي مارون استفاده شده است. نتايج بدست آمده از ترکيب آناليز خوشه‌اي با رگرسيون قطعهاي غيرخطي و شبيه‌ساري مونت کارلو نشان از دقت و کارايي قابل قبول اين شبيه‌سازي را مي‌دهد، به طوري که ميانگين مقادير اشباع آب سازندي در مدلسازي با مقادير اندازه‌گيري شده در آزمايشگاه بسيار به هم نزديک مي‌باشند. بعلاوه در اين تحقيق از آناليز حساسيت جهت تعيين موثرترين پارامتر ورودي، در تعيين اشباع آب سازندي استفاده شده است. بر اساس نتايج بدست آمده تاثيرگذارترين متغير در تخمين درجه اشباع آب  لاگ چگالي ميباشد. لازم به ذکر است که نتايج اين پژوهش تنها براي منطقه مورد مطالعه صادق است و براي ساير مناطق تنها استفاده از متودولوژي اين پژوهش توصيه مي‌شود.

</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">اشباع آب سازندي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 روش رگرسيون قطعه‌اي - غيرخطي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 روش آناليز خوشه اي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 روش شبيه سازي مونت کارلو</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
آناليز حساسيت</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13951223124605339-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>