﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>34</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2009</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biostratigraphy and sequence stratigraphy of the Sarvak Formation at Fahliyan Anticline (South of Yasuj) </ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>زيست چينه نگاري و چينه نگاري سکانسي سازند سروک در تاقديس فهليان (جنوب ياسوج)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>امیر</FirstName><LastName>احمدی حیدری</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>صیرفیان</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان </Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></History><Abstract>In this study, biostratigraphy, depositional environment and sequence stratigraphy of the Sarvak Formation at Fahliyan Anticline was studied.  8 species of benthic foraminifera (4 genera) and 8 species of planktonic foraminifera (11 genera) in the study area were recognized. 6 biozones have been recognized by distribution of the foraminifera, which in stratigraphic order are: Favusella washitensis Zone, Orbitolina-Alveolinids Assemblage Zone, Rudist debris Zone, Oligostegina flood Zone, Whiteinella archaeocretacea Zone and Helvetoglobotruncana helvetica Zone. On the basis of these, the age of Albian–Turonian was considered for the Sarvak Formation. Based on petrography and analysis of microfacies features 9 different microfacies types have been recognized, which can be grouped into 3 depositional environments: lagoon, shoal and open marine. The Sarvak Formation represents sedimentation on a carbonate ramp. Sequence stratigraphy analysis led to identification of 4 third-order sequences.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در اين پژوهش زيست چينه نگاري، محيط رسوبي و چينه نگاري سکانسي سازند سروک در برش تاقديس فهليان (جنوب ياسوج) مورد بررسي قرار گرفته است. بر اساس مطالعات انجام شده 8 گونه از فرامينيفرهاي بنتيک (4 جنس) 8 گونه از فرامينيفرهاي پلانکتون (11 جنس) شناسايي شده است. 6 بيوزون بر اساس پخش و پراکندگي فرامينيفرها شناسايي گرديد: Favusella washitensis Zone, Orbitolina-Alveolinids Assemblage Zone, Rudist debris Zone, Oligostegina flood Zone, Whiteinella archaeocretacea Zone, ,Helvetoglobotruncana helvetica Zone. بر اين اساس سن آلبين – تورونين براي سازند سروک در نظر گرفته شد. 
بر اساس مطالعات پتروگرافي و آناليز رخساره¬اي 9 ريز رخساره شناسايي شد که مي‌تواند در 3 گروه درياي باز، سد و تالاب تقسيم شوند. محيط رسوبي سازند سروک رمپ هموکلينال هست. تجزيه و تحليل چينه نگاري سکانسي منجر به شناسايي چهار سکانس رسوبي رده سوم شد.  
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">زاگرس</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
سازند سروک</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 زيست چينه نگاري</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 رمپ</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
چينه نگاري سکانسي</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13951111121064808-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>