﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>34</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2004</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Geochemical Investigation and Mineral Matrix Effect on  Probable Source Rock's Potentiality, Darquain Oilfield in the  Abadan Plain</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle> مطالعه ژئوشیمیائی وتاثیر کانی ماتریکس بر پتانسیل سنگ های منشاء احتمالی میدان نفتی دارخوین واقع در دشت آبادان </VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>بهرام</FirstName><LastName>علیزاده</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه چمران</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>نسیم</FirstName><LastName>آزاد بخت</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه چمران اهواز</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>سید حسین </FirstName><LastName>حسینی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه چمران اهواز</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>الهام</FirstName><LastName>ترهنده</LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی نفت ایران </Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day></History><Abstract>Darquain anticline is located at 5 km northeast of city of Abadan. The axis trend of this oilfield is north through south. In this study, Kazhdumi, Gadvan, Garu and Sargelu Formations in Darquain Oilfield, in Abadan Plain, were analyzed by Rock-Eval 6 instrument. 
S2 vs. TOC plot revealed that kerogen type in this oilfield predominantly is of mixed of types 
II &amp; III. Significant S2 Adsorption by matrix of Kazhdumi Formation in well numbers 1 and 
2 (5.33-14.06 mg HC/gr rock) and Gadvan Formation in well numbers 2 and 3 (3.1-3.2 mg HC/gr rock) is due to low thermal maturity as well as low Gas-Oil Ratio factor. In Garu and Sargelu Formations amounts of adsorbed S2 by matrix are respectedly 0.82 and 0.84 mg HC/gr rock, that represent a medium thermal maturation and medium to high Gas-Oil Ratio factor. Quantity of TOClive  in the Kazhdumi, Gadvan, Garu and Sargelu formations estimated to be  in the range of 0.6-1.6, 0.2-1.9, 1.53 and 8.38 by weight percent respectively. This represents potential for the studied formations fair to excellent petroleum generation. Also the studied wells were modeled, by which the Ro of the source rocks were calculated according to their depth. Also transformation ratio of organic matter and the initial TOC is estimated. Transformation Ratio of Kerogen in studied formations ranges from 0.12 to 0.66. This is in accordance with estimated Easy Ro by PBM software (0.5-0.8). It can then be concluded that Kazhdumi Formation is in early oil window and already started to generate hydrocarbon. This is also verified by Tmax data. The Gas-Oil Ratio of Kazhdumi and Gadvan Formations is 0-1 indicating variable hydrocarbon generation. Also this factor for Garu and Sargelu is 0.58-1 indicates that they have more gas generation potential rather than oil generation potential. 
The inferences drawn from It can be inferenced from iso TOCoil and TOCgas maps led to the conclution that, in west and southwestern parts of the basin, the depth during deposition of mentioned formations was more in compare to other parts of Darquain.  
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">تاقدیس دارخوین در فاصله 5 کیلو متری شمال شرقی آبادان واقع است .این میدان داراری امتداد محوری شمالی جنوبی است . در این مطالعه سازند های کژدمی ،گدوان ،گرو وسرگلو میدان نفتی دارخوین در دشت آبادان مورد آنالیز راک ایول 6قرار گرفته است .نمودار S2 در مقابل کل کربن آلی (TOC) نشان داد که تیپ کروژن این میدان غالباًمخلوطی از نوع II وIII می باشد. مقدار قابل توجه S2 جذب شده توسط ماتریکس در چاه های شماره 1و2 سازند کژدمی (5.33-14.06mgHC/gr rock)
وچاه های 2و3 سازند گدوان (mgHC/gr  rock  3.1-3.2) به علت بلوغ حرار تی نسبتاً کم ونسبت پائین گاز-نفت می باشد .در سازند های گرو سر گلو مقدار s2 جذب شده توسط ماتریکس به ترتیب 82/0و84/0mgHC/gr rock بوده ،که دارای بلوغ حرارتی نسبتاً متوسط ونسبت گاز-نفت متوسط تا بالا می باشند .مقدار کربن آلی فعال در سازند های کژدمی 6/1-6/0گدوان 9/1-2/0،گرو53/1وسرگلو 38/8 درصد وزنی است که بیانگر سنگ منشاهائی دارای توان هیدرو کربور زائی متوسط تا غنی می باشد .هم چنین چاه های مورد مطالعه مدل سازی شده ومقدار Ro  سازند های سنگ مشاء بر حسب عق محاسبه ،ونسبت تبدیل ماده الی ودر نتیجه TOC اولیه برآورد گردید .نسبت دگر سائی کروژن در سازند های مطالعه شده در محدوده 66/0-12/0بوده که با توجه به Ro% Easy بد ست آمده از نرم افزار PBM 9/0-5/0می تواند نشانگر قرار گیری سنگ منشاهای مذکور به استثنای سازند کژدمی (Easy   RO%=0.5-0.65)در اوایل پنجره نفتی وآغاز تولید هیدرو کربن باشد ،که با مقادیر Tmax نیز تائید می شود .فاکتور گاز-نفت سازند های مذکور برای سازند های کژدمی وگدوان (1-0) نشان گر محدوده متغیر پتانسیل زایی وگاز زائی این سازند ها می باشد .هم چنین این فاکتور برای سازند های گرو وسر گلو (1-58/0)،نشان می دهد که پتانسیل گاز زائی این سازند ها بیشتر از نفت زائی آنهاست .از نقشه های هم ارزش TOCoil وTOCgasسازند کژدمی می توان استنباط نمودکه عمق حوضه در زمان ته نشست سازند مذکور ،در غرب وجنوب غرب میدان بیشتر از قسمت های دیگر میدان بوده است .
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">تاثیر ماتریکس</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
سنگ منشاء</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 آنالیز راک ایول </Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 نسبت گاز-نفت</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
میدان نفتی دارخوین </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13950207115792044-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>