﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>34</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2007</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>A comparison of the Surmeh and Dalan formations reservoir potential in the Persian Gulf</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>مقايسه پتانسيل مخزني سازندهاي سورمه و دالان در خليج فارس</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList /><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></History><Abstract>
Abstract
The giant oil and gas fields in the northern Persian Gulf correspond to reservoir intervals which comprise Surmeh and Dalan formations. The main production units in these formations are their upper carbonates with typically ooid grainstone to dolostone lithofacies. As a comparative study the petrophysical characteristics of these formations were considered based on core logging, well logging and petrography of thin sections. The upper carbonate unit of the Surmeh Formation was studied in the Tabnak Field and the Dalan Formation in the South Pars Field. The average porosities were 17.15% and 8.50% for the Surmeh and Dalan reservoirs respectively. Their permeability’s were 308 md for the Surmeh and 30 md for the Dalan reservoirs. This contrast in porosity-permeability data of the studied reservoirs correspond to their depositional and diagenetic history. The high reservoir potential of the Surmeh Formation correspond to its interparticle primary porosity partly remained after partial early cementation and its intercrystalline porosity due to dolomitization. This is different in the Dalan Formation which had a different diagenetic history and its porosity mainly reduced during compactional processes during the burial as well as burial cementation. However, although the Surmeh reservoir has a higher porosity and permeability, it has a lower production yield, because of its limited source rock and migration pathways. 

</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">چكيده
سازندهاي سورمه و دالان به ترتيب سنگ مخزن بزرگ¬ترين ميدان¬هاي نفت و گاز منطقه خليج فارس هستند. بخش اصلي سنگ مخزن اين دو سازند در واحدهاي کربنات بالايي آنها قرار گرفته و از رخساره اُاُييد گرينستون و دولوستون¬هاي مختلف تشکيل شده است. مقايسه داده¬هاي پتروفيزيکي حاصل از بررسي مغزه¬ها، مقاطع نازک و نمودارهاي چاه پيمايي دالان بالايي در ميدان پارس جنوبي و سورمه بالايي در ميدان تابناک گواه آن است که ميانگين تخلخل در مخزن سورمه 15/17% (درجه خيلي خوب) و در مخزن دالان 50/8% (درجه متوسط) است. همچنين، ميانگين تراوايي در مخزن سورمه 308 (خيلي خوب) و در مخزن دالان 30 (متوسط) ميلي دارسي تعيين گرديد. از عوامل اصلي تفاوت آشکار بين خواص مخزني دو سازند مورد مطالعه بايد به شرايط و محيط رسوبگذاري، بافت و کاني شناسي اوليه و تاريخچه دياژنتيکي متفاوت آنها اشاره کرد. کاهش محسوس خصوصيات مخزني سازند دالان با افزايش عمق بيانگر تأثير زياد دفن عميق همراه با افزايش تراکم و تشکيل سيمان در اين سازند است. در مقابل، پتانسيل بالاي مخزن سورمه ناشي از حفظ تخلخل بين دانه¬اي در اثر سيماني شدن ناقص پيش از تدفين و گسترش تخلخل بين بلوري حاصل از دولوميتي شدن آن است. نبود ارتباط کافي با سنگ منشأ مناسب سبب شده است که سازند سورمه علي رغم کيفيت مخزني بهتر و ضخامت بيشتر در شمال خليج فارس از درجه اشباع هيدروکربن و توان توليد کمتري برخوردار باشد
</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">پتانسيل مخزني</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 سازند سورمه</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 سازند دالان</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
خليج فارس </Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13941127938131105-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>