﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2010</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biostratigraphy and microfacies of the Asmari Formation in north flank of Khami anticline (north of Gachsaran)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>زیست چینه‌نگاری و ریزرخساره‌های سازند آسماری در یال شمالی تاقدیس خامی (شمال گچساران)</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>25</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>منا</FirstName><LastName>رحیم‌آبادی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>علی</FirstName><LastName>صیرفیان</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>حسین</FirstName><LastName>وزیری مقدم</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>فرزاد</FirstName><LastName>ستوهیان</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></History><Abstract>In the present study, biostratigraphy, microfacies and sedimentary environment of the Asmari Formation in north flank of the Khami anticline in the north of the Gachsaran province is investigated. The Asmari Formation at the study section with a thickness of 276 meters is a thin, medium and thick to massive limestone, nodular limestone, marl, marly limestone, dolomite and dolomitic limestone. In this study 166 thin sections are studied and 23 genera and 24 species of foraminifera have been identified and 3 biozones are introduced. 
1-	Archaias 	asmaricus-Archaias 	hensoni-Miogypsinoides 	complanatus 
Assemblage zone. (Chattian) 
2-	Indeterminate zone (Aqutanian) 
3-	Borelis melo curdica-Borelis melo melo Assemblage zone. (Burdigalian) 
Thus, the age of the Asmari Formation at the study area is Chattian to Burdigalian (Oligo-Miocene).
Based on study of thin sections and by considering the sediment texture, distribution of skeletal and non-skeletal grains, 12 microfacies are recognized which were deposited in open marine, bar, semi-restricted and restricted lagoon. Four platform types for the Asmari Formation at the study area in comparison with the recent studies on Asmari Formation including: 1-Rupelian-lower Chattian: Distally steepend ramp, 2-middle Chattian-upper Chattian: open shelf, 3-Aqiutanian: homoclinal ramp, 4-lower Burdigalian: carbonate platform.</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این مطالعه زیست چینه‌نگاری، ریزرخساره‌ها و محیط رسوبی سازند آسماری در برش یال شمالی تاقدیس خامی در شمال شهرستان گچساران مورد مطالعه قرار گرفته‌است. سازند آسماری در این برش با 276 متر ضخامت دارای سنگ‌شناسی آهک نازک لایه، متوسط و ضخیم تا توده‌ای، آهک ندولار، مارن، آهک مارنی، دولومیت و آهک دولومیتی می‌باشد. با مطالعه 166 مقطع نازک میکروسکوپی، تعداد 23 جنس و 24 گونه شناسایی و براساس آن 3 زون زیستی برای سازند آسماری در این برش تعیین گردید که شامل زون‌های Archaias asmaricus-Archaias hensoni-Miogypsinoides complanatus Assemblage zone. Indeterminate zone. Borelis melo curdica-Borelis melo melo Assemblage zone.  می‌باشد. با توجه به زون‌های زیستی موجود سن سازند آسماری در این برش از شاتین تا بوردیگالین تعیین شده‌است. همچنین بر اساس مطالعات ریزرخساره‌ها 12 ریزرخساره شناسایی شد که در دریای باز، سد بیوکلاستی و لاگون نیمه محصور تا محصور ته نشست شده اند. چهار نوع پلاتفرم در این ناحیه در مقایسه  با سایر مطالعات اخیر صورت گرفته بر روی سازند آسماری شناسایی شد شامل: رمپ با انتهای شیب‌دار در زمان روپلین- شاتین زیرین، شلف باز در زمان شاتین میانی-بالایی، رمپ هموکلینال در زمان آکی‌تانین، پلتفرم کربناته در زمان بوردیگالین زیرین.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">سازند آسماری تاقدیس خامی الیگوسن-میوسن ریزرخساره‌ها فرامینیفرهای کف‌زی بزرگ</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/13970820165509-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>