﻿<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ArticleSet><Article><Journal><PublisherName>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </PublisherName><JournalTitle>مجله زمین شناسی نفت ایران </JournalTitle><ISSN>8738-2251</ISSN><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>34</Issue><PubDate PubStatus="epublish"><Year>2008</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></Journal><ArticleTitle>Fractures systematic analysis Asmari reservoir Formation in the Marun oil field (based on image logs interpretation results)</ArticleTitle><VernacularTitle>  تحليل سيستماتيك شكستگي‌هاي مخزن آسماري در ميدان نفتي مارون (بر اساس تفسير نتايج نمودارهای تصويرگر</VernacularTitle><FirstPage>1</FirstPage><LastPage>10</LastPage><ELocationID EIdType="doi" /><Language>FA</Language><AuthorList><Author><FirstName>میثم</FirstName><LastName>فارسی مدان</LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی نفت ایران </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>محمدرضا </FirstName><LastName>مهدور</LastName><Affiliation>شرکت ملی نفت ایران </Affiliation></Author><Author><FirstName>زهرا</FirstName><LastName>کمالی</LastName><Affiliation>دانشگاه بیرجند</Affiliation></Author></AuthorList><History PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>29</Day></History><Abstract>
In the oil buildings to investigate fractures in the reservoir rock fractures in stages of production and field development is very important and necessary. Now application of software repository in the realization of this issue will help to petroleum with the geologists.. Marun oil field is one of the largest oil fields in the South West Iran of the city of Ahvaz in the Northeast and the North embayment Dezful of geology in the eastern. Marun field is the most important Asmari reservoir. The aim of this study was to investigate systematically Asmari reservoir fractures and the development of fractures in the reservoir. For this purpose, using image logs, best and most complete method interpretation and results of 11 wells in fracture studying and 16 wells in in-situ stress direction studying. According to frequency of fractures (based on image logs interpretation results) in the southern and north-eastern limb of the field, The theory of tectonic folding and bending events later caused the possible activities during the north-south strike-slip faults affect the compression force has been created to strengthen. Most of image logs data in Marun field are fractures with extensions; N155E, N130E, N95E, N60E, N30E.
</Abstract><OtherAbstract Language="FA">در مطالعه ساختمان هاى نفتى، بررسي شكستگي‌هاي سنگ مخزن در مراحل توليد و توسعه ميدان بسيار مهم و ضروري است. امروزه به كارگيري نرم افزارهاى مخزنى در تحقق اين مسئله به زمين شناسان نفتي كمك شاياني مي‌نمايد. ميدان نفتي مارون يكي از بزرگترين ميادين نفتي جنوب باختر ايران محسوب مي‌شود که در شمال خاور شهر اهواز و از لحاظ زمين‌شناسي در قسمت خاوري حوضه فروافتاده دزفول شمالي قرار گرفته است. سازند آسماری مهم‌ترین سنگ مخزن میدان مارون مي‌باشد. هدف از اين تحقيق، بررسي سيستماتيك شكستگي‌هاي مخزن آسماري و نحوه گسترش اين شكستگي ها در مخزن مذكور است. براي اين منظور استفاده از نمودارهای تصویرگر بهترین و کامل‌ترین روش بوده و لذا نتایج تفسیر نمودارهای تصویرگر 11 حلقه چاه در مطالعه شكستگي ها و 16 حلقه چاه در مطالعه جهت تنش برجا مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. با توجه به فراوانی شکستگی ها (براساس تفسير نمودارهاي تصويري درچاه ها) در یال جنوبی و شمال خاوری ميدان، نظریه وقوع دو حادثه تکتونیکی چین‌خوردگی و خمش که بعدها در اثر فعالیت‌های احتمالی در طول گسل‌های امتداد لغز شمالی- جنوبی تحت تأثیر نیروهای تراکمی ایجاد شده است را قوت می بخشد. داده‌های نمودارهای تصویری اين چاه‌ها در میدان مارون دسته شکستگی‌های غالب با امتدادهای N155E, N130E ,N95E ,N60E ,N30E دیده می شوند.</OtherAbstract><ObjectList><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">ساختمان نفتی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
نمودارهای تصویرگر</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
شکستگی</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
میدان مارون</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
 فروافتادگی دزفول</Param></Object><Object Type="Keyword"><Param Name="Value">
</Param></Object></ObjectList><ArchiveCopySource DocType="Pdf">http://journal.ispg.ir/WebUsers/ispg/UploadFiles/OK/139503091026302423-F.pdf</ArchiveCopySource></Article></ArticleSet>